this is a production of Cornell
University so today we'll sort of have
three portions um the first portion uh I
will focus on why Garden based learning
is so important um followed by Roger's
portion where he'll talk a little bit
about the Cooperative Extension intern
program and then Megan will sort of wrap
things up with her experience from her
internship this summer in Skylar County
and then we'll have some time for
questions so at this time I'd really
like to know who is an attendance so if
you could please take a moment to sort
of share who you are and what your focus
is um if you could type that into the
chat box it would be
wonderful great thank you
Paulina she's interested in starting a
gardening program in Lewis County thank
you so much that's great so Paulina is
just starting out and um it's very
exciting it's a very exciting stage to
be in who else is out
there Jen Jen Clancy forage Garden Club
leader awesome thanks Jen I'd like to
have just a few more so we can see who
is with us looks like we have April
April a nutrition educator in Jefferson
County Farm the school coordinator
wonderful looks like we have a good
diverse group today some people starting
out and some people who have been in the
field for some time have some experience
under their belts some people focused on
nutrition others on Horticulture it's
just that's great thank you it's great
to know who is in
attendance so we can talk a little bit
about why gardening uh kind of goes hand
inand with Cooperative Extension so
Cooperative extension's mission is to
enable people to improve their lives and
community Through Partnerships and our
cor Cornell garden-based learning
mission is to provide Educators with
inspiring research-based gardening
resources and professional development
to support engaging empowering and
relevant learning experiences for
children youth adults and
communities uh we do follow the 4
Mission in empowering youth to reach
their full potential working and
learning in partnership with caring
adults so you can see that these
missions really go hand inand um and we
really lean on each other it's a great
partnership so in my portion um this is
Fiona speaking I will really like to lay
down some sort of research based
findings on why garden-based learning is
so important so before I start I'd like
to sort of see why do you think this
work is important if you could just take
a moment to share why you believe Garden
based learning uh is Meaningful in in
your work or your personal
life you can type that into the chat box
it would be great
awesome thank you
Colleen people learn more when doing
handson work and are more willing to
come to learn to appreciate appreciate
our environment hopefully we conserve it
so
true Megan any people anytime people can
get out into nature and get hands-on
experience they appreciate
more now they're coming in
fast can I you people back to their food
source from Paulina thank you Jen says
it encourages healthy eating and teaches
where food comes from these are all
wonderful
points April said kids learn best by
doing non-traditional Learners can grft
Concepts that may struggle with from a
textbook you can teach anything through
growing and preparing food I agree April
thank you
awesome thank you
everybody so really Our Hope for this
future generation is that they respect
and care for the natural world I think
we can all agree upon
that but the reality is that there is a
extreme disconnect with nature in this
future
generation children are inre
increasingly disconnected from nature
due to overstructured schedules loss of
Green Space parental fear and the
prevalence of
electronics and if children are losing
their connection with
nature who will care enough about
wildlife and Open Spaces to advocate in
10 or 20
years if children don't have direct
intimate experiences with nature they
will not care if it goes away they need
good times in the outdoors to realize
how wonderful it is to dig in the mud to
eat fresh berries to appreciate the hard
work of bees this in time with nature
should start early and continue through
life what we're experiencing is nature
deficit disorder sort of coined by
Richard BL um it's real and it's
happening I actually found this
yesterday uh from the big book of nature
activities a year round guys to Outdoor
Living um and it just sort of States
some really interesting figures for us
to look at so 2500 is the number of
advertising messages a child Encounters
in one day that is
crazy
2738 is the number of hours the average
North American child sits in front of a
glowing screen per year
wow 183 of the number of hours a child
spends outdoors in unstructured play per
year wish that figure was swapped with
the one above
it and 300 is the percentage that
obesity has increased over the past 20
years for children age 6 to
11 it's just
astonishing 300 is also the number of
corporate logos the average child can
identify but only 10 is the number of
native plants and animals that the
average child can
identify and I feel like these figures
you know aren't just appropriate and
sort of relevant to children but also
our society as a
whole so our job is to really bring that
connect Back To
Nature so our hope our children will be
physically active and healthy the little
girl is so cute on her Barbie
bike but the
reality is something much different half
of American kids do not meet the
physical activity
guidelines they get 46 hours of video
games or television play a
day that means there's less time for
them to outside exploring playing
getting muddy and dirty finding trees
and falling out of them all those really
important sort of pieces to
Childhood I do feel that childhood is a
critical time to establish healthy
lifestyle
habits another hope is that our children
will be nutritionally healthy and food
secure which means they can access and
consume safe affordable culturally
appropriate nutrient filled
Foods there the reality is that they're
nutritionally
deficient factors include poor access
lack of
affordability convenience and habits
many youed live in food deserts and have
limited access to healthful
Foods approximately 18% of Americans Age
2 to n years are obese and obesity is
the number one Health concern among
parents in the United States that's TS
drugs and smoking that's
crazy our hope is that our children will
have the education that they need to
feel empowered to establish leadership
and
confidence this is such an important
foundational time to establish these
things and to try new things and to ask
questions but the actual
is kind of fallen into a fit or fail
school system I education has become
streamlined teaching has become to hit
the standards and the standardized tests
it's not for the
individual and really memorization has
taken over
Mastery there's less time for critical
thinking creativity and
Imagination education has become rigid
and
strict and I can definitely Echo this
portion where I felt like
you know when I was in school it was
more about jumping through hoops and
memorizing things for an a rather than
really using my critical thinking
skills so to fuel the future of kids we
have to think about their entire entire
lifestyle I hope that wasn't too much
Doom and Gloom for you but it's really
important to share that this information
it's critical at this point in time in
our society
and now to the B stuff that Gardens are
a wonderful gateway to learning and
Discovery for the whole child look at
that Garden I wish I was there right now
it's so
beautiful so let's talk about some of
the positive effects of
gardening so children who Garden are
more comfortable with the outdoors have
increased awareness and appreciation for
the natural world
world have ownership responsibility they
become environmental stewards they
establish that important sense of wonder
and desire to ask
questions you there have been studies
that show that the love of gardening is
not so much about gardening but about
making
decisions having the freedom to make
your own decisions is incredibly
powerful and this can happen in the
garden I love this John brough's quote
that knowledge without love will not
stick but if love comes first then
knowledge is sure to
follow we need to connect kids back to
that love of
nature children who Garden also have
improved nutrition and health
awareness healthy eating can help
prevent or delay chronic conditions and
Studies have shown that kids who plant
it eat it or at least try it
these healthy food choices start during
childhood and will continue through
adulthood early exposure is
key there have also been studies that
children who Garden have higher learning
achievements they have higher test
course especially in science and
math they also discover unique personal
strength
and feel more I can and I
belong they learn to make decisions and
problem solves they gain greater
self-esteem they learn interpersonal
skills teamwork and I'm more likely to
build stronger relationships with others
and they're more engaged in their
communities which I think is really
important and
wonderful gardening in schools it
increases achievement scores increases
parental involvement and Community
involvement really supplements that
Hands-On learning that might not be
already be in the school
system enhances storytelling written
expression read and comprehension and
spelling just overall it's
wonderful and gardening might provide
you know that type of learning that's
more Hands-On and experiential so there
really is something for
everyone and the benefits of gardening
aren't just for youth therefore all ages
uh it enhances mental health helps
reduce stress lowers your blood pressure
it leaves muscle tension and helps
combat obesity I know that when I've had
a hard day at work or somewhere else
that when I get home once I start
weeding and pruning and caring for my
plants I feel a whole lot better it's
just
therapeutic here's a quote from a child
that I think just about sums everything
up gardening makes me happy it makes me
proud of me gardening makes me feel
healthy I can garden with family and
friends I love
it so as you can see in our garden we
are growing way more than plants this
work is important this work is real we
are cultivating passion and empowerment
with the Next
Generation we are empowering both Youth
and adults to become more
to become environmental stewards and to
care for their natural world we are
inspiring Youth and adults to make
healthier choices and Lead healthier
lives all right well I hope that sort of
gave you a good foundation of why Garden
based learning is so powerful and uh
especially critical at this moment of
time um now I'd like to turn it over to
Roger all right thank you
Fiona um let's TR for over here to make
sure we can I can work these slides for
youall uh and good morning thank you for
being here today um my perspective here
is a little bit from a cooperate
extension uh educator and how we have
this is our second year with
uh College of agon Life Sciences um
intern so we've gone through the program
now I think we applied four years and
we've won an intern for two years so I
wanted to share and I apologize my first
slides are going to be a little bit on
the boring wordy side but it's how we
wrote for our intern because I thought
it was more important for me to share
with you the wording uh that we use
because I believe that's important on on
how you're developing your program to
make it fit a course for yourself but
also how that it works uh for Cornell to
be able to provide one of these interns
uh which has just been a blessing um
having Megan this year and Britney last
year if anybody sat through Britney's
presentation last year uh these are both
great youth and and really benefited our
program beyond what I can put on these
slides so let me go to my first slide
here and I apologize again it's going to
be a little wordy but maybe you can use
this in when you're
writing so the project summary and
intended outcomes that we identified
were the interest in gardening is
growing throughout New York State and
CCE continues to explore the most
Innovative avenues for which to educate
and Inspire
citizens demonstration Gardens have
proven to be an important arena for a
number of significant learning
opportunities Skyler CCE has identified
the need for a continued a strengthened
approach to a local demonstration garden
as a way to help hundreds of local
residents learn more about ptic culture
and area Educators learn from our
success so it's also about sharing you
know and everything so sorry oh that's
all right that's all right thank you
f so and a pict of I'll just explain a
little bit on you know some of our
different things there um before I go on
the reading this side so there are some
must strawberries that we have from a
specialty collector that we got some
strawberries donated and that's our figs
uh growing in our garden uh Chicago
hardy uh so we do some weird things and
we do a lot of common things in the
Coronel vegetable trials things like
that so um we try to mix a lot of
different things in for the uh intern
experience um so part two of the project
summary and intended outcomes here on
this slide this Garden based learning
intern will help Skylar CCE build upon
the success of last Summer's internship
to further develop utilize and maximize
the educational benefits of the
attractive spacious teaching Garden
which lies adjacent to the CCE office
complex and was established five years
ago as an outdoor
classroom um the initial progress of our
garden was a um a grant um a health
Department of Health Grant from our
local community uh we adopted the grant
to fit um the proposal for our garden
and got us established which I'll show
you some slides here later um so we're
trying to to keep this teaching Garden
idea um we call it teaching Garden arc
when they come to visit they call it the
Learning Garden because of what they get
out of working with us in the Community
Partnerships that we've
developed so
next I want to spoil us and show us a
little bit of winter here because I know
we're so excited about getting through
summer uh so this is I think this year
this is going to be the best time in my
garden is a feel that nice snow out
there uh so continuing on the summary
and intended outcomes here the summer
intern will begin with an overview of
important initiatives such as
sustainability diversity and inclusion
as well as practical guidance related to
stakeholder needs assessment and success
uccessful program development processes
help develop and deliver a season long
curriculum with input from the
leadership share the results of the
approach through diverse documentation
which will include a web-based success
story uh to be distributed through CCE
news in the Cornell Garden based
learning blog and potentially host a
regional Workshop to share with other CC
educators are learnings from the
trajectory of a two-year internship
experience of a growing audience base so
this is that part there where the
regional Workshop to share uh with you
other Educators uh what we have learned
and that's my goal here today and we'll
have plenty of time for questions at the
end uh because we want you to to take
this we feel really blessed that we were
uh awarded an intern two years in a row
and we've made so many strides with our
garden due to that intern of working
with audiences that uh in the past I I
was not a full-time Horticulture
educator so how would we could pull this
off with just a part-time and and now
luckily this year event I'm back
fulltime um has worked to our benefit so
next okay the students
roll too
far okay so the brief description of the
student interns role and
responsibilities
so under the supervision of the
collaborators listed above that would
have been in our in our writing for our
intern um we will participate in a
preparation session which I think Fiona
and Marsha worked with Megan to get her
started and give her a little background
about the garden based learning develop
and deliver targeted educational
programs for both Youth and adult
audiences we work with Head Start is in
our building Arc uh has a group home
nearby uh they've come out twice a week
would' like to come out three times a
week uh Wick uh is in our building on
Fridays pens is youth at risk program in
our building and we worked with those uh
which there was a lot of boys that one
evening um they were a lot of fun and 4
as a teaching garden with guidance in
intentionally adapting uh Cornell
garden-based learning
curricula create enhance and Lead
activities which support the maintenance
of the garden observe how volunteers are
developed supervised and rewarded and
work with Educators to implement two
volunteer trainings and gain experiences
monitor for pests collect data and
variety trials we're always getting
plants donated um the most recent ones I
can think of were the Ruckers cranberry
trials that we did but we did straw Bell
trials you know variety trials so we're
always getting some things from Cornell
um strawberries and so on like that and
lastly they're reporting share the
results regionally and Statewide to
educate and Inspire others uh Megan's
part of this is going to be the the most
beneficial to all you uh of all the
projects hopefully that we've given her
successfully through this
year what qualifications were needed uh
so in writing for the intern we had to
identify those so the candidate will
need to ex need excellent written and
oral communication
skills a genuine desire and documented
interest in working with people is
necessary she or he should be intended
of detail and should possess a general
knowledge of and enthusiasm for
gardening and home food
production and lastly there a desire to
work with a variety of audiences and an
interest in the ability to perform
physical work in outdoor
conditions um all these are really
crucial and I'm just going to step back
through these one more time um written
and oral skills uh for Megan has been
her blog and her ability to write
articles for us that have just been
exceptional uh working with people
you're working with Garden volunteers
one minute you're working with an
audience of maybe youth at risk uh the
next moment so she was put in various uh
programs that she'll talk more on um an
enthusiasm for gardening I think
whenever I interviewed Megan uh she had
worked for a CSA last year um and had
really shown even though Megan she'll
tell you more of it she's from a animal
Science Background really had a love of
plants along with that and that was
necessary for this to work out really
well uh and in that last one they
working with a variety of audiences and
interest to perform physical work in
outdoor conditions this year working
outside in the garden if you didn't like
a little bit of heat it would not have
worked at all so so Megan uh
has this Keen ability to be able to work
in the heat more than probably I was
even able to um uh so it was
extraordinary to find a youth that that
really tolerated all right so next uh
benefits and skills that we could
hopefully even provide our intern so we
said to increase knowledge of CCE
successful program development process
we bring that to the table basic
gardening and local food production
experience
uh volunteer
development written and oral expression
in turn will gain significant experience
and facilitating learning experiences
both all adult and youth audiences in an
outdoor classroom environment through
the co-leadership of numerous classes
and activities so we just try to develop
uh a listing of what we're giving back
um we take a lot from an intern probably
in any of the programs but what are we
giving them back that they can take with
them Beyond um uh her experience here
and for Megan I think I signed her
farewell card with uh if you grow others
you grow yourself and so that sort of
follows with Fiona's little tagline
there that we we do more of it just grow
plants uh the audiences that we reach
really have this need to learn gardening
and it's so neat to see an intern work
with those audiences and and hopefully
we we provided that
opportunity so here is my welcome slide
before I go through a little bit about
our garden on there but uh here's a
little where I wanted to get you to chat
a little bit is what type of gardens do
you want to work with or already working
with back home um ideas would be you
know do you have a teaching Garden or
Learning Garden like ours are you more
working in a community garden a school
garden a food plot I know some of you
answered a little bit with Fiona but
just drop me down like what audiences or
or what type of garden are you planning
back home or already have but you're
utilizing so I'll give you a minute here
before I move on okay we work with you
to elderly and workshops but do not have
a designated area or garden this is our
next wish to have in our program thank
you
Colleen uh Katie I'm hoping to get some
demonstration Gardens going in Orleans
County we started with two small raised
beds one dedicated to herbs and the
other to pollinator native plants thank
you Katie
well keep them rolling in everybody I'm
going to move on a little bit to the
Garden here uh here's our little welcome
board um this is the center of a
teaching platform that we have uh that
we developed in our garden with you can
see some benches sort of there and
there's eight poles that are for um
grapes uh whoops I got April we hoping
to help more local school Implement
Gardens and garden education in addition
to local procurement thank you
April um so this little teaching
platform you I'll have a little better
picture of so as I said a couple years
ago Department of Health in Skyler
County uh had this
grant um why you have connections in
your community is they contacted us that
nobody had applied for this grant uh
that's like not heard of anymore there's
probably people fighting over grants so
they said Roger we know you're new but
we've heard you want to establish a
garden this was a big grass plot out
along the road uh they said we can help
you do that if you write for this grant
you are pretty much the only person so
far uh so I wrote for this Grant and
this was not to be uh taken lightly this
was $7,500 I think to start it um we
used it for infrastructure we be we
built this teaching platform and you'll
see an arbor that we put over top of
some picnic tables that were out in the
middle of nowhere nobody would come out
and sit because the three picnic tables
we're in the baking sun and we also put
a little Arbor for our entrance uh and
you'll see this packed gravel that's
around here this is all wheelchair
accessible and also the raised beds were
made for wheelchair height um we did all
that with the initial I would say 95% of
the plants were all I wrote different
companies and they were all more than
willing to donate plants so we have paid
for very little of the plants um and I
feel blessed at this point my I have a
little Nursery at home that I've been
able to donate some plants this year uh
to help the garden along because it's
really my passion uh so I did donated
some fruiting plants this year so we
just keep adding as we go so here is I
think the first couple weeks after it
was developed um with the raise planners
the um teaching platform in the middle
which is sort of an Old English style
Amphitheater the Big Arbor down at the
end we beefed up because we put Hardy
kiwi on top of those and off to the
right of the picture you can't see would
have been our uh wheelchair entrance off
of the main uh walkway coming in um
because we wanted to make sure this
Garden was developed for all folks to to
be able to participate in our
programs this was probably now about two
years back Megan was laughing at me she
said if you took this picture today you
couldn't see through any of this cuz
that big Quinn in the foreground and his
elderberries have probably doubled that
size uh the grap Vines have taken over
that whole Arbor so you feel like you're
in an inclosure uh now that they have
grown um so the garden has really taken
off and this is all just volunteer
because like I said I was only part-time
as of last year um so volunteers our
first three Master Gardeners came out of
Tomkins County last year so we didn't
even have a Master Gardener
program uh so yeah Megan loves this
picture I caught her right when the bug
bitter uh but so this is some of our
like Master Gardeners our G our garden
volunteers our uh nutrition staff and
Megan working on a ladybug adoption
night where we Department of animology
was donating or not donating but um had
bred the nine spotted ladybugs and we
had a adopt them and release them in our
garden night uh so you know this is a
good diversity because it is four
different groups together working in the
garden at one
time this is something uh and I said I
won't be labor these because Megan's
going to show you uh this is a lot of
her work this is her ladybug adoption um
flyer we make the interns we we teach
them and then we make them do everything
that we would do create Flyers book
rooms uh help with the speakers uh with
the ladybugs she went along we picked
them up up at Cornell uh it was a cool
experience of videotaping the ladybug
larve um so this was just one of her
Flyers that she created she'll talk more
about that later she did this trifold
which was just a real creative uh all
about ladybugs for kids uh we gave that
out the night that the folks came in and
adopted and I think we had as many
adults as kids adopt ladybugs that night
it was really just a cool um educational
event and in the
garden okay Community groups U we Mar we
talked about Arc this is the arc group
that was out in the garden um uh pins
diversion is youth at risk uh we we all
know wck had Start programs in our
building office for the Aging in our
building department of social services
has a work crew that we have worked with
uh and they have expressed like how
great it is to learn gardening skills
when they're already teaching their
participants work related uh skills so
they really appreciate coming out to our
garden and this just a little history
behind this slide is the folks from Arc
had gone to a Rain Barrel um building
workshop uh somewhere else not at our
garden they loved our garden so much
you'll see the water is light there they
donated their Barrel to our garden uh so
it's really incredible that they thought
about us uh and we love working with
them Megan will talk more about
that of course uh on our previous slides
uh Megan has worked on uh her internship
blog it is amazing she'll talk more
about it there please go on
there I'm not nearly that creative of
putting videos into my blogs I'm lucky
and I could just type A a simple letter
to you guys so uh so these youth bring
other skills that that I I feel bad that
I don't know
better our plant Sines is our CL the
fame in our garden um Megan was thrown
right into any new varieties you'll see
some of these were from my farm um
donated uh we Tred to get the newest
plant material that we see that is
available that folks want to learn and
these are some bush cherries from
University of New Hampshire uh the meter
program I believe um so when we bring
that in
automatically gets a signp put on it
because the garden is 247 open folks
come there to learn they're welcome to
taste tests it is just of course the
deer visit as much as people do uh we're
working on that um but so the signage is
the most important thing so Megan got to
do a lot of signs a lot of research on
the varieties um it's a lot of work
researching where they came from giving
credit
um designing the so
on uh along with our signage is our
nutrition I believe and Megan would
probably talk more about it that there's
12 um sort of like those brochure
holders that you would get for an open
house at a home that's for sale they're
clear with a flip top lid we have them
space all around our garden and we try
to put them either with timely planting
information or here some of our uh
nutrition
education um one slide you saw our
nutrition educator Lisa is just
part-time and she's at Camp during the
summer we have no other nutrition staff
so without an intern I would not be able
to look up recipes and get them out to
the Garden I just would not have time
for that so so she was able to get
timely recipes out there when crops were
coming ready obviously here kale and
rhar were in season in the garden uh so
she kept up with that and we and we did
some monitoring and Meg talk more about
like how many do we put out there how
many were taken you know things like
that we did some some um recordkeeping
also this is um Master Garden program is
back after a long Hiatus in Skyler
County so she was um tasted to get a
Master Gardener we want you kind of deal
you know little we went through ideas of
like Uncle Sam you know or or we had a
Batman theme for R be a superhero be a
master Garder in Skyler County
so we worked long and hard on uh
developing uh because our Master
Gardeners go out to local farmers
markets and stuff on like how do we find
past present and future Master Gardeners
to our program so we developed this on
there
um on on developing a master Gard
program summer wreck this is Megan
she'll talk more about this um she went
out with our youth educator Paula so
this was a 4 event uh up to a summer
Recreation program in Odessa New York
and worked with you for many ages like I
said I'm not going to steal Megan Sunder
but just wanted to share that we do
outside events get our intern out of the
garden so she's not out there sweating
every day how can we get her out and
utilize her and I heard she did a
wonderful Turtle project that she'll
talk to you about more little publisher
we've worked hard on this I started this
but we keep up with this little drawing
every time you um put new plants in they
get uh updated on here and when we had
some permaculture tour go through last
year they were really impressed uh that
a garden map existed they go to a lot of
deat gardens but nobody really puts
where the plants are for you to find
them you just sort of randomly come
across them so the Garden map was really
uh a great thing uh for for folks who
visited us
um so I think Megan it's your turn so
thank you everybody I'll take questions
at the end
then right uh hopefully you guys can
hear me okay
um as Roger and Fiona said my name is
Megan uh I was the Skyler County summer
intern and I'm just here to talk about
my experiences with the program what my
big takeaways are and why other
extension programs um like what some of
you guys work for might uh consider
wanting an intern
uh going into this job I really didn't
know didn't know what to expect my major
is animal science as Roger said so I had
pretty limited experience with
horiculture but I worked on a farm the
previous summer so I was interested to
see what the extension office had in
store for me um initially my job just
inail fixing up the garden weeding
mulching making new signs uh and
facilitating the many bi-weekly
workshops with Arc that Roger mentioned
before um and any other community group
and helping out with various projects
around the office but it ends up being
so much more than that and um I'll break
it down into a few categories because it
it ended up extending Way Beyond Way
Beyond the initial
scope so first um the
garden uh I most the entire plot I took
out a ton of weeds and this all took
this is just kind of the the general
labor of it it all took a longer than I
thought uh mulching it and just taking
down all the old signs putting up new
signs um I took like lot the before and
after picture so you can kind of see the
progress that there was throughout the
summer uh I planted a ton of new seeds
uh we acquired a big donation about
halfway through the summer that had tons
of like tomatoes peppers cucumbers and
cantaloupe plants um as Roger said he
donated several of his own plants
including a goji berry bush a couple
blueberry varieties and three blush
cherries uh that I planted with members
of Ark updated all the garden signs made
new ones and put together um some
healthy garden relevant recipes that we
put in the garden flyer holders for
passbys to
take oh sorry I'll slow
down um and I'm so happy with how the
garden looks now obviously I could
continue to work on it forever because
there's always something to do but I
think it's taught me most of what it can
for the meantime which is invaluable
enough um I'll go back to
this
secondly uh working with Community
groups each Tuesday and
Thursday all out each Tuesday and
Thursday one to three members of Ark
would come and their caretaker and I
would facilitate a garden activity with
them and sometimes it would be something
simple like we just plant seeds or read
water or read weed um and then sometimes
I would prepare a more intensive
activity beforehand uh like we made
Turtle Sprouts which is the picture
right in the middle and it's sort of
like a very easy atome chiaia pet um and
I did that with the summer W program and
I did it with Arc and I think both of
them uh really liked the activity and
benefited from it we extended the
opportunity to work with Wick and pins
diversion but um never heard back from
Wick we had one evening where we worked
with pins diversion about a group of
maybe 15 boys um and they were great
they were really uh into the garden and
even though we were dis mishing we
weren't doing anything necessarily
exciting I think they really enjoyed it
and then finally I worked alongside
Paula the picture to the far right um
doing the summer wreck program where her
and I would put together hourong
activities for the adessa central school
um that took place each Tuesday for a
month and the activities were all Garden
based and the kids ranged from
kindergarteners to sixth graders um and
the activities would get like a little
harder with each age group but I'll
discuss more of that in a moment and
then
finally uh working on stuff in the
office made a ton of signs all for the
garden u a lot of them was just updating
older signs and then sometimes I made
new signs for do plants that we had um I
had a bigger hand in in like advertising
and marketing than I expected um so like
the ladybug option for instance put
together several Flyers uh the trifold
poster that you see in this slide as
well as like a
brochure um and along the way learned a
ton about ladybugs I could talk your ear
off about ladybugs for an hour not that
anyone wants that um but this was just
an example of Duties that I ended up
having that I didn't necessarily expect
but I'm happy that I was able to
contribute uh so now I'll talk about the
takeaways Sor I'm gonna kind of go
back uh I realized the power a garden
can have um it provides an affordable
way to grow fresh produce um I and I
discovered just an absolute passion for
it I love horiculture now and I'm
considering pursuing that that further
um but as you can see the garden really
evolved over time it's it has all its
signs which like Mark different areas of
the garden now um fully mulched and
weeded the Head Start Garden looks
absolutely amazing although that's a
good part um K in one of our Master
garders uh planted a cayenne pepper bed
two of those from the donation that I
received from um a woman who works for
Ark Roger nine made these
netted raised beds so that the deer
couldn't get to them deer were the
absolute bait of our existence this
entire summer they ate everything but um
this like netted bed was it it's
producing tons of tomatoes um because
the deer weren't able to get to it uh as
you can see everything just it it like
looks a a lot more put together but um
my pride and joy from the summer for
sure
okay um so the the big
takeaways uh a garden is it's so much
more than just plants it's and and I
kind of thought this is cheesy going
into this but like it's absolutely true
a garden is helpful in so many different
ways that you wouldn't even expect uh
obviously it produces a lot of food um
it provides an affordable way to grow
your own fresh produce which is really a
valuable tool especially for like lower
income families who sometimes can't
afford all the fresh produce that they
need um for the final installment of the
summer wreck program we made a garden
salsa where we used ingredients either
found in the garden or we had to
supplement some uh from a grocery store
because we didn't have enough for the
entire group of kids but um getting to
like see the kids like like actually
working with like the tomatoes and
onions and peppers that we had grown
ourselves was exciting it's like they
can do that too they can grow it and
then they can make a delicious snack out
of everything that they harvest from
there um it provides a source of
Education working in the garden just
personally has taught me so much this
summer I've learned a ton about plant
and insect insect life that I probably
never would have gotten as great of
detail it um about if I've just taken a
course um I believe anyone who has a
garden even if it's just for like
Leisure or pleasure would inevitably
learn so much over time uh luckily I
have Roger to thank for sharing his
expansive knowledge um about plants with
me which in turn I tried my best to pass
on to either the children or the ark
members that I worked with over the
summer um just learning the basics about
soil health and how cents grow what bugs
are pests like etc those are things
that'll stick with you and be useful
like your entire life um just with the
kids we would of course do garden
related activities which were fun like
the turtle Sprouts or we played bug
Bingo but um I think from each of those
activities there was a takeaway where
the kids could remember something like
oh this insect is especially bad on this
plant like in the future if they're just
out in nature and they see that bug like
I hope that they'll remember the things
that we taught them even if it's totally
small uh like Fiona was saying earlier
gardening is incredibly therapeutic um
um I've been told several times that
members of Ark who came to the Garden
frequently for the workshops that I did
with them really benefited from the
experience and I could even see it week
to week like a few of the members who
continually came back throughout the
summer would come and they'd be so
excited to see me they'd like come out
of the car and be like what are we doing
today what have you got planned um and
it was really exciting to see like that
Weekly progression that they were
actually thrilled to keep coming back um
and by the end of the summer some of the
members were like so excited that uh
when I told them that I was leaving they
actually got really sad and I'm sad that
I can't continue working with them um
just because it was such a beneficial
experience personally I would just use
the garden as an escape fat a lot of my
mind or wasn't having a good day and
like Tia said just an hour or so out in
the garden I would feel infinitely
better uh as far as self-fulfillment
it's I mean gardening is work work it's
fun and it's relaxing but it's
definitely work you'll weed and you'll M
Mulch and you'll sweat and you'll get
incredibly discouraged when things that
you plant die or when a deer eats
something that you just like put in the
ground um but the gratification that
comes with seeing like the first tomato
that you planted ripen or the Sprouts
coming up that you planted um it's
unbeatable and it's it's really
fulfilling and I tried to point out this
progress to especially the ark members I
worked with because we planted a lot of
seeds so each week they came back I
would take them back to where we planted
the seeds be like look the just seeds we
planted and now they're scrubed and
they're coming up and one day they'll be
flowering um and the fact that they can
have even just that small amount of
ownership over the garden and its
success is a great accomplishment um and
finally uh Garden can be and at least in
my experience this summer The Perfect
platforms for forming connections both
with nature and other people um there's
something so essential with connecting
with plants and the Earth that a lot of
people lose nowadays like Fiona was
talking about uh you cultivate an
appreciation for the Earth and how we as
people work with it and communicate with
it and that's really invaluable um and I
I also truly believe that everyone can
enjoy a garden even if they're not
someone who particularly likes being
outside like everyone can find something
about it that they enjoy and and number
of people I've met and befriended in the
garden is truly uncountable like just
people who walked by The Garden or
walked through it I would talk to them
for 10 15 minutes and and just see that
like they really appreciated the beauty
of the garden um so whether my role was
as a facilitator or teacher like with
Arc or the kids or just as like a
helping hand like with my co-workers or
the master garders I can honestly say I
won't forget the people I've connected
with this summer and I hope that they
think of the garden as fly as I
do uh so to kind of close up um I know
we're sort of running out of time here
but why have an intern for all of you uh
people listening if you're considering
having an intern or applying for an
intern in the future um I I'd like to
just share my own experience uh so that
you can know that it it really can make
a difference both to the intern and to
your program um
regardless oh sorry uh an intern Can Be
A New Perspective I was lucky in that
Roger gave me a lot of freedom to atten
to the garden and plan activities with
Ark as I saw fit and as a result a lot
of new ideas evolved I like created new
beds in the garden and signs dividing it
into easy to follow sections like the
butterfly garden raspberry patch um but
I had minimal uh prior experience with
gardening and working with Community
groups so I learned as I went
and hopefully I was able to look at
everything from a fresh point of view um
also a intern can be a helping hand in
tons of in tons of ways as I said
earlier I ended up having a lot more
duties and helping out with things that
I didn't expect which was great um
because I helped out Roger Kathy Paula
the people I work with um all on a
number of different projects while still
routinely working in the garden and as a
result got so much accomplished and
really gained tons of new skills in like
different areas that I didn't expect
over the course of Summer um and finally
like having an intern you could really
change the students life I was really
indecisive about what I wanted coming
into this um summer which is I mean
clearly why I'm an animal science major
in an internship pretty unrelated to
animals but uh working with the
incredible people in the extension
office and connecting with so many
community members I began to get a
better idea of what I love to do um of
course I'm still unsure about a lot but
just this summer has convinced me uh to
at least pursue a minor in horiculture
um because I wouldn't trade the
experiences I had for anything and while
the summer was hard I don't regret a
single part of it and I loved it um so
thank you to everyone I worked with to
Roger Fiona um and I think now we're
going to ask some questions try to
engage you guys yeah thank you so much
scer and I wanted to just chime in she
didn't highlight that one picture but
those ladybug cupcakes were
amazing they were like the highlight of
ladybug adoption night so our nutrition
staff kudos to them they want to throw
that in there they were tast they were
tast the they have ladybugs in them no
no I
wish all right well um thank you so much
for listening so patiently for uh the
last few minutes so now is your time to
sort of um ask any questions that are on
your mind or um yeah we'd really like
this next we we blocked off the next
half hour or so so there's plenty of
time to um you know have a lively
discussion don't be shy so you can
either type your question into the chat
box or I believe you can raise your hand
and I can um unmute you
uh so ktie I think I can answer that one
how did you protect your sence from the
elements out in the garden they really
only um our color isn't stay fast yet we
were we are trying to figure that out um
so the pictures of like the apples and
so on do not last too long but the Black
Ink um on a card stock has last of this
pretty much for a year till we replace
them again but the color fad really fast
so we have not been able to solve that
one there yet so if anybody ever has a
good color fast printer ink or something
um we're we're trying to work on that
but the black on the card stock has has
lasted
fine great looks like you have another
question from Paulina where do you get
most of your funding from um sort of as
stated in the um presentation um all the
plants were donated uh so that is 100%
or 95% um we had a little pot of money I
think $300 each year was set aside from
copper extension for the Garden in our
budget so we purchased tools and
knickknacks and things like that with at
$300 um but like I said everything that
was built came from the initial um uh
Department of Health Grant was all the
major construction and we really never
did any more construction after that one
I wish we had but uh we never finished
our one walkway
let's see far back are we on colen said
um oh hang
on do you plan on only having College
interns or do you plan on using High
School
interns um we'd like to have uh
additional interns I know we were really
blessed to get two years through the
cows program probably be lucky to ever
get a third year U because I heard two
years was pretty pretty incredible um
we're always looking for interns um
it's hard sometimes uh because we are
out uh especially for like Megan she had
to drive out each day uh from from Etha
where she lived um Britney last year
lived in Watkins Glenn that was really
close so maybe a high school one uh or a
high school program that actually has
some youth uh we could also take a look
at Elmyra college and some local
colleges where some youth might have to
do a little bit of intern um before they
graduate so we'll have to do a lot of
exploring over this winter of some other
options awesome uh and a followup from
Colleen said if funding or interns are
not available in the future how will the
garden be sustained or kept alive okay
so Colleen's questionnaire um interns
are going to be a question mark so we
know we have three Master Gardeners that
completed the program up at Tomkins with
Pat we uh plan on sending a couple more
uh folks that are interested in the
master Garden program and they've been
really reliable in helping with our
garden uh Debbie who is one of our
Master Gardeners actually has to take a
bus because she cannot drive twice a
week she comes almost all year long she
is really dedicated so we have
passionate people also a lot of our
volunteers that aren't Master Gardeners
just love the community engagement in
the garden because it is very focal and
and they like to just come out there and
just help out and when I put a call out
for help like the weeds are getting a
little big
how can we get a weeding party together
they show up it's just incredible the
interest level we have um
so I I don't believe that interns are
going to be I think like I said before
two years was pretty lucky um but maybe
we'll develop other ideas I am also
full-time now so be able to help out
especially when Megan leaves I'll be
doing the arc uh tours twice of the week
and stuff so uh she's made a good base
for us to keep it running for the rest
of the fall and then we have the winner
to to regroup and go from
there great another sign question were
the signs laminated in house or sent out
to a printing company um that was
actually a project for Megan she
laminated actually she blew up one of
our laminators uh this year so so we
know the amount of laminating we did but
we uh we we burned one up so so uh we do
a lot of laminating uh on those signs um
so so um she did everything from
developing some brand new ones to
printing out the old ones uh to
laminating them and then we had this
whole little system where we um have a
um uh try to Soil and Water uh
Department puts in fencing and they
split a bunch of uh pressure treated
poles when they're pounding they donate
those to us and we cut them into little
uh angled sign holders that sit out in
the garden I should have did a close-up
one for you um so we put a little dab of
silicone behind where the staple is
going to be the sign goes on and then
the staple goes through and then a dab
of silicone on the outside of the staple
so water doesn't ruin our signs and then
like I said we are really pretty good
except for color making one full season
before we have to replace them back out
there and we we just consider that part
of our budget for the garden putting the
sage out there because that is our
silent salesperson if we were selling
something but it is one of those folks
or one of those projects where we see
folks in the garden when I'm leaving at
night sometimes at 9 o' there might be a
family out there picking some fresh
raspberries and reading the signs uh and
then the same in the morning if there's
joggers they'll stop and look at what's
that Quint tree I've never seen
something like that so people always and
we just had Megan's farewell meal out in
the garden yesterday and when we went to
come in I had three questions in a row
of folks sto because somebody was in the
garden and they asked the garding
related question that they may not have
come in our building for because you
come through security and it's just a
little spooky to some folks to have to
come through sheriffs and stuff so when
you're out in the garden you get like
Megan said you get approached by tons of
community members uh asking what this is
how do I solve this you know I have
trees dying from the drought how do I
water them properly so it's that
connection when you're out there is
really good for that
awesome thank you um I have a question
for both Roger and Megan but also for um
everyone else that's attending um does
everyone have sort of like a top garden
based Learning Resource or a top
activity that they find uh works really
well um it could be anything um yeah
feel free to
share um uh I mentioned it a few times
and this is the turtle Sprout activity
but it's a Act I pulled from Cornell's
Garden based learning website and it's
meant for uh believe ages like
kindergarten to maybe like fifth grade
or something but um it it kind of has
all the essentials of gardening packed
into one and it's fun like kids get to
like draw their own turtle uh and then
you fill just the stocking with some
grass seed with Ark I believe we we did
Dill instead but um so you just put some
sort of like seed
in the bottom that's small enough where
it'll come up through the panty hose and
then soil on top and tie it off and you
just water it every other day it's very
simple and then it starts growing um and
unfortunately I wasn't able to see the
kids that I did this activity with a
second time like a week later because I
would have loved to ask them if they
like kept up with it if it actually
started sprouting um but I think that's
just like a a fun activity really
affordable and like we did it we did it
in Mass amounts we had like 30 kids plus
I did several more the next day with Arc
and it was very cheap um and fun and
taught them a decent amount about
gardening in a short amount of
time yeah I'll chime in with another one
um along those same lines of being very
affordable and very easy and sort of not
too material intensive um in this one
you can call them seed bombs or seed
balls or seed anything really so um you
pretty much just take a large chunk of
clay and each um person gets a a small
piece of it they flatten it out and in
the middle of um sort of the clay Patty
you put some soil and some seeds they
can be wild flower seeds they can be
really any type of seeds I've done that
with basil before um and then you smash
it all into a ball and um it's just so
easy the kids love the tactile kind of
fun getting dirty part of it um but
they're also taking Seeds home with them
to plant then or plant at a later date
so that's another really easy one that
you can set up you know if you didn't
know you had a group coming oh wait we
can always do seed balls because those
are really easy to set up and and fun if
we scroll down we might have somebody
after Katie maybe oh good point let's
see
here um so somebody asked about gravel
uh for our Pathways you think landscape
fabric instead you feel gravel was
better so um our walkways have fabric
underneath so that is like part of the
answer and then a little bit chunkier
Stone and then a really fine I think
they called it stone dust from our
landscaper and when that packs it is
hard as cement with just a little loose
on top um so wheelchairs uh strollers uh
even walkers go through it really really
well because of how it packs uh so but
it is all three levels in there so the
fabric is below to keep weeds from
coming up I only get a little
transitional weeds at the edge that try
to come in but they pull really easy out
of that it's probably a good two inches
thick of that stone dust uh and that was
put in from our landscaper and um I like
I said if I could ever afford to do the
other half of the garden so there's an
exit back out on the other end uh we
would continue with that stone dust
because it has works so well for
wheelchairs on
there and uh Pauline has question do you
have principal worksheets for that
activity um I'm not sure if that is
directed towards the turtle Sprouts or
the seed balls but um I know the turtle
Sprouts are on the Cornell Garden based
learning website if you go to um lessons
and then activities they should be in
there um and there are downloadable P
PDFs and while you're on there you'll
find a whole lot of other great
activities too so it's definitely worth
checking out
um and yes we will be posting the slides
the whole webinar has been recorded
thankfully I remembered it's really easy
to forget um once I am able to download
uh the webinar and sort of transfer it
to a different format I will then upload
it to YouTube so if you have any
questions and are able to find it um in
the next few days you can always email
me uh my email address is up there
Fiona I wanted to share um if you ever
uh some of you probably have the old
project wet uh curriculum um in there is
the water cycle game it is a little bit
more CU I had to build it and laminate
the the dice that you roll but the
little beads that the kids get in
through the water cycle game um and then
they share that bracelet at the end with
their friends and they can see they got
five of the dark blue in a row because
they were stuck in the ocean it's where
the water droplet travels so sometimes
like if it's like coming out of an as
you're in it's only like one time that
you're there but sometimes you maybe get
stuck in the cloud or in the ocean
multiple times and you may get seven
beads in a row because you don't leave
that station so they really grasp the
understanding of where that water
droplet and oh that makes sense that it
wouldn't be there very long versus yeah
I'd be stuck as a water droplet in Ocean
for a long time and they all talk up
their beads to each other at the end and
ask what color is that I would never
green I was never in a plant my little
water droplet never made it there you
know and something like that so it's
really cool the way they share it
afterwards which is a really win for me
that that they understand it enough to
share with their friends and talk about
you where they were in that cycle a
little more prep work because you got to
buy the beads um and and the U make the
little dice but but it is a fun water
cycle
game awesome are there any other
questions about just maybe General
Garden based learning theory or um about
the internship or anything else that we
could help you out with
[Music]
today well thank you yeah thank you to
everyone for attending um thank you to
Roger and Meg for their awesome
presentations and I just do want to
stick in a quick plug for a webinar that
Cornell Garden based learning will be
hosting on September 7th um we have some
really exciting upcoming projects this
this following year and we'd like to
sort of uh give you a teaser about them
and give you some more information about
how you could be involved so please get
that on your calendar September 7th I
believe it is 9:30 to 10:30 in the
morning um and we're looking forward to
seeing you all there
so if you uh have any other questions
feel free to to ask them uh but if not
thanks to everybody and have a wonderful
day thank you everybody thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu