This is a production of Cornell
University.
So, it's Mast's week, right? It, you
know, it seems like the world stops uh
for us in the golf world when this
happens. We talked about it last week.
Talk about it again. And in honor of
that, we got a sports turf discussion
today. So, uh we are going to find a way
to twist this thing uh into a golf
discussion to the start, Evan. And I'm
going to ask you a couple of questions.
And I'm wondering your thoughts because
there are some things I think for golf
folks that are listening that I think
will be really fascinating because we're
starting to look at putting surfaces in
a way that you used to look at baseball
infields if you don't mind. Sure. Hey
golfers are athletes too. Yeah, that's
right. They are now. Uh that's for sure.
Uh we got this note, Carl and I got this
note from our good pal Rick Slatterie uh
who's down at the Masters. What did he
say, Carl? He walked 25 miles in two
days. Man, he's putting the steps in. is
putting the steps in and thrilled to see
a pimento cheese sandwich for $1.50. And
anybody that gets down there knows uh
that's exactly how this works. Carl,
come on with this guy. Tape his mouth
shut because he couldn't hold his uh
tongue. He was getting himself so upset.
I'd like to hear your thoughts on, you
know, taping your mouth shut. I think
this should be something we could use in
other parts of our lives as well. Why
should it be confined to this guy? Uh
what are your thoughts about the
mentality that drives a golfer to do
this ridiculousness? This, you know,
this speaks to my theory that golf just
makes people crazy and you know, they
you could see really smart people just
in all other walks of life and as soon
as you put a golf club in their hand, it
is all out the window for whatever
reason.
Well, this poor guy, I think, played a
cornfairy event uh like this uh and and
you know, was completely serious about
it helping his
game. A couple of guys that don't need
help. And of course, as an old guy
myself now, just want to raise
everybody's attention that while Ludvig
Oldborg at 20 years old or 21 years old
is on the leaderboard, my man Freddy
Couples is T13 and Bernard Langanger, 70
67 years old, will probably be the
oldest guy to make the cut. He's at even
par right now. So, we'll see how it goes
today and what he's able to do. But
we're very excited about these two old
guys really showing up. Okay, Evan. So,
we talk about firmness on putting
surfaces, right? I know you're in the
We're going to talk about your line of
work and that you're currently doing
with Biocore and in field uh uh safety
and measurements. Um uh we look at a
variety of different ways. There's a Kle
hammer uh on the right making an indent
and either a traditional true firm or
even the PGA railroad ball bearing that
they drop uh at a uniform height to
measure firmness. So this is a very
commonly uh discussed term now. It's
getting more widely known. What is not
as widely uh studied and known is the
strength of that surface. Right. And you
studied this a little bit with your clay
work years ago. So, you know, no matter
if it and of course this may be the
first masters they have that's really
firm and fast cuz they get rain all the
time and then they run those subairs and
oh, everybody's the subair thing. And
this still happens in the top millimeter
no matter how much they run that subair.
So, here you are uh back in your
Pittsburgh pirate days as a working man.
Now you're now you're a senior engineer
with Biocore. Um and when we had you on
years ago, uh you know, when you were
doing your infield work, we were talking
about cleat in cleat out and how the
ball was responding to these clay
surfaces. So, my question to start this
out before I get to the weather and we
get to the meat of the sports
conversation today is what are your
thoughts about ways of potentially
measuring this or understanding it a
little bit better on a putting surface?
Well, I feel uh only a little ambushed
by this question. So, um, I think real
quick just from an engineering
standpoint, there's there's all
different kinds of gobbleygook terms
that that people use to describe
materials. Young's modulus, elastic
modulus, sheer modulus, and all these
terms describe the way that a material
deforms in different directions under
different means of loads, right? So,
firmness is typically thought about in
the vertical direction or normal um
forces. Whereas a shearing strength, I
think that's pretty intuitive. I think
most people understand sheer strength to
be in sort of a a perpendicular or
co-planer direction to the surface,
right? So in uh in sand root zones,
we're really relying mostly on the
anchoring of the grass plants to provide
the stability. My old adviser Andy
McNet, he would say, you know, we've
tried in the past to to stabilize sand
root zones by changing the particle size
distribution and with this sort of the
CU concept that's really caught on in
the golf course world for firmness.
Well, if you do this sort of thought
experiment when you have an athlete
running around on the surface with no
grass, if you had this high uh high CU
sand that's very non-uniform and ideally
you could have some of the particle
packing working to to fill that in. Do
you really think that's going to
stabilize the surface or I mean the
reality is those athletes are going to
still blow that sand all over the place,
right? So, you're really relying on the
network of roots and ryomes in the case
of a you know Kentucky bluegrass sports
field or a Bermuda grass field on a golf
course. you know, if it's a a bent grass
or even a bent poa surface, you're
relying more on the stoleniferous growth
habit, which is contributing to this
organic matter on the top. So that I
guess that's kind of a starting point
for the conversation. We're really, I
think, in this case, concerned a little
bit more with the organic materials,
whether they're living or dead, and then
certainly the degree of decomposition on
the top. See, this is so great. I am you
and you give me an answer like that. I
got to do this more often to to people.
That was absolutely brilliant. And I
think you're right. what we're trying
there's two parts to this. One is how do
we measure it right to simulate a ball.
There's a lot of discrepancies even in
dropping a thing down on the surface to
determine it you know is it correlated
to moisture is it correlated to organic
matter. Now you know we have this the uh
uh USGA method of organic matter testing
the uh OM246 where you know yeah you're
honing in on the 2 millimeters. So I
think you know this is there's no
answer. This is what's great about this.
This is the beginning of the thinking of
how we have to measure this because
firmness is only part of the equation,
right? You can get it firm, but when you
get those forces from other directions,
especially when you consider the spin
rate, uh if they're hitting a uh you
know a close iron that they can use the
grooves and get the spin on the ball, uh
it really adds uh quite a bit of
complexity. And then at the end of the
day, what does a s golf course
superintendent do? Should we verticut
and put more sand in here? Do we need to
airify? Uh is it is it a brush? Does
brushing help? You know, I don't think
we understand really what it takes to
manage that upper millimeter, right,
Evan? Where this reaction is occurring,
right? It's not a deep thing. When the
ball hits it, we're only talking about a
millimeter or two, right? different than
your sports field where the cleat is
entering into the substrate a little
bit. Yes. Yeah, I totally agree. The the
surface surface really is what you're
managing. Um, you know, honestly, it's
similar to a infield skin. You're really
managing that top, you know, maybe inch
or usually less than that, just where
the cleats are interacting and in this
case where the ball's interacting. I
think one thing that sticks out to me on
this picture, you can see um obviously
the living plant material on top, but
this sort of turf slime or or
relatively, you know, degraded organic
or intermediate degraded organic matter
anyway, which has very little shear
strength and probably whose physical
properties is highly dependent on the
water content. Um that type of material
has a very high water holding capacity
due to its you sort of I guess molecular
structure and sort of random randomly
oriented um organic molecules. But also
uh
um will depend highly on the water
content, right? So when it's dry, it's
pretty stiff. It's it's probably
compressed a little bit. When it starts
to absorb water, it's going to swell.
And even if there is some sand in that
top layer, some grit, that swelling
could potentially open up that, you
know, that medium so that the sand
grains are no longer in such intimate
contact. This is so great. All right.
Okay. Let's get to the weather and then
we're going to get to the meat of the
discussion. Um it's been pretty wet. Uh
we're going to talk about temperature in
a minute, but when you look at sort of
rainfall across the region, there are
very very few places maybe along the
Great Lakes where we were a little bit
drier and it looks like the coast is
going to stay wetter uh than inland. So
if you're along the coast, you can
expect quite a bit of rainfall in the
next few days. It could be a wash out of
a weekend. Uh I hope I'm not in the
baseball business because I'll be
dragging a tarp a fair amount in this
kind in in this kind of weather. Um, in
the golf world, seed head suppression,
you're pretty late now for your first
application of proxy for the spring,
which seems very odd to be saying that,
but you're pretty late. And in if you
still have some embark lying around and
you're one of those folks that still use
embark, you still have a little bit of
time, particularly into upstate New York
and the Hudson Valley. Um, you know, we
were talking about soils in the low 50s,
uh, mid50s last week at the 2-in level,
and now you're hardressed to find a soil
in the 50s. And we talked to RT Gitano
who was our guest last week uh about
this. And of course, this in the
springtime, that two in soil temperature
is going to track the air temperature
pretty closely and even cooler uh with
moisture in there because, you know,
we're wet and we're cool and we've been
cooler than normal regionwide. uh you
know two to two to minus2 degrees at
normal, maybe a little bit above normal,
but not uh essentially uh what we would
think we'd be warming up. And it looks
like cool and wet is coming. The eight
to 14 day probabilities are looking like
at least for the next week, maybe until
May, we're going to be pretty wet and
cool, which you know, this is the pretty
typical spring stall that we talk about
every year. I mean, it was 17 degrees uh
just the other day in Ithaca and and I
and I I shuddered. I'm hoping that a lot
of fruit trees have not broken dormcancy
yet because then they're going to be in
all sorts of trouble. Now, when you put
all this together and we look at our
growth potential model, this is the map,
nice and easy to see, grass isn't
growing in New York State and it's not
going to be growing for a few more days
uh anytime soon. And so when you talk
about athletic fields, and I thought I'd
start out with a picture from Greg
Chorvis, a regular contributor and
listener to the program, uh sending a
picture from a local school district
that I think he worked with a while ago,
uh trying to help him out. And then
other people got involved, uh I maybe
you want to believe well-intentioned,
but not really smart, uh about just
dumping ditch material. Carl, do I have
this right? They cleaned out the
community ditches and they dumped it on
these baseball fields. Um, and
apparently that's not their only problem
because if you take a wrong step, you're
going to kill yourself on these stands.
So, it's obviously clear that the grass
isn't growing and fields aren't
necessarily in good shape. At this time
of year, you know, you get reports that
fields are being overused, especially
when they're not growing and they look
unsafe like this. you put kids on them
and all of a sudden you get hurt. Um,
and now we start to talk more about
faceplanting concussions. Uh, you know,
where, you know, concussion care for
parents and young people that are on
these fields. Again, we oftentimes think
of firmness, right? And concussions.
I've had some experience uh having to
report about concussions in division one
athletes from my time uh uh serving the
athletic department uh here at Cornell.
And uh a number of years ago, we put
together a concussion report from
various sports from football and soccer
to ice hockey, wrestling, and lacrosse.
And you can see uh we have many many
years where we're above average. uh
whether it's a men or woman sports, um
you can get a a high number of
concussions. Now, obviously, we're not
talking about ice uh in this particular
presentation, but we try to make
adaptations, right, guys? We try to make
adaptations to the game to try to
prevent this. And and the new kickoff
rule in football is is certainly a a
demonstration of that. It's a it's a a
small percentage of the number of plays
in a football game, American football
game, but but has a higher percentage of
concussion and injuries associated with
it. And of course, we go and test. And
this is where we start to get into the
discussion about firmness and testing.
And we care a lot about this, but it's
almost
non-existent at the high school and
collegate level that I'm aware of. In
fact, I would think it's safe to say
other than the companies that come in
and test the synthetic surfaces,
virtually no one in the Ivy League is
testing their surfaces for safety and
performance other than the uh synthetic
turf people that put that stuff in. So
just to remind everybody uh we have a
really good sports field management
website which we are in the process now
of updating and looking forward to
launching that in the next year uh in an
updated fashion. And of course there's
the best management practices for sports
fields that the
SFMA or back then the STMA the New
England people really led this charge
and you can find uh this publication
pretty easily on the web anywhere. Okay,
Carl. So now I'm ready for you. I was
recalling
recently that there was back in maybe
2002 or 2004 or
2006 in the middle of the season, Bill
Bellichic decides to pull out natural
grass and put in synthetic turf. Well,
now he's down at UNC with Little Wayne
and his new girlfriend, and he wants
natural grass. And I'm wondering what
this is about from one end to the other
where he is. And of course, early I was
talking about firmness. Now we're
talking about traction, which brings in
these multiple forces, right? Not just
the downward force, but these rotational
forces. And Carl, maybe I hope I set you
up enough to start the discussion with
Evan. Yeah. So Evan, you set it up
really well. the the direction of the
force and and how we measure that
probably matters. We've used uh and last
year we did this testing about twice a
week on our fields, a variety of fields
here at Cornell. And we've got the
really simple Turf Tech shear strength
tester. It's just that co-planer as
Kevin mentioned. You you stick it in the
ground, you rotate it, it gives you a a
shearing number, a force that uh the
maximum sort of force before that the
turf breaks. And there's different
things you can put on the bottom. Uh,
and when we looked at the data last
year, we were really looking at it for
our soccer teams. We have a Burman, uh,
for those watching the yellow line on
this graph, that's our game field.
Kentucky bluegrass predominantly. Not a
whole lot of practices, just games in
the fall. U McGovern is our practice
field. Both men's and women's have their
own field. It's a poor arai field uh,
and a satellite location. Uh, and when
we looked at the traction data last
year, that that Kentucky bluegrass
surface Burman had higher traction
numbers in the summer, but as we got
into the season, August, September, when
we start playing on that field, uh, they
really sort of narrowed to match the
McGovern field. And if we look at the
firmness data, if we look at the ball
roll data, they all did the same thing.
Burman was sort of different than the
practice field. And then they got they
they sort of uh, you know, coalesed
together towards the end of the year.
Now, part of that is probably more
rolling. Uh Chris Siko, our director of
grounds and sports turf, took the height
down a little bit on the bluegrass, but
what he also did was he added ryrass in
in June on that blueg grass field at
Burman. He got a great catch of of that
overseated rye. And as we saw that rye
come in, we saw the traction values go
down and start to match that poa rye
traction of the McGovern field. So now
we're starting to think about the growth
habit of the grass. Evan, you mentioned,
you know, that shearing is really a
function of sort of the vegetated growth
and organic material down below. So now
we're wondering like is that why that
that ryrass in place of bluegrass, is
that why we're seeing these things
coales? And then Evan, you guys measure
traction in a much more complicated way
uh with the beast, right? This this uh
huge machine, you're riding on it. I've
got some pictures on here. So now I want
to set you up, Evan. Why do you measure
traction in this sort of way? It looks
like it's coming in at different angles.
It's probably rotating. Why do we need
that? Whereas the traction device is
very simple. Uh is it too simple? Is it
really capturing everything we'd want to
know when when we're considering
traction?
As you alluded, there's excuse me,
there's a number of different variables
that we need to control in this
situation. you know, athletes have all
sorts of different sizes, different
cleat engagements, um, both within
within sports, within, you know, age age
groups, within even genders. And so,
this device, the Beast, is it's designed
very specifically around NFL size
athletes. Um, it is configurable, so the
weight stack can be changed, but this
was developed in response to a desire by
the league to, um, really attack lower
extremity injuries, which comprise about
60% of the injury burden in the league.
So the concussions often gets a lot of
the press, but in terms of total time
missed, the lower extremity injuries
actually play a little bit bigger role.
So this this device um one one of the
main t So that that's number one is that
it it it replicates the loads and the
forces associated with the extremely
large athletes in the NFL.
Okay. So Carl, you mentioned yesterday
um which position, Evan, is it the
lineman who have to plant that
heavyweight? Is it the receiver who's
running lightly to make a cut? Uh is it
the quarterback who's stepping back and
playing? Where do you get the force you
want to replicate? Do you go to the most
extreme? Several years ago, there was a
a biomechanical study done with um
professional football athletes running
around on force plates, you know, highly
instrumented artificial turf surface to
get a sense of what are the vertical
loads, what are the shearing forces that
they actually apply to the surface, how
much can they use, how much do they
need, and this has been done at other
places in the literature in the past
both with American football and with
other athletes. So, we basically use uh
the 50th percentile NFL athlete to
represent this particular test. Okay.
And and the other thing that that we
found, and this actually persists across
sports, that generally the most
energetic maneuvers apply about two and
a half times the player's body weight to
the surface at the peak the peak
vertical loading. Whoa. Okay. So, just
to be clear,
300B uh um linemen are putting 800 lb or
700 pounds of force down. That's right.
That's why this device is so much it
looks so much bigger than an NFL athlete
because it is bigger. ways to talk more,
right? And the other, you know, the
other thing to think about positionally
is the mode of cleat engagement can
vary. You alluded to the linemen sort of
digging in at that lower angle with the
receivers. They may be be turning
abruptly to make a V-cut, but they're
also often accelerating and decelerating
at very high speeds. And often times
those high-speed decelerations are
associated with some of the non-cont
injuries like you referred to in the um
in the kickoffs. We certainly think of
the headto-head, you know, the the sort
of violent collisions between the
players and their helmets, but also that
hard deceleration is associated with a
lot of ACL injuries and other things in
that sphere.
All right, Carl, what's this? So, so
this is where I wanted to get to is uh
you guys presented at that Loftboro uh
international sport conference uh that
that you turned us on to last year. And
this this is data from the beast, right?
On a variety of different surfaces.
There's synthetic, there's Kentucky
bluegrass on its own, there's bluegrass
or ryrass stitched in with the
artificial, so these hybrid surfaces. Uh
maybe you could just talk a little bit
about some of the findings there, Evan,
and what's interesting about uh
different kinds of synthetic, different
kinds of natural, and maybe why we're
seeing the stuff at Burman with the
traction values differing now that we
added uh per eye in there. Totally.
Well, I'm always impressed at your guys'
ability to find, you know, from one link
to still information that you find
always the the critical thing. So yes,
as you mentioned, this was presented at
a sports engineering conference last
summer, summer of 2024, I guess. And
this is an experiment that we did uh at
a couple different locations, including
our plot here at Biocore. And the
different colors of lines represent the
traction response of each
surface. So if if you haven't seen a
graph like this before to the audience
to walk you through it, on the x-axis is
the degree of rotation. So, it's
measured in degrees starting out from um
the original cleat position and then
rotating through a full turn. And you'll
notice that it goes the axis goes all
the way up to 100 degrees, which if you
think about rotating your knee 100
degrees, that's well past where your
ligaments would start to give way.
Right? So, this is a we we refer to this
as an injury test. And we're interested
in not only the peak load that builds
up, but also the rate that it builds up
and um how much load is required to move
the cleat through a given amount of
rotation. So the y-axis here is the
torque which is actually the same unit
that you're measuring on that turf tech
shear vein. And you'll notice where the
numbers are are you know an order of
magnitude higher given the higher normal
force or the the vertical load. So each
of the again each of the lines
represents a different surface tested
with this this beast device. And you'll
notice there's a big span not only in
the peak load but also the displacement
associated with where the cleat releases
or where it reaches its maximum force.
So for the the synthetic turf lines on
the left, the gray ones, they're a lot
steeper and they also reach a higher
peak load. The the purplish lines
associated with the blue grass and the
um the stitched hybrids in the blue
grass at different densities, they tend
not to reach quite um as high peak load
and they take longer to do so. So that's
another thing we're interested in, not
only the total force that builds up, but
um how do you get to that point? And
that's one really cool thing that you
can measure with this sort of device
that isn't captured by a manual or
handheld device.
So, so Carl, before we get to the last
slide, Evan, in simple terms, this is
you plant your foot and you're more
likely to slip a little bit, right, on
natural grass and less likely to slip a
little bit on synthetic turf. And when I
say slip, I mean the subtlest of sort of
slippage that takes that energy away
from the joint. Is that a fair? I would
I would partially agree. I would shy
away from using the term slip. I think
often times when we see an athlete slip
or we refer to that, it's a more um it's
it's a less complete cle engagement. So
oftent times the studs may not be
penetrating all the way into the soil.
Maybe it's more like that initial
picture you showed of the golf ball
really just touching the whether it's
the thatch, the mat, however you want to
label that sort of intermingled organic
layer or sometimes in a very dense maybe
a ryrass surface that's wet and slick.
Sometimes the cleats don't engage fully.
That's not necessarily what this test is
after, but I do agree with the part
about um in general the grass is um more
we call it more compliant or not as
stiff and so it it does begin to to
release or to uh deform at least in a
more significant way. All right. So the
in my mind the $64,000 question is
where's the sweet spot? Where am I
getting maximum
performance and also or optimized
performance that also optimizes for my
safety, right? I mean, is it looks like
where they stitch where you put
synthetic fibers in and I know Ryan
Woodley's got this in the outfield now
at for the Brewers. Um uh it looks like
where they stitch it's it's it's stiffer
not less compliant you would say. Yes
that's correct. Does is it is it
worrisome is the stitching now are they
able to and I'm ass sure they are stitch
at different densities and does that
then change the stiffness and is that
the way to optim one of the ways to
optimize performance with safety I think
it is and so first of all just to
reiterate what you described there is a
sort of envelope right you have the
floor of traction where you need to have
some be able to run around it's it's not
like running on a beach but Then there's
some upper limit where there's a there's
a concern that the foot can become
fixated. And to answer the second part
of your question, I think the purple so
the purple and the blue lines hopefully
for people that can see you're not color
blind. I think this is actually colorb
blind uh friendly color palette. And um
Carl, I know you're an R user. This is a
colorblind R package by Claus Wilky.
Okay. Um in any case, the four so the
four purple lines, you've got the bottom
solid, which is just the pure Kentucky
bluegrass, and then stitched at three
different densities. And so we find that
the higher the fiber volume within a
given area or root zone volume, as you
might expect, that the traction becomes
stiffer and more significant in terms of
the peak load. And so that's it's
interesting because it suggests that you
can control the available traction
depending on the way the surface is
constructed. The blue lines are
bermutarass with the same stitching
rates. And you'll notice they're
squashed together a little bit more. And
so we would hypothesize that this is
probably because the Bermuda grass
already has such a robust network of the
roots and underground stems that it
doesn't I would I'll use the word
benefit. I don't know if we mean that
you know correct but at least
directionally it doesn't um it's not
enhanced in terms of traction by as much
as the bluegrass might be. And there's
maybe why Bellich likes the natural
grass going down south or or the Bermuda
grass going down south. Oh, there you
are coming to his defense. If I'm
throwing a Hail Mary there on on my
hypothesis, maybe that's why we we like
natural grass on on the warm seasons
that have and a lot of times it comes
down to this debate of grass versus
turf. And it's really not as simple as
that. And this graph doesn't really
depict that super well, but if if you
squint, you can actually see one gray
line that is beneath two of the blue
lines, which is a hybrid, and kind of
right in the carpet, the yellow carpet
hybrid. So there are some grasses which
have higher traction loads and
especially when they're hybridized than
some of the synthetic fields. So often
times, you know, coaches especially will
get an idea in their head that I want
grass, I want turf, and it's not really
an absolute. And I I'll also just point
out that since that happened, I don't
remember the year exactly, it was early
2000s, right? The the technology and the
skill of the sod growers has really
evolved. And so um grass grass in that
era probably not so comparable to some
of the grass that you can obtain even
late in the season. Now, now it is
interesting because uh as we've talked
about or will talk about more over the
show is, you know, when the World Cup
comes, they're going to play on that
carpet hybrid grass, right? That's
that's the natural grass planted in a
synthetic surface. Um and that looks
like it's um you know, pretty strong.
Now, it's a different animal to a
certain extent with soccer. They they
like that ball to skid, right? It's a
round ball sport, but it does look like
it's closer to synthetic as far as
traction or less compliant, so to speak,
uh, than it is to natural grass. So, I'm
wondering, um, that that's that if they
they can also play around with fiber
density in that hybrid as well. And I'm
sure they're going to use this data to
determine what's the best way to go
there. Now, John's pretty smart guy.
Definitely. And I again, I want to be
clear, this is only three products that
we tested. One of them we sort of made
ourselves like a homemade kind of off
label carpet hybrid with super high
fiber density. And so this doesn't
necessarily reflect the suite of
products that would be available or
might come become available anyway.
Okay. All right, Carl, here's your last
slide. Let's wrap it up here. Well, so
the great thing is that Evan already
nailed this for us. I was going to ask
the question are different athletes
different loads and and Evan, you
already answered that. The other part I
liked about this slide, Frank, was uh
Declan Rice there, my guy for Arsenal
Football Club with two gorgeous free
kick goals against Real Madrid the other
day. Just top level. So, so we answered,
you know, the idea that, you know, maybe
different sports and different athletes
win within a sport. Lineman, receivers
experience loads differently. But I got
a question from from Ben Palmer who
asked here. Evan, I don't know how much
you can talk about this, but you guys
collect data for the NFL. Um, are there
instances where the turf and a lot of
that is safety data, right? Are these
fields safe? Do we look at injury rates?
Probably you can't comment too much on
that, but have the turf managers used
that data that you collect and
implemented certain practices that
allowed them to get to, you know, higher
or lower on the traction scale? Is is
there anything you can talk to about um
sort of the turf managers at stadiums
using that data from you guys? Yeah, the
turf managers um in general are pretty
excited about having another tool to
look at to track and monitor things over
time. We're still sort of in the infancy
of determining how do you go from a
traction measurement to something you
want to do. There's there's a pretty
good amount of research in the
literature using other traction devices
about how to influence the shootute
density and potentially the root mass.
The other thing we're excited about is
working with the the manufacturers and
the sod growers because a lot of times
they govern kind of what you're able to
deal with once you're the field in the
field manager scenario. And in the
high-end football cases obviously
there's um a pretty frequent replacement
schedule associated with concerts and
also with the high use. So, we
definitely look forward to providing
them, you know, more things that are
useful and um that's going to be a focus
moving forward. And well, and I can't
let you go without having some
conversation. And I know we're really
we're over to 30 minutes, Carl. So, we
weren't as fast as we want to be, but I
do want to ask a question about
something you just said there, Evan,
which is boy, you you really enjoy being
able to work with the sod growers, and
it feels like turf grass managers can
make adaptations in the things that they
manage. Um, do you find the same thing
to be true with synthetic turf
manufacturers and people that can manage
those fields or are you more constrained
when you get a particular type of
synthetic field based on what you've
seen in the NFL? Well, this is one of
the beautiful things about natural
grass, right? That it can be shaped and
molded, you know, ecologically depending
on what the management variables are.
And sort of the sports turf manager is
the most critical, you know, the spoon
that stirs the pot, so to speak. I do
think there's appetite in the synthetic
turf world and you see how it's evolved
from, you know, the the sort of dark
ages of stadium construction, the donut
hole stadiums, you know, in the 1970s
and the turf that people used to play on
then compared to what it is now. And uh
sometimes how quickly we forget both on
the natural grass side going back to the
early 90s playing in the Super Bowl
stadiums and then also the artificial
turf. So I think both both ends of that
um dichotomy have have progressed pretty
significantly and will continue to do
so.
What a very good answer, Evan. You are
gonna make a really good senior engineer
from Biocore. All right, Carl, we're
here. It's Evan, it's so great to chat
with you. Anytime we can bring up first
principle things, right, Carl? Uh with
with forces and things like that. We're
very happy uh to talk about engineering
with a couple of uh not so bad for a
turf grass guy who turned out to be an
engineer with Biocore. Well done, Evan.
I think your brewers need some pitching,
though. I'm pretty sure Brewers need
some pitching. Your your Pirates need
some pitching, too, other than that one
guy. Okay, Carl. Good to see you both.
Thanks very much, Evan. Everybody,
thanks for joining us. We'll see you
next week. See you next week. Take care.
Thanks a lot, Ev. See you, bud. This has
been a production of Cornell University
on the web at cornell.edu.