this is a production of Cornell
University
and thanks Kevin for inviting me and
really had a number of great talks this
morning with people already so the title
of my talk is about the role of the
Andes in neotropical plant
diversification and after I sent that
title I realized that I've only spent
about six months working on this topic
and so
what you'll see is a lot about lowland
rainforest diversification and then
um
the latter part focused more exclusively
on the Andes which which is a sort of
more recent development
um and as Kevin mentioned I'm very
interested in tropical forest biomes
this graphic will probably explain why
this shows the global distribution of
tree diversity and we have three main
biomes here we have arboreal forests
represented in blue we have our our
tempered Zone forests in red and we have
our tropical forests in green and each
of these boxes represents the number of
species of trees in each of these
regions and this these numbers on the
side indicate the total tally so you can
see 161 species about 1600 species here
and then 43 000 species in the tropical
realm so it's a huge diversity in global
terms in tropical forests
and then when you think not at the
regional or Continental scale but at a
very local scale there are many species
that are packed into very small areas in
tropical forests so in this forest in in
Ecuador
algentry noted that there were 300 tree
species All Above 10 centimeters in
diameter in a single hectare of forest
so this has been a topic that's been
interesting to biologists for over a
century there are two main ways to
approach this question of why is there
so much tropical diversity one is
through an ecological approach which
would focus on why there are so many
species coexisting in small areas that
be focused on competition or bivory
the other way approach would be to look
at the evolutionary history of those
forests and that that's sort of the main
area that my lab is interested in
laughs
um so the overall talk outline I'm going
to talk a bit about the history of the
tropical forest biome
um
I'm going to talk more exclusively about
rainforests and particularly work that
I've done on the phylogiography of
widespread rainforest trees
and then finally I'm going to talk about
ambient plant diversification and its
role in sort of creating all this
diversity
Forest history we have to go back to
Alfred Russell Wallace and he noticed
you know way back in the 19th century
that one reason why tropical forest
probably had so much diversity is
because they've been so stable as a
biome not only do they not have these
very bitter Winters and you know
dormancy that's required of of plants
and animals but also over geological
time periods they've been much more
stable so they haven't been recently
wiped out by glacial glacial activity
um and so if we think about the
geological history of tropical forests I
want to just prevent present a little
overview this will take us back sort of
starting at the KT boundary
k3t boundary is where we at least have
fossil records we know we had forests
that are similar to Modern forests so
the KT boundary and Beyond in the
paleogene we have
here is our representative of the
tropical forests and since we're already
outside of the tropical region we have
to give another name for these forests
this is what we call Mega thermal
forests so these are forests that cannot
endure any kind of freezing they're
they're warmth loving so the mega
thermoforests extended all the way up
into New York Michigan during the
paleogene and so there's a much greater
expansion of forests from 65 to 24
million years ago
and this because the Earth was much
warmer and there was less of a
latitudinal gradient in changes in
temperature
and we know that from fossil records in
Columbia that tropical forests were
highly diverse even in this very early
stage of rainforest development as
diverse probably as today at least at
the generic level level of Genera
if we look at the neogene sort of the
past 24 million years until the
beginning of the ice ages we had many
important developments for us the mega
thermal forests sort of shrank and
contracted into the equatorial regions
so now they're mostly within this
tropical area
but we see a lot of developments
geologically we see the the emergence of
the Isthmus of Panama
which is a land bridge that connects
South America and North America allowing
for the Great American biotic
interchange
we see the development of the Andes
Mountains during this this period in
time
and so this is important in terms of the
development of sort of South American
Landscapes
and then finally the quaternary the past
2.6 million years this is a period
marked by Major climatic fluctuations
glacial interglacial periods and when
there were glacial periods that's when
the forests shrank the most in their 65
million year history it's a much smaller
extents than they were in the past 65
million years and this led to the
development of The pleistine Refuge
hypothesis which posited that the
contraction of these rainforests would
have led to an accelerated rate of
speciation during the past 2.6 million
years
and so this is the overall view if we
look back 65 million years to present
this is these are proxies for
temperature Global mean temperature and
this represents a higher temperature so
the peak temperature was a sort of
paleocene eocene boundary and then our
global temperatures have got
increasingly cool over the cenozoic and
now they're they're moving back up into
these areas but the area but the
temperatures that are predicted for the
year 2100 are similar to some of the
temperatures that we see here in this
neogene time frame and they're even
warmer earlier in the Earth's history
yeah one thing that we discovered in
just looking at the phylogenies of in
the biogeographic history of the major
families that comprise rainforests if
there has been a lot of movement across
continents of rainforest lineages so
even though we think of South America as
being isolated for tens of millions of
years there's actually been dispersal
events that have been significant and
then that have resulted in the invasions
of
Continental biotas
um very quick depiction of continental
drift
um
has about 65 million years worth of
movement and at 3 million years ago we
have Panama connecting North America and
so we have this great American biotic
interchange but at many points
throughout the past 65 million years
there have been migration events while
South America was an island continent
including from these megathermo forests
that were in North America and Europe
which we call the boreotropics from
Asian forests from Africa and Toby
Pennington and I tried to quantify the
impact of this migration and we looked
at the yasini forest inventory plot
which is 25 hectares has 1100 species
and we estimated that 30 percent of the
tree species and about 30 percent of the
biomass the actual stem counts came from
immigrant lineages
um so it's a very important impact of
long distance dispersal
so this led to there are two major ideas
when I was a graduate student that I had
thought about about tropics and the one
that is associated with Alfred Russell
Wallace is that the tropics are a kind
of Museum of biological diversity
because of the state stability of this
biome and their long history and being
even more expansive than they are today
species will be able to accumulate over
time without much of an Extinction rate
and so under this model you'd expect to
have fairly old lineages that go all the
way back through the center Zerg
but under a cradle model this is where
these other ideas about you know the
impact of potential pleistocene refugia
coming into play or maybe you know more
recent geological developments driving
speciation under those models the
tropics may be an area of active
speciation with high Extinction rates
where you would expect most of the
diversity to be more recent in origin
and that's kind of broadly called a
cradle model
and we can represent that
phylogenetically under a museum model if
we think back through the synagogue from
the present back to the KT boundary or
the kpg boundary under a museum model
we'd expect common ancestors of our our
species in general to sort of coalesce
going way back through the past 65
million years whereas under a cradle
model we expect very small Branch
lengths and more recent diversification
an example of the the Cradle model was
founded in the genus Inga so Inga is a
tree genus about 300 tree species only
found in neotropical forests most of the
species are widely distributed and
morphologically very distinctive from
one another
um Toby Pennington James Richardson and
colleagues tried to work out a phylogeny
and found that they couldn't work out
the phylogeny there was not enough
phylogenetic resolution not enough
genetic Divergence among the species
and they placed the the genus phylogeny
into the broader legume phylogeny
and estimated that the genus arose 6 to
10 million years ago
with two-thirds of the species
originating during quaternary
which was consistent with sort of a
pleistocene refuge hypothesis
and they they suggested that you know
this is this may be the case with most
Amazon tree species that uh most Amazon
trees may actually be very recent in
origin
so my my supervisor postdoc collaborator
at the time and I were invited to write
a perspective piece in science for this
article and it just didn't strike us as
being
very realistic and the reason being is
that when we think about the force that
we were familiar with in Bar Colorado
Island and yasini there's a very deep
taxonomic structure so not only are
there lots of species but at higher
levels the level of genus and families
there's also a lot of higher level
taxonomic diversity so that for example
in this yasumi Forest
with our 1100 tree species in a 25
hectare plot there are 333 Genera and 81
families of plants represented
and so we can look at the distributions
of how many
species there are per genus on the
average so about 160 of those Genera are
represented by a single species and many
of those Genera are in fact monotypic
there are many gender that only have a
single or one or two or three or four
species they're species poor and so Inga
is actually the extreme extreme outlier
it's a Genus that has 43 species in this
Forest plot so in this regard Ingo is
something of an outlier
and so at the time I was doing Philo
Geographic work and I became interested
in particular in widespread widely
distributed species that were found in
both in Central America and in South
America
and also thinking about the age
structure of some of these species poor
Genera
and so my first work was focused on
Symphonia globulifra this is a species
in Ecclesiastes
it's very distinctive in rainforest it's
something that I as a graduate student I
saw it frequently in manaus Brazil as a
postdoc I saw it in Panama when I
visited French Guiana I saw it in Forest
plots there I saw it in yasuni
everywhere I traveled I saw it and and
interestingly enough it's also very
common and widespread in Africa
um it has a very distinctive morphology
which is very important because when
there's a thousand trees in the forest
you want to be able to identify your
species no matter which Forest you're in
so I could always identify it to a
combination of characters these aerial
buttress uh these aerial roots and a
sort of a bright orange latex very
distinctive globular flower
um
and another really useful point about
Symphonia there's only one species of
Symphonia found in the near tropics and
it has a very distinctive pollen type
and the pollen has been used extensively
by the oil industry for stratigraphy so
if they want to find a character that
indicates that there's rain forest in a
particular region or find the age of a
particular site they often look for
Symphonia pollen so we actually have a
pretty good record of the fossil
distribution of Symphonia relative to
other rainforest trees
so at the time they were that I was
doing the study there were no follow
Geographic studies of tropical plants
tropical trees and one of the things
that Drew me to Philo geography was was
traveling and so I was able to visit a
lot of these sites visit forests that I
hadn't seen before collect Symphonia and
then I relied on herbarium material to
fill in the gaps or bury a material from
Africa and from other locations
and I use standard plant systematic
markers its chloroplast DNA
not knowing that these would even be
variable within this species
so this is a these are the sites that I
visited and this is actually based on
its internal transcribed spacer sequence
and each of these colors represents a
distinct haplotype or sequence and these
uh these circles sort of show the
clustering of where the related
haplotypes occurred
um so there's an Amazonian group
a an area west of the Andes up through
Central America it's highly diverse it
constitutes a clade a West Indian clade
and then this this African group and
this shows the fossil history so
Symphonia fossil pollen first occurs
about 45 million years ago off the coast
of Nigeria so very old as a Genus at
least
the first neotropical records are off
the coast of Brazil and in the Maracaibo
Basin in Venezuela at about 15 million
years ago
and then in Central America we have the
first fossils appearing about 8 million
years ago
so just based on that fossil information
and Loan
we can infer that there have been some
Oceanic dispersal event that led to the
establishment of symphony in the Amazon
basin sometime in the Maya scene
because the West Indies have always been
islands and this is a very distinctive
genetic group this would have had to
have derived either from South America
or from Africa and then there there had
to have been assuming that there was no
Isthmus of Panama eight million years
ago there had to been dispersal from
South America into Central America by
Oceanic currents
this is the phylogenetic reconstruction
of Symphonia and all the other species
of Symphonia beside Symphonia globulifra
are found in Madagascar there are about
20 species of Symphonia Madagascar and
then one species everywhere else these
are the Madagascar the madagascan
species and these are uh
the clades within West Africa and then
sister to this neotropical group so
there's a clay that's just sort of the
Amazon region and Guyana shield and then
one that's in the trans Andes I use the
15 million year fossils to sort of
calibrate this clade in that um
gave me
you know approximately seven million
years at the age of the Central American
group which is consistent with the
fossil record
so the thing to note about this is we
have this very high level of
phylogenetic resolution and phylogenetic
depth within a single widespread species
and the species is actually older than
the entire genus of Inga which has 300
species it's a it's a Genus that it
co-occurs with in just about every
Forest but it's a very old species and
when I when I publish this work the
editor of the journal said well this is
really a living fossil you should sort
of sell it as a living fossil it's very
unusual just unchanged morphologically
for such a long period of time the other
interesting thing was what it revealed
about Oceanic dispersal leading to sort
of the assembly patterns of these of
these forests
so obviously I had this great result and
I wanted to see what I could learn about
other widespread species
so the next one that I looked at was
saber pantandra now Saba you might be
familiar with is the K-pop tree
it's one of the most enormous trees
you'll find in the Amazon basin
this is a selfie taken by Robin Foster
back in about 1966 on on BCI in Panama
or Colorado Island this tree just fell
down last year unfortunately this is
called Big Tree you can see it's got
these huge buttress roots and uh it's
got these uh these little seeds that are
wrapped in sort of a cottony silk
um it's a very fast growing it grows up
to two meters per year
it sort of establishes along river banks
and the largest ones are along the
salamois river in the Amazon basin with
nutrient-rich areas
a little bit of Natural History I love
Natural History it keeps me going this
is bat pollination of Symphonia taken by
photo taken by a colleague of mine in
Brazil
so what I found with Symphonia is a very
different pattern so using those same
sets of molecular markers this is
another haplotype map
the bottom part shows the chloroplast
DNA so the chloroplast DNA using the
most variable chloroplast region was
entirely monomorphic in other words no
variation throughout Central America
Amazon basin and Africa absolutely no
DNA sequence variation just one
nucleotide variant in the west coast of
Ecuador and there were some its
haplotypes but showing no
phyloggeographic pattern whatsoever
and it turns out that the other species
of Sabo are located in the Amazon basin
there are several other species so the
species likely originated in South
America and it got through long distance
dispersal probably the oceanic currents
arrived in Africa we know that it
arrived in Africa before pre-columbian
times because there are records of Arab
traders moving the species in the 10th
Century into Asia
um so it naturally got into Africa but
over a very recent time scale and very
weak phyloggeographic structure
and probably not a very old species
um
in general
so then I became well okay we have these
extreme cases we have one widespread
species it's very charismatic and well
known but a very recent in origin and we
have another one that's very ancient and
everywhere you go it shows deep follow
Geographic breaks and Divergence and so
I wanted to understand more about these
patterns and I decided to focus
particularly on looking at the Andean
bear barrier and looking at populations
that were located on either side of the
Andes in Northern South America
this this was fascinating to me I was in
Ecuador and I was reading the catalog of
the vascular plants of Ecuador and I
came across a quote by Peter Raven and
he indicated that you know right when
they were tallying the plant diversity
they said that 30 percent of the plants
found in little in rainforest of Ecuador
are found on both sides of the Andes
and so that that account that's about
1400 species so he said that about 30
percent of the lowland Flora has been
around prior to the uplift of the Andes
and that may that means that a large
portion of these ecological communities
have been really stable for several
millions of years because the Andes are
several million years old so I was
really interested in this idea and
thinking wow there must be large
components that are very old in these
rainforest communities
um and this is a situation known as
vicarians when you have a widespread
population and then it's sort of broken
up when a barrier Geographic barrier
rises in the middle of it that's called
vicarians so that vicarian's history
would indicate that these populations
would have a neogene age be going back
prior to the pleistocene
and so we have our northernmost Andes
these are so the most recent part of the
Andes to form in in Merida
um this would have been the final
barrier that would have been presented
and the uplift of Merida Andes is about
2.7 million years ago sort of right
between where the neogene and the
quaternary are and so as a way to test
this I looked at uh estimated the ages
of the ancestors of these populations
and if they fell well within this
neogene period that would support Andean
vicarians if they're a well in the
quaternary that would indicate some kind
of dispersal to get around the Andes and
I just want to note that not only are
the Andes important as an elevational
barrier but also right beside the Andes
you have this really dry area the anus
and so any plant that is able to get
around the Andes is going to have to
deal in some way with drought you know
with drying dry habitats
um so I picked I had 14 study species
some of them were dealt with an
individual case studies were sampled
much more broadly but for all the
species I at least sampled in Panama
Western Ecuador in the Eastern Ecuador
using these same sets of molecular
markers
and that included save a pentandra
Symphonia glaviolifera
as well as some other species that are
fairly well known like acroma which is
the balsa wood producing tree
um
Jacaranda well known for its flowers
and I also looked at well actually a
student of mine Jordan demos looked at
some functional traits associated with
these trees so he looked at drought
tolerance through ecological niche
modeling we looked at where these
species were found some of them like
Symphonia globulifra were only found in
the wettest forests true rainforest
whereas others were found in drier
Forest areas they were found in
seasonally dry forest indicating they
had more drought tolerant abilities we
also looked at some other characters
functional traits
so the results were that nine out of the
14 species had a neogene aged population
structure so they had population
histories that went back before 3
million years ago
none of these species had much
morphological variation despite these
deep temporal divergences among these
populations
and we also noticed there was this
Association the species that did manage
to somehow get around the Andes during
the quaternary
those tend to be the drought tolerance
species
um and now we're currently looking at
more species we have 85 species all
together that are shared between the BCI
and the acne forest and we're using
other molecular markers particularly rad
seek DNA to analyze these divergences
but this figure just gives you an idea
this goes back
through this 10 million year history
and we can see here's the age for our
Crossing into Andy and Divergence of
Symphonia globulifra and it's not even
the oldest species you know there are
several species that have higher levels
of genetic Divergence between their
cross-andian populations then Symphonia
does
there's this group particularly down
here this very old
then we have a couple species of sort of
the pliocene pleistocene boundary then
we have a group that definitely seem to
have their origin of quaternary or sort
of younger
but you can see some of the things that
species like Symphonia have experienced
they've experienced warmth Global warmth
warmer temperatures than are expected
for the year 2100 or global climate
change
they've experienced the uplift of the
Andes the development of the Merida
Andes the closure the isms of Panama
these have been species that have been
part of rainforest for all this period
and this just shows this sort of how the
drought tolerant and intolerance species
sort of segregate out so the drought you
know all the youngest species are
drought tolerant indicating that maybe
that have played a role in allowing them
to get around the Andes so the Andes is
really a filter it sort of lets the
drought tolerance species through but it
keeps the rain forest Specialists on
either side and separated
so this isn't Alfred Russell Wallace's
quote this is mine and it's just to say
that alongside species like Inga which
definitely do represent recent
diversification in kind of a cradle mode
there are many living fossil lineages
many lineages that are just hanging out
in the rain forest for millions of years
without much notable morphological or
ecological Divergence
okay so where do the Andes fit in we've
seen how they fit in as a barrier but
they actually contribute a whole lot
more to neotropical plant diversity so
here we have our our original photo and
here we have the the Andes
so there are estimated 45
000 plant species in the Andes
44 of those are endemic to the Andean
region so that's a huge amount of the
overall contributions neotropical plant
diversity this localized on the Andes
and there are many many important
linkages geologically between the Amazon
and the Andes and I've explored these a
lot recently in collaboration with
geologists who will dispute every point
that I bring up today but but for the
time being I find this a very reasonable
scenario this is a review paper by
Karina horn from back in 2010 and it
shows the cenozoic development of the
Amazon basin even before there was an
Amazon River so at the very beginning of
the cenozoic 65 to 33 million years ago
this is the Amazon drainage sort of
moved in this direction and it actually
flowed probably out through where the
Orinoco River is and you see that
there's not the Alpine habitat would be
in Red so there's not much montane
habitat at that point it's just slowly
developing
um and so as the Andes are uplifting
particularly these Northern Andes
they're causing uh
these drainage patterns to shift and
they're causing to at one point shift
northward at one point develop a large
Wetland system
until finally they force the drainage to
move Eastward and so we have the
development of the modern Amazon River
at about 10 million years ago
laughs
we have the continued rising up of the
Andes and as the Andes raise up all of a
sudden it changes the climate
it adds new precipitation there's a rain
shadow effect there's lots of moisture
now nearly available in this area and it
also changes Global circulation patterns
of air as well
and it also changing the Amazon basin in
a very important Way by adding
nutrient-rich sediments so for the first
time you know these are very ancient
cratons that are Sandy and not very
nutrient Rich all of a sudden you have
these new parent material rising up and
depositing all kinds of sediments into
this region so it's changing ecosystem
properties like like carbon flux as well
as well as promoting different kind of
ecological niche
then finally over the quaternary we have
the development of the giannos this dry
area and then all the climate changes
that are associated with the ice ages
in terms of biogeographic processes I've
discussed a lot about how the Andes work
as a barrier
um and it's a barrier to up of 30
percent of the rainforest species in
Ecuador
it acts as a corridor particularly for
temperate zone species to actually move
into this region in Northern South
America and potentially most of them are
are residing in this region in in
speciating when they get here some of
them actually do move into the lowlands
and of course it's acting as a
speciation pump or a cradle of
diversification
certainly the Alpine habitats have seen
an incredible amount of diversification
but I think that with these new
sediments that were formed in the slopes
of the Andes I think that also promoted
some diversification and I think that
may be where we have
Inga playing out because Inga has its
Center of distribution as a Genus on
sort of this slope of the Andes
foreign
this is a great review paper by Lou Bird
and wagon that came out recently there
have been a lot of phylogenetic studies
of clades in the Andean region and they
did a synthesis of the of these studies
and they tried to place all the ones
that had any kind of age estimates
associated with them into context and
they Associated them with different
regions of the Andes so they separate
the Andes into a northern region sort of
a North Central and Central Andean
region in the southern Andes
and these are progressively younger As
you move north southern Andes being
potentially the oldest part of the Andes
and
and if you kind of squint your eyes and
you know don't apply statistics
you can see that the southern Andes do
have quite a lot of older lineages with
ancestors that go back into the myocene
and for the northern andian Clays there
actually are a lot that seem to have
their origin in the quaternary or the or
the pliocene so it is you know
potentially possible that we'd be able
to sort of find this association with
the age of the mountain and the age of
the clades that are associated with them
so this is a project that um
that I've recently began participating
in in this past year with a group of
geologists and we had funding from NSF
from Frontiers and Earth System Dynamics
and um
the goal of it there were geologists who
are really interested in the Amazon
biodiversity and how it was generated
and they also know a lot about Andean
history and we wanted to get together a
group of people that were experts in
Indian uplift geomorphology
paleoclimatology contemporary climates
ecosystem function and they really
wanted somebody that could contribute in
terms of the plant phylogenetic history
or in Philo geographic history
so we've been meeting together regularly
and talking about these patterns and and
some questions we have like in the plant
side are we want to know like was the
diversification that we see in the
Indian clades was that because these
plants migrated into new habitats it was
very open and didn't exist before they
just immediately started occupying these
novel habitats or as some people have
suggested is it because these habitats
are kind of like Islands so these
mountain tops are like Islands so that
whenever you have climate change these
islands grow
and sometimes coalesce and then shrink
back again and so this would be a kind
of pleistocene Refuge model applied to
the tops of the mountains
um
so we wanted to know sort of what are
some of those dry what is driving that
diversification and also what are the
major drivers of the diversification
apart from allopatry with respect to
ecological niche important ecological
traits some people Al Gentry suggested
that the ability to move into
hummingbird pollination opened up a lot
of ecological space for for high
elevation plants as well as genomic
evolution
um and then what is the contribution of
the andeons associated species with
lowland rainforest diversity
thinking about Inga you know to what
extent did this cradle of
diversification impact Amazonian Flora
so we we actually will be gathering our
own data pretty soon starting this
summer
um but over the past few months what
we've done is we've gone into the
literature and we've done a
meta-analysis of existing studies and
this is a inventy collaboration with
Stephen Smith this is what when you get
a Gmail from him this is how his face
appears and anybody who knows him knows
it that's exactly what he looks like and
he's just like a beard in black glasses
and this is his undergraduate student
Carolyn who he's been actually getting
to do all the work of developing scripts
to pull out DNA sequences from genbank
Analyze them in large scale and we then
these uh diversification analyzes that
are based on
techniques that were developed by Dan
raboski who is actually a PhD student
here very recently laboratory of
ornithology so any questions about this
he'll be giving a talk here in Cornell
in a couple of weeks so
please hold your questions for him
there's a lot of mathematical magic that
happens in there that but what this
shows is a phylogenetic tree with sort
of a heat map and it shows when you have
changes or significant shifts in the
rate of diversification
diversification being sort of the
speciation rate minus the extinction
rate and this is the net impact
um
and so here we have a fast rated
diversification
slowing down and then showing a
significant Slowdown
for example in this clade here we have
the Andy and clade this is the the
common ancestor of the Andean Group
which is shown here with this Green Dot
and there's actually no evidence for any
change in the diversification rate when
this group reaches the Andes
this is the kind of thing that we're
looking at with this data
um and blue being slow rate of
diversification yellow medium red is a
rapid rate
so that that example that I showed you
there was berberus you might be familiar
with Japanese Barberry which is invasive
in Michigan
so when this genus reached the Andes it
it did speciate but not in any rate that
was different from the background rate
of speciation in other geographic
regions
this is one of the classic papers and
really important paper in
sort of explosive diversification
patterns in the Andes and this is a
Genus lupinus in the lupins and here you
can see the geographic distribution of
these lupines and as soon as they hit
the Andes represented in Orange you see
very very short Branch lengths and lots
of species similar to that Inga tree so
a very recent explosive uh phylogenetic
diversification accompanied by
incredible diversification at the
morphological level so these are some of
the some of the plants that evolved
during that radiation so including
everything from herbaceous to to trees
this all evolved within a quaternary
time scale some of the fastest
diversification rates that were measured
for plants or animals were published in
that paper
so when we look at we pull out all the
all the sequences from genbank for the
lupins from all over the world we put
them in a phylogenetic tree we can see
that across all lupines there are some
areas and some of this might be affected
by sample size as well that are are
slower or slower evolving or more
quickly evolving and here we have our
Andean group right here
but you can see that there's really no
evidence for any significant rate change
lupines
evolve very rapidly in the Andes but
they're already evolving very rapidly in
the Rocky Mountains already evolving
very rapidly in in the Mexican mountains
and when they were in the Andes they
just continued to evolve very rapidly
and uh
in all fairness the authors do recognize
that in the subsequent paper so this is
just a general pattern of Lupine biology
not necessarily something that's
specific to the Andes
draba is a is a group that does show a
strong signature of Andean
diversification so
compared to all the taxes that are
outside of the Andes when it hits the
Andes it's it it has a significantly
increased rate of diversification
festuka
um
this is another one that shows a strong
signature of Andy and diversification
but you also see that it shows a
significant slowdown so it Diversified
initially very quickly compared to the
rest of the clade of festuka but then
diversification rate slowed down
and so this would indicate to me that
potentially this is a group that
Diversified initially as these plants
came into the novel habitat but they
weren't necessarily affected by the
climatic fluctuations of the pleistocene
valeriana shows a similar pattern where
it showed a significant increase in
diversification initially followed by a
Slowdown to the present
so the initial results of the this
meta-analysis that there's quite a lot
of variability
some groups come in they speciate to
some degree not any different from the
background levels of speciation some
groups come in and show real rampant
radiations
some of them show radiations and then
stasis over coming into more recent time
scales indicating that probably
my hypothesis is that they're
diversifying initially as they reach
these new habitats but they're not
terribly impacted by pleistocene climate
changes
foreign
so the Future Works
my colleague Steven Smith is really
interested in incorporating as much data
ecological data as is possible into
these analyzes including biogeographic
data so we want to look at excuse me
um
the ecological correlates of these rate
increases
we would like to also do more
transcriptomic work we want to look at
the genus clusia which is in the
ecclesiacy this is one of the only
tree lineages that has cam
photosynthesis which allows it to
photosynthesize in very dry periods it
has a combination of C3 and cam
photosynthesis and this is a Genus that
shows high levels of species turnover As
you move up slopes in the Andes and so
we're interested in looking at the
evolution of that photosynthetic
mechanism and how some of these may have
impacted
evolutionary divergences within the
Andes
and we're also interested in working
with the geologists to better pull
together geological history with the
plant phylogenetic history in particular
biologists have been working for a long
time thinking that some of the high
elevation habitats like the paramo are a
certain age a maximum five million years
but these geologists say that the ages
of the eastern and western courtiers of
the Andes are very different and in the
western parts of the Andes which are
sort of a volcanic origin as opposed to
origin by uh
faulting that these might have a much
deeper history so we want to see if we
can find clades that are much deeper
in age than five million years
um
so I'd like particularly thank Stephen
and Carolyn I graduated in Jordan in
postdoc Ashley Thompson and my uh
geological geogenomics colleagues and
I'd be happy to take any questions
thank you
so at one point you mentioned the
genomic correlates if you're interested
in the area exploring letters
well one thing that this team is doing
now is developing biologies based on
transcriptomics he said he'll take that
the transcribe it might be sixteen
thousand of them from a number of
lineages and then perform a foreign
College genetic analyzes of those
various genetic groups and you can look
to see if there are certain groups
certain genes that are outliners are
evolving much more quickly we have
deeper branch
um and so that might be one way to sort
of get at what are the actual functions
that are involved that are evolving more
quickly than otters inside of these
groups that might perceive the
diversification before enables and to
move into the technological space so
that that would be one aspect yeah what
about things like looking at the living
fossil lineages versus the more
dispersal
to dwell dispersed lineages or read sort
of changes they think they're done with
it was like if you're a Symphonia for
example well one thing that I'm very
interested in is looking below the
surface of species like sometharnia I
mean I find it hard to believe that it's
such a biotically challenging
environment such as tropical forest but
huge amounts of pest pressure
pathogens
insect damage you know constantly that
there would be a lot of evolution
happening that may have to do with
secondary defense or other traits that
we're just not saved and taxonomically
so I I think that would be very
interesting to look at
it the last few examples we presented
are the various
et cetera
in a relative rate changes speciation
events I was wondering if there is a
higher level pattern of vivacious and
Woody and that they fall out into these
categories initially and then you're
looking for patterns within each
category and that that's a really good
question and uh
I think I want you to look at that these
are just the initial results now that
it's a very good point so they're all on
the same scale yeah I mean I'm not sure
if some of those groups it is
there's some Woody elements there but
I'm not sure if that applies together
investigations about affordably
and how that affected their Elementary
yeah I would expect there'd be less
for some reason but okay because of
longer generation times and things like
that but um
this is a more General and maybe like
naive question about a species
diversification but after something like
a long distance disparation dispersal
event
you know you might expect that species
to like diversify when it reaches its
new ecosystem but do you also see a drop
in species diversity that we're of
species that were already there sort of
like
the species that has come from far away
is an invasive and how does that impact
the ecosystem that moves to well I think
um
there aren't many cases where we have a
long distance dispersal event whereas
species arise in terms of an already
species Rich environment diversifies I
think in the case of the ambient region
I think a lot of attacks are arriving
there and then entering in an occupied
space because they're able to diversify
and just like new islands you know
diversification without too much
competition and at some point there may
be a point where there's no longer much
space to be made because there's a
certain carrying capacity but in the
dispersible event that I that I
mentioned there was never you know apart
from the ambient colonization there was
never much uh speciation after the long
distance ability
is not grounded
so how did you calibrate those metal
analysis again
so this meta-analysis don't have any
kind of time calibration on them so
they're just looking at the sphere based
on the numbers of those sort of the
relative ways so they don't really they
don't really try to put pages on this
and it probably wouldn't trust any any
kind of NHS that you would put on it
which is not enough of a possible record
for this for this tax
and it's also yeah some of these methods
are dependent on technology sampling and
so
um
how extensively the sampling is done so
that there are many limitations
I'm trying to just sort of understand
what these limitations are and what
questions
along the uh well these types of
diversifying species do they still cross
hybridize and produce hybrid progeny
um but I'm only very familiar with the
Inga and those species to my knowledge
are very morphologically distinct and
without too many intermediates and they
also tend to have widespread overlapping
distributions so it's not as if they
speciated in small isolated valleys and
then having that contact but somehow
they manage the species and then develop
reproductive barriers to
wider overlapping distributions for the
other groups of the Miami
cases because
you have a
population that's widely distributed and
then have it interrupted by the Andes
how do you can you rule out this
personal algorithm is to attempt the
similarities between the two components
yeah that was the main question is
um like was that
Peter Raven started suggest that this is
a sort of a My caring scenario
where the enemies just divided the
populations
for the alternative hypothesis is some
kind of dispersal and
what would be nice to do with you to get
enough taxes to just determine whether
that's been the case and there are some
relatively low areas in the Andes 2000
meters where conceivably some affordable
periods of time there could have been
some kind of dispersal they're also did
a big dispersal in that sort of what is
now Beyond us sort of along the slopes
of the mountains there are other
possibilities and also like in the case
of simonia and Seva yeah kind of done
around tradition and occurrence as well
before the before this was
what happens when you start nesting
species which are inside into higher
attacks in your analysis in other words
do you find that let's say a family
level with some families are prone to
throughout the diversification of slow
diversification because there's always
this idea as to
is there something intrinsic to a Clay's
genomic potential to morphologically
diversity well I'm starting to think
that about legumes that I'd be
interested in what people have to say
about that but they've got every time to
get into
legumes are a dominant family trees in
the rainforests around the world
so there might be something
there might be certain groups that
really can Diversified for some reason
available propensity for some reason or
another it could have to do with their
reproductive biology or
previzable supervisors symbiotics
it did come up earlier you know
we didn't talk enough about it but I
think that would be very interesting to
look into college that's what I was
pushing for was correlation
that's the exploration did not Escape
I guess that's it
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu