this is a production of Cornell
University thank you everyone for
joining the pppm Dei committee is lucky
today to host Theo newold a PhD student
from the Pennsylvania State
University their research focuses on the
influence of agricultural Management on
the composition of fungal Endo fidic
communities in maze co-advised by
doctors sharifa Crandle and Gretchen
cual
they are a fellow of the prestigious
foundation for food and agriculture
research program and the first student
to work towards a dual title microbiome
sciences and Plant Pathology PhD at Penn
State they have been spotlighted in
numerous Outlets including a nature
career feature article Theo is the
outgoing chair of the aps diversity
equity and inclusion committee and has
worked for social justice causes
throughout the various institutions they
have
attended through their background in
service they have been not only a
personal inspiration to me but to many
others I know in the Plant Pathology
Community today's talk is a bit of a
pivot from the typical ppmb seminars
since instead of discussing Theo's
research we are highlighting the
humanity behind the work and showcasing
the diverse lived experiences of members
of our community please welcome Theo
newold thank you so much Izzy I'm
incredibly humbled by by your by your
introduction and I want to apologize to
everybody it was my greatest intention
to be with you in person um my partner
was injured and so everyone was I really
appreciate you being able to Pivot um
and allow me the space on
Zoom so as Izzy said my name is Theo um
I'm a third-year PhD student in the
department of Plant Pathology and
environmental microbiology at Penn State
um I'm also a far fellow as she
mentioned and a microbiome dual title
student and now typically when we come
in to hear research talks often times
the recommendation that's given to us is
to use a personal
experience to bridge our audience with
our
research but today instead I'm going to
actually use my research as a bridge to
my journey and why I view the importance
of this kind of work talking about and
highlighting my mentors and work in
service
so my disseration work largely looks at
understanding how agronomic factors
shape the folar fungal endite community
of
maze now classic definitions of
endophytes typically say that these are
organisms that live asymptomatically
with implant tissue and that they either
have a positive or largely commensal
relationship with their host and this
often time ignores the cases or
situations in which parasitic um
organisms colonize that tissue as as
well excuse me um and so for for my
definition I'm focusing on organisms
specifically fungi that live
asymptomatically within a host for at
least part of their lifetime and that's
obviously building on previous
definitions and really why do we care
about
endites well fundamentally we're really
interested in them for Bio control um
and we're interested in them in the
context of their of their pathogenicity
and ability to cause disease now
traditionally when we think about end
ofy research specifically in maze we
think about most work that's been done
in Roots and seeds and this isn't
surprising right the relationship
between nutrient uptake and roots and
yield or seed Health are going to be
fundamental to our Growers who are more
most interested in the um yield outcome
of their crops um this work also
typically prioritizes beneficial
relationships um without um directly
talking about
pathogens but we really haven't looked
at what factors Drive these communities
in an above ground or for my work folar
context and why we might think about
this is in relationships to pathogens
and disease we know that these organisms
colonize full of your tissues and those
can serve as inoculum points um for
these pathogens we might also think
about the relationship between or the
success of um potential biological
control agents in um these systems and
the potential for existing microbial
communities to shape the success of
those agents and then thinking about the
ways in which climate change um May
reshape these communities and really
focusing in um on why this work is
important now what we're looking at are
a wide variety of large categories of
potential drivers of these communities
um we know um in a broad sense that
these drivers uh going to be largely um
interaction between abiotic and biotic
factors things like environmental stress
um anthropogenic
factors and my work focuses on five main
areas looking at neighboring vegetation
cover crop s looking at anthropogenic
factors such as management style um and
environmental stress and all of this
work in the context of the folar
environment the leaf is a really unique
plant organ that's going to be
continuously experiencing extremes
extreme cold or heat continuous UV
radiation direct impact with those
anthropogenic factors throughout the
season um and so this creates a very
unique space for
colonization some of my objectives I
have F five main objectives the first is
to look at these communities over the
developmental time of the plant
including the planted seed and harvested
seed and how these communities change
over developmental
time then looking at cover crops we know
that for both um conventional Management
Systems as well as organic systems that
the use of cover crops is increasing um
and we're really interested in how these
different leges are going to be
impacting these microbial
communities also thinking about very
broadly the use of organic versus con
conventional management practices and we
know that these regimes vary and they're
really more of a scale um between those
two different categories but thinking
about how those different practices
shape these communities and similarly
thinking about non-target fundas side
effects this conversation comes a comes
up a lot actually in Pennsylvania where
tarpot of corn is going to going to
likely become a bigger issue and Growers
who may not have been applying
fungicides prior may start to apply
fungicides and so thinking about how
those known non-target effects are going
to shape these
communities and then finally thinking
about stress I don't have to give you a
quantifiable measure of drought to tell
you you could walk out into a maze field
here in Pennsylvania in July or August
and you can feel it drought has been a A
continuing ongoing issue for the last
couple years and is likely to be
exacerbated as climate change impacts
are felt I'm not just here where I am in
Pennsylvania but also across the Globe
places like the global South so thinking
about how these stress events
specifically drought events are going to
be shaping these
communities all of this to say that it's
complex factors that bring these fungal
endites to their
host and I think very much in the
context of the agroecology
space in the context of the human or
socioecology space and how our lived
experiences bring us to where we are all
of us today in in this talk in some way
way or form are in the context of
Academia we all got here but had
different unique lived experiences that
brought us to where we
are I like to think of this as in the
context of
intersectionality and the context of the
experiences and identities that we bring
into a space and how that shapes our
interaction with that space say our
research for example intersectionality
comes from the field of specifically um
black feminism the word was first used
by crr Shaw in 1989
to talk about the intersection
intersectional relationship of race
class and gender and how those
specifically related to people's
experiences with discrimination and
disadvantage but we can think about it
here as the intersection of our
identities and today I have a very
unique
opportunity to take you along On my
journey and to highlight the mentors
that brought me to where I am and my
work in service
because humanizing people is very
important often times especially in the
academic space it's very easy to
dehumanize people especially when we're
under a lot of pressure we're able to
push off the realities of the world and
focus in on a specific objective I need
X or Y from a particular person and they
don't get that to me well that's on them
but when we humanize people we think
about their experiences what they're
dealing with on the day-to-day it makes
it easier to empathize and to connect
with them and so that's a big part of
what we're doing
today I want to come into this space and
recognize my identities I know realize
I'm not there in person but one of those
identities is that I'm white I'm a white
eff feminite person and so some of the
things I'll share with you today you
will perceive differently than if I was
a person of color or
male another one of my identities is
that I come from poverty which I'll talk
about in a little bit so the knowledge
that I come into this space with is
going to be different than some of you
who may not have experienced that I'm
also blind which means I'm entering the
space
disabled I'm also fat and I'm also
transgender and those are going to play
heavily into the experiences I've had
and how I enter this space
today when we talk about our lived
experiences oftentimes this imaginary
goal that we're going to inspire people
comes up and I tell you my goal is not
to inspire you for the love of God don't
tell me I inspired you my goals today
really are um really are simplified here
and the first off is I want you to take
away this idea that mentorship is a
critical element of success whether
that's academic success or professional
success whether you're a brand new
graduate student or you're someone who's
been in the field for 25 years mentors
are important I also want to highlight
the fact that mentorship does not have
to be complicated it can be as simple as
believing in somebody as trusting
somebody
and that prioritizing service and
Community actually will enrich our
graduate experience as well as a
professional careers
overall and I also really want to focus
on this idea that authenticity is
powerful when you show up in a space as
your authentic self people see that
people who may share similar identities
or experiences to you and they will feel
seen and included as if they belong in
that
space like all stories we're going to
start at the beginning in Huntsville
Alabama in
1992 I grew up in Rocket City USA about
until the age of five at the time this
was a very small place if you've been
there today you know it looks nothing
like this the biggest things of the time
were the Huntsville mall pictured here
and the rocket
center at the time it could be cut said
that I lived in a perfect white picket
fence home and family my father was a
computer engineer my mother a
stay-at-home Homemaker who took care of
me and my sister cooked beautiful
dinners and maintained our Iris
beds as a child I can remember this
picture up here is our old home used to
be a pine tree in front a pine tree in
back and I remember running through the
grass in hot summer day and smelling the
pine and it felt so comforting and
idealic but like things that often
appear idic they're often not and when I
was five about a year after this cute
picture of my sister and I were T was
taken my mother packed my sister and I
into a U-Haul with all of her belongings
less than $100 in her pocket and drove
across the United States to
California in California I grew up in
Altadena it's an interesting ju to
position because as you can see from the
picture it's beautiful with massive
sloping mountains lots of
green it's also famous for being in a
lot of movies for being where famous
cinematographers and artists live but
it's also a place of extreme poverty I
grew up in a largely redlined
area and without resources it meant that
my childhood was a little bit
complicated and this was further
Complicated by the fact that while we
lived with my grandmother at the time
who I am very generously compared to for
her strength and
passion she was dealing with a lot of
health problems one of those is
uncontrolled diabetes which made her
incredibly um abusive
and so I grew up in this environment
where we didn't have the resources
necessary and
abuse which made my academic
world fuzzy it meant that school became
a place to
escape but it also meant for me at least
this lack of resources that I struggled
heavily in school as a blind student who
didn't have uh updated glasses or didn't
get to see the my eye doctor frequently
enough I struggled to read to write and
to engage with the work that I was doing
and because I struggled and had poor
grades my mother who had never gone to
college made it very clear that I likely
would never go to college myself because
she couldn't afford it and because you
had to be a straight A student to get
scholarships she didn't know that you
could go into life altering debt to get
an education but at the time the
accumulation of my home life my lack of
resources and my struggle in school
meant that I really didn't know I was
there and I really didn't
care it was up until I got to my 11th
year my second to last year of high
school I just transferred from a uh
local Charter School to the Blair IB
Magnet High School another in
interesting juxtaposition in my life
where while simultaneously being a very
well-recognized institution it was also
poorly funded sat along a um freeway and
across the street from us was a power
plant but this was a serious moment of
change for
me I remember day
one after we have the initial meeting
with with all of the all of the teachers
we got our books and our class schedules
everyone Milling around the campus
looking at all the different clubs and
things available to do and against one
of the far fences there was a rickety
brown table with huge three poster
display Boards of people people in
hospitals people setting up
beds everything in the medical field and
I ran over super excited it was a unique
opportunity I thought I want to be
involved in this and this little old
woman sitting at the table Miss Deborah
Hawks who's pictured here she saw my
enthusiasm and made sure I was able to
get
involved she didn't just see my
enthusiasm as an initial starting point
she saw it as my main driver she cared
more about my enthusiasm and excitement
throughout my entire program than she
did my
grades she gave me every opportunity in
a way that no one else had saw my
potential in a way no one else had and
most importantly she helped get me my
first research experience when I was in
high school it was 11th grade we were
working with graduate students from
Caltech on what's very politely called
the solar Army it's a huge NSF Grant to
support um interact research experience
es for for high school students focusing
on sustainable energy and the project we
worked on was identifying alternative
catalysts for solar
panels it was an incredible opportunity
not only did I feel seen in the lab seen
in this space my enthusiasm and
capabilities were beyond my grades I got
the experience to not only do research
but also present that research at one of
our
conferences and I knew at this point
that I wanted to go to college I wanted
to pursue
science and at the time I participated
in a program that would have gotten me
into uh a Cal State
University but it was me and 40 other
people competing for that single spot in
the Cal State University system and
while I didn't make it I did get
accepted into University but the thought
of going into debt even at the time
which was only $20,000 a year was so
scary to me that I just decided to go to
our local community
college and for those of you who've gone
to City College or Community College you
know that often times this is a extreme
point in our lives of positives
negatives and a lot of growing
up for me it was so much so that I
really wasn't sure if I wanted to
continue with school by the time I
finished in
2015 I was ready to call it
quits but I was also really trying to
escape home and let me tell you there's
no better place to escape home than the
coast of
California I applied and got into
California State University Monteray Bay
where I did my bachelor's and this is
really where things
changed in my second to last spring
semester I took a plant physiology class
with the only guy on campus doing plant
work I was so excited I got to work with
Dr Timothy miles he was he was our our
professor for the
class and he saw just like Miss Hawks my
enthusiasm my enthusiasm mattered more
than my grades in this space the
constant questions and excitement about
the topics and at the end of the
semester when his graduate Stu or sorry
when his undergrads
graduated he offered me the opportunity
to come work in his lab funded research
mind you to work in his lab to the
undergraduate research Opportunity
Center and this was an incredible point
in my life I was so excited the work I
did focused on comparing molecular
diagnostic tools and optimizing DNA
extraction methods for pyop cinemoi and
blue blueberry and
avocado and while I also got the
opportunity to present at a local um
Symposium on campus I don't have any
pictures because I was so happy but Tim
also sent me to my first American
phytopathological society meeting it was
2017 San Antonio
Texas I was so nervous I couldn't even
say the name of my pathogen I think I
just called it
momy I was scared and excited I met so
many different people studying so many
different things that when I came back
to Tim I said Tim I have to be a plant
pathologist I have to do it this is what
I want to do with my life i' had such a
good time i' found passion and Tim goes
well I guess you're going to grad school
and well I didn't have a lot of context
for grad school Tim's connection to the
foler Pathology world did bring me to
organ State University where I worked on
my
masters and I worked on my masters with
Dr wal
mafy my research was really cool I got
to explore the um Fitness cost
associated with stul and fungicide
resistance in the great powdery mil
pathogen Aeros aater and the research
was great and I learned a ton but really
what Walt did was two things he trusted
me he trusted me way no one else had he
trusted me to fail and he trusted me to
succeed he was there to pick me up when
I failed and there to push me when I
succeeded he trusted me to come in at 5:
am which by the way would not recommend
um and get my research done but
something else he also did aside from
trust me was that he always came into a
space authentically now for him it was
largely because he didn't know any other
way to enter a space but he was always
100% himself from cargo shorts and
flipflops in
Winter to to the appreciation for
students with non-traditional
backgrounds while it was
something and his trust in me and his
authenticity really helped me see and
express my authentic
self part of this was exploring
exploring my gender identity and using
new pronouns part of this was bringing
my partner to campus events and talking
about my perspectives and Views and
needs in the context of social
situations but also got me involved in
supporting other students and regardless
of of how you feel about employee unions
they're a critical part of The Graduate
experience I so happened to serve not
only an executive Council of our
employee union the Coalition of graduate
employees at Oregon state but I also
served as a liaison between our
department and the union and this was a
transformative
experience at this time I also got the
opportunity to serve on several
diversity Equity inclusion committees
within the department of Bot imp Plant
Pathology at Oregon
State and in that time one of the main
things that I did was rather than
focusing on equality which at the time
was the main focus at the time I brought
in this idea of equity not only
including that in the name of our our
committee but also in the language that
we crafted in support of the
Department's efforts now when we think
about equality typically this is
everyone having exactly the same thing
the example you can see in this picture
we have three people watching a sporting
event one and each person has a single
box but one person at the end is already
very tall and with the Box they can
definitely see the show or the game but
they don't really need the box and the
person at the other end is a lot shorter
and even with the one box they still
can't see that's equality but Equity is
the redistribution of
resources and so in this example we see
the giving of the box from the person
who's very tall to the person who's very
short who now engaged with that game and
so I included language on Equity as a
reminder a reminder that we need to
actively be involved actively
redistribute our resources to support
underrepresented students coming into
the department and I'm very proud of
that during my time in Oregon State I
also had the Deep privilege to meet Dr
Brian klin who used to be who oress is
was was an alumni of of
Cornell she like me was also blind she
gave me a lot of advice and perspective
on her experience in building resources
and self- advocacy but she
also brought me into the diversity
Equity inclusion space on a much larger
level Brienne saw my unique experiences
as valuable and
important she said that people with
diverse experiences like mine need to be
in positions of power and authority and
so when the opportunity came to nominate
chairs for the diversity Equity
inclusion Committee of APs she nominated
me it was 2020 we were on Zoom I was
incredibly overwhelmed by this
opportunity but everyone voted for me
and I was brought in this was a
transformative
moment the cdii has become a home for me
I've had many mentors and people that
I've worked with over my time with them
and some people ask us why diversity why
is diversity important well here's the
answer from the website which talks
about how diversity is an integral part
of APs history and Mission and values as
a society for me I think about diversity
as an integral thing to think about
because when we're not centering
diversity it's very easy to exclude
people whether intentionally or
otherwise from the research
space and research is emboldened and
strengthened by the power of diverse
perspectives and ideas when everyone
thinks the same way we're never going to
think outside the
box one of the great problems of our day
is being able to address major Plant
Pathology challenges and without people
with diverse perspectives we can't do
that and the field doesn't move forward
and for me that's really why I care
about diversity in the context of of
APs I want to highlight some terminology
as we move forward thinking about
diversity and inclusion so diversity is
the summation of of identities right
people's sexual orientation gender
expression race but all these other
identities as well such as citizenship
status that's diversity but
inclusion is where all of these
experiences all of these people have a
place at the table and a
voice and when we think about inclusion
one of the biggest biggest uh parts of
our work when like when I served with
with the diversity Equity inclusion
committee within um Oregon State's Plant
Pathology Department um and also within
EPS is we're not just trying to bring
people in we're trying to get them to
stay to want to stay and so to be
inclusive some ways that we can foster
retention are first by building trust
and the this is not an exhaustive list
by any any stretch of the imagination
these are just some examples of things
to think about so first is building
trust we can build trust through being
transparent about expectations and
policies in the University system we
might think about this as being really
transparent about our expectations as
advisers but also as advises what do we
plan or expect to get from the people
who who are leading us might also think
about this in the context of of APs so
what does the aps meeting look like what
are the expectations for people coming
into that space right and by being
transparent we actively build trust we
can also practice
allyship and being an ally is is not an
identity that you can can give yourself
it's an identity that you are given for
your work and practice of allies ship
for different communities and so when we
practice allyship this looks like um
using pronouns and chosen names so for
example my pronouns are they and them My
Chosen name is Theo even though my legal
name is Chelsea right and so actively
being supportive by using the correct
name and pronouns we can work to change
spaces when issues of accessibility or
safety are brought to our attention so
thinking about this in the context of
the University system if you have a
gender queer person who doesn't have
access to a gender neutral restroom what
are we ways in which you can support
access for that person and for the
community right and then listening to
people is really awesome it's great but
if you listen to people and you don't
respond you don't act on the things they
tell you that comes back to point one
where you're you don't actively build
trust so when we we also have to act
when we listen to people and then
creating a culture of honesty and
critical
self-evaluation authenticity as I said
is really important being honest is very
important what does honesty look like in
this particular context it means coming
back to point one
transparency and then critical
self-evaluation isn't just you as an
individual person but it might be your
department it might be your college it
might even be your lab right lab group
thinking about um critical self-
evaluation so the cdii really focuses on
that connection between diversity and
inclusion to do this we actively provide
training um and career developmental
resources for people within within the
um within APS we work to facilitate um
development of social contact right
interaction with people this is really
important especially coming out of the
the key parts of the shutdown thinking
about ways in which we can interact with
with each other um more um we act to
promote communication and interaction
among members with diverse backgrounds
that's a big part of that inclusion
portion um and then really inclusion
comes down at the bottom this enabling
the integration of all underserved or
under represented groups these are kind
of the main the main goals of the
committee I was asked to talk about sort
of key things that came about while I
was working with the committee from 2020
to 2023 um the first thing um I did and
this happened around the same time I was
working with the Oregon State the Oregon
Oregon state folks was this inclusion of
the word Equity I realized when I was
putting this together I couldn't
remember the original name of the of the
cdii but I think it was the diversity
and quality and inclusion committee
but adding the word equity in there as a
call to us to remember to to um actively
redistribute resources and and promote
inclusion um I worked with our
accessibility subcommittee on crafting
an article and accessible presentations
that was for ismp PMI which I know has
been used in some of the courses here at
Cornell um and then comprehensive
recommendations for APS on accessible
meetings this is for both inperson um
and online meetings um and a big part of
this is that we update it every year and
resubmit it to leadership as
recommendations um we also work to
include pronouns and chosen names during
um annual event registration as well as
disclosure um an accessibility uh
request during registration the
accessibility request is a really big
one um we felt really strongly about
getting that through largely because
prior to this prior to open disclosure
people would have to email somebody to
ask for um support um and really what
this really ended up H resulting in is
that the person who was getting emailed
either lost the emails were too busy
um and we're trying to deal with
accessibility requests at the last
minute that often couldn't be put into
action so people weren't being able to
fully engage with our meetings we also
worked on developing The Hub which is an
APS diversities resource um website
through the aps website and this really
came about by work by Dr um Dr maram
Carter who headed the um black lives
matter task force and put together
anti-racism Resources with with her task
force back in um 2020 and
what does some of these what does some
of this work look like so annually we
have an lgbtqi networking event at um
plant Health we also work to hold um
hold workshops such as our mentorship
Workshop in 2022 and then we work to
have panels both during the annual
meetings um and online throughout the
year um I'll note that these last two we
we put together um the beyond the land
acknowledgement any invis um envisioning
accessible science we put together but
due to Exterminating circumstances
really weren't able to come to fruition
but really we're we're incredibly
dedicated to this work and so even when
thing we're not able to host the events
we plan um moving forward and continuing
that work is is very
important thinking about why someone
might want to take on leadership uh
whether that's with the CDI or in the
context of of any other APS committee um
I was asked to talk a bit a bit about
sort of the outcomes or the benefits and
these are the three that I found I
really thought about I thought about
resume building right these are things
you can add to your CV you can also um
build leadership experience oftentimes
especially as grad students we don't get
the opportunity to practice leadership
in this sort of capacity and so this
gives you a really large platform for
doing that and then building your
mentorship network um these are some
people that I met out of this committee
work who serve as both professional and
academic and career mentors to me and I
am incredibly um I I think this is an
incredible as asset from my work with
the
committee um some other ways in which
you can be in service can also look like
um being authentic and showing up on
social media for me um this has looked
like my work um my my specifically my ex
or Twitter page which I focus on
highlighting my identities including a
rainbow flag that I'm disabled and queer
um as ways to show to other people who
might see this profile who might also
share this identities and might be
thinking about whether or not they want
to stay in Plant Pathology or stay in
the sciences and where they want to go
that there's space for them um that they
can take up space and that they're
wanted wanted here in our
field also being visible um in your
discipline so I think in more of a
professional context for me I use
LinkedIn pretty heavily um and I share a
lot of the um more professional side of
the work that I do um or I'm involved in
so for example involvement um recently
with The Graduate women in stem here in
their Empower conference um and really
highlighting more the professional side
of my identity in this space but also
thinking about taking opportunities to
share a lived experiences so like like
today with meet we coming in and talking
to you today even though we're over Zoom
right we recognizing this is a very
vulnerable
thing right but these are also great
opportunities to show people that
they're welcome in these spaces some
other examples I have a mini profile for
example with women in in science and as
Izzy mentioned earlier yes I was
interviewed for for nature careers
talking about sizeism um the scientific
workplace so these are great
opportunities for building visibility
and then the last one I want to touch on
very briefly is this breaking bonds of
shared trauma in your
profession um ways in which I do this is
promoting very actively um and
prioritizing mental health with the
undergrads I work with um when they're
having bad mental health days I really
don't want them in the lab I want them
to focus on themselves and that is a a
strong line that we we build together um
and I I urge you regardless of where you
are in your career where you are in the
context of of your field to think about
ways in which you break or build or
reinforce those bonds of trauma in in
your profession because this can be a
critical critical part of how we retain
people in our field going forward I've
actually uh taken a step back from my
work in social justice what happens when
you spend a lot of time talking uh you
don't actually get to spend a lot of
time listening and things are always
changing I think about the lgbtq queer
and trans space that I take up the
current situation
politically with what it looks like to
be Trans in the United States and the
fear that builds from
that and so part of this is really
stepping back and listing so that I can
go forward and do better work in the
future I'm also focusing on exploring my
needs um and exploring New
Opportunities so what this looks like is
I back in 2021 um I joined the
Department of Plant Pathology
environmental microbiology here at Penn
State with Gretchen CAU and Sher crle um
I've taken more of a agroecological
research um opportunity with them um I'm
focusing more on family here we can see
a picture of of my partner Michael and I
but really this also includes focusing
on my mother who is who is aging and
dealing with health issues and really
thinking about what it looks like for me
to be involved in her life while also
doing grad school um I also um pursued
the far fellows program um as a major
point in in focusing Less on academic
career paths and more on industry I've
got involved with alternative um
leadership opportunities on campus such
as our graduate professional Student
Association got involved in other
professional societies such as the
ecological Society of America and have
continued my union work with the
Coalition of graduate employees here at
um Penn
State I wanted to very very briefly and
we can I can talk with the grad students
about this later mention the farf
program if you haven't heard about it
before it's through the foundation for
food and agriculture it's just one of
their many branches of the work that
they do but it really focuses on
professional development and career
guidance for this next generation of
agricultural and food scientists um and
really what it does is it provides stien
um as well as professional development
funding and training um and formal
mentorship support to graduate students
specifically graduate students are
really interested in nonacademic track
um career paths and we can talk more
about that later if you're interested
I wanted to bring it back to those
initial
outcomes just to remind us that
mentorship is a critical element of our
success it's a critical element of My
Success I owe most of what I have to to
the mentors who have opened open roads
for
me the mentorship does not have to be
complicated right Walt just showed up as
himself Walt trusted me and that was
enough to give me strength and personal
and personal
power and that prioritizing service in
community is an enriching part of our
careers whether it's graduate school or
professionally you I personally believe
that science is such an important
valuable thing to us as as fundamentally
to human beings that I want to bring
people in and keep them there and I
think that that's a big part of the work
that we we all should be doing in some
way in our career and then the power of
of authenticity showing up as yourself
shows other people that they can show up
at themselves and that's a critical
element element to to who we are as
people I wanted to thank the people who
fund me in my my graduate research I
want to thank the labs that supported me
provided uh feedback on on my
presentation and getting me to where I
am today and to remember and appreciate
the mentors who supported me in in my in
my
path um I'm more than happy to take
questions and I would love to connect
with you I tried to separate these QR
codes out as much as I possibly could uh
so that if you wanted to scan them you
can also my name if you just Google me
typically shows up um shows up on on
Google pretty pretty readily but I'm
happy to take any questions you have
now thanks so much Theo for that I
really appreciate it um what questions
do we have from the
room oh yes sorry please go ahead should
I or um I think if you yeah just talk
real loud
probably thank you so much Theo your
presentation it resonated with me in a
lot of different ways um I wanted to ask
I mean I know it's like it's really
important to focus on positive
relationships and positive mentorships
um yeah
is could you talk a little bit about if
there have been any barriers to
understanding in your lived experience
and like how you managed to overcome it
um because I think like
for I I don't know my lived experience
like I have some invisible disabilities
so like there's uh a lot of difficulty
there with like um allowing people to
like fully understand how things impact
me and I'm wondering if you have any um
any similar sort of experiences and how
you went through that I think one of for
me a big part is and I think I mentioned
this early on the mar family didn't have
a resources um part of that was that I
essentially didn't know I was disabled
until I was in
college I didn't realize that I had
struggled academically because I didn't
have the things I needed right to
succeed and I think often especially for
like A5 folks who may get diagnosed with
with other invis with with invisible
disabilities later on uh that that could
be a big part of it as well thinking
about the resources we didn't have
um going forward it's really been about
discovering the resources that I need
and making it very clear that those are
what I
need that doesn't mean I always get them
right so like I may need support I may
need like a support person to drive and
there's obviously may not be funding to
bring in a supp person to drive me
around so it turns to you know who in
the lab has time does my husband have
time who can I find have time how can I
shift my research project around right
to meet the availability of people to
drive me to go do sampling it might also
look like me doing uh like what we I
would say situational sampling right
where it's close by readily available I
don't have to do a lot of driving or
going to a bunch of different um
research sites largely because of of my
disability um I think also it's hard to
explain to people so when I say I'm
blind right we know that blindness is a
spectrum and so I am able to see and
read a lot of things but can't always
and so it's it ends up being about Nu on
and how to communicate that Nuance
nuance and often I can't and I end up
just kind of giving up and walking away
because it feels weird to continuously
have to like
validate my experience so that's sorry
I'm I'm rambling at this point but
that's that's what I can share on
that I I agree thank
you great talk thank
you excellent what other uh questions do
we have from the
room uh yes please oh I was going to say
um I was curious if you could elaborate
a little bit more on your like thought
of recommendations as a Dei advocate for
ways that inclusion be incre um I know
you talked a little bit
about I'm sorry can can you repeat the
question Izzy I think I only heard the
first first like quarter of
it sorry do you want to try talk Lou or
should I oh saying um I CU if you
elaborate expectations
for
disability around specifically
disability
inclusion is that is that the question
sorry like I said it's hard for me to
hear do you have for increasing
inclusion um in Academia sorry like like
like
categorically uh sure like the one
example that you gave of um including
you know on in registrations like uh
you know do you have do you have any
like requests um you know for things
that you need and how that was a a
really um you know that was something
you know it's kind of a game changer
that's really uh any other
recommendations like that I mean one of
my biggest recommendations is actually
at like a university level that um
specifically around I mean you were
talking about like accessibility
oftentimes we have offices right whether
that's a diversity inclusion office
whether that's a Ada office right that
are most of the work that they do is
geared towards undergraduate students
and the work that they don't typically
do is around graduate students or
postdocs who may not fall under the the
normal like HR Support and so I think
first off is education in those spaces
around Pro around what what's needed so
like what are the resources that are
needed um and then thinking about where
the funding and support from the
University what advocacy departments can
do around making sure that money is
allocated to those
resources
um was that kind of what you were
thinking I'm like like I said I'm having
a really hard time hearing hearing H the
question yeah that's great thank you
okay uh other questions from the
room okay um it looks like and great
we're within time um in the chat oh
fantastic talk thank you so much heing
all right terrific well thank you so so
much um in 4133 man we now have the uh
post seminar lunch for uh grad students
and postdoc so um we will meet you via
zoom in a couple minutes all right
lovely thank you so much thank
you this has been a production of Corel
University on the web at cornell.edu