this is a production of Cornell
University good morning everyone thanks
Lynn for very nice
introduction um I'm also very fortunate
to work with Lynn because she's an
amazing with scientist and I think
working together you will see that in
our presentation today we are doing such
a good job I think as we scientist um so
my presentation today will be really on
novel Technologies um applied to
specialty crop on just showcasing some
of the uh projects that L and I have
been working over the last three to four
years with these new technologies this
way uh just my background very quick I
mean like Lynn mentioned I'm an
associate professor on extension
specialist in wheat science for
specialty crops um I have have a trueway
split where I'm I'm doing research I'm
doing extension I'm doing teaching but
basically it's 100% all the time um
especially this semester four semester
for me is really big semester for
teaching I have two class and I'm
teaching in semester in four semester
I'm teaching uh we San sat and I'm also
teaching an introduction to
articulture so my resarch station is
located at the Philip IM maruchi
blueberry and crownberry research and
Extension Center right in the middle of
the pine Baron sou part of New Jersey um
initially I did a lot of work on
blueberry on cranberry uh but over the
years I expanded that to Specialty crops
including veggies and tree fruits at the
station we have a very diverse group of
researcher uh we have people from USDA
uh on on rodg um breeding uh doing work
on cranberry and blueberry breeding we
have a bioinformatician we have a
diverse team of enologists plant
pathologist and wheat scientists and we
have also a molecular biology as well
and since we are working on cranberry we
have someone from Ocean Spray which is
located on our resar station as
well so yes I mention
it what are specialty crops you know
that will be the topic of what we are
discussing today but special Chups for
me in my opinion are any fruits bearing
a plant that is not so filor or wheat
which doesn't exclude the fact that from
time to time I can do soybean work as
well but everything else truthfully for
us in new is considered specialty crops
uh my research on extension focus is
really on cranberry uh because New Jers
is wrong Kingdom number three in the US
blueberry we're ranking number five
Peach We're still ranking number five in
in in the US on in the veggies uh New
Jersey is ranking relatively high for
for pepper so I did uh in the in the
last few years I did work on pepper
cooker bits asparagus and I'm increasing
my work on Grape as well okay and when I
was mentioning the maruchi center the
maruchi center is located right here in
the pons but I have extension I have
research site in South Jersey right here
at Ric and I have also research site at
Snider in Northern J so different type
of environmental condition between South
J uh on on North J which is probably
closer from what you have here in New
York so just I mean some of you know
what we're are doing in in my research
in my we s team at rers uh we try to
understand the biology and Ecology of
Valu weed species that treat the
sustainability sustainability and profit
profitability of major uh new ja
specialty crop we are uh looking at
developing integrated weed management
practices to provide effective and
economically viable strategies and
definitely over the last few years we
have been doing a lot of work assessing
the risk and benefits of uh New U uh new
we control Technologies for new J
specialty
crops yes when we're looking at weeds I
mean it's always good but what we'll be
discussing today in context but why are
weeds really important for specialty
crops well if you're looking at uh what
would be the Y losses uh due to
unmanaged weeds in some of the major
North American crops everything else
being conducted perfectly meaning that
you're getting good vertiz you're
getting good disase on insect control if
you just let the weed compete uh you're
getting between 50 and 70% yeld losses
for some of these U major crops so for
soybean for example that will be
equivalent I mean we are losing around1
17 billion doar each year due to weed
management issues uh same thing for corn
dve in Sor dve in seven over 700 million
doar of of Y loss caused by by weat
competition so the direct competition
for nutrients or water or any kind of
resource is not the on impact of weeds
you have other impact to consider some
of these Weed really reduce Harvest
efficiency right here you're looking at
Palmer amarant in corn look at the size
of Palmer yes it's me right on the
picture I'm not small Palmer can grow
extremely tall and when you're starting
to get Palmer in a cornfield clearly
when you will be harvesting just the
fact that you have Palmer will reduce
not just your yield but the speed at
which you can harvest the crop as well
uh this one is a picture that I took in
in blueberry what you see right here is
daughter growing in blueberry and
daughter can be extremely parasitic and
cause severe yield losses in blueberry
just because it's a parasitic plant so
we have daughter in blueberry we have
dter and cranberry so yes I mean
parasitism is something to consider some
of these wheat can also be o for pest on
uh on disease so that's something to
consider as well and the last thing is
probably my one of my favorite weed uh
just because it's it's in in Cranberry
right here so you're looking at
cranberry on everything that you see
which is kind of yellow brownish is
actually called Carolina Redwood I spent
a lot of time before getting tenure
working on Carolina Redwood and that was
really interesting because you cranberry
is a really low growing crop and you
have this Carolina Redwood which is
overwhelming dominating the cranberry
canopy so when you're applying fungicide
when you're applying insecticide to
Cranberry most of the spray will be uh
intercepted by the Carolina railro so
just because you have the weeds uh you
will affect other Management program as
well you will not get your insecticide
you will not get your fungicide where
you need them to
be okay so when we're talking about
weeds um herbicide is still the number
one solution for weed management so in
2022 there was um around two
266 million Acres of crops in in the
United States that were treated with
herbicide so it's it's a domino
um in term of aage is really the
dominant pesticide that we are using for
for managing
pest um however this can be rapidly
changing the big problem that we are
facing on vpan onl will not deny it
because they are also working on that
but clearly I mean herbicide resistance
is really a major issue that we are
facing these days is
533 unique case of herbicide resistant
to 168 herb that have been documented in
the US meaning that aide that were at
some point controlling these weeds uh at
a specific rate are not controlling the
weeds anymore because the weeds evolve
resistance okay they were
able either by by different way to to to
survive this resist to this abide
application we have export Market access
especially when you're starting to look
exporting to Europe some of these
herbicide may not be accepted in other
countries so uh we we may have ction on
what we can export to Europe or or or
China any anywhere else consumer
perception I mean more and more
consumers are reluctant to the use of
pesticide including herbicide of course
and the last thing which is really to
consider as well is that yes I mean when
you're using a pesticide it's not
something which is neutral I mean you
have to take into account the fact that
you need to protect your worker on some
of these aide also I mean you heard
about 24d or D combat drift some of
these a that may be causing a lot of
injury to to to other crop as well so
that's something to consider on that
that's that has been a problem in recent
year with some specific
herbicides uh increasing prevalence of
of herbicide resistant weeds yes many of
the herbicide resistant Cas are located
known for soybean corn wheat and baray
and rice but if you're looking at
specialty crop if you're looking at our
chart we're actually number six uh in
term of AR number of case of herbicide
resistance so it's not just something
which is for agronomic crops it's also
something which is affecting us in
specialty
crops and just a picture of what we have
in New Jersey on L on vipan could draw
the same table for for New York but yes
I mean the first case of herbicide
resistance in New Jersey was documented
in 1980 smooth P grid resistant to the
photosystem to inhibitor atrazine
simazine and metrozine and just last
year I mean I documented a new case in
New Jersey where we have a goose grass
evolving resistance to glyphosate in
soybean field which is also a problem
for us in specialty crops because many
of these weeds will not just stick to
the soybeans they will move to the crop
cropping system especially if you're
looking at New Jersey we have a very uh
intricate network of crop where you may
have a soybean field on next to it you
will get a Blueberry field so guess what
I mean these Goose spaces will love
moving into the Blueberry Field
so that's some that's something to
consider ored uh my team will be working
on investigating ore resistant to parat
and potentially to mesotron as well so
we have constant case of potential aad
resistance that that are popping up in
in in New Jers as
well the big game changer these days is
also the fact that we have some new
regulatory changes that are um that that
we have to face especially regarding the
dunger spes act so all federal agencies
including the EPA U who are registering
pesticide must ensure that the action
they carry out fund or authorized does
not negatively impact treat on UND
dangerous bases of their critical
habitat and one good example for us in
the East including uh New Jersey and New
York I'm goates in New York as well the
B turtle is one of these uner spes that
we need to consider in term of
protection and making sure that when you
are using herbicide Insecticide
Fungicide uh the use of these pesticide
will not be putting a great or treat on
on Spaces that are already uner so these
days there is a new EPA uner spaces act
work plan for herbicide uh that has been
uh that has been produc produced on on
basically the plan will introduce some
new restriction on the use of some of
these abides so our Growers will have to
face uh new mitigation measures for
reducing spread Rift reducing runoff
erosion and potentially reducing any
kind of other speci measures that will
reduce pde exposure to uh to uner
species on their habitat so clearly I
mean if you're looking at the picture of
using herbicide these days we are
getting into a different environment
we'll not get the same Freedom at using
herbicide probably in the future so
clearly that may make that can make
every side more difficult to use so we
need to start looking at What
alternative we can have to
herdes um so there was a paper publish
in 2018 2018 looking at what will be
with Management in
2050 um we know that herbicide are not
going away we'll still need to use some
of this herbicide we don't know in some
situation how to replace them um I also
want to point out that we don't have any
new mode of actions that have been
released um across large acreage on
specialty crops in 30 years so there is
nothing in the pipe basically
if you're looking at other disciplines
in pathology onology yes they're getting
new pesticide new Insecticide Fungicide
that's not the case for us in in in weat
science so that's also something which
is stimulating the fact that we need
really to look at these new technologies
biological control um L and I were in a
class with Steve before we're discussing
that but we don't really have biological
control in weat science okay if you're
an enologist you know that you can use
some biological control for controlling
insect we don't have this kind of
opportunity uh in with science um
there's work which is conducted on on
uning crop biology for improving the the
crop competitiveness that's something
that needs to be further developed but
most of what we're doing these days is
really looking at these Nel new tools uh
looking at Precision Agriculture and
looking at robotic equipment uh that can
be U not replacing but supplementing the
use of
herbicides so that's what we'll be
discussing
today and I will discuss three different
type of technologies that um uh I've
been investigating um L investigated the
same kind of Technology as well so we'll
be looking at targeted spraying right
here we'll be looking at autonomous
Ceder on weer on the last one the most
exciting one is looking at Laser weer
using laser for killing the
weed so the first one which is really
what I'm calling the op optically
targeted abide spring and that's
something that we did in in ibush
blueberry and and Lin conducted the same
experiment uh looking at grape um so
this kind of Technology oh well my two
principal collaborator well ly of course
but I'm also ly and I we worked a lot
with a um with Roger b a uh because this
project was considered to be an
integrated solution so coming up with
something that can be reduce the amount
of ab that we are using so IU was
financially supporting this project the
project that I will present so when
we're looking at blueberries there is
different challenges when you're growing
blueberries the first one is that you're
not working on a flat ground you're
working on ill rad so you are working on
three-dimensional surface if you want
which when you're applying aide when
you're applying any kind of anything to
the soil may be more challenging uh we
have a lot of drip irrigation and I've
never been a big fan of drip irrigation
why because you have an single entry
point of water where you can wash out
wash off all theide out of the salt
profile so for me that's something
challenging to work with um we have we
population that are consisting of annual
weeds we we can deal with that but we
have also a lot of prual weed spaces
you're working with the penal crops and
you will see that in wheat science many
peral wheat spaces are really associated
with penal cropping system and we don't
have a lot of herbicide that can really
uh tackle these peral weed spaces um
something which is also to consider with
in term of wind management for blueberri
that blueberries are developing from new
canes okay so each year you have
production of new canes that will be the
support of future production for the
crop so you need to make sure that when
you app playing herbicide you save these
new canes you don't damage you don't
damage these new canes because otherwise
you will geop parize your potential uh
your yield potential in the future uh we
have a relatively narrow for uh weed
control especially with post emergence
because when you're looking at Blueberry
this way when they're starting to be
loaded with blueberry what will happen
is that many of these Branch will start
bending over Z row and when it happens
there is no way you can get any kind of
equipment moving between the rows for
cultivating or applying herbicide so
that will narrow the time at during
which you can apply herbicide and
definitely you can see it on this
picture but we really have a lot of
Reliance on on cultivation on some soil
between the rows which is a challenge as
well okay so why Burberry with control
matters well most of our blueberry in
New Jersey are grown on sun acidic soil
with low M low low water retention um
the crop has a very shallow root system
which means that yes if you have any
kind of competition especially with the
weeds because you have really um you
have very low water retention in the
soil I mean the Wheats will be extremely
competitive for you know for for or
pumping water um so yes the crop is
really highly sensitive to water stress
as well as disease on insect pest so you
really need to get good weed control
because yes it's it's weats can be
quickly be a problem weeds can be also p
on disease I man I mentioned it before
uh and again I mean Wheats can prevent
proper targeting of insecticide on
Fungicide and if you look at the next
slide right here you see what I mean um
you're looking at aeed right here
growing in blueberry and typically these
ored if they are not managed early on
they can grow taller than the blueberry
and they can really intercept any
insecticide or fungicide same as I was
showing before with scina redwoods why
do we have ored issues in blueberry
because still many Growers are relying
on glyphosate for controlling ore and
this is a perfect case of herbicide
resistance of glyphosate resistance we
know that our population of ored are
completely resistant to glyphosate we
cannot kill them with glyphosate it
takes time for Growers to integrate the
fact that they need to change their
practices that glyphosate may not be the
solution
anymore all right so when we're talking
about optically guided targeted spray
system for weed control what may be the
advantage of this system okay when we're
using the abde we want the abde to be
especially postemergence abde the one
you appli on we have emerged you want
this abide to be precisely located on on
the way that you want to control so if
you're using something that can just
apply the abide exactly where you need
it that would be great because you can
reduce the volume of abide that you
apply annually instead of doing a
Broadcast application you're just
applying the Abad where it should be uh
you're reducing the crop injury
potential associated with post abide
application because you just apply Z
abide to the weeds you don't apply
theide on a broadcast basis um what we
did in this study that we also try to
evaluate new herbicide that are not
specifically labeled for a crop using
system because be you since you can
potentially reduce the damage CA to the
crop you can eventually consider that
new abde may be label because you will
reduce amount of injury to the crop um
on event that could be considered as a
mitigation strategy for preventing of
Target herbicide movement that could
negatively impact uh T species so again
I mean you don't do a Broadcast
application you just put the Abad weight
needs to be
so so this this system a whe it system
uh you can see it right here used in
agronomic crops um and I will explain
the way it's working but clearly you
cannot apply this kind of system in
agronomic drops in a in specialty crops
if you want to work in specialty crops
we opt we decided to use a smaller
system which is really mounted on this
ATV and you have a detection system
right here and you have the spray system
associated with it so very smaller
system but more practical um you know
than than using this kind of system but
again the technology the basic
technology is the
same it's
working so the way it's working is that
um you have a sensor right here which is
meting blue light okay this blue light
will be absorbed by the weed chide by
any kind of vegetation if you want and
in turn after absorbing the blue light
the chlorophile will uh will produce
will emit near infrared in reaction to
the blue light
these neide will be sensed by the sensor
on the sensor will actuate um uh will
trigger a spray boom so that will
trigger the application of Abad exactly
where you detected
cile so you can see it right here you
have the sensor which is located right
here you have the picture of the sensor
projecting blue light on the ground uh
and it's divided in one two three four
different section each section is
corresponding to a specific number
nuzzle so you have four different
independent nuzzle that can just uh
independently apply herbicide where
weeds have been detected by the
sensor so we had this project in 21 uh
2022 both in New Jersey on New York uh
Lyn was working on Grape and I was
working on blueberry and again this
project was funded by by a for um within
the integrated solution
program so our goal were really to
evaluate the potential to safely apply
novel and non-registered abide using a
commercially available optically guided
spray system and we wanted to compare
this system the efficacy of this system
with a regular Broadcast
application so we tested different T and
I will not get into the detail but
basically we had references right here
glos glufosinate was our standard abide
that blueberry and gra grow can use I
was you also using two forine in
blueberry because it's labeled for use
in blueberry it's not labeled for use in
grape no uh everything in red right it
was new Abid that we tested to check if
there was you know if using this pre
Precision system would improve crop
safety using using the Abid on you had
two different application method either
bonded or or using the we it
system so if you're looking at we
control in blueberry uh four weeks after
application I look at three different
major weeds in our Blueberry Plantation
ground cell ored b Lane we had similar
level of weed control using either a
regular bonded Broadcast application
compared to the optically guided weed it
system so uh in term of pure we control
efficacy Effectiveness we have the same
level of efficacy between the two system
uh where it started to be really
interesting is that if you're looking at
crop uh injury uh really right here uh
that was grape canopy injury Lan
observed increasing injury over time
with some of these herbicide with a
bonded application which was not the
case of vision guided application um so
the way we are thinking it's working
that yes some of these systemic
herbicide may have been taken up by the
plant and because you do a bonded
application we have you have more heride
that can be potentially absorbed by the
plant compared to uh the vision guided
where you just put side on the we when
you're looking in blueberry we had a
different picture in blueberry okay we
saw especially if you're looking at the
new cane stunting we saw more damage on
new canes more stunting associated with
a vision guided in red uh application as
compared to the bonded application on
the think I mean my hypothesis is that
definitely this kind of system it's nice
but it's not artificial intelligence
you're just talking about a sensor which
is detecting cile so there's no
difference between the C profile of
blueberry plant on the Crile of a weed
so clearly especially on on the new
canes we applied herbicide on the new
canes because it was sensed it was
detected as as a green
tissue um that you can see it here we
had two different time of application we
had the first application and the second
application right here in the first
application when the canes were
relatively small that's the canes right
here we got a lot of injury the second
application that came later in the
season we saw definitely less injury
because the can started to get bigger so
we less exposed to to the airide
application but that's what you can see
on on the herbicide I think that this is
one yes this one was FL peroxy herbicide
and you can see that the new can
starting bending it's it's a group W
group four herbicide so you can
typically see the damage associated with
uh oxic abde um so different you know
the way you're considering the system if
it's grape or blueberry you may have
different result using this kind of
system did we achieve reduction in aide
use yes definitely when I look at my
data we measure the volume of aide we
are using on um looking at Blueberry uh
treatment we say between 40 and 55% of
the abide using this system again I mean
we got the same level of weight control
the big problem we got in blueberry is
that yes because it's not artificially
artificial intelligence basis you got
injury to the new
canes um so that crop injury gave us an
ID actually uh in 2024 this year well
yes we conducted a new triol with Lin
where we are looking at evaluating uh
the weed it sprayer right here using it
in grape for controlling suckers okay
not trying to control the weed but
really trying to control the suckers you
don't want to get any vegetation growing
on this Str because that's uh nutrient
that we not be available for where you
want to get grapes to be produced by the
plant okay so we had two system we had a
typical uh spray application that's
where my technician applying um right
here applying aide when working on
applying herbicide on the suers right
here on the second one was using the we
it sprayer is barely visible but each
time the we it is detecting the green on
the trunk and he applying a beside
strictly on on on the suers on the plant
so that's data coming from from New York
here um Lynn got the same level of um uh
sucker control between a traditional on
sucker uh removal uh using the one or
using the vision guided the optically
guided sprad system the difference
between the two was on the one spray
system she uh she used less herbicide
compared to the vision gued sprad system
but it was more mostly on this case
because when they spray the ab side they
spray both side okay when with a one
spray they only spray one side of the
plant they didn't come back the other
way now if you're looking at um yeah you
did some further experimentation on this
one comparing one side application of
the vision guided sprayer versus two
side actually you're getting the same
level of biomass reduction um looking at
these two type of application so the
vision guided one side will be providing
the same level of control of of a
regular application uh for us in in New
Jersey again I mean you're looking at
the percentage of fresh rate of the
suckers are as Express as percentage of
the non-treated control on removal we
were at the end of the season at 6% of
what we're getting otherwise without
removing the suckers and we got the same
level with the we it sprayer with the
vision sprayer if we are just using the
wand yes we get significant ly um better
control of the suur but at the same time
you re use twice more herbicide doing
that so clearly I mean for The Growers
is not I mean that's what they're doing
the on removal is typically what the
Growers will be doing so they were well
I mean if we can save herbicide go
faster just using the vision G sprayer
we we are we are all for it we don't
need to have someone working along the
vine along the roads to spray her
besides so what next we a vision guide
sprayer we want to get more automation
um Cornell got a great idea it's using
this new robotic um platform the farm NG
Amiga on try to get something fully
autonomous so transferring the the
vision guided sprayer to a fully
autonomous platform so you can get U um
you can get application of aad without
having someone driving the ATV like I
show you before so that's where we plan
to go in the future with this system uh
looking at um autonomous platform which
is a second type of equipment that we
are looking uh to investigate in um in
our research so we were looking at um
the the no Nao o autonomous platform um
on it's a project that we conducted yes
with linnn but also with Matt berui on
CLA plas Meer at University of Aransas
so it's really a Multistate project
investigating this new platform uh so
what are some advantage of robotic
readers
uh with this kind of equipment uh you
can really do weed prevention you can do
early detection and remove all of the
weed before they really start competing
with the crop um this kind of equipment
can be extremely precise so we can have
precise targeting on removal of the weed
uh you can reduce herbicide use and
actually what we're doing is that we're
not just using herbicide it's pure
mechanical control uh you have Labor
efficiency you don't need someone so
it's fully autonomous um scal scal ility
you have big system like I mean the farm
Droid and there are bigger systems than
the farm Droid but you also have very
small system that can be adapted for
very small farming operations on the
last one is cost savings yes you have
initial in high initial investment when
you're buying this kind of system but
later based on reduced labor on on the
use of pesticide on reduced use
pesticide you can you can saving cost
later as well by by just um using this
kind of equipment
so uh basically Aon platform for me are
mostly tool carrier so you will see many
of them fitted with you know finger
weers or shunks anything that can
mechanically control the weeds um on the
one I mean what is really uh necessary
required with this platform is that you
just don't want to use GPS GPS is not
precise enough okay you need to get
something that will give you centimetric
Precision you're planting a crop you
want to make sure that when you're using
cultivation it's killing the weed it's
not killing the crop and sometimes the
weed can be growing extremely close to
the crop so you need what we're calling
the RO time kinematic uh which is really
a a Next Level GPS if you want where
you're getting this centimetric
Precision that you need for for
controlling the weeds where where they
are so that's what you have right here
on on the Nao o which is really a small
robot the on that we are using uh it has
a GPS rtk Receiver right here you have a
toolbar in the back um this one is
relatively small it's only weighing 300
lb uh it's 100% electric uh it's
something also to consider it's not
based on fuel it's really based on
electricity on autonomy it has up to
eight hours of autonomy so you can run
it autonomously in the field for eight
hours uh what you can do with it is that
yes you can do weeding okay you can do
mechanical weeding by using blade on
torsion spring wiers you can use finger
wiers but what I really like with it is
that you can use a Ceder so we have been
using uh a single row Seer attached to
the Nao o robot and I like it because
you can create a map of your field you
have a GPS system on board you can
precisely locate where your rose your
corn Rose whatever crops you're planting
and later you can come back for uh
controlling the weed between the rows
because you know precisely where
um you know where um where Z rows are
located um so we did some work uh over
the last two years now we got it last
year uh we are looking at the efficacy
of autonomous mechanical we control
Based On Tools application frequency on
WE density diversity how do you compare
this kind of tools with a standard
chemical weight control on what is a
crop safety and and I will point out
that right here when you're working with
something like cabbage it's really
important that when you're owing when
you're mechanically controlling the
weeds you're not damaging the crop
because otherwise you will see yield
reduction so uh sorry we conducted trial
in 2023 at rers Cornell oners of Aransas
New Jersey on Aransas we worked on sweet
corn on New Jersey on New York we worked
on transplanted cage so you see right
here the na o cing Con on right here
walking the ground tining the ground
between the rows of of
cabage two videos yep so right here you
see the seeding autonomously no one is
controlling the robot it's seing
autonomously uh the corn on later again
it's fully autonomous you have equipment
which is coming just to control the
weeds between the rows of the
car all right so what kind of data did
we get if you're looking at trial we did
in 2023 at RG looking at the weed
biomass uh we tested different uh one
two or three passes of the n o and when
we were getting tree passes we're
getting the same level of weed biomass
reduction than using a standard aide
application so yes it works in term of
reducing weat pressure Lynn did the same
work at cage last year at Corell uh one
pass was sufficient maybe not to provide
the same level of we control as abide
but significantly reduced
we uh we biomass compared to an
untreated
check um right here it's again my a
different Tri we had on cage at reders
we did the O we did four passes We
compare with a standard Premier serde
which is prefer we use prefer on three
passes of the robot on WE gold tunder
right here and clearly uh four passes of
of the O were sufficient to
significantly reduce the biomass on was
at the same level of what you will
expect with a standard abide which is
gold tender so uh it was working well
for controlling the weed the big thing
and I mention it because it's big
problem we still have to face with this
kind of equipment is that if you're
looking at the yield if you're looking
at the cage head weight clearly with
four passes of the O we had a
significant reduction in in head weight
on on the fact is that it's mostly
associated with damage mechanical damage
that you're getting when you keep
running this kind of equipment you don't
have enough even if we have rtk we still
uh we still eat basically the
transplanted cabage and we got
sufficient mechanical damage on the
cabage for causing a significant
reduction right here and we saw that
with the O only with also so it with a
prear aile plus um plus a robot uh with
it when we're using just prear we don't
see this kind of damage IA didn't damage
the
crop uh that's a trial that we oop sorry
that we did uh this year in sweet con uh
again I mean we were looking at pre-
only preemergence abde pre and
postemergence abide and we had two
frequencies of of use for the robot
equipment we had either bi-weekly uh
twice a month a weekly application and
when we're using weekly application of
the of the O we are getting the same
level of we controllers what we're
getting from a standard preasur and post
emance Abad application program we had
some week we that escaped the the Nao o
robot and essentially this one full
panicum even with heride it's it's hard
we to control uh and clearly as this one
because it's emerging late in the season
the O didn't do such a good job at
controlling this
one uh when you're looking at uh ear
weight on ear lens clearly I mean all
the application um if you're looking
right here at the weekly application of
the na o right here you have the same
ear weight as well you will get from a
standard Abad application program now if
you're getting a bi-weekly uh definitely
bi-weekly was not enough so clearly we
need to have a frequent almost yeah
weekly page of of this kind of
Technology if you want to get good with
control okay what is next with this one
um again we want to get more autonomy we
want to try to use uh new tools um that
we can integrate with this technology uh
especially there's two different type of
tool that I think will be interesting
for us Lyn mention it in the
introduction I do significant work
looking at cover cropping in veggies on
we have a hard time sometime
establishing our cover crop between the
row of veggies so we know that using
this kind of robot maybe something that
um if we are uh using it with a spreer
we can potentially start Sing cover
crops between uh Z rows of of of of in
of crops in plastic culture system the
other one is that right here you have a
um broccoli planted in in red clover and
sometime you have significant
competition between the cover crops the
red clover on the broccoli and we are
thinking that we had something for
mowing the red clover between the row we
will significantly reduce the level of
competition uh due to the cover crop so
we want to test potentially a mare for
reducing cover crop
competition all right let's move to
probably the most exciting ones which is
really the laser weer which is work that
ly and I did last year duplicated
between New Jersey on on on on on
Cornell New York
so um so we worked with Travis Parker
for carbon robot from carbon robotics
using this a laser weer platform um um
coming straight from
California so carbon robotics was funded
in 2018 and its headquarter in Cal
Washington the units are made in the US
in Detroit
uh on in 20 early 2022 carbon robotics
launched the laser Wier targeting large
vegetable grower States so Arizona
California New Mexico Oregon Washington
idah U so right now this technology has
been mostly developed on the west coast
not so much uh application not so much
testing on the East Coast so laser
readers are on farms in at least 17 us
States including New York now on three
provinces in Canada with expansion into
International markets to follow um so
the way it's working I mean what what we
got here for testing was is uh I would
call it the Research Unit that was their
protocol that was their prototype sorry
that they they planed to Commercial and
finally they evolve towards something
which is really attached to the Tractor
so that's the commercial units $1.6
million that's what you can see uh um in
California but some onion Growers here I
forgot the name the Tores uh got one
unit as well in new jerse so that's the
commercial unit which is working with
the tractor this one was initially uh
developed for fully autonomous uh laser
weeding and that's not the way the pur
okay they decided to get with something
which is really attached to the Tractor
so we end up getting this one for
experimentation this
year so the way it's
working um have a nice video right here
so you have Artificial Intelligence on
board uh which is I mean your projecting
light on the light will really help the
artificial intelligence discriminating
the crop on the weeds identifying the
weeds as to the crop on this system uh
is driving directing lasers and you can
see some of them you can see some smoke
right here and when you have we
detection the laser are specifically
targeting the wheat and burning the
Wheats okay um yeah you see right yeah
right in the middle uh it's impressive
because you will see some picture it's
not touching the crop so you really have
excellent discrimination between the
crops on the weeds and we got we didn't
see any crop damage associated with the
system so it's quite impressive to see
uh just a picture of what it looks like
uh when when you're using it the first
thing you need to know is that you need
to use it on small seedlings okay so
it's something that yes you need to use
really it's not a you need to look at
your crop when you're using this system
you need to know what is the size of
your of your wids because that will
determine the efficacy of the system so
right here it's on brok you can see that
all the we that I CLE circled in in
yellow right here you can see the the
burning of the green point on the weed
so it's really targeting not the leaf
it's targeting the growing point of the
of the weed so it's really precise
enough just to do that um on right here
you didn't see any damage on the
broccoli same thing right here looking
at some of the P at that I planted in
New Jersey you have the P right here I
mean these we are extremely close to the
p on the P was not damage now something
which is interesting to consider too is
that the system will give higher
priority for contouring smaller weeds
like this one okay why because
controlling a big pig weed it's not so
big but it's already big enough for
controlling a pig readed like this one
that really require too much energy for
the system too much time spending on
this one so they're giving priority to
controlling the smaller weeds uh versus
the bigger weeds with the bigger weeds I
mean you can always send a small crew to
just all on on remove some of these
bigger
weeds so we had a triol in New York on
on New Jersey we look at different crops
so we look at uh peas we look at spinach
Lin look at beats as well um we had
different uh treatment we had the of
course on Tred we check we had pre pre
CDE in spin we had Post abde in PE in
New Jersey um we had preab followed by
laser reading and we had laser Reading
Alone uh for for
comparison so when you're looking at our
pre P triol right here in New Jersey
you're looking at the Weeden City 14
days after the second laser weer pass so
we did two laser two laser weer pass
during the season you're looking right
here at two different type of herbicide
one which is a standard bentazone a
period a that is not label but we wanted
to use something different as well uh on
you're looking right here at the carbon
robotic in blue you have the laser
reader the carbon robotic laser weer and
clearly in term of weed density we had
the same level of weed density as what
you will expect from a the standard aide
which is bentazone right here the weed
free was cleaner of course because we
were manually weeding the plots
periodate not as much uh it's something
that we are we're investigating it but
not such a great control with his a side
if you're looking at weed fresh biomass
at Harvest again excellent uh efficacy
of the laser weer I mean I was really
mind blown by this type of application
is that you just do two passes on it was
sufficient to give you the same level of
control of what you will get with the
standard
aide now if you're looking at uh yield
we collected the crop fresh biomass at
Harvest on clearly what was really
interesting also to check right is that
uh we got the same level of crop fresh
biomass with a laser reader as compared
to the wheat free and um that was not
the case with bentazone even if we get
good we control with bentazone this
herbicide may still be causing damage to
the crop and later it will translate
into crop fresh biomass reduction so
advantage of the laser weer right here
is that yes you're getting the same
level of weed control but you don't get
herbicide injuries that may be
associated with
herbicide um and when you're looking
looking at the yield yes I mean we had
significant yield difference I mean the
laser weer was at the same level of P
yield as a wire check on what
significantly higher than what we got
with with
herbicides uh looking at spinach weight
control right here uh same thing looking
at weat Fresh biomass at Harvest
excellent control with the carbon
robotics with a laser reader uh we don't
have basically any weeds left over at
the end of the season now when you're
looking looking at the he weight what
was interesting as well is that uh you
had the same level of I mean this
spinach was weighing as much as what you
will get in the weat free but right here
the dual herbicide plus the carbon
robotic laser weer we had lower yield on
this one and again that may be something
that may be related to crop damage
caused by the herbicide and actually
that's something that Linn demonstrated
here in New York where right here you
have herbicide herbicide plus carbon
Robotics and car Robotics and when
you're looking at P at beats sorry on
spinach we definitely have lower
emergence where you have herbicide or
herbicide plus carbon robotics plus
laser weer because these herbicide may
have significant effect on emergence of
the crop so that's that's really
something interesting you know with some
things that we as we scientists are not
documenting enough on that the kind of
experimentation when you can start to to
see that okay so that was similar
experimentation the crop stunting again
greater crop stunting in beats and
spinach associated with the use of the
herbicides so what's next for the laser
weer uh we continue laser weer
evaluation for early season using in
crubs that can be sensitive to herbicide
injury like beats and spinach I think
for some high value specialty crops like
in my case um uh basil that may be
really something interesting to test we
don't have any abide in basil very few
abide very ineffective abide so using
the laser Wier will be something
interesting to do a brief Overlook at
some other novel Technologies so I
mentioned the farm engine Amiga so
that's what they already did at clarel
where they Associated the farm NG
platform autonomous platform with a weed
it sprayer so combining two of these
Technologies together to get something
fully autonomous um I will be working L
will be working as well with a zaso zap
reader which is using electricity I
didn't develop it today because I didn't
do it but did work with electricity but
that's something that we want to use for
um uh vegetable crops for example to get
some smaller units for for prod research
um we did some demonstration with
autonomous U uh unit for weed control in
grape um so you can see this one that's
a naot fitted with finger wiers at the
same time have some turning a f you see
how f it goes autonomous controlling the
weed you're walking the ground at the
same time you're getting some training
St uh that's something that we don't
have on the EOS I don't think we'll get
it anytime soon but that's the vcan
autonomous weer where actually you have
cameras on board that are detecting the
crop on actuating some some fingers if
you want for for King the weed between
between the um you know in the crop so
what did we learn so far
um these technologies will does not
necessarily eliminate the need for
herbicide especially pre-emergence abde
we still need some of these abide uh
because they're not eliminating all the
weeds you may still need to get manual
labor for for controlling some of these
weed some weeds will escape they're
always escaping there will always be a
place where the weed will escape so what
selection pressure could we be impacting
with this technology that's something
that we don't know we know that for aide
we don't know it so much for for um this
kind of Technology uh not all
alternative practices will be comp comp
compatible with the new technology as I
said I'm working with cover crop how
does cover crop will fit using some of
these new tools we don't know it yet uh
but we really think that there's a role
for this tool especially as companies
are coming to the Northeast uh to test
and modify their equipment U on again we
cannot place all the eggs in the same
basket last slide uh um there's many
questions that we need to address before
seeing full adoption of this technology
the first one is the cost not just the
cost of the unit uh the laser reader is
costing $1.6 million but you also need
to get additional Services okay you need
to get GPS you need to get rtk you need
to get Wi-Fi what about local support
this is very highend technology do we
have the capacity locally to provide
support for supporting this technology
uh adaptability most of these
technologies have been developed for the
the West Coast okay different
environment different soil different
condition different growing condition so
how does it fit on the East Coast I mean
we have weeds that are emerging on a
much more frequent basis than California
for example we have much more rain so
how does it fit for us on the on the
East Coast uh infrastructure and
Regulatory Readiness uh operation on
safety of Transportation how do you
transport some of these units how do you
transport the laser wither here I mean
is there any specific regulation that
you need to use if I'm starting to talk
to Rod g i using laser wheer the next
thing I know is that I will have people
from rodar telling me you have to be
extremely careful can damage your eyes
so you know you have all this kind of
Regulation as well uh cellular service
internet service base station so you
have to get all these service available
as well for using these new technology
on changing the N the nature of the
labor I mean this is highend technology
and not many people have been trained so
far for using this kind of technology
and yes I mean we're living in
communities where people are you know I
mean wi management is something that in
blueberry farm veggie Farm in New Jersey
many people are still doing it manually
what will these people do if we start
getting this kind of Technology widely
available so we need to start thinking
to to that as
well all right so future
studies uh yes we'll be evaluating new
autonomous robotic platform so I plan to
work with a farm and jiga uh I will be
working with electric reader we just
order a zap um a zap reader from zaso uh
I will be ordering well I order the XP
Cofe weer and I will be using the zap
reader as well uh we'll be continuing if
possible the assment of laser weding in
high value annual crops uh we are also
planning we already did some work in
cranberries looking at hyperspectral
Imaging for we detection and I wanted to
mention that uh Lena is a leading Pi on
this one Bradon myself and other we
scientist we receiv received a planning
s planning Grant in 2020 for for
identifying the novel technology
adoption barriers on drivers uh by
surveying stakeholders on the national
basis so all right that's my funding and
knowledgement over the last few years on
yes the Dream the Dream
Team well if you have a time for any
question
yes like in the CER Lakes area a lot of
Vineyards will maintain
undervine vegetation and I'm curious for
the blueberry farmers in New Jersey is
like the ideal weed management
completely bare under the vines or is
there room for some like competition or
ground cover so the question is that
yeah for blueberry can we get some weeds
growing under the under the blueberry
bushes okay can we toate that answer is
no uh mostly because traditionally I
mean yes Growers don't want I mean our
blue Growers don't want to see Wheats in
the system uh it's also because as I
mentioned we are growing blueberries in
Sundy soil with really low water
retention capacity on you may have weeds
competing if you have a dryer quickly
enough you will see the blueberry bushes
uh dying I've seen picture from a
drought maybe 20 years ago where that
such highweed competitions as the
blueberry bushes were dying because yes
I mean this
the the water you're providing even with
drip irrigation will be benefiting the
Wheats will even not be absorbed by by
the crop so I would say depends on the
nature of the soil you may have soil
here where you have higher retention
capacity for us in in blueberry Sundy
Sundy soil so water is penetrating
through the so very quickly on low
organic matter content I mentioned that
we do a lot of cultivation which I think
we need to change because cultivating
the ground is just
deating the organic matter over time so
if you're combining both definitely we
have salt that cannot keep the moisture
actually we're working have a project
where we are working trying to uh change
things by growing cover crops uh between
rows of of blueberries uh the big
challenges is that again you're working
on acidic well on sunndy soil so you
don't have so many cover crops that can
fit in this kind of condition on you're
working on salt pH which is 4.5 so many
many cover crop will not just grow well
under this condition okay so that's that
may be
challenging yes sir if the Machinery is
so expensive how do kind of small
farmers and
communities afford it is that like a
rental the cost of the technology that's
a good question I I think right now yes
I mean you see adoption of some of these
big Technologies by by big farms and
truthfully I think that for us New
Jersey and probably as well in New York
as a smaller farm that don't have the
capacity right now to adopt this
technology as a farm maybe they start to
come together maybe they can provide
sufficient funding for that um I see two
things I mean not every crop will be
used for will be useful for this kind of
Technology uh doing the laser Wier let's
say in squash production you don't make
enough money there's not enough profit
profitability in squash production for
adopting this kind of highend
Technologies now the thing that may
happen too is that over the years I mean
this kind of Technology will keep
evolving and I expect that within the
next 10 years we'll see we'll start to
see smaller units that can start to be
affordable for smaller Farm like we have
on the East Coast on its yes I mean
again this system has been fully
developed for giant farming operation in
California uh we are coming here they
are coming here to see us and clearly
yes I mean maybe a few big farm can
adopt it on the East Coast but the
majority of the smaller Farm they don't
have the capacity of doing that but I
mean if you're looking at yes I mean
that's the case for laser weer if you're
looking at the the Nao o robot that I
was showing it's 70,000 bucks so you can
have small organic farming operation a
very small farm where they can start
considering buying this kind of
Technology because yes I mean it's it's
effective for weight control it can be
really effective I mean you have a steep
learning curve with some of this
technology the Nao o uh I show you the
slide where actually you have good we
control but you're getting so much crop
damage that you know I mean it's you
need to learn to use this tool as well
and to make sure that maybe you can thr
it a little bit of crop
competition if you know if you don't get
too many crop damage at the same time
you want to mention like the the Amiga
the cost of the Amiga oh and like the
out oh you boot it so you can
so um so Terry was saying yeah the the
laser weeder is definitely um an outlier
uh but we do have two units in New York
and we have two more ordered by growers
in New York um there are some very high
value large Farms um but like the amga I
think the Amiga ran runs about 15,000 so
it starts to enter a range where it does
become more affordable there is then
there are um companies that are are
building smaller more affordable units
and there's also there are some people
who have a push for open uh open source
systems uh guy Coleman out of Australia
it has built an open weed locator which
is basically an open source Vision
guided system you know and uh I think
that runs about $400 but you're just
going to have to be extremely talented
with like building it um you know
building your own spray system but there
there is kind of this potential to uh to
min
the the cost and as Terry said uh more
companies are entering the market even
in the laser weer Market uh using
different lasers and so the cost is
expected to to drop the thing to when
you are talking about the cost that you
have the cost of equipment but you need
to get all you know this technology it's
not just putting fuel in it you need to
get access to rtk you need to get access
to GPS you need in some case to get bu
base station for thega for example you
need to get these other services as well
that sometime maybe you know may not be
available um New Jersey in the Pine Bar
I don't have Wi-Fi I don't have I don't
have a good cell phone service so if I
don't have it on my own cell phone I
know that this kind of system will not
be working as well uh too so that's
something to consider too so there I I
think we'll be there at some point but
the thing to I mean I didn't mention it
that many of these
Technologies they are excellent
Engineers they are not plant biologist
okay these guys think that they're
coming with new equipment it will be
wonderful it will be working great under
the East condition they don't know what
other the condition they they have a
tendency it's changing but have tendency
working as a company and they don't
always come to see us University
extension people uh it's starting to
change okay we saw that last year uh but
initially it was mostly driven by engine
on they may not have the focus on a
cropping system on weed management you
know on weed ecology weed biology they
may not be familiar with that and it's
something that you need to integrate
especially here on the East Coast
because well our condition I mean
California it's easy you don't have rain
if you don't have rain you don't have
wheat here it's it's a different
challenge yep you notice the laser weer
did you notice a difference in
performance when it was weeding annual
versus so we didn't see the difference
because we didn't have
prols oh yes we have not said you have
you had nut Edge I didn't have nuts Edge
so Linn can talk about the nut Edge but
that that's something that yes
definitely is interesting to check
because uh you may make the assumption
that the nut said you know it's a tuber
so you can kill the one which is aerg
but you still have uh spruing that may
be coming from from the tuers so
uh I don't know I mean did we see
something on this one yeah we had we had
regrowth of of nuts Edge we we we killed
some small ones but um this is this is
the whole what do we leave behind who
wins and perennials are going to be no
matter what system we hear perennials
are probably gonna rise to the top of
the winter I think for nut Edge because
we're working on anal crops nuts Edge
what will be important is that if you're
looking at the Ecology of nuts Edge at
some point during the SE on Mid July the
nuts Edge will turn to our production of
new nuts new tubers for next year
instead of producing new shoots so in
term of we competition if you can get
the nut Edge at least under control up
to Mid July we tend to see that you know
you will be good because basically you
don't have many uh clonal population uh
coming from the from from the nuts so I
think that's something that yes I mean
you may still get Reg grow but at least
you will not get the giant you know
clonal patches of nut Ed that you can
get if you leave it uh
uncontrolled yes what do you think about
the application of either the lasers or
some of the other Tech in more of
ergonomics setting with large scale oh
that's a question for
people uh I mean I that's a good
question I don't know for I I think for
the laser weer on vipan tell me if you
know you think otherwise I think the the
laser weer is really well adapted for
specialty crops uh because also high
value crops uh do you make enough money
do you need you know many of these
agronomic crops I mean they still have a
huge diversity of herbicides that they
can use they are not as limited as what
we are in specialty crops so they may
not have the same need for laser weeding
than we have in special
but what they have in in in agronomic
crops the targeted application that I
was mentioning before Blue River for
example they have this kind of targeted
application where clearly they will
still rely on herbicide but they will
really you know rely on lower rate of
herbicide because of more precise
application of the
herbicide but I I don't think I don't
know thean but I don't think that the
laser weer it's not something which is
explored for agronomic crops I I don't
think so and it all depends on the cost
of the technology right and the value of
the crop are high value crops where you
can spend and a half million
dollar but so I mean we
folks four bus five
bus there's a
lot they they have more to other
to which which is still working the
laser weer is also much slower than if
you went to Blue River talk last week
they were going what 10 miles an hour 12
mil 12 miles an hour the laser meter is
not doing that 1.5 they can't cover the
Acres right but
uh leafy greens that can cover
yes going going into the future that
this is the future maybe maybe in the
future we'll see units that can go
faster as well all right I want to thank
everybody for coming for The Graduate
students here there is a lunch provided
uh with Dr Boson
in 413 yes thank
you thank you all and um if you have
questions for Terry you can reach out to
him via email you can uh get in touch
with me I can put you in touch with him
uh thank you so much Terry and we are
looking forward uh to 2025 we are
already planning the project it's gonna
we think it's getting
exciting this this has been a production
of Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu