this is a production of Cornell
University
hey guys and I've got a few things I
want to go through but mostly this is
just information for you so if you have
questions at any time you know stop I'll
be happy to talk as much as you guys
want about any particular topic so
basically I'll start telling you a
little bit about myself so
you know my family didn't have a lot of
people that went to college you know we
had a few that ended up in nursing
school but certainly nobody went to grad
school so I was really interested in
science in high school I loved biology
what do you do when you like science in
high school right I didn't know so I
thought okay I'll try to be a doctor
because that's what you do and you don't
know anything about academia or research
or science so I went to school you know
thinking I was a pre-med and then the
more I get into it the more I learned
the more I thought well maybe that's not
for me so I volunteered in a hospital
and at the same time I got a job working
in a lab on campus doing research with
streptococcus mutans which probably most
of you have in your mouth right now
causes cavities hopefully not in your
mouth right now and I absolutely loved
the microbiology research and I
absolutely hated working in the hospital
I'm still not really fond of hospitals
and so the idea of being a doctor it
just was like no way and but the more I
got into the research the more I
realized I loved it and so then you know
from there it's like I got an advisor
and I was working with somebody in the
lab you know professor was very helpful
and he said yeah you know there's lots
of things you can do with a PhD in
microbiology you know you can do all of
these interesting things and so I went
to grad school and I didn't think I
wanted to be a professor when I went to
grad school I thought I wanted to work
in the biotech industry in particular I
wanted to clean up contamination in the
environment using microbes but then as I
learned more about myself and as I
learned more about microbiology I
realized I was really fascinated in
microbial ecology and what happens in
soils and that basically led me to our
am today and so that's part of the
process of like deciding if you want to
go to grad school or figuring out what
you want to do right now is getting
experiences so getting internships like
maybe
the Botanical Garden or somewhere else
you know taking time to figure out what
excites you and narrowing down the list
of things you want to do with your life
right I mean that's hopefully what you
guys are thinking about right now and
maybe I'll be able to help you a little
bit but my job today is mostly to give
you some idea about what grad school is
all about and if you're interested in it
how you might get in
so there's a few things I want to cover
what is grad school all about
why would you want to go to grad school
what you can do to prepare to go to grad
school and then how that whole
admissions process works and I'll sort
of take them on in that order so
what is grad school grad school is
it's basically
training to become good at doing
research right grad school is much more
focused than undergraduate so an
undergraduate you're doing credits you
know you're taking courses primarily
they're other things you're doing of
course but you're getting your degree
because of the coursework and credits
that you're taking you know there's 120
credits you got to take and you got to
satisfy all these criteria that doesn't
really exist in grad school grad school
is about doing some kind of original
research right it's like finding
something where you're going to make an
individual impact in a new way and yes
you take courses in grad school but
they're very flexible and there aren't
many of them it's mostly focused on a
real practical experience alerting
exercise and the real goal of grad
school you know you're gonna have some
focused area that you're becoming an
expert in but the real unifying theme is
you're learning how to learn you're
learning how to how to design research
how to perform research and how to
answer a question that it's not
something you can just look up in a book
right there's lots of questions out
there that we don't have the answers to
going to grad school is getting the
skills it takes to be able to answer
those questions you just can't look up
in a textbook so maybe you can write
your own textbook someday
so in terms of grad school there's a few
different degrees you might hear about
or think about there's a MPS degree
which is a master's of
professionals these professional service
studies
this is a little bit less common in the
sciences typically it's more coursework
focused it's usually a shorter program
one or two years and usually it's for
somebody you know if you're interested
in going into industry and you want to
be a CEO for a company that makes
fertilizer or one of these big AG
biotech companies like Bayer crop
sciences or something like that and you
know you're gonna be a manager but you
really want to know a lot about soil
science so you can understand what the
people who work for you are doing that
might make sense to do an NPS in soil
science for example so you're focusing
on a particular area to improve your
knowledge in that area but you're not
going to go on to be a professor in that
topic right it's much more focused
master's degree is
very much still a research degree you
know but what you're doing there is sort
of learning how to be a scientist maybe
more than learning how to direct a
research program so if you want to be
able to direct a research program either
in industry or academia you really need
the PhD so the PhD is sort of like
you know you're able to identify new
research topics design a research
program to answer that question
get the funding to do it manage it and
then get a positive outcome whereas with
a master's degree it's more like well
you're able to do research but you might
not be in a position to sort of come up
with new ideas or sort of direct the
whole research program
any questions about those sort of
different degrees a
master's is usually two maybe three
years a PhD can vary the fastest I've
seen somebody finishes like four and a
half years and the longest I've seen
somebody take was eight years
eight year student spent a lot of time
abroad and he did lots of interesting
things so he was using his time well
that's a good question so
so
that varies by field and so what I'll
and so there are there are slight
cultural differences and practices
across different fields so if you're a
microbiologist or a plant biologist or a
chemist
you're gonna see some differences so in
general the way I like to describe it is
if you're in a laboratory based
environment like you're doing bench work
in the lab all day those people
typically go right from the bachelor's
degree to a PhD right they don't usually
get a masters whereas people who do
field work you know either ecology
Natural Resources Plant Sciences those
people it's more likely that you're
going to get a master's degree before
you get the PhD and it might be more
expected that you do so plant science is
kind of funny because we've got the some
of the plant biologists or like doing
genomics in the lab all day and then
we've got people in horticulture who are
out in the field all day and so you're
generally gonna see you know those field
people it's more common that they'll
have a master's before the PhD whereas
the bench people it's almost exciting
almost
consistently everybody just gets the PhD
without a master's so to some degree it
varies and I and my own personal I don't
have never heard a good explanation for
why that is but the best guess I have is
that if you're in a if you're in a bench
science program you know most of those
research jobs
tend to be directing research rather
than performing it and so if you want a
direct research you need a PhD and so a
master's degree isn't quite as
marketable if you're in a bench type
environment whereas in those field based
environments there are many more sort of
management level positions whether with
government or extension where that
master's degree is a pretty marketable
thing and so I feel like it's kind of
market driven but yeah that is what it
is but so if you have an adviser if
you're thinking about grad school you
know in a particular area that you know
you should ask or try to figure out what
the particulars are for that area
so why might you want to go to grad
school
number one you should you know in the
sciences you should really like science
and really be interested in research but
there are some other good reasons so
there's a good reason in terms of salary
if that sort of thing is interested
interesting to you you know there's sort
of this old saw out there that you know
if you get too much education it's hard
to get a job or maybe you educate
yourself out of a job and that's not
true so if you look at the statistics
from the Bureau of Labor Statistics
which are national u.s. statistics if
you got a if you get a doctoral degree
not a medical degree but a PhD
over your lifetime you're likely to get
43 percent more salary than if you just
have a bachelor's alone and the
unemployment rate at least as of 2015
for people with a PhD is 1.7 percent
which is about a third of the
unemployment rate for people who have a
bachelor's so if you have a PhD you're
more employable and you're going to earn
more money if that matters to you and
even with a master's the unemployment
rate for a master's is 2.4 percent which
is like half of the unemployment right
right now for everybody else and even
with a master's you're gonna get 18
percent higher salary over your lifetime
than someone just with a bachelor's so
if you're interested in science you know
if you're thinking about you know these
things are important to you yeah it's a
good idea to think about grad school the
other thing is in the sciences it's
mostly free right so if you go to get a
PhD if you go to get a masters or a
research degree at a university
generally you're going to get your
tuition covered so your tuition is going
to be paid for by the program or by a
fellowship or some other method maybe a
teaching assistantship and you're going
to actually get paid to go to school so
you're gonna get a living stipend it's
not a ton of money but it's enough to
pay all your bills and cover your health
insurance and everything you need while
you're in school so it's a pretty good
deal you end up with getting your
education paid for you also end up
making more money over your lifetime and
you have a low unemployment rate so if
you think it's something you're
interested in you know it can be a good
choice
any questions about all that stuff
alright so then the other thing is how
do you prepare right so what can you do
to prepare for grad school
in terms of preparing for grad school
and in terms of your application I mean
there are really three things that you
want to think about
one of the things is your coursework
right you've guys have already picked
majors you're thinking about majors
you're thinking about your concentration
probably if you're in the plant sciences
major and so that's going to really
dictate your coursework so that
coursework is of course important but
probably the single most important thing
in terms of grad school is is real-world
experience so like in my case you know I
volunteered in that Hospital I did that
research in the lab you know I joined
the lab as a junior and I worked
throughout my junior and senior years
and I had one whole summer where I was
working on the research
real-world experiences so like
internships
you know working in the lab independent
research credits honors project it
doesn't have to be just in one lab but
but those experiences are going to help
you to know you know what you like and
what interests you but they're also
going to really help to
give you the skills you're going to need
and sort of develop your background so
that you can get into graduate school if
that's a choice you want to make
and then the other thing to mention
there in terms of real-world experiences
a lot of people like to take a gap year
so so you get your bachelor's and then
maybe you're not ready to go right into
grad school or maybe for some reason
you know you think there's something you
can improve about your preparation for
grad school so a lot of people will get
a job you know it could be a job as a
technician it could be a job on a farm
some people go into the Peace Corps you
know those sorts of experiences if
they're related to your area of interest
you know if they're related to your
professional sort of educational goals
and why you're going to grad school
those kind of experiences are generally
going to help you write because when
you're making an application for grad
school those people want to know are you
really interested in this do you have
skills and so you're gonna develop that
interest and get those skills not just
in the classroom and so those real-world
experiences are really important and you
know if you're a freshman if you're a
sophomore it's definitely a good time to
be thinking about it if you're a
transfer student coming in maybe later
on definitely you want to try to get you
know some of those experiences as soon
as possible when there are lots of
different ways to do that
so the other thing I wanted to talk
about is admissions but before I start
talking about admissions you guys are
really quiet and I know you must have
some questions so does somebody because
I and I know that if you have a question
there are probably ten people in the
room who have the same question so it
would be really helpful maybe if
somebody would ask yeah
so you you're asking the question from
the point from your point of view like
where do I want to send my application
yeah that's a great question so yeah
there's a ton of programs out there and
it can be hard to navigate and I would
say the first thing you need to do is
figure out what you want you know what
are your interests you know that that
old question that people ask you that
you hate to get what you want to do what
do you want to be doing in 10 years
right
you know you need the first thing you
need to do is be answer to answer that
question real well it's hard right and
that's why I say get experiences because
getting those experiences will help you
to answer that question you know you
have to know who you are before you know
where you want to go so if you have that
bit ready you know then I guess there
would be two things to do the first and
probably most valuable thing is
hopefully you've been working with
somebody in the lab maybe that's a
graduate student maybe it's a professor
maybe it's your academic adviser but
you've got somebody in a in a sort of
mentor kind of relationship you know
maybe it's Marvin here in this class
right but you've got somebody who you
can talk to who has a network right
they're a professional they know the
area if you go to that person and you
say hey I'm really interested in this
area of study you know they're going to
be able to tell you probably off the top
of your head okay here's half a dozen
programs you might think about applying
to and even if they don't they probably
know somebody who could give you that
list right so so tap into that network
when you when you're sort of doing
research you're developing a network of
professionals so tap into your network
and them and they'll provide you really
good information yeah and if there are
other people you're working with you
know whether it's an internship or in a
lab you know the graduate students ask
them to write so you know sort of canvas
your your network and get information
and then the other thing is as you're
as you're interested in this area you
should be reading so as you get more and
more interested you want to do more and
more reading and if you're doing
research you're probably getting papers
to read maybe you're seeing scientific
papers and your classes or maybe you're
just reading stuff from the internet so
those articles are going to talk about
the science but you're also gonna see
the names of people who made those
discoveries write those names down write
when you see an article that has a
really exciting conclusion who's the
senior author on that you know what
institution are they at so keep a list
of the kinds of stuff that you find
exciting and then who did the work and
where are they maybe they're all the
people doing this work or at the
University of Minnesota or something you
know that's something you want to know
so if you're reading a lot of papers and
you find that all the papers you're
excited about are written by like five
people you should probably apply the
institution's for those five people are
at write so those are really good and
then the web you know and then you look
online that can be harder but you know
if you look for plant science programs
you know not every place in the country
has one so you find the ones that do if
you're interested in a particular area
you know look at the faculty bios and
find a place like you might look at the
Michigan State and if you're interested
in a particular area maybe they have
only one person really specializing and
when you read their background it looks
really lame and maybe you look at UC
Davis and they have five people in that
area and they're all really dynamic
right then you'd want to make that
application there so I would say use
your network you know do some reading
you know and then and then do that sort
of web-based search
yeah good question
you got a question
so that's tricky right so so there are a
couple
so funding is one of the big things and
we could talk a lot a long time about
this and it's an important thing for
grad school because you do get funded to
go to grad school but whether or not
that funding comes through is one of the
big things that dictates whether or not
you get accepted so when you're getting
accepted to an undergraduate program
mostly they're looking at like your
merit you know your your GPA the
coursework you did you know they're
looking at like that whole piece and
that's certainly important for grad
school but it's only one of the pieces
for grad school you know this funding
piece is really important because we
don't have unlimited funding we can't
just I'll pay for anybody to go to
school and so we have to sort of figure
out how to provide that money for you
and so so really in the bigger picture
there's three ways right there's
fellowships there's teaching
assistantships and then there are
faculty grants and and these all three
of these are the mechanisms we used to
fund students and
when you're admitted you might be
admitted with one kind of support but
over the course of a PhD you might
actually move between all three and if I
admit ten students it's unlikely that
all ten of those students will have the
same kind of funding package so with
fellowships there are two basic kinds I
would say there's kinds that you apply
for and they're the kinds that the
school you're applying to will nominate
you for so the ones that you apply for
you have control over but there aren't a
ton of them so there's like the biggest
one that you guys should all know about
is the National Science Foundation
graduate fellowship program so that's a
really big program it's competitive but
if you get funded there it's fantastic
right you can almost guarantee that
you're going to get accepted anywhere
you apply if you get one of these NSF
fellowships
the due dates are usually in the fall so
you want to plan ahead but I would very
much if you think about going to grad
school you really want to look at this
and think carefully about making an
application but there are other things
like the Ford Foundation has fellowship
program I
notice USAID still have fellowship
programs but there's a lot of programs
out there and you sort of have to look
around they tend to be specialized NSF
is very broad but but there are a lot of
specialized programs I want to say the
armed services have some fellowship
programs maybe than some of the national
labs do so you have to hunt around the
one I would recommend because it's broad
and almost anybody could apply for it is
the NSF program so if you apply for your
own funding and you get that from that
external agency that travels with you no
matter where you go and that's fantastic
short of that you don't have to have
that you can apply to school the school
can nominate you for a fellowship like
an internal fellowship so Cornell has a
lot of internal fellowships we use for
recruiting purposes and so like as the
director of Graduate Studies I get your
application if I see your application
I'm like oh this would be a great
candidate for this funding you know I'm
gonna nominate you for that you won't
even know I nominated you for that if
they don't accept you then okay I'll try
to fund you some other way but if they
do then I'll send you a letter that says
congratulations you know you've received
this fellowship you know please come to
Cornell so you don't necessarily know
that that's happening but that's one way
that we could fund you so that's sort of
fellowships and then the teaching
assistantship so faculty teach we teach
courses and so we need assistance with
that and so teaching assistantships are
a way that the university pays graduate
students so that for some of their time
they're helping with teaching and it's
capped at how many hours a week you can
be expected to be teaching I think the
maximum is like 15 hours for most
assignments in reality you spend
spending a lot less time than that
actually teaching but but that would be
a way to sort of pay your salary and
tuition as well in the sciences you do a
little bit less of that if you are in
the humanities they actually usually
have to that they don't have as many
fellowships and and grants as we do in
the sciences usually and so they can
spend a lot more teaching but but ta
ships aren't that onerous in the
sciences you but so that's one way I
might be able to provide your funding is
my unit might have five or six ta lines
and so that means five or six people I
can support with those ta lines and
again you wouldn't know anything about
that you're gonna make the application I
know I have so many slots I'm gonna try
to put people in them and then the
faculty grants so Cornell doesn't give
faculty any money
to do research right they give us space
and offices but that's it
when we get hired they give us some
money to buy equipment but then they
don't give us any more money so after
that if you want to do research you need
to get grants so National Science
Foundation USDA AG and food research
initiative Department of Energy you know
NASA
you know international agencies we need
to hustle to get grant money to support
our research the biggest component of
that money is usually people you know
it's salaries its tuition its health
insurance and so that's how we pay for a
lot of grad students so but that's
tricky because many of these funding
programs might reject ninety percent of
the applications that you make and so a
faculty member is constantly submitting
grant applications and they can't always
predict when and want is going to be
funded and maybe to get funded just by
chance right so one year that faculty
member might need to admit to students
and then the next year they might admit
none or maybe three years in a row they
might admit none so so that's a source
of funding but it's also somewhat
unpredictable so when you make an
application you know I can't tell you
where your money is going to come from
but I need to have a source of money to
admit you whether it's a fellowship or a
teaching assistantship or a faculty
grant
and there's a lot that goes on there so
I'm happy to answer any follow-up
questions
any other questions
good so in terms of then in terms of
Admissions and getting into graduate
school I would say that really there are
sort of three pieces to that
the the one piece is sort of the merit
of the applicant
sort of what you bring to the equation
the second piece is something I would
call
your fit with the program and the third
piece is the funding and I think we
already talked a little bit about the
funding funding is usually a big
constraint so I would say that you know
we usually get more applicants
who are who are high quality and and the
other thing I would say is that at the
graduate level
you know if you if I if I think there's
a reasonable likelihood that you're
gonna be successful in graduate school
I'd like to be able to admit you right I
mean obviously we use merit as a
criteria we want the best and brightest
but but really I'm only going to exclude
you for sure if I don't think you're
gonna be successful in graduate school
if I think you're going to be successful
I want to try to admit you and so but
the reason I can't admit everybody is
usually funding right so funding puts a
cap on who we can admit and then we're
trying to admit the people who have the
highest merit and have the best fit and
we can talk about merit in a second but
this fit thing is interesting because
you know gets back to the question you
had earlier about where do you apply
right so let's say you know maybe you
didn't do your homework when you decided
where to apply and you applied to a
university and you're really interested
in let's say you're really interested in
using drones to you know measure
plant health in some way right which is
a cool thing to do and you apply to a
university where there's absolutely
nobody working with drones right and
they look at your application and
they're like holy crap this person has
an NSF fellowship you know they have a
4.0 GPA they've got this wonderful
internship and they want to work with
drones we don't have anybody doing
anything with drones do you think they
should admit you
they probably would not be doing you any
favors by admitting you because if they
admit you they might they might admit
you because you're just a great
applicant you have your own money and
they might hope that they could convince
you to work on something other than
drones but if they don't have a faculty
member working on drones and if that's
what your heart beats for you really
have no business going to that school
right so they should reject you because
there's no fit they don't have somebody
who can properly advise you and direct
you and mentor you in the area that
makes you excited you know what you're
trying to learn and so I would say that
in general
fit is important so if you're applying
to a school and they don't have
expertise in that area
that can be a problem so more often what
happens is you might be applying and
let's say they do have somebody working
on drones but that person is going to
retire in a few years and because
they're retiring in a few years they're
not taking students again you know
you're not likely to get accepted
because they can't suit you know there's
going to be nobody there to work with
you
you know let's say there's a couple of
people working at that program but both
of them just took five students last
year and they can't possibly take
another student you know they're not
going to be able to admit you right
because they want you to work with those
people if those people can't take
students you're not going to get
accepted right so this fit question
they're going to look at your
application and try to figure out you
know who with this university would the
student be best suited to work with and
if they can't find anybody who's well
suited to advise you then they're not
going to admit you right even if you're
a great student even if you have funding
you know they need to have that fit
piece and sometimes it's hard for you as
an applicant to predict that but you can
help yourself by doing your research
right if you're applying to a place that
there's only one person doing that
research or no people doing that
research you probably might want to be
careful about that whereas if there's
like five or six people all doing the
same thing your odds of making a match
are much better right if there's only
one person by all means reach out to
that person say hey you know I think
your research is great I want to make an
application you know are you taking
students at the moment
do you have funding for new students at
the moment and if they say wow this is
great I would love to have a student but
I haven't had a grant in 20 years and I
have no idea how I would fund you that's
a red flag right you know you might
think let's not make an application
there so you can sort of weight things
in your favor by doing your legwork
right you can look at that who's there
how many people are there you can reach
out to them you don't have to like ask
them to make a commitment all you have
to say is are you do you think you'll be
likely to take students next year you
know do you have funding for a new
student at this time and it's possible
faculty are busy they might not get back
to you but it's an easy question and so
most often they'll say yeah you know
there's a good chance I might be taking
someone and then you sort of put that in
your notes and you say okay that's a
good school to apply to
so so the funding the fit and then and
then the merit so the merit I mean the
the pieces of the application that
relate to merit or your coursework right
GPA is an important thing in getting
into grad school but probably not as
important as getting into undergrad I
would say there's a wide range of GPAs
that we accept into graduate school and
partially we're not as concerned about
GPA just because you don't spend as much
time in the classroom you know what we
want to know is are you going to be
successful in research you know the book
learning isn't as important anymore we
are very interested in what courses
you've taken so if you've taken really
easy classes if you've sort of not taken
important classes that we think are
crucial to getting into grad school in
our area that's going to be more of a
problem than if your GPA was a little
bit lower than a 4.0 right
and you guys are all going in the right
direction because you're plant sciences
majors you know got good core
requirements you know you're doing the
background that you would need to get
into a lot of different programs in the
sciences so that's probably not going to
be an issue for you
so there's coursework you know we do
look at GRE scores right but Giri scores
again we don't expect perfect GRE scores
you know most of the students we admit
tend to be in the top quartile
but but people below and you're not in
the top quartile can we'll get accepted
it's sort of a balancing game you know
if you have a really high GPA but your
GRE is a little lower you know that's
probably gonna be okay
so those are two components we look at
but neither one of them are sort of
determinative in its own right and then
the letters of recommendation are really
important right and so this is why again
you want to have real-world experiences
because if you take a course with
somebody and they you know they you're
one of 200 people and
you know they can say oh they did really
well on the final that's not a really
good letter of recommendation right
whereas if you do an internship or a
research experience where you're working
with that person closely over a whole
semester or maybe multiple semesters
that person's gonna be able to write a
much better letter that recommends you
for who you are for your capabilities
and your strengths and your interests
and so getting to know you know
professionals is a good way to be able
to get good letters of recommendation
and then the last part of your
application itself is your
your statement of purpose and so you
have to write a statement when you get
into undergrad -
but that's a little bit more of kind of
like an essay I think the statement of
purpose for grad school you know I like
to describe it as more like
you know it's more you telling your
story it's you talking about where
you're coming from and where you're
going and filling in the gaps in between
so what I like to say with a statement
of purpose and going to grad school is
you're trying to convince the admissions
committee that you're really interested
and passionate in this area that you're
trying to get a degree in and that
you're well prepared to be successful in
that endeavor so usually you want to
start off with where you're coming from
so how did you learn about this topic so
you guys are all interested in plant
sciences so you might say oh I got
interested in plant sciences because I
had this really remarkable experience
once that involved a plant right and so
whatever that is anybody why are you
guys in plant sciences
did anybody have a formative experience
or it's like this is the only thing the
cows would accept you for
yeah why'd you guys pick plant sciences
death by the pool
yeah
that would be a superb way to start that
kind of statement yeah somebody else
yeah
yeah why can't you be a florist oh
okay okay and they wanted more and
better things okay good
awesome time pathology there you are
yeah
sure and these are all great right so
this is how you sort of start talking
about it you know it's your interaction
with professionals right your real-world
experiences you know these are the
things that ground you and you say hey
this is how I got excited and then the
next step is what did you do with that
information so okay I applied to one of
the best schools in the world to study
plant sciences you know I went there and
I worked with professionals and I did
these research experiences and I
understood that you know this is really
what I want to do I want to learn about
plant pathogens or I want to learn about
agronomy and I took coursework and I did
this internship and then I did this
other internship right and so you're
sort of telling your story and then you
say and what I've really realized is I
want to do X you know you then sort of
project forward you say in 10 years 15
years I want to win the World Food Prize
by you know increasing productivity of
something or other right so you project
forward what you want to be and you say
to get there what I really need is a PhD
in plant sciences from your school all
right so you're telling that story so
where did you start what's your interest
how did that interest grow how did you
develop your skill set where do you want
to get and why is the degree at this
program that you're targeting the
natural inevitable next step for you on
your trajectory to a Nobel Prize
unfortunately we don't have a lot of
Nobel Prizes and the plant sciences you
can get them you can get them a little
harder yeah so that statement of purpose
is important and it's also important in
terms of telling your own story if
there's something in your application
package that you're worried about or
something that you want to emphasize
this is your chance right if you're
really proud of thing you did you want
to fit that in there if there's
something that was really important you
want to fit that in if there's something
you're really nervous about I mean it's
quite common that you know maybe you had
a real hard time in that organic
chemistry class or maybe you know you
got a D in calculus that would be me
sorry but maybe maybe you did badly on
the GRE test right you don't want to
ignore that because somebody's gonna see
it right but you can tell your own story
you can say you know I got a D because
you know it was really a big adjustment
you know going to college and my
girlfriend dumped me and my grandma died
and all this bad stuff happened but you
know the next semester I turned it
around and got straight A's you know so
I owned that and I made sure I doubled
down and I improved so then you take
this thing that looks like a weakness
and you turn it into a strength in a
story of personal development right and
so the statement of purpose lets you do
that so I think frankly that's the first
thing I look at when I look at an
application because if somebody is
passionate and committed about what
they're doing and they know who they are
that's usually pretty obvious as soon as
I read that and if they're just adrift
and they don't know what they want to do
and they're going to grad school because
they don't know what else to do that's
obvious too so that statement is
something I think that's really
important but those other components are
the you know statement the GRE is the
coursework and very much
well I guess your letters of
recommendation and then that real world
experience piece so we're going to look
for that but that'll also help you to
write that letter
good
other questions about grad school or
applications I'm so you brought up what
I'm grad school they're like this word
whatever color
hmm so it's that that can vary I mean it
you you really
you have to look and read the
description of what the fellowship is
all about number one and think about it
and then I would take that fellowship
application to some professional you
work with or an advisor and get their
opinion on it and then all of those
programs are going to have some kind of
coordinator or project manager or
program officer and I would very much
touch base with that person you know it
might be that those guidelines are
really straightforward and you feel
comfortable if you have any question or
even if you think it might be helpful
you know it's okay to contact the person
in charge of that program and say hey
this is who I am this is what I'm
interested in you know can you give me
advice in what you're looking for you
know is this suitable and that can be
very helpful right rarely ever would
that be detrimental
so that can help to get information so
each program has different you know some
of them are designed for you know maybe
they're designed for trying to enhance
the number of people doing international
research or you know people with a
certain background
you know NSF tends to have different
focus areas like biology or chemistry or
engineering so you'd want to sort of
suss that out
yeah yeah yeah I mean the other thing
you could do I don't know we must have
these resources at Cornell certainly for
NSF but you can find out sort of who who
has gotten these awards in the past and
you should be able to sort of figure out
sort of you know you know get some sense
as to how those people have been
successful I
know we have a few programs that are
aimed to trying to help students get
those NSF fellowships but they're sort
of all over campus so I'm not sure that
I could point you towards one
where should I start
so you can take it as many times as you
want hi
the only score that you really see in
the application is the highest score so
they don't show you
like every time you've taken the test
usually they show you the highest score
so if you get a low score and you want
to take it again there's really no
penalty because if you do worse it's not
going to show up if you do better it
will and the bad one will go away I mean
it costs money and time and effort to do
that so you don't just take it 20 times
but no I mean you can take it when you
feel like you're ready it's not it's not
really it's not a real heavy content
based exam you know so it's kind of like
the SAT in that regard where it doesn't
require a lot of coursework you know you
don't have to have like knowledge and
the plant sciences to do well on that
test it is unfortunately one of these
things where test prep makes a
difference so you know getting a book
and reading about questions practice
questions if you want to take a course
on how to do it those those things do
help
but but yeah early and often potentially
you know there's there's no downside I
think to doing that
they in the past they have had some
Subject Tests you know we never get
those scores and so I we don't require
them it used to be that some
universities did I don't even know if
they still offer those but they have in
the past had some so so if so generally
they're not required if your program
requires it you'll actually see you know
and that's a good reason to look out you
know for what programs you're interested
in because there might be a particular
program you want that requires a
particular subject test but in general
no they're not no not a lot of programs
I'm familiar with and particularly in
the plant sciences I'm not aware of
anybody who would require a subject test
just the general GRE
I've covered most of the things I want
to talk about so do you guys I mean do
you have other questions so so
what grad school is all about I guess I
didn't talk a whole lot about what you
can do with a grad degree that's
something we should talk about but
preparing for graduate school or getting
admitted
anybody anybody have any suggestions
what can you actually do with a PhD
besides be a professor because you can
be a professor you have to get a PhD if
you want to be a professor what else do
you do with a PhD what are people with
PhDs do
anybody know anybody know anybody who's
not a professor at Cornell who has a PhD
yeah what does he do
mud mud floods
MD PhD oh
so so are they a sort of academic like
professors or are they actually doing
just research not just research okay
good you know it's actually it's sort of
ironic but if you get a PhD you can look
at the salaries of PhDs and then you can
look at the salaries of I'm sorry MDS
and PhDs PhDs always get less than md's
which we're not disgruntled about that
at all but if you get an MD and a PhD
you actually get less money than if you
had just an MD it gives you a sense of
how the MDS think about the phd's right
if you get the PhD they're like ah come
on what's wrong with you
anybody else anybody knows somebody with
a graduate degree and what they do for a
living yeah
Oh
super cool so that's you know very much
you know sort of a business kind of
environment so it like aerospace stuff
yeah that's super cool so my my I was
the first person in my family to go to
grad school but mine one of my cousins
you know she actually went to the
military and then she got a master's in
physics so she's working in a hospital
now working on these giant machines that
image your body you know sort of look
basically repairing them and make sure
whom they work properly which is kind of
cool it's not aerospace yeah so so
academia is pretty common I think boy
you know I think I had some statistics
on this yeah so like 30 to 50% of your
PhDs are going to be academic you know
professors or instructors of some sort
about twenty to thirty percent or in the
private sector so like Boeing one of my
PhD students is
working at Bayer crop sciences he's
working in their sort of
genomic research area so he's doing
genome analyses of plants and microbes
to try and find things that are valuable
for the company you know I've got other
people who came through my program who
are working at biotech startups in
agriculture or biotechnology kind of
industries so a lot of people get
research either research administration
or sales or technical or data positions
or even writing a lot of PhDs you know
you get a lot of writing skill doing a
PhD and those scientific writing skills
are quite marketable so about 20 to 30
percent of PhDs are in the private
sector maybe about five to ten percent
in government so we have a lot of
scientists and particularly plant
sciences and EPA USDA NRCS
the National Science Foundation USGS
even the Department of Energy right so
so these these government agencies
employ a lot of scientists right and so
that's opportunities nongovernmental
organizations as well there are
international research organizations or
sort of conservation organizations that
you get a job with with a PhD so there's
lots out there in fact probably the
majority of jobs are outside of academia
but they're all related to research and
and sometimes they may not even you know
you get a PhD in the plant sciences you
know the skill set you have of course
it's a natural for you to get a job
relating to plant sciences or
agricultural biotechnology but that
skillset translates in a lot of ways so
you know there are jobs and like you
could get jobs probably in the Patent
Office right if you've got this
knowledge you know they need people with
knowledge because you're patenting stuff
that relates to plant science all the
time and so somebody with a PhD and the
plant sciences would be marketable there
you also have that skill set in terms of
research maybe that data analytics
there's a lot of big data and plant
sciences and if you know how to work
with big data a lot of the ways you work
with data whether it's DNA sequence data
or census data or some corporate kind of
data you know those computer skills are
going to translate pretty well so so
even if you're going into the graduate
degree in the plant sciences of course
you probably like plant sciences you
know but that degree is still somewhat
flexible you know you're not you're not
necessarily pigeon-holed and there are a
lot of and that's why the unemployment
rate for PhDs is so darn low
good
yeah
that's a great question
that's a great question and I would say
yes and no so I think where you go
where you go is probably somewhat less
important than who you work with
and so the reason for that is because
your training is going to be very
strongly influenced by the program of
the of the person you're working with
your mentor they have a professional
network they're known for a certain
thing they're good at a certain thing
and they're gonna be training you in
that area so if the world expert in and
using drones to measure agronomic
variables is at
you know Humboldt State in California
not to like to mean Humboldt State but
but say you're at Humboldt State you're
probably better off going to Humboldt
State if that's your area of interest
rather than like going to like a Harvard
Stanford if there's nobody doing that
thing at Harvard or Stanford I mean yeah
you'd have this fancy degree you know
but if you're interested is being a
leader in that area you want to get
trained from the leader in that area and
professionals know that you know like so
I'm a microbiologist I know you know
there aren't so many microbiologist out
there that I don't know the people in my
field I know them and so I know if you
came from a particular area I know
something about you you're gonna have
certain skills I'm gonna have certain
expectations and that's based on the
person not the place
it might differ a little bit if you're
interested in industry you know if
you're working in an area outside of
your focus so if you're in the plant
sciences and you're staying in the plant
science is who you work with is probably
more important than where you go but the
further you get away from that core
discipline so if you're getting a job in
a biotech industry where they don't know
anything about Plant Sciences or you
want to get a writing job you know they
might be more impressed by the place
rather than the person right so I won't
say that the place doesn't matter but it
matters more the further you get away
from the focus and the more you're
maintaining that focus probably the less
the place matters and more the person
matters good
and that's again where as a student you
don't always know who the best people to
work with are but that's why you want to
develop a network while you're here at
Cornell because the people who you're
going to be working with your advisors
and the graduate students and the
postdocs they'll have a sense and
they'll be able to tell you oh if you're
interested in this you probably want to
work with one of these three or four
people yeah
oh
that's great
yeah starting your own companies that's
another thing yeah yeah
and you want to make your own job
we were having that
gives you a level of credibility yeah
because you're able to you know you're
you've got a director level position you
can identify a research project and then
lead that project and and whether that's
in academia or starting a company it's
the same same skill set I mean in a lot
of senses you know being a faculty
member is kind of like running a startup
you know cuz all of your funding comes
externally and that's like capital
investment right so you're basically
always drumming up capital to do your
research so there's a lot of
relationship between starting up the
small company and being an academic so
oddly enough and the science is at least
yeah
yeah other questions again I think I've
covered everything I wanted to cover
there's probably a million questions we
could answer
yeah
so I like to tell people you know if you
want to take
it depends on what you do with the time
so so the best case scenario if you're
taking time off is you're doing
something that relates to your area of
interest so for example and it might
actually be strategically important for
you to do that so the best case is let's
say you came in as a transfer student
and let's say you didn't have a lot of
opportunities to do research while you
were here at Cornell and you remembered
you know Dan Buckley at this talk told
me that I should have a lot of research
experience before I go to grad school
okay well you know with your
undergraduate degree you can probably
get a job as a technician either in a
company or maybe in a research lab
somewhere on campus maybe here at
Cornell so then you work for a year or
two doing research in the plant sciences
something related to it doesn't have to
be exactly the same but something close
to what you're interested in so then you
apply for grad school you're actually
gonna be much stronger you know with
those two years break then you would
have been right out of undergrad because
now you're coming with this background
the skill set another good letter of
recommendation and probably a stronger
statement of purpose because you you
know better who you are and what you
want to do so to the degree that that
you take a gap year or years and you're
doing something relevant and that's part
of your story part of your arc you know
to get you where you want to go then
it's a great idea
if it's totally unrelated then it's not
as good of an idea right the longer
you're out of grad school doing
something that's not relevant to this
goal you know people are gonna be like
well what were you doing you know if
you're really interested in going to
grad school for X why did you spend five
years doing something totally different
you know I mean and maybe you have a
good reason for that maybe you can
justify it but it's going to raise some
question marks people are gonna be like
well why did you you know go mountain
climbing in the Andes for five years
what you really want to do is molecular
biology in the lab right so maybe your
mountain climbing in the Andes because
you're trying to find a rare plant that
you want to study you know the molecular
biology of then it make sentence rate
but but you just have to think about how
that fits into your story
anything else
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at Cornell edu