this is a production of Cornell
University so I'm going to talk today
run through fairly quickly a whole bunch
of different directions uh the
introduction said I've investigated
numerous angles and so you're going to
see a little bit of a lot of different
angles in this talk um so broccoli
production in the northeast of course
I'm betraying my California upbringing
and pursuing this topic at all um but it
turns out to be uh a really interesting
one with a lot of potential in various
different directions so why would one
care about broccoli production in the
Northeast so we've got a number of
different things happening right now
that kind of makes this a compelling
thing to pursue so I think you're all
aware that locally grown is a big deal
everybody's talking about locally grown
produce as being something attractive
and that is showing up in the
marketplace as uh the supermarkets and
wholesalers are starting to think about
how can I get local product into my
store where can I Source it who can I
buy it from
uh We've despite the lower diesel prices
this year for the past several years
diesel has been very expensive that's
made transportation from California very
expensive in fact the wholesale price of
broccoli and much other produce on the
East Coast half of that cost is the
transportation and half of it is the
cost that was paid in California uh that
cost has not come down with the diesel
price by the way it's still the same
high price so that's a barrier that
provides an opportunity uh to make money
for Growers um we're looking at reducing
the carbon footprint so
shipping uh 10,000 lbs of broccoli and
10,000 lbs of ice across the country has
a substantial footprint not only with
the diesel but the Ice uh we can reduce
that our uh vegetable Growers uh value
diversification on their Farms value
diversification on what they're selling
so both in the rotation and economically
diversification is good uh and also as
we've noticed with the shortage of water
in California this year that having our
production Diversified around the
country can help provide we're calling
it food security for the United States
that we don't fall short of crops that
we really like during periods when the
one location that it's grown something's
happening there that prevents us from
getting it so there's a number of angles
to why we would want to uh be looking at
broccoli in the Northeast right now why
broccoli people love broccoli who ate
broccoli in the last
month yeah how about the last week we've
probably got some Vegeta look at that
yeah so everybody eats broccoli just
about right it's a very very popular
crop and so this this chart shows how
the broccoli consumption per capita has
been going up of course the population's
going up too uh the interesting thing to
me is down here at 1970 we're about half
a pound per person a year that's not
very much it was an Italian special to e
vegetable pretty much in the 1960s it
really only became sort of something
everybody ate relatively recently and um
so there there's a big upside for for
kale by the way it's a half now after
the
burst in the last few years it's gone
from a quarter to a half so it's really
gone way up but you can you can imagine
the trajectory over the next several
years um so there's only upside
potential so where do we grow broccoli
now well we grow it in California of
course is the answer uh so this shows
you uh the big numbers are how many
acres of production there are in each
part so you see on the coast in the
summer in the desert in the winter time
and a little smattering on the east
coast and when you get to the very
northernmost County where it's good and
cold uh there's a little patch there um
a little winter production down there
but really it's a little smattering and
in fact I think we have worked with each
of the Farms that represents a dot in
this map uh so there's there's potential
for increasing that on the on the East
Coast uh so why can't we do that simply
well first of all the varieties that
exist are poorly adapted to our Eastern
growing conditions temperature water
humidity are and variability in all of
the above are really big challenges and
so what's been done to date is to raise
broccoli where the conditions are
optimal for it and that has worked but
as demand goes up we need to find more
places uh the
other significant obstacle is that for
any one location we have a Rel
relatively short harvest season so here
it would basically be September right
now you can grow broccoli just fine if
you harvest in September the problem is
that your customers need broccoli 12
months out of the year and they're not
going to abandon their reliable supplier
for a month to take your stuff that's
the Grower's dilemma so supplying year
round turns out to be a very important
uh element of getting into the
market and because of that situation the
distribution Network for Growers
throughout the East is not really set up
to handle a product uh with a fresh
market product with this volume so just
getting it from The Producers to the
stores the very common question from
Farmers I can grow it just fine but who
do I sell it to very common question
from retail produce uh buyers we really
want local broccoli but we can't find
anybody to raise it for us so this seems
like a dilemma that can be overcome and
it turns out this distribution network
is the problem so where do we start
well of course start with breeding and
improving the crop because that's what
we're really good at and I'll talk in
more detail about that uh but breeding a
better crop doesn't help unless the
farmers can buy the Seed of it right
that's where the rubber meets the road
you can buy the seed if there's only
6,000 Acres of broccoli in the East the
seed companies don't care they're not
going to spend money on developing
varieties marketing them releasing them
raising seed and selling those seed if
there's only a few Growers so they
haven't been motivated to do anything at
all that's been a big
obstacle so we've tried to put together
a project where we contempt them with
the promise of having a lot more acreage
in the east so it's worth their while
and so This Promise of volume markets
has developed the promise of potentially
having a lot more Eastern Growers more
seed sales and Seed Company
interest and so just to show you what
the what the problem looks like uh with
warm nights not enough chilling hours to
put it roughly for those of you who've
taken plant physiology and recognize
that system so the flower buds need cool
temperatures to decide to develop and
obviously that didn't happen uh at the
right time in this one and so you have
some very teeny tiny floral primordia
there and some big flower buds there
that managed to squeak through while it
was still cool uh so that's what a
western adapted variety looks like here
in the summertime this is a variety that
was bred for growing in warmer summer
conditions probably nobody would buy
this unless it was a friend who was
selling it to you right uh
and this is Pac-Man this is the variety
that Eastern broccoli production was
based on for about 20 years until maybe
five or 10 years ago uh it still looks
pretty rough you can sell that in some
markets but certainly not in the
supermarket trade or the restaurant
trade so we need to have varieties that
look better than that so that's our the
physiological goal and the breeding goal
of the project so I want to run through
really quickly some of uh the physiology
we did a number of years ago because in
case you've forgotten or are not yet
aware uh because we're going to be
picking up on on this uh soon so in
development you have vegetative marem
you recognize a little Dome on top there
uh at a certain point the flowering
reproductive transition comes along and
so now you have a reproductive Marist
stem you can tell the difference the
main difference
floral primordia just show you you can
get a good siiz head consisting of
nothing but floral primordia AR rested
in development um the inset shows them a
little bit bigger and there's the it's
gone all the way to flower buds uh so
you may ask what's the genetic
difference between these because you
know if we had the gene we could solve
it well all three of those pictures are
taken from exactly the same
genotype it's an F1 hybrid commercial
green cauliflower variety called Green
Harmony it's widely raised in Asia it's
an F1 hybrid they're all the same the
difference is the temperature so it's
gene expression is very important what
triggers gene expression after a certain
number of U chilling hours are uh
accumulated so we'll take a quick look
at that so leafy is a gene that usually
if it turns on that's when you start
getting the floral differentiation and
here you can see a vegetative marem so
the white speckles are where the gene is
being expressed so it's low in the
vegetative one starts to get higher
right in the outside surface of those uh
reproductive meristems and then when it
goes to flower buds uh it actually looks
a little bit lower which it stays high
at that point in a arabidopsis it's a
little different so Denise Duo is a
graduate student here um who looked at a
whole set of candidate genes that we
believed from arabidopsis work uh would
tell us where the level of control was
and we found many genes that didn't do
anything interesting at all even though
we expected them to uh but there were a
couple so leafy when the transition from
the U floral primordia to the flowers uh
the leafy drops off and when you have
the earlier transition we see that the a
pedala one which is the petal
designating uh Gene turns on uh so we
have a couple of transitions so the
question is what leads up to that and so
we compared as development proceeds or
the expression levels of uh so we see
leafy stops at this one and AP1 turns
off there have another one called
fruitful that was doing some interesting
things uh so to go to the next step
we're asking what regulates these but
when you compare broccoli with what's
going on in
arabidopsis we were not encouraged to
say Well it happens this way in a rabid
offis so therefore it must be happening
the same way in broccoli they're just
not being expressed at the same stages
and it's a very complex network uh that
leads up to that and we ended up having
uh a very large number of candidate
genes to try to pursue a candidate Gene
approach so that effort more or less
stopped at that point and the uh given
the situation the next step is really to
pick it up at the genomics level where
you can look at all of the genes you
don't have to know in advance uh and
look at what that variation is so that
is a direction that Zach stanel will be
pursuing here if he went to grad review
you saw some of the populations that he
has available uh to him to begin that so
that'll be continuing
onward um but then we come to the
Eastern broccoli project which funded no
molecular work whatsoever uh but many
other things so this is a project that
was funded by the specialty crops
research initiative uh and it had a goal
of having year- round broccoli
production of a quality that consumers
want and so here are sort of the Harvest
Seasons starting in Maine New York going
south we've got the mountains of Ken
Tennessee Kent and Virginia uh South
Carolina North Carolina and then uh
South Georgia and Florida are sort of
the different production areas we're
looking at and the harvest season in
each of those and one of the things you
can see is that there is gaps even when
we've got all the production areas going
there are still gaps in the production
season and so the goal is to expand each
of those production Seasons by
increasing the environmental uh adapt
adaptation of the broccoli so that we
can go wider and have them overlap a
little
bit so to realize the opport
the
well the
oper I guess to find the yearround
production uh we need not only the
varieties that have the right traits we
need the uh really wide adaptability so
that's a trait of sorts but uh it's
really a fundamental behavior of the
plant uh we need to get the varieties
released the seed companies need to be
producing the seeds selling the seeds of
them uh we need a grower base that can
expand so people are expert at growing
vegetables uh but not currently doing
broccoli how can they start doing
broccoli where does that make sense for
them
um and looking at the Supply so that
we're having enough broccoli coming on
the market to meet the demand but not so
much that it depresses the price and
finding that balance is actually not
only challenging but very location
specific you can tank the price in one
market and have a shortage in another
one just a few hundred miles away uh and
then finally make sure that the the
product that's raised in the East is
valued by the consumers uh and by the
uh really the produ ju managers they're
real
U uh roadblock in this one so we set up
uh a set of six objectives in the
project uh to try to hit all of those
and I'll talk a little bit about most of
them and so you may not even be able to
read that but this is uh some of the
team that was working together and so we
had a breeding group
um nutritional quality we don't want to
have the broccoli be less healthy that
would be rude uh the big Regional trial
system in many locations we looking at
uh economics uh both National Market
systems and consumer decision making uh
we have a team from the seed companies
who are responsible for
commercialization uh a number of
different Farms an extension team to
make sure that the uh Growers had
appropriate guidance and and then a
bunch of distribution and Retail it
turns out it's it's not like this one
big flow of broccoli there's hundreds of
different markets all with their own
expectations so we try to uh represent a
lot of those and so a lot of integration
with industry in this project so looking
at the breeding element of it so we want
to improve the public sector germ plasm
the in the public sector there's a lot
of opportunity to make improvements that
don't make sense for the
companies uh especially bringing in in
uh more unusual traits or starting with
uh material that's a little bit more odd
than commercial material uh we also want
to discover the best seed company
germplasm they've got lots of packets of
seeds sashed away that didn't have
enough market potential before but maybe
it does now let's find it uh want to
combine the excellent traits that are in
the commercial germplasm with the new
traits that would come out of a public
program um
we want to understand the quantitative
genetics of the traits these are
difficult traits in understanding how
they behave and interact uh is important
for making progress uh nicking trials
for hybrid production uh not all couples
are made in heaven when it comes to
broccoli so some of them are very
productive of seeds some are not if
you're a seed company seeds are your
products so if you have a hybrid that
you want to sell in the plant it just
doesn't make a lot of seeds well that's
that's low productivity that's a really
big problem so it turns out that the
hybrids you see on the market are from
very fun uh parental pairs so we have
three public programs so griffs is one
of them here at Cornell U and Mark faram
with ARs at Charleston South Carolina
and uh Jim Myers at Oregon state who's
been breeding for
uh really the processing industry as
well as for organic production so we
wanted to bring that in and then three
private programs the seed companies beo
senta and seminis were the ones who
elected to join us and as the person
trying to get all these people to talk
to each other in common language we find
that each of the breeding programs has a
very distinct way of going about things
uh different populations different goals
um so one of the uh
techniques was to try to encourage them
to compete a little bit with one another
so we have a regional trial program so
trying to make sure that everybody feels
uh the competitive urge to have the best
material in the regional trial uh that
uh proved helpful but then at the same
time uh we want them to collaborate with
each other to generate cross program
results that are uh even better uh and
then we really want want to get the
public material licensed so that crowers
can get it uh licensing is is how it's
done these days but having the public
material then go to a seed company in
one of many forms
um and uh become available and provide
Revenue to keep uh these breeding
programs
going um so they're are the Breeders I
mentioned them so here are the traits
that the new varieties need so you
notice it's a long list for starters uh
I'll only mention briefly we need the
stability across environments wide
adaptation uh because in any given
location you're going to have a lot of
variation in the weather and you don't
know how to predict it if you remember
365 days ago what kind of jacket were
you wearing and what are you wearing
today that's normal variation uh we need
the uniform bead so that's really
genetically chilling requirement uh we
need a a good dome on it and that's just
so the rain falls off that's all all you
need that for but you can have a
relatively flat head in California it
doesn't matter we need one that sheds
rain so it doesn't rot
uh want to make sure it has all the
ingredients that make it healthy uh the
market likes really small flower buds
right now but really small flower buds
are difficult to hide hide uneven flower
buds behind the big ones hide stuff a
lot better uh so how much do you need
that it needs to look really green
because people buy broccoli because it's
healthy and green is healthier right
everybody uh works that way in their
head and this turns out to be not just
chlorophyll content but wax structure on
the surface what color antoin so there's
a lot that goes into the uh green so all
of these are complex traits there's not
a single Gene trait in the bunch so if
figuring out how to pile all these
together U is no small matter U and to
really address the the first one in
particular we've set up a system of
regional
trials where we are testing the material
in very different locations so we want
to identify the wide adaptation to the
east uh we want to collect a data set
where we can start to understand the
genetic control of some of these traits
there's huge environmental effect on
essentially all of them and there's a
substantial genotype by environment
interaction so to figure out anything at
all you need massive data sets um we
particularly want to understand the
variation in nutritional quality because
that's that's again a feature people
like we do see quite a lot of
environmental variation um you see the
Bena Forte broccoli it's being sold as
uh U glucoraphanin and enhanced broccoli
type and they don't tell you what
concentration it is because it varies
quite a lot with the growing conditions
they say it contains four times as much
as normal broccoli and that's entirely
true if you grow a regular variety and
benfor next to each other the benfor
generally runs about four times as high
but how much the absolute number uh
depends on the environment so we've got
a lot of variation there
um we're trying to identify where
different germ plasm has complimentary
traits so you get one with a great Dome
and one that's really green but you're
not getting any that have both for
instance and
um and we want the companies to buy and
license the public sector
material U so the these Regional trials
they were set up in three phases the
first one we allow lots and lots of
entries we're essentially culling at
that stage we've got five locations two
plantings at each location so lots of
observations on those um but not a huge
investment in them uh so that's an
effective culling step and that's where
we can attract uh so anything a breeder
thinks might look interesting it doesn't
have to win it just needs a chance to
win then we have a much more elaborate
stability trial here we have uh five
plantings at four locations but that way
we try many different times during the
season uh and really get a sense of how
it behaves we get vast variation in what
happens we try to hit a stressful time
and non-stressful time and sometimes
nature cooperates this is also where we
look at the nutritional studies um and
finally we go to looking at commercial
yields where we're on grower Farms
seeing how they uh how they actually
behave what kind of yield are they are
they going to make money uh you know
that how much does it cost to harvest
them do you have to go in three times or
seven times that makes a big difference
uh we spent a lot of time standardizing
across locations so we had little
diagram for how to score different
things uh we got together and made sure
everybody sat in the same room and
looked at broccoli head oh is this a
three for green or a for for green
talked about that for a long time uh to
make sure that everybody was scoring the
same way at each location because we're
trying to compare numbers across
location so having that be standardized
was really important so some of the
stuff that comes out of it just a little
Glimpse we can do uh this this is an
Association uh among the different
traits that we scored uh and so each of
this are a scatter plot of
um how the two traits are related to
each other so here's an example of
firmness and bead size usually smaller
flower buds make the head firmer and it
is sturdier and you can see that there's
a very strong positive relationship
there so the a lot of the firmness is
actually caused by the flower buds being
small so that's what you would expect
not surprising you have some other ones
so plot uniformity is the plant-to-plant
variation um is not at all associated
with firmness you probably wouldn't
expect them to be uh but so there's you
find some are completely unrelated and
then one as I just implied small beaded
ones it's harder to hide
non-uniformity and so you'd expect a
strong negative correlation there that
the small beaded stuff tends to look
less uniform and sure enough that's a
negative relationship but the the way to
look at that is hey there's some here
that have small beads and look uniform
great so breeders are great at tossing
out the junk and looking at only the
good stuff and so that's what happens
here is you keep the good stuff
uh and then in comparing the material
over these many you have to
really condense the information so we
ended up using spider plots as one way
to describe it so each of the axes is a
different trait and they're grouped a
little bit so we've got firmness bead
size bead uniformity are the first three
so those are important traits that are
difficult to get the Dome is also
important and uh sensitive to heat a lot
of the time then head uniformity
color uh head expression how far it
comes up plot uniformity and holding
time uh which you can see it's uh
sensitive green is grown in cool
conditions red in hot conditions so
green magic is when we started was the
most common Variety in the East Marathon
was the most common Variety in the world
you can see that uh it goes down to
horrible low numbers when it's warm uh
Iron Man was being sold for being tough
that's how got its name uh the red line
is a lot smaller than the green line
Castle Dome was another standard we
looked at so this was from the seconde
breeding
trials
uh we've got some that uh are fair in
the heat sensitive traits but really do
very nicely in everything else others
that have really quite High numbers uh
in the heat sensitive traits and are not
too bad in the other one
so we're able to uh look over the
different materials and so uh
skipping several years ahead now uh so
this is this is the slide that I'm
actually very excited about so how fast
is the breeding progress when you're
working with very complicated traits
well if you're working with talented
breeders who know the art of breeding
progress is fast so on our raing system
uh a three was generally set at where
the minimum commercial quality is so if
it's a three you can probably sell it if
everything else is okay and four was
considered really good commercial
quality and we went to five because some
of the traits go beyond that and so here
uh I put the axis at three because it's
the minimum and the top at four because
that's what we ultimately want to see
each of these bars um is uh the average
of
120 data points so they're pretty uh
strong as far as variation so the red
lines are the standard so it's the same
varieties every time five different
standards that are averaged together and
the green are the five best lines in our
phase one trial so when we started this
was material that was people had it they
thought it might be good uh so the best
of those you see that they're a little
bit improved in the uniform bead little
bit smoother Dome the Dome stays okay
and they're a little bit Greener so
that's what we started with and three
years of breeding later now the uniform
bead is well into the commercial range
uh the the Dome is
still well into the commercial range
here on smoothness we've maintained the
Dome haven't given up on that and
they're much Greener so we've had
remarkable progress here
uh so we've had and there's further
crosses being made so the anticipation
is that this will continue up but to be
able to go from barely commercial to
really well towards having everything
hit commercial a lot of the time it's
tremendous Advance on the breeding end
uh so to do that is a a picture we've
gone from this in August to this in
August this one happens to to be one of
marks but Griff has lines that also look
like this in the summertime so that you
can sell and that is what the seed
companies are interested in
commercializing the uh
U so the material that we started with
here in the early one that is what has
become released as commercial varieties
and so they've been in the yield trial
so just to show you graphically the how
the yield trials were laid out with the
different production areas on the x-axis
here in the year on the or on the year
on the x-axis different uh locations on
the y-axis uh but how you try to fit so
that the growth happens when it's warm
enough but it's done and ready to
harvest before it gets either too hot or
too cold uh depending on which end of
the season you're on so we tried to fit
the different locations you can see we
go from very cold areas to the very warm
areas to try to cover the whole
season uh and these yield trials have
have shown that the new material is uh
stable and Superior in each in their own
locations we've had six varieties
released by the seed companies in the
first four years of the project and are
expecting a couple more to come out this
growing season um so the you know based
on the early stuff so the better the
better stuff is on the way it's in the
in their
pipeline uh but I think that is a great
result just thinking about uh in your
own research what's the mechanism from
getting it from your lab to Industry so
it's for sale in the marketplace there's
an awful lot of steps a lot awful a lot
of time so seeing this much progress in
in four years uh is
really uh remarkable and that's the the
Breeders uh and seed companies in the
project that have moved it along like
that uh so then we come to the Growers
where are The Growers going to be and
how can we uh fit the new varieties in
and look at how where we can stretch the
season a little bit uh where should we
encourage new production and one of the
elements of looking at that is to look
at climate data we've got tremendous
resources in climate data so we can look
at some uh patterns to try to guess
where it might fit well and so I first
do sort of a rough picture here I'm
using selenis where the production is
currently I'm using as a proxy the mean
minimum temperature what we actually use
in the model is number of days that the
nighttime temperature exceeds
65 uh but but that's much harder to
draw uh so just the mean minimum
temperature
uh on actually a daily basis uh and so
you can see Selenas is pretty flat so
blue here is where it's really too cold
for it to grow red is where it's too
warm for it to grow or for it to produce
nice heads uh so the Eastern location in
Caribou main up there in the north uh
they have similarly cool middle of
Summer that's why they can produce it in
the middle of summer but very different
pattern there in the continental climate
if you look at Geneva you see that we're
warmer than Maine uh and just touches
that Red Zone in a tantalizing sort of
way Western New York is very productive
for coal Crop Production uh so a little
bit of improvement uh and we can uh
probably do a lot so what about nearby
areas so as an example I'll use Fremont
Ohio it's on the southern shore of Lake
eries or so it's not that different it's
just a little bit further south and so
you can see they pop up into the red
area quite a bit and so it's actually
quite a lot less suitable you'd have to
make pretty big uh changes in the
temperature uh tolerance of broccoli to
go to that area so if we look at the
harvest season Selenas actually harvests
from April through November and then
they move down to the desert um if you
look at Maine they actually start
harvesting in July and they go until
early October whenever they get frozen
out so you see that's quite a bit
shorter season I've got up here sort of
my guesses what the harvest season would
be uh if you look at New York
um that slope is steep right that's our
problem it's changing fast and what we
know is that there's a lot of
variability in that but that's uh what
our harvest season can look like and you
see that that Fremont Ohio is steeper
still and it's not so much that they're
warmer it's that they're steeper that
makes it a problem so their their season
is quite a bit shorter too so that's
going to be a
challenge the other issue we deal with
is rainfall so this is this past June do
you remember
[Laughter]
June uh
so that that's a deadly amount of water
The Roots need to breathe those roots
are not breathing um and I like to
compare broccoli production to dragster
racing if you miss a shift in dragster
racing you're kind out of the picture it
doesn't matter and it's the same thing
with broccoli and this is a Mis shift uh
it isn't making the transition from
newly transplanted to Rapid growth uh
quickly and uh then ends up being a big
problem and you'll get to see a little
bit how big
uh so looking at also at The Growers how
should they produce broccoli uh to make
it profitable uh has to be more
profitable than whatever they're growing
now and we need some hard numbers on
that and some production systems one
thing I
uh noted is that uh with cabbage which
is very similar to br in many ways uh we
produce about 50 to 55 tons per acre in
New York in the Southeast on much
lighter soils they around 30 tons an
acre uh and yet both locations are
producing uh typically 400 to 450 boxes
an acre about half of California
so if you monkeyed around with the
growing a little bit could you move
Western New York production a little bit
closer to California than it is in
Georgia
and so we tried some nutrition and
particularly plant population changes so
the traditional population here is uh
similar to other transplanted vegetable
crops maybe 14 15 16,000 plants per acre
so we're going with some higher numbers
here so here there's the rows are 15
inches apart and there's a every fourth
row is skipped and they're either 6 8 or
12 in apart in the row um we know that
there are production systems that will
will pack them even as tight as this
52,000
population so this is 2 weeks after
transplanting what they should look like
they're filling in in the row for the
most part uh except for the 12in one uh
3 weeks you've got a pretty solid stand
uh here uh four and a half weeks this is
about when the herbicide wears off so
you know weed management is one of the
big problems so if your herbicide wears
off and the Weeds start germinating at
this point how big a problem are the
weeds going to
be they basically don't stand a chance
the root the broccoli Roots fill the
entire soil and there's no light coming
to the ground so weed management really
works out nice if you have this kind of
growth um and 52 days is when Harvest
begins uh so on this one you can see
it's a little bit lighter green because
the uh nitrogen is moving towards heads
fact few little leaves that were shaded
out they're moving the nitrogen up into
the head so doing very high fertility
production but not excessive fertility
uh nitrogen's being used effectively so
what happens uh in terms of productivity
with these so here's a graph of the
cumulative yields so the uh lowest
population does uh exactly what
experience has been with low populations
uh it starts to produce you do three
cuts and you've got uh a yield here we
got about 550 because we're doing uh
high fertility there so we beat the
state average on that one with the
intermediate population there's about a
5-day delay in maturity so you're giving
up something there but there's more
plants that produce heads uh so you're
putting up the yield close to 700 on
that one when they were packed
tighter
then they started competing with each
other so even though they were only
delayed a few more days uh they start
pooping out and so there's a lot of
plants that don't make anything
harvestable at all so they were too
tight uh so we found that moving up into
the 30s 30,000 something uh is going to
be a lot better than 15,000 which is
where people generally are now uh found
with quality so I used a hollow this is
hollow stem here a hollow stem
susceptible variety uh in this trial uh
it's a delicious tasting one so it's
popular for that uh and it's basically
how thick the stem is determines whether
the pith is going to open
up and so if you look at the head weight
these are all 5in heads so the heavier
heads are the ones that have thicker
stems that's the dimension that's
changing uh and at the low population
we're getting big thick stems with lots
of hollow stem at the highest population
we're getting undersized heads we want
to try to keep them close to2 kilos uh
so the intermediate population not only
gave the highest yield it gave the
highest quality so this tells us what
the optimal population should look like
and so Growers can find uh what their
own is but they said we're doing to see
when you make money so let's do the
numbers on that uh so 2013 was an
excellent year for growing broccoli uh
it did very well the green curve is the
revenue the red curve is the total cost
and we're figuring everything owning the
tractors the barns interest payments all
of that stuff so this is not marginal
cost it's total cost
uh by way of comparison good corn crop
is worth
600700 it's way down
there so this is very big money compared
with uh even some profitable crops uh so
the low population make pretty good
money intermediate population make even
more money 2014 was a challenging year
we had a hail storm come through just
before heading another Mist shift if you
will uh where the plants really were
shocked they stopped growing for several
days just from the physical shock of the
the hail storm uh so we had lower yields
then
uh but if you look at those differences
where the profit is that intermediate
population still made good
money going with a lower population just
barely broke even and even that one is
higher than the industry standard so
moving those populations up
is going to make broccoli a lot more
economically attractive so 2015 I showed
you what 2015 looks like it was a
terrible terrible year so what happens
when you have a terrible year with that
huge investment well the costs are still
high and at the lower population it
still pulled it out it turned out to be
all bunching broccoli instead of crown
broccoli uh so the highest population
lost money but the grower still doesn't
lose a ton of money even when there's a
really disastrous event so sometimes you
don't you don't make much money but at
least you don't you you have $6,000 an
acre at risk there so uh coming out even
with that one is actually pretty good
news in a terrible
year uh so to continue down the line of
the economic analysis uh for uh making
that money here's the price per box over
the last five
years uh at Eastern Terminal Markets so
prices vary all over the place depending
on how you're uh who you're selling it
to but the terminal market price at
least is basically the same thing all
the time so you know what's going on
there and they're reported every week so
you can get the numbers on them uh
looked at the blue line is a bunch and
the green line is a crown the market is
more and more Crown cut there's a few
holdouts that are still doing bunches uh
the southeast which is very conservative
in their food tastes New York City which
apparently is very conservative in its
food tastes you want to draw that
inference uh and U organic tends to go
with a bunch but the bulk of the market
these days is Crown you can see that
there used to be a differential between
the two but for the last few years
that's pretty much gone
um the price jumps around a lot from
year to year so if you're a grower going
into a spot market like this uh it can
be very hard to budget and so it's
really important to make sure that uh
at4 $15 you're making
money and sometimes you make a lot of
money but you don't know when that's
going to happen uh some years there's a
transition right around uh New Years it
often uh comes as they're switching over
production uh from Selena to the desert
and sometimes um there's a big extra
Supply coming out of Mexico right around
then that they're trying to catch that
so we looked at the total production
costs for the East to see how they
compare with
California and we looked at some models
and the the numbers came in remarkably
similar they're all like 111 and I'd put
several dollars of error bars on each of
these because it depend so much locally
uh but these numbers are definitely
competitive but what goes into those
varies a great deal uh that the cost
structure so California Water costs a
lot here water comes down free Power
sometimes too much but it comes down
free land is very expensive in
California land is not very expensive
here uh labor is much more difficult to
get here so there's there's significant
differences
one of the big variables so yeah so I'll
remind you so the price chart $15
production costs 11 so that's kind of
where your potential profit margin is
one of the big variables is the post
Harvest costs so broccoli is all really
rapidly growing tissue right it's
respiring like crazy and so if you take
a bunch of broccoli that's at out in the
sunshine and you put it in a box and you
put a bunch of boxes together and
they're all busy respiring
at a very high temperature what's going
to happen they're going to get hot
they're going to turn yellow they're
going to burn up all their sugar they're
going to be awful so it has to get cold
really quickly and there's been a lot of
work done on this and cold means 32
fahren it doesn't mean 38 38 degre
rapid rapid
enough respiration to cost a lot of
quality from the farm uh to the B
so getting it cold is critical so
there's a number of different
Technologies and it depends on the scale
that the grower is working at uh so one
of the most common is hydrocooling where
you basically dip it into ice cold water
so this is
a conveyor belt that takes the Box takes
it down into the ice cold water up it
comes again really very simple
straightforward not very expensive you
have to have access to gigantic blocks
of ice at low cost but if you've got
that that's pretty good one that lasts a
lot longer is this liquid ice injection
so here the boxes are open there's a
dispenser and it dispenses a bunch of
chipped ice on
top that works great on a small scale
but doing those boxes one at a time uh
is high Labor uh one that we've seen
that doesn't cool very much is just
using the tap water or well water
that's whatever the temperature of your
your groundwater is uh that'll take a
lot of the field heat out so if you are
delivering on the same day it'll be cold
enough as long as it gets sold within a
day you can get away with it that's
really cheap if you have that water
available then cooling with solid ice
this is absolutely the cheapest one the
one everybody starts with because all it
takes is one of those plastic shovels
and a box full of ice from the ice
company and you shovel the ice into the
box one by one uh very labor intensive
it costs a fortune per box uh so for
people starting out they use that one
but the incentive to switch to something
else uh is quick what they use in
California a huge scale it is actually
not super cheap but they have to do this
to get it across the country and that is
they inject an ice water slurry into an
entire pallet of boxes and so the water
ice mixture goes in there it gets into
every nook and cranny and the water
comes
out
um so finally I mentioned that it's hard
to get Market access for Growers here
and it's hard for the markets to access
the
Growers
and these are a bunch of the problems
that people have run into and we have a
program going on in New York and a few
other states in the East that is is
Under The Heading of food Hub and these
are aggregation sites where there's a
manager who will work with a number of
different farms and consolidate
shipments uh work with Buyers who are
used to calling up Selenas and saying
hey I need two truckloads of this and
that uh that they'll be able to speak
the same language as the buyers and be
able to negotiate fairly Among The
Growers uh to meet know it looks the way
it should look comes in the amount you
promis
uh it allows them to use cooling
technology more
efficiently uh and so developing these
food hubs is something that's moving
along we're having a great time working
with the uh really the extension system
is where the strength is in this
one uh so the question now
is can broccoli be as cool as
kale uh
so uh so that's that's the last slide so
I've told you a little bit about the
breeding and the physiology uh and how
we're taking that and how do you bring
it to Market so that the seed companies
have an incentive to Market to the
Eastern Growers so that we can have a
good base of Eastern Growers all the way
from imoc uh to the St John River Valley
in the north with in particular a nice
big group in Western New York where
there's huge potential uh for tens of
millions of dollars of production in the
next few years so that thanks very
[Applause]
much um is there any interest inting
like the
non-heading um there are uh non-heading
broccoli varieties but the labor cost in
harvesting is so high that uh that is
very
limited
no the the non-heading types have
receive much less greeding so the
quality consistency is lower the
productivity is
lower of
Fortune great for uh Market Gardens and
home
GS so of all those traits that you
believe to be the most important it's
the doming that is the one really change
the do do you know I me it stayed about
the same right do you know any genes
that control doing based on work
inas or so the uh so the flattening of
the Dome is when the outer branches the
oldest branches start to grow first as
it's getting ready to bolt it's getting
closer to anesis uh those will start to
grow timing of that
station relative to the maturity of the
head uh that that timing is shifted as
all so that's that's what under so I
don't know which G's control that for
sure but that's the that's the timing
event that's
different a genetically complex
trait this seems like an obvious
question but are you working with any
Poop House Growers or doing any trials
in hoop houses uh it doesn't seem like
that's going to pay off for most markets
because we can move up and down the
coast uh that uh the cost of producing
broccoli in the hoop house uh is so much
higher than shipping it from a few
hundred miles away which is the distance
that the hoop house would benefit so for
the non-heading types there's actually
some work in
uh on the Atlantic seaboard for doing
fop houses with some of the non-heading
ones they can actually over mure them
and so they work on for a CSA a
restaurant you can have those in very
early spring
February
that's we have a we have a question
from yeah Thomas uh what are other goals
of the project in next
pH so the major goal in the next phase
of the project are easy to answer
because I'm busy writing the grand
proposal right now uh so we want to
understand uh the genetics of the
complex traits better because to improve
them further uh we're going to have to
use molecular markers to identify the
combinations because we're not going to
get enough difference uh between uh
single we'll call them one one level of
uh genetic uh tolerance from a high
level just that stacking uh because
they're not single Gene traits I'm going
to be careful about my terminology here
uh but to put more layers of that on uh
we need to be using the molecular
markers to see when we're combining uh
different sources of resistance uh
developing the uh the food hubs is
actually a significant part of it
because we need to make that volume grow
and getting the the new Growers who
might be uh say 10 to 100 acres of
broccoli uh that kind of scale for their
broccoli as part of their uh vegetable
mix um they're going to need the
distribution
channels and getting that Regional
trialing system expanded to include a
lot more seat companies so there's more
contribution the overall uh Improvement
of varities those are the areas that
we're looking at uh primarily
for Thomas in terms of carbon footprint
yeah might it not be argued that
Trucking broccoli
fromi to New York or Boston is as carbon
intensive as flying it from California
to New York
well but Trucking the trucking yeah if
you're going yeah deoc to Boston or
versus selus to Boston or actually
theuma to Boston in that case
uh it's not a huge difference because
they're both big yeah and likewise going
from
U ariso County name to Atlanta we're
going from Guan in Mexico to Atlanta
that's not really very good you so you
you do hit a sort of Break Even point
there and that's where Miguel Gomez's
work has been modeling that as far as
for each of the different major markets
in the East U how much should be
supplied from East Coast but a distance
for it to make sense so we don't try to
invest in something that really doesn't
have very much potential because there's
not that much local benefit
I'm just curious about is is a spring or
fall a better Market or is it does it do
better in spring fall in this region way
better than the fall way better spring
is really challenging because it wants
to grow when it's warm vegetatively and
it wants to head when it's cold and
that's the exact opposite of what
happens in the springtime so spring is
really difficult that's our most
difficult season to find
adap well I want to thank Thomas for
fascinating
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu