this is a production of Cornell
University
justed now we're going to find out if
it's going to go down easy or hard
yeah yep all
right
fingers it down yeah maybe that would
make more
sense if you want to have a look in
there you can see the old where the this
is how big the leaf to give you some
idea that's how big the leaf was and so
you're seeing in there is basically
that's the the actual corn right there
and uh I don't see any bud coming up yet
which which is a good sign that probably
means this will be a little dormant a
little bit longer suck on Roots there
yeah well and that's a good definitely a
lot yeah yeah okay all well I'm going to
so get a
Legge that sounds like a good
one oh look at this we found buried in
here I was this is really cool so I I
had feared this was lost it it had gone
into the pot we planted this on August
11th
2013 uh and it was weighed on June 1st
of 2013 and it weighed 18 lbs uh which
is very good because I'm expecting this
to weigh a lot more based on how big the
air was
get on the song got
it
okay there is
excitement
wow almost feel like an
archaeologist what blow baffles me is so
what do you think did all that media
just s of weak out through the botom the
pretty compressed yeah that must yeah
that's pretty
true I think this could weigh more than
the other one I mean this is a m cor and
we have a good scale downstairs that
Andy and I tested yesterday
that on from the top The Roots come from
the top of the Corn and uh and then they
go around it and go down and grow around
the cor as the cor gets converted to
energy for the for the plants they
necessary plant them several inches down
because if you don't The Roots will sort
of go
up be out of the soil
which pretty soon I think we can flip it
over
yeah
yeah you know this may not so my punch
actually is that this may not be a
flower because do you see buds are the
bud is on the periphery which may mean
that this won't flower which is good and
bad it's good
because when it does flower it'll be a
really good a huge specimen because I
I'm
yeah I I'm going to guess that this
weighs about 50
lb you see all these roots that are
coming off the top of the corner yeah
that's really good that's a good
observation but I mean I'm actually
really really pleased is the help of
this you know it's always you're never
quite sure what you're going
to get Andy knows this as a potato
grower sometimes you uh you just don't
know what it looks like till you dig it
up I'm really conf this is this is
great yeah it's impressive how it's sort
of recess the the area where the bud
differentiates
from and what's different about Titan
that that compared to some other arams
is is it really rarely
produces what I would call a corlet uh
smaller corn other species like conc
would have uh quite a number of smaller
corn arms in there that you could grow
up if you wanted
so um aside from leaf cutting the way to
propagate Titans seems to be perceive if
I remember correctly reading it in in
one of these articles he he actually was
saying correct me if I'm wrong or look
this up but he was actually cutting one
of the
uh uh leaflets you know this is actually
a single leaf uh but he was cutting it
right here where it was first compounded
and rooting that and then eventually
what happens is a little bit form will
develop around the base of that so it is
possible to do these through Le cutting
but uh we haven't we haven't done that
here we get down to the corn and not
much else yeah I think it's it's I mean
I think at this point if we weigh it and
maybe you know I don't think there's
more than a pound of media that would be
getting weighed when I when I weighed we
stinky it actually weighed one weigh 51
lb but I had about this much or maybe a
little more promix on it so I just sort
of round it down down 50 so I was saying
earlier Craig you know the the pedial on
this was was much had a much wider
diameter than than the the last heroid
the last vegetative state of our our
flowering Titan so that was when I was
really excited about the fact that we
had obviously another strong specimen so
um the the actual diameter of the pedal
was was about here and you can see right
along the edge of plant where that or
the edge of this indication where that
was so what do you think should we take
this downstairs and wa one two
three I think it was about 16 close to
half a meter yeah yeah this is a decent
size Tim is a one of our Dutch interns
so he really knows uh geoides pretty
well youever seen have you ever seen a
Lily that
big amazing yeah
yeah we're going to go find out how much
it weighs okay so we're measuring in
pounds yes all
right all
righty wow 55.9 lb 55.9 lb including a
little bit of media but not too much
yeah I'm going to say that we're at
least 55 corn absolutely the corn would
probably I haven't actually paid
attention to these things over time but
I wouldn't be surprised if the corn
weight decreases for a little while as
it as it
descat uh So based on flower on the
weight it's it's a it is a blooming size
qu uh and I'm I'm really excited now to
see whether this does based on where
where I see the new but emerging my
hypothesis is that it will be a
vegetative stage which is also
encouraging that means that the ne when
it does Bloom you can have a really
large bloom this is this is a huge farm
so this is is this is as good as it
could I mean this is just way better
than anything thought it would be so
good news this could be not so weed
stinky
yeah this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu