This is a production of Cornell
University.
Well, I had a good week this week, Doug.
I took the kids to uh Yankee Stadium.
Oh, that's fun. We had a We took our
turf class uh to Yankee Stadium uh with
some additional people interested. We
had about 25 people we took down uh to
visit my old college pal um Dan
Cunningham. And of course, you've been
down there with me uh as well. Um, and
you know, it reminded me of when I
taught in Matt when I taught at Madison.
I used to take them up to Lambo. Yeah.
Yeah. We had pictures of the class at
the center of Lambo and then we went uh
we took the train. We we took a bus down
to Yankee Stadium. Uh, and then got on
the subway and went down to Central Park
and visited Zack Holm who's the director
of turf care uh at Central Park. did
some grass ID uh of the ryrass and poa
in the field there uh and then hung out
a little bit uh at Sheep's Meadow.
Super cool. Yeah. Yeah. Tuesday, that
was Monday. Tuesday, we got up and went
out to Delh High Sunni Delh High where
we had a walk and talk promoting the
apprentichip program that the New York
State Turf Grass Association is working
on with a bunch of the superintendent
organizations. Tyler Bloom's outfit and
there are about a thousand students
pursuing apprenticeships in gatekeeping
uh grounds management in New York State.
So this is a very exciting time and we
got to meet some and see some of the
students at Delhigh doing projects on
the golf course. Got to interact with
Tom Kaufman who's been the
superintendent there for many many years
now. Um, and so it was a great visit and
actually we got to see some robotic
mowers. Uh, MTE was there. That's Matt
Simon, a former superintendent now
selling uh, robots for MTE. And it was
very interesting because you know from a
workforce perspective you know
automation and apprenticeships those
apprenticeships better be teaching
technological skills because a lot of
what these uh folks are going to be
doing is going to be involving
technology now assumably so this
generation younger generation will be
more uh comfortable integrating
technology uh into their work life.
Okay, you know, Carl, thanks for joining
us. Glad to have you. I'm on time for a
change. It's so great. I was literally
sitting there like, "Okay, what do I
do?" Carl's not here. Okay, I owe you
now. Yeah, for all those years I've been
late, right? Um, but you know, we got
dog pictures. How about a shout out for
the cats? Now, I'm not a big cat guy,
but I got three barn cats, and cats have
their usefulness. They're not very
interested in you per se, but they are
interested in uh in some of the things
that bother you around your facility.
And then my man Will Benson with my
absolute favorite dog in the entire golf
turf industry. Will is the
superintendent at Laurelwood Golf Club,
Little Nine-hole MUN, uh in Eugene,
Oregon. And that is Sandy the Chihuahua.
And to watch Sandy cruise the golf
course is something that is worthwhile.
Anyway, to the weather. It was cooler
last week and now we're starting to see
the switch change, right? We're about
normal between three to seven days of
normal. You got to go into the highest
elevations up in the Aderondex and up in
the Green Mountains and into Maine where
you're more than a week behind. Uh
certainly those areas are a little bit
behind normal. almost everybody else,
especially with the heat. When we have
this conversation next week, you're
probably going to see most people going
to be normal. Bjney
Hornson tweeted a great picture of early
spring grass growth in Iceland. In case
anybody thinks their spring is slow to
emerge, there's always Iceland. Now, I
don't know if we propose to buy this
place yet. I know we're planning on
buying the other joint, but for now
looking at the grass types here,
obviously Bejney is saying those first
two rows there of creeping bench grass
completely straw brown. The next plot
fescue and creeping uh colonial bent
grass, fescue and colonial bent grass.
Then the row of straight fescue. Then
the row of straight colonial bent. So
you can see in this thing, you know, we
talk about bent being slow in the
northeast and Doug, you probably talk
about it with with Chris Zoo along the
lake, right? Where it's really cool,
man. You've got to do a lot of things to
get the bench grass growing and probably
not the best grass uh for Iceland golf.
Have you been to Iceland, Doug? Never.
Never. Okay. Be's got to get you there.
Okay. Um, you can see we're progressing
slowly in the sort of touch points of
spring, like when is a good time to get
a broadleaf herbicide out in the spring.
It's never ideal to do it at this time,
but this is a good benchmark of when you
might get an amine or an esester
formulation of a broadleaf weed control
product to provide some measure of
control. It is not ideal for sure. Fall
being a much better time. But you can
also pick up some winter annuals as
Randy Prosstac tells us a twofer where
you might get some winter annuals before
they flower and get some of the
perennial broadleaf weeds. And this is
from old work at Purdue from many many
years ago back in the thral Riker days
the ancient days. Okay. What this means
is if if we're getting ready to spray
weeds, it means some of the weeds are
beginning to flower. And we've got our
pollinator risk assessment, which you
can see with this map, is really sort of
tracking when you shouldn't be spraying.
As it becomes ideal, if you look here,
as it's becoming ideal for these
herbicide applications, it's also
becoming risky for the pollinators. So,
if you're going to use these products,
mow the flowers off as best as you can.
If the flowers aren't there, the the
bees aren't going to be around. And we
get a lot of visitors to lawns in the
spring, especially with the winter
annuals and the spring ephemerals like
lesser celandine that might be
flowering. Soils are still cool in some
places again in those high elevations,
you're in the 40s. Uh, and then you go
down to the Philly area and you're in
the mid60s. and Long Island in the upper
50s60s. And these are trigger points now
for where many of your root pathogen
fungicide applications will go down. So,
we'd encourage you to keep monitoring
your soil temperature and determine.
We're going to have Mingi on uh the show
at some point this spring to discuss
some of the new root pathogens that he
is actively uh uh finding with his new
molecular techniques which is obviously
going to shape the way we do control in
the future. All right, pretty dry last
week, right? Most areas got very little
rainfall. You had to go up along the
Great Lakes and northern areas to get
the rainfall, but the rainfall's coming.
You look at the forecast with uh preip
minus evapo transpiration and you can
see we're going to have an excess of
water uh in some of these areas and we
have another risk model on the forecast
website that indicates when that rain
comes there are parts of the region that
are at risk for runoff. Listen, we put
our pres down now. We put our broad
leaves down now. We put our root
pathogen materials down. You know, maybe
you're putting a broadleaf down. Maybe
you're putting a fertilizer down. We
tend to put a lot of things on the land
in the spring. Monitoring the runoff at
this time of year is really critical
just to get a sense of days you should
avoid. And you can find all this at the
forecast website. All right, we're
getting to it now. Doug got a couple of
guys posting about rolling fairways. Let
me tell you how much this warms my heart
to see people rolling more. And we're
gonna take up this topic of traffic and
rolling and organic matter because I
know Carl's got a few things we're going
to chat with you about. But the sort of
theme for today is traffic. And it's
something that I know you did some work
on. We're going to want you to speculate
and extrapolate from where you did those
rounds of golf in those plots, right,
with those fertilizer rates. Remember
that from years ago when you did that?
Yeah. Okay. So, here's rolling Jim
Pavanetti style at Fairview. And here's
rolling Meadowbrook John Carlo style uh
on Long Island. You know what I mean?
Big wide units rolling. Everybody's
starting to see the benefits of this.
The obstacle has been it takes too long.
I don't want to use a tractor. Blah blah
blah. But look what's pulling these
things, right? These are utility carts
now with very wide things. Now you can
get the big Trimax one that Beth Paige
has got. Then you got to use a tractor.
you're getting into the big heavy
weights and very few people to my
knowledge have sort of studied different
rollers uh on fairways. I'm not sure
Nikolai even studied fairway rolling but
Doug here's something interesting. Paul
Gardano did this work back in 2013,
right? Where he had a native soil and he
had a USGAA root zone, right? And you
know it, you know that what came out of
this is rolling reduces
infiltration, right? So here's my first
question to you. You're looking at a
graph here where I've drawn a line at 20
cm per hour, right? So that's what an
inch
No centime in 10 inches an hour. 10
inches. Yeah. 10 inches an hour. Okay.
If would pe many people will hear people
say, "Oh, rolling reduces infiltration.
I shouldn't do it." The eight times a
week rolling a root zone still keeps it
at 10 in an hour. My question to you is,
do you care that it reduces it if it's
still 10 inches an hour? Yeah. It just
means you can't play during Hurricane
Katrina. You know, you're going to have
to take a day off.
One day. One day. Yeah. One day. So, in
your mind, as long, you know, eight
times a week on a proper root zone still
provides enough infiltration. How about
a different question? What about the
native soils that at even at eight times
a week are roll are at 10 centimeters,
which is five inches an hour. Do you get
worried there?
No, I mean, and that's native, but it's
got to be a uh sand sand top, sand cap,
right? So, yeah, that's why we build
sand greens is because we don't care
about compaction. And, you know, you're
going to have to manage organic matter,
that's going to be the thing that you're
going to want to manage, but the these
reductions, even though they're
statistically
uh significant or you see the
differences, they they don't matter in
in terms of real life, right? So, we're
talking root zones, Carl, and I know
we're going to talk about measurements,
and it comes from the great grassroots
uh Wisconsin golf course superintendent.
Doug, I think sometimes this is the only
place you put this stuff, isn't it?
You you squirrel it away if somebody
isn't uh you know, honored like I am to
receive this monthly for the last 30
frigin years. Um uh and writing for it
for many years in my time there, I come
across this article. Well, I I I rip it
out. You can see it's on my desk. And
Carl's like, "Carl, you got to look at
this." He's sitting there taking a
picture like it's 1970, right? We got to
read this thing like it's 1970. Okay,
Carl, fire away. Yeah. So, so Doug,
maybe you could just set up what this
research was. There's different volumes
of top dressing over over three years,
right? So, different volumes of top
dressing, uh different frequencies at
which those volumes were applied, and
then different sand. So maybe you could
set some of it up before we get into the
the nitty-gritty here. Geez, this is so
cool. You guys make my slides for me.
Wonderful. All right. Um yeah, that's
exactly it. So we we did a USGA green.
We wanted to know, hey, what what
database management is is what we're
really interested in. So like let's
start to use some data to make some top
dressing decisions. So how much sand
should we put down down the year? uh
does the the particle size of the sand
matter or if we apply it weekly is it
any different than than monthly? And
then you know that we're interested in
firmness as being something that we're
starting to measure more and more and we
realize there's all kinds of different
firmness meters out there. So we wanted
to see uh what what we got from that.
And surprisingly
um you know first of all fine sand
versus standard sand. A lot of guys are
switching to fine sands because they
think that it's going to give them a
firmer surface. But if you look across
the sand size uh category in the middle
there, um you don't see you don't see
any differences at all really. Uh we so
that surprised us. Um I guess you do see
the GS3 ball picked up on
um uh the fine sand actually being
softer, but the other four devices
didn't pick up any difference at all.
So, one of the things was like, well,
these different these devices are doing
different things. They're showing us
different things. So, which one should
we do? And I don't have a great answer
for that. Um, but basically what we're
finding is a lot of these decisions
didn't matter. You see tiny differences
here, but the amount of sand you put
down, some devices you saw small
differences, other devices you saw
nothing at all. uh the frequency the s
like very very few of these decisions
influenced firmness which was surprising
to us. And so the other surprising
thing, Doug, and I don't have the the
organic matter, or maybe I do in the
next slide. I'm not sure if I do, Frank,
but you definitely saw the organic
matter. I I don't have the 100%. Yeah.
And the top one. Yeah. Talk about that,
Doug. Yeah. Basically, the the only
thing that mattered. So quality didn't
matter or I mean the these things didn't
affect quality, didn't affect growth, it
didn't affect ball roll speed, tiny
differences in firmness. So the only
thing that really showed up was that
these decisions do affect the amount of
organic matter in your top inch. And
when we did when we put down the least
amount of sand, we had the most amount
of organic matter. So you would have
thought, hey, that's going to be a
softer green. Not really. Um when we put
down the most sand, we got the least
amount of organic matter. That's going
to be firmst. No, not really. And that
the the USGA is the most amount of sand
and the pace turf is the least amount of
sand. So you can kind of scan across
there and see uh and look for those
differences. And and Doug, the relative
amounts of sand were pretty different.
So that USJ was something like I don't
know 20 per cubic feet per thousand and
the the Micah Woods method was like a
third of that, right? Yeah. The USGA
method which is uh was about like 20 25
26 cubic feet per thousand and the pace
turf was 14 and the woods was in
between. So basically twice as much sand
uh from USGA to to PACE and then the
woods was kind of in the middle
and that's a clipping volume way. So we
thought hey people are collecting
clipping volumes why don't we match up
sand with clipping volume production
makes a lot of sense and it's cool that
it that it fell right in the middle
there. Uh but in terms of the biggest
differences between the amount of sand,
it would be USGA versus PACE, which is a
climate based method. And USGA is just
kind of, hey, every every month, every
three weeks, go out and put this amount
of sand on regardless.
So, let's uh let's review the evidence
here, Carl. I just want to make sure we
don't we're not missing the lead. Uh and
I want to take apart two things, three
things. One is when you say fine sand,
you mean it it meets USGA
specifications, it does not meet USGA.
No, it's it's it's it's kind of like the
sand they're using at Ruckers where it's
uh it's got more fine uh sand than than
allowed, but it's not like grossly out
of spec. Okay. So, it's the stuff Jim
Murphy's been saying, "Yeah, this stuff
is fine. It doesn't have a negative
impact on on turf." And it just it's the
the higher fines helps the sand get into
the canopy of these more dense newer
cultivars. Okay, deal. But the theory
was that's also potentially going to
make it firmer.
Yeah. Yeah. And it did not. It Yeah.
Well, I mean it did, I guess, with uh
No, it didn't at all, actually. And And
you know, you thought, well, what what
does a fine sand do? It holds more
water. Um, but the difference wasn't
related to water content either. So,
we're just And the co the coefficient of
uniformity, which is kind of the higher
the CU, the firmer it is. That fine sand
had a higher CU. I can't remember the
exact number. I think it was like 2.5
versus the standard sand, which was a
two. Everything was pointing to this
fine sand should should make it uh more
firm, but it didn't happen. And what my
theory on this is like it's more about
the plant growth characteristics. you
know, the sand matters if there's not a
not a lot of uh roots or turf on top,
but once that stuff gets involved, I
think the the root zone makes less of a
difference. But I don't know, we got
more, you know, we got more to this is
just one situation. So, so and the other
thing be before before we leave this
slide is Doug, could you take a minute
because you did a separate study where
you looked at how these different
devices correlate to either uh surface
organic matter or soil moisture as I
recall. Could you review for the folks
watching and listening roughly, you
know, you've got a cle, you've got a
true firm, you've got the PGA method
where you drop a ball bearing and
measure the dimple depth and then you
got GS3. Oh yeah. Um, so it was it was
all the data from this study and we b we
just looked at the correlation between
the other measurements we had and so we
saw and I'm and I don't have the slide
in front of me and I'm not going to you
know I'm just going to talk in general
the heavier devices so that'd be like
the big cle and the ball drop um the
ones that put more force uh tended to be
better related to the soil moisture and
then the lighter drops which would be
the like the true firm the little clay
leg, the GS3 ball, uh, tended to be more
correlated with surface organic matter
and turf grass quality and things like
that, which kind of makes sense to me.
Those heavy drops are getting down into
the deeper in the root zone. The lighter
drops are measuring more the grass
surface. Okay. So thinking about what
they measure and thinking about what you
found
here, your theory is that the plant the
the soil moisture which also includes
the
plant is not as maybe you know I'm
trying to figure out how once the plant
gets involved it's absorbing most of
what we're measuring.
Yeah. Oh, I mean, think about when
you're as you're putting force down on
the surface, the first thing the ball
hits is the grass and the thatch, right?
And then if it gets through that, it
starts to be absorbed by the soil and
the soil strength is is influenced by
the moisture of it. That's right. So, if
you do a real light drop, it really
doesn't have a chance. It the the grass
and the thatch absorb it all. You do a
real heavy drop, you still get the grass
thatch interacting, but it then it
pushes down and maybe you get a signal
into the soil moisture. Okay. Um All
right, Carl. Well, you're going to ask
him
about action. Yeah, I Well, no. Now I
want to ask you about the organic matter
model. So, it the funniest part about
this research is you would have
predicted firmness goes up with more
sand. Wrong. But what you were able to
predict like very accurately was how
organic matter changed over three years
uh with just this model that has been
sort of sitting around. Can you talk
about like this Ohio State organic
matter model and and and how is it so
good? What do you what do you even put
into it to get it so good? Yeah. Well, I
didn't do any Ed McCoy at Ohio State
built this with uh Jeff Broadbelt of Dry
Jacks and so give those guys 100% of the
credit all and I think they made me
aware of it. Um this is probably six,
seven years ago. Yeah, we built it into
Greenkeeper. Um and it's it's an Excel
spreadsheet and that's how when I go
around uh and talk about this to people,
I just show the Excel spreadsheet and
can I do that now? Can I show my screen?
Yeah, 100%. Is that okay? 100%. And
basically what you uh
um what you see with
it
is and it's kind of complicated. So I'll
walk you through it, but it's based on
temperature. Organic matter builds up
and in cold environments because it
doesn't break down as fast. So it's a
story about accumulation and decay. So
the blue line here, this is this is
Madison, Wisconsin. And I just put in
the weather data, the or the climate
data for Madison. So here's how average
high is 26° in January. Average low is
11. You just go down the line, you enter
your average high and your average low
in Fahrenheit. And then it shows you
here's how your organic matter
accumulates. That's the grass roots
growing. And here's how it breaks down
by the soil microbes. And that's all a
temperature thing. Okay. So now um and
then you know if we grew a warm season
grass in
Madison, I wouldn't have to worry about
managing organic matter because my decay
is higher than my accumulation. I also
wouldn't have to worry about having a
job at a golf course because warm
seasoned grasses don't grow, right? So
you have to tell tell what type of grass
you're growing. So of course we're all
cool season people
here. And now let's go to that's
Madison. Let's go to Lake Placid. You
just grab the average highs and lows in
Lake Placid. And so you just look at the
VA factors here. For accumulation, we're
about one. And for decay, we peak around
6. So what's Lake Placid going to look
like? Very different. So peaks around
one. You get a little less accumulation
because it's cooler there in June and
September than Madison. And you get way
less decay. So th this is your
accumulation of organic matter. You got
you got problems up in Lake Placid with
and you know everybody knows that. I've
been up there to Lake Placid and seen
the thatch on the fairways. It's not
because the the managers are unskilled
or they're doing something wrong. It's
because they just have a massive amount
of accumulation. Now let's go to Beth
Page down on Long Island.
Obviously very different climate, but
again when people talk about growing
grass, you know, New York, it's all the
same, right? Look how different that is.
Wow. You're accumulating and you're
accumulating different patterns. Your
decay is you're getting you're matching
your decay with your accumulation in in
July and August. So nothing's happening
there. And you get the spring and fall
accumulation patterns. Um so does that
do you think that we should be just top
dressing everything and airifying
everything the same in New York because
it's New York cool season gr? No,
absolutely not. So that's the value of
this model. Now you can go you enter
your organic matter contents here maybe
5% at the surface two and a half one and
a half you have to you have to send
these into a lab and this follows the
USGA's kind of you know organic matter
246 Michael Woods has been promoting I
won't spend too much time on that but
once you enter organic matter if you
have your climate then it predicts what
your organic matter is going to look
like for the next five years uh based on
your top dressing. So here at soil
organic matter in the top inch here at
Beth Page you can see it's slowly
increasing and that's based on these top
dressing aeration
uh events that we have. So if you look
over here it says uh top dressings. So
if right now I put everything to zero.
So no top dressing, no drying, no hollow
time, no solid time, no deep furry
cutting. Now we're going to go back down
and see what happens. So if you stop
doing everything down at Beth Page,
you're going to start at 5%, that's
where we are today, and then five years
later, 60 months, you're going to be at
10%. Not good, right? So we have to we
can use this model to say how much stuff
do we need to do to keep our grass
around 5%. Now, one of the questions we
don't know is, is 5% good? What about
six? What about four? I'm just saying,
hey, five is kind of normal, so we're
going to start there and then we can add
these top dressings. So maybe you top
dress once a month. Oops, use the wrong
uh wrong one. We top dress once a month
starting in May, June, July, August,
September, and maybe we do a holotine
event. I'm sorry, do a holotine event in
October. And that includes the surface
top dressing. That's in the fine print
of this model. Let's go back and see how
that did. Oh, we're still going up. Now,
I don't know. Maybe again, like I'm not
saying six and a half percent's bad, but
we might have to be more aggressive than
that. Maybe we put in uh two top
dressings a month early in the
season. Do something like that. And we
go down and Oh, wait. That's too
aggressive. No, we can back off on this,
right? Let's Let's just uh let's get rid
of uh get rid of that one. Let's get rid
of that one. It's a planning tool. Yeah,
still going down, right? And for all the
guys who have to schedule out like, you
know, member guests and men's leagues
and women, you know, like by month, this
is like a really effective tool to
communicate either, hey, if we don't do
this, it's going to go up or hey, maybe
we can get rid of some of these, you
know, three of these hollow tine events
a year and can still maintain. It's uh
and because it's so accurate in your
data, like we're talking less than
0.05%.1.
Yeah. Well, right. So the so the thing
I'll say about that is you know when I
show this off like great it's a model
you know could be completely wrong right
you're just showing me dots so when we
tested it we did this study for three or
four years and we started at the start
and we entered our top dressing it was
like exactly on like dead on and we're
like even I didn't expect that I'm like
oh it's going to be close or something
but I mean if you go I'll stop sharing
here well let me do one more thing
before I do that let's go so now look at
these
operations this is Beth page, right? So,
we got one top dressing in May, two in
June. We'll put this back on down to
one, and you know, it's going down. So,
we start at five, and by the end of five
years, if we're that aggressive, we're
just above four. Now, we're going to go
back and we're going to change that to
Lake Placid.
Yeah. And so, same operations, different
climate. And we're going to go back
here. And it's even it goes down even
harder. Now we're down at three and a
half. So even though those accumulation
patterns were uh those graphs were
different, you can see you're probably
not top dressed in May in Lake Placid
and maybe do one
here. Um and maybe get rid of the
September one. We go down and now we're
at four now. So totally different stuff
and it's pretty accurate. I love it as a
planning tool and an educational tool.
The other thing I I like I learned about
it is nothing happens below one inch.
Yeah. Why are we air frying down three
inches? I'm not Oh my goodness. Oh my
goodness. It's 10:30 and if you start
that now, we're going to be here for
another hour and I didn't even get to
growth and traffic as a traffic as a
growth regulator and then looking at
fertility. But we are at it. And if you
wanted to know about top dressing and
measuring firmness, I guess I'll ask
this one question, Doug, and then we'll
let you
go. It if you use that tool and you're
looking at organic matter, you just told
me it sort of doesn't even matter how I
supply this sand. Uh if I supply enough,
right? Enough. It's like the MLS. It's
it's enough. More isn't better. Uh there
seems to be a sweet spot. This is
something that's going to take us years
to figure out, but you're really saying
you can, as Carl said, you can design
your top dressing program around your
events and not inconvenience people if
you just have to get a certain amount
out based on your planning. It gives you
more flexibility. Yeah. And then and the
big picture takeaway was the the
aggressive the USGA method brought our
organic matter to 4%. The cut that in
half, we were at 6%. couldn't tell a
difference. If you're gonna if you're a
superintendent, you're going to pick
one. You're going to put half the sand
down 100%. You know, so what we we need
to find is where what's too much? 6% was
great. How about seven? How about eight?
You know, that's that's what we really
need to to figure out is where those
thresholds lie. So great. All right,
Doug. Thanks very much, Carl. Glad you
could join us, Carl. Just made it in
time to get the modeling stuff that I
Thanks everybody. We'll talk to you next
week. Yeah. See you everybody. Thanks.
Take care. This has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu.