this is a production of Cornell
University this is Anu rangarajan I am
the director of the small farm program
and I'm really excited to share with you
more about uh the program the kinds of
things that we do um and help you
understand a little bit more about the
way we sort of present ourselves in the
world but that's it's led to a little
bit of confusion so I'm hoping I can
clarify it so I just wanted to
uh give you
first I'm just trying to advance my
slides there we are um uh tell you about
the program itself and where we sit we
are in the College of agon Life Sciences
um our funding comes primarily through
small grants and large grants from the
USDA uh and we are supported um in part
uh with some funds from the college and
through Smith lever um what our goal is
and we were started in
2001 because at that time around the
country there was a tremendous um cry
out for greater attention to the needs
of small farmers uh this emerged from uh
the famous pford case in which USDA was
sued for not addressing the needs of
black farmers in the south so they
committed funding uh to develop small
farm programs across the country and
that is it's from there that the small
farm program was started I joined the
program as the Director in 2004 and have
totally enjoyed myself uh we have a
really great staff that I'll introduce
you to over the process of our call our
um webinar today but share with you
really the kinds of work that um we're
trying to do to enhance the viability of
small farms in New York the Northeast
and in fact now we're working nationally
so I think our strengths are really best
defined um through the way in which we
try to identify critical issues that are
affecting small farms and their
viability and then how we develop
collaborations to address those issues
uh we are uh always thinking about the
types of Publications or information
resources that will support small farm
development whether you are just
thinking about farming all the way to
where you've been farming for 20 years
and you're thinking you may want to rest
strategize your business or add new
Commodities uh we try to serve all those
Farms either from uh initial startup all
the way to when they're optimizing their
performance to developing a mature Farm
business so we are doing a lot of things
um at all of those points uh but I think
we're probably most known for our
beginning farmer support and so I'll be
sharing with you stuff about that but we
do um uh have a network of Educators in
across the state that have committed to
supporting small farm and new farm
development and in every County of the
state we have one individual who's
identified and I'm not sure um if any of
you are those folks but I would
encourage you to find out who because we
do send resources out to them and they
those Educators May in either in your
county or surrounding counties have
other resources locally to share around
small farm
development
so um I just thought I would back up and
tell you what is a small farm and uh the
USD da defines that as a farm that has a
gross annual revenue of less than
250,000 a year this number some people
are pushing on it thinking it should be
closer to 350 but this is where we're at
right now and you should know that 90%
of the farms in the country and in fact
in New York fit this
definition uh the most rapid growth in
farms at this point are those Farms that
are very small that may be grow seeing
less than $25,000 a year and this is
from the sort of energy that's been
focused on developing new Farms but
there's a lot of people and probably
many of the people that you work with
who um are really um just growing
something on a fairly small area and
selling it very locally and
supplementing their family income and
their own family food security so we are
thrilled and excited to help anyone who
wants to identify themselves as a farmer
and frankly the more people who call
themselves a farmer the better in my
book so um what we have observed that
you know most our farmers are really
diverse they are often Diversified
Vegetable Farms are Diversified across
um Enterprises so they may have mixes of
vegetables and poultry or beef and fruit
uh any combination honey um uh maple
syrup uh we have folks doing small scale
value added there's a huge diversity and
and I think a really optimistic and
positive sense of possibilities in our
small farm
sector so um a little bit more from uh
the people that we actually are able to
reach we have uh serve and I'll show you
how to join that where we share updates
every two weeks on important resources
or information that are of interest to
small
producers um but when we recently uh we
did a survey because we were trying to
understand more for example about where
do small farmers actually sell their
products and um I'm really sharing this
just again to drive home the point that
um when you look at the farm size they
are a majority of them are below 50
acres um and then even um the highest
percent of the people that answered our
call for information were farming less
than 5 acres and this again may be many
people you know and you work with and
again that gross revenue quite low um
the majority of the people that are
accessing and sort of communicating with
us um are making less than 25,000 a year
we do have Farms that are making more
than 250,000 a year uh and so while USDA
may not call them small um uh I think
that we create a home for them and I
tend to use a much more flexible
definition of what's a small farm and I
tell people that if you think you're a
small farm you are and the reason I say
that is it's really contextual and it's
a lot based on your community the people
you interact with and where you go to
sort of find your um colleagues and so
we have some f farms for example that
may participate in a lot of our
programming that make well over 250,000
but they align with the values and the
sort of energy of the small farm
movement um Enterprises based on some uh
uh surveys that we've done recently
really focus heavily on poultry and
vegetables um again if you were even
thinking about starting a small farm
these are the easiest entry points as
well um the least amount of capital
required for getting into uh production
at a more commercial level um uh we tell
people at least $10,000 and some leased
land and you can and well- drained soil
ideally you can start a vegetable
operation um so uh this is just again to
give you a sense of where we're seeing
the energy and the sort of growth across
the state the majority of our Farms have
not been in business for that long and
this is part of a result of our new Farm
project which has been really out there
and recruiting people into the program
but over 60% of the people that we are
reaching are have been farming for less
than 10 years um but we do have quite a
few that are what we call the sort of
mature Farms over 15 years in
production that just uh really um I
wanted to just give you a little bit of
background on who we've been serving
traditionally and we know that that's
changing um and so we're developing
resources to address some of the changes
in that audience so I and the way that
um Lori and Jen had shared with me some
of your interest is that there may be
individuals you work with that um really
would love to scale up a little bit and
maybe add some income to their home and
or their youth and want to start some
kind of a business and experience what
that is to be an entrepreneur and I
think there's a tremendous amount of
energy um an excitement in the small
farm sector for entrepreneurs we know
for example that um the interest in
Local Foods is growing and that uh
there's a demand for uh farm products
and direct sales uh every year it
grows ideally we could dream of 25% of
all of our food being sourced locally in
time in Tomkins County we've achieve
that actually um uh but we when we think
about the rest of the country there's a
lot of challenges with that but we still
keep working towards it in New York
state um there's a growing number of
csas in farmers markets I'm sure you're
all familiar with these um but one thing
that we've faced with these is
um um is
that just a
second
um uh that there's some saturation
happening in these markets uh and so uh
we have found that some of our producers
are really interested in um new
wholesale markets that are sort of like
direct marketing but you're going direct
to a wholesale um institution so food
hubs are an example of that some
institutions are really interested in
buying uh direct uh groceries like
Wegman's and others and the Independent
Grocers are starting to enter the scene
of rying to provide easy to access
wholesale markets um and then rest rests
which have been a stronghold for many of
our small producers and so we see that
for entrepreneurs not only developing in
and creating products for direct markets
but also thinking about diversifying
their markets to include wholesale and
different sorts of strategies primarily
to manage risk and to ensure uh some
more Farm
security so a lot of our work and I'll
share with you some resources that are
emerging um to
support um
uh both uh the direct markets but really
the wholesale Market Readiness so here
is a list of different things I want to
share with you and I'm going to do this
primarily by doing a tour of the website
because if you haven't been to our
website it can be a little bit daunting
um because it there's a lot of
information there but I wanted to share
with you what I felt are really
important uh resources that you may need
to know
about um uh that can support your work
and and I'm hoping that uh We've
designed these really to help Educators
across the state um get Farms to do some
of the work on their own before they
start taking up a lot of your time so
keep that in mind we're trying to help
with designing materials that help you
be more efficient to give you easy to
access resources that you can share with
these new Farmers or small farms that
might come to you but then also we want
to hear from you what you feel our res
resources that you need um going forward
because that's where I think we can do a
lot to support your work so um I'm going
to shift now
to um uh the website and I hope you can
see this uh can everyone see this
website if you can yep all right
great thank you so um the first thing to
note uh at our homepage and you can see
it's small farms. cornell.edu um is we
feature events that are coming up across
the state and so these events for
example co-managing Farm stewardship
with food safety gaps in conservation um
this is a resource for example that's
been released um microloans um grazing
methods um uh and opportunity for
learning these are some events or
activities that we want people to know
about um I on this page I wanted to
point out to you um uh the strategy to
join um our list and so down here in the
corner it says sign up for the E newss
and we really encourage folks to sign
into this e newss um using this uh
template um we have a few questions we
like to know and I can even try to
extract from you the number of people
who are gardeners or home homesteaders
or aspiring Farmers that have been
subscribing to us if there was any
interest from you to know who that in
your own county is already um
interfacing with us um we also are
always really deeply interested and
committed to enhancing the diversity of
our audience and so we really ask and
hope that people can share with us uh
more about um uh their own backgrounds
and uh we are recently working really
hard to create create supportive
strategies for military veterans to come
into agriculture so we ask about um if
they can self-identify as a veteran and
I'll share more about that so um again
um from the homepage across the top
there's a whole bunch of buttons here um
and I'm going to probe a few of those
I'm going to probe the quarterly a
little bit um share with you some more
about projects and
resources so um if we go if you go into
the resource tab you will find um some
of our most popular
guides and the first one I want to show
you is this guide to farming in New York
and we developed this years ago and this
is been one of our Flagship Publications
um from the guide to farming in New York
um if you get calls from individuals who
are either interested in farming or have
more questions about uh business
structure strategy marketing
considerations I would encourage you to
sort of spend some time at this website
and see what you can find here um we
have resources on developing a farm uh
for example uh different structures and
the issues that they are important and
these are all designed all of these fact
sheets are designed to be either
downloaded as a full guide or um you can
use them uh
independently and so um it tells you
when we've revised it and we actually
when there's new information we revise
every summer and so we have a whole
group of authors that have helped us
with this uh to revise it so here is an
example of the fact sheet for example on
Farm Insurance which will tell you the
issues around having supplemental or
product liability insurance and um in
basically information to really make
sure that small farmers are considering
risk management and how they're going to
protect themselves and their family so
um again this is is just the guide to
farming in New York has we did print it
at one time and um I when we printed I
think we handed out over 10,000 copies
and really the excitement for this came
from established Farms not just new
Farms there is information in here that
any farmer really needs to know about
and so uh definitely explore this guide
and um hopefully you will find it
interesting and helpful in the that
you're doing uh with gardeners who may
be wanting to scale
up and so um this particular resource is
just one of um several that I think are
important for you to know about I'm
going to dig in a little bit to the
urban guide in a minute well actually
I'll just do that right now so the urban
guide to farming we use the same model
of the guide to farming in New York but
here we're focused strictly on an urban
environment and in this case the uh
topics are different some are similar
but major and we encourage people to use
the the general guide as well but here
you may have some specialized issues for
example dealing with soil contamination
so this again is printable as a fact
sheet and you can use this to share with
somebody who's really interested in um
doing Urban farming or has a concern
about soil contamination there's a
tremendous number of resources that are
linked and we're currently in the middle
of doing a complete update of the guide
and adding a few nor more sections uh
the sections that we want to add are um
uh focused in on mushrooms and Agro
forestry as well as some more dive down
into Hydroponics and and these new sort
of vertical farming strategies that
everybody seems to be excited
about um so that's a bit more about the
two guides to farming these other
resources are um the on Farm if you have
people doing poultry this on Farm
poultry Slaughter this was driven by a
liability insurance issue where a bunch
of farmers were calling us and saying
they do not they're getting cancelled
from insurance policies and that was a
big concern to us so we acted very
quickly to respond to that working with
insurance companies to create what we
felt were guidelines to support Safe
Handling on farms for poultry Slaughter
um and because there's an exemption
under a thousand Birds we want to make
sure that people are are really um if
they're doing it on farm that they're
considering all of the components of uh
setting up a good system that's both
efficient for them for labor and safe
for the quality of the birds they're
producing um there's an online course
that complements this and Lyn Biven has
been a real leader for us and she's out
in Western New York and an extension
educator another important guide
um is the guide to direct farming of
livestock and poultry now this is a this
is a guide that's a little bit outdated
but Martha and Tatiana have agreed to
help us with updating this and so we're
hoping that this coming summer we can
actually update the guide but this has
probably been one of our most
popular um uh resources that we've
produced because there's so many
questions around both slaughterhouses
and processing um regulations and then
how to handle and direct Market poultry
and livestock so I wanted to make sure
you knew about
that um and so that really gives you um
a few of the overviews um as far as
timely information it really is um uh
through
um I'm sorry I'm trying to get to the
page
here um it's through our um
uh small our our our update and so
please do sign up for the update these
are every two weeks and if you haven't
been receiving them but there's a ton of
resources that we both share on our
website home page uh but we also have
these inside
um uh in the updates that are come as an
email I'm trying to
um remember I think um here is the list
of the archives under our news button
and so you can see for example if you
open up one uh the one that happened
last the most recent one one of our
recent ones it tells you uh both
different things to be happening um at
Cornell different announcements and then
events that people should know about and
then uh some job opportunities we get a
lot of people sharing job opportunities
with us and then grants and so this is
our way of trying to provide timely
information to individuals who um uh you
know people that are developing their
Farms looking for
support so um again I really do
encourage you to join and get the the uh
update the other Flagship publication
for us is our small farm quarterly and
so this is a quarterly magazine and I'm
not sure if any of you have ever written
for it but we would welcome submissions
because our editorial team is made up of
mostly you Educators from around the
state who help us um and they provide
articles or they recruit writers for the
Articles um this is an entirely
volunteer publication um we're lucky to
have a nice partnership with uh Le
Publications who put out country folks
and so we generate all of the content
and they do the printing and um put it
in uh to the country folks as an insert
so it goes to over 30,000 families
across the Northeast um but what's
exciting here is that you know anywhere
in our website you can search a topic so
for example if if you were interested in
grazing you could hit that and what it
would do is basically give you a list of
a bunch of the different articles um uh
that we have uh both on in the quarterly
historically uh this top one is about um
uh grazing online course which I'll tell
you about a little bit more um you can
just click on it it will pop you to the
article that was written by Nancy Glazer
educator in Western New York talking
about um renting grazing land and so
this was originally published in the
quarterly but we want to make sure that
all of these are available for folks
going forward and then you can see here
in that same issue there was a whole
bunch of other articles that may be of
interest to
you um
so uh I think let me just double check
here so over time um we have always
struggled because as I've described uh
small farms are really diverse and uh
how do you pick where to sort of focus
your efforts and trying to support the
development of such a diverse sector of
our farm our farm fing culture so um
because of that what we have done every
other year is we host what we call a
small farm Summit and that Summit uh we
recruit broadly across the state using a
webinar type format and so we'll have up
to seven or eight sites around the state
where we ask producers to gather along
with those interested in their success
so Educators uh we get members of
different nonprofits uh Soil and Water
and our CS uh all sorts of folks would
Gather in these different locations and
then what we try to do is really focus
on helping them help asking them to help
us
prioritize uh the directions that a
program like this should take and we ask
them to gather in regions because it's
really important to us that we're always
cultivating uh regionally strong
collaboration and so but getting people
into the room is so much more important
I think than anything that we do um and
that's the hardest thing in our culture
now is to actually have people feel like
they develop meaningful relationship so
we have uh intentionally designed the
summit even though it's only every two
years we're hoping that we can um uh
really uh help people connect with those
around them that can
help we in 2012 we at we actually had a
survey and we had over 700 small Farmers
respond to help us prioritize where they
thought uh are the real opportunities to
enhance the viability of small farms and
the top five that came out of that was
distribution to reach local
markets um uh figuring out how to do
this how to help small producers no
matter the scale actually get themselves
into local and Regional markets more
effectively and more
efficiently uh economic impact of small
farms on communities this is like a huge
huge question uh we have all these small
farms and um that are supporting local
food and hiring local kids and and what
is the impact of them on their farms and
interesting I found it really
interesting that this was the second
priority from a farm
community uh helping deal with livestock
processing issues how do we identify
where they should be and who and how do
we expand or improve our access to those
processing facilities financing and then
greater invest investment in research
and extension and other services so this
is just giving you a flavor of the kinds
of information we get when we ask
farmers where should we
focus but the but one of the things that
I found really interesting is we asked
Farm uh small farmers you know where do
they see themselves going in two years
as far as the new ways they want to
Market and what I want to highlight is
this growth and interest in
wholesale and in two years a bunch
currently the major maity of our farmers
are using Farm stands or farm markets
and
csas um and all of these ups as their
primary direct channels in the way that
they share their products but um this
idea of selling to restaurants and food
hubs and
groceries uh has really um been
interesting and exciting and we have
some very small producers in the state
who are doing this and and finding that
they're being really successful
so one of the things that we've done as
a program is invest in developing a
curriculum to treat to help new
producers or existing Farmers become
more wholesale Market ready and we're
rolling this out on April 18th and 19th
it's a two-day inservice your colleagues
are the instructors we have folks from
across the state that have worked with
us uh to develop this and uh Violet
Stone in our program has been leading
this effort and the the materials will
help producers make decisions on how to
shift to a wholesale Market how do they
match their production to the demands of
these markets um what's the culture
among these different types of markets
and then how do we figure out how to
work together and Foster these
opportunities in within regions so
that's just really more of a teaser and
something I want you to be aware of this
is a professional development
opportunity the people that we want to
have attend are people like you
Educators around the state who may be
getting these kinds of questions or
anticipate that it may become a bigger
part of their
work so uh just to put that in mind um
as you uh in your planning and if it's
something that's of interest to you so
what I'd like to do now is go back again
to our website and share um a couple of
more uh res sources so uh this is that
wholesale marketing piece uh baskets to
pallets preparing small and midsize
Farms enter food hubs cooperatives
restaurants and groceries um and so this
is the basis of it we do have a
wholesale market watch and a list serve
that you can sign up and we share
information about that we've also had a
series of webinars that if you're really
curious about understanding what small
farms are interested in this I would
encourage you to go and take a look at
some of these webinars where different
Farmers have shared with us their
transition from direct to wholesale and
you would be surprised how small some of
these Farms
are um and so we have a big group of
folks and this is the group of your
colleagues that have been helping to
write this curriculum so uh stay tuned
uh I hope it's something that you would
might be interested in going
forward so there's a few other uh things
that are happen at the program and
um uh What uh are other areas that I
can't really dig into with you right now
um but I just wanted you to know about
our we have a whole new effort focused
on helping farmers who are interested in
grazing um and so we have a grazing
initiative um and we also have a program
that's focused quite heavily on tillage
and soil Health Management for small
producers
so those are two um projects that are
really specific and really focus on a
particular sector and we do take these
things on
periodically I want to focus in on the
um uh our beginning farmer project the
Northeast beginning farmer project so um
this actually emerged from all of you uh
in 2006 we kept getting
uh we started having conversations with
Educators that we were connected with
and and uh and they kept saying you know
I cannot believe the number of people
coming to me with the interest in
starting a farm and I don't know how to
respond and then what we observed is
that everybody around the state was so
busy creating their own curricula and
trying to put together their own
materials and it seemed like a kind of a
crazy waste of a lot of people's time to
not have a centralized resource and so
that's when we really brought together a
team of Educators and created the
beginning farmer project our vision is
that every new farmer in New York has
access to the support information and
training they need to be successful like
that's our mission and we wanted to be
that anyone who wants to farm regardless
of where they're at can do this and have
people that can help them with it so um
uh in order to do that what we have
really done and worked really hard as I
mentioned is create
um small farm and beginning farmer
contacts within every CCE office around
the state and we are welcome to add you
to our list online of references at our
homepage there's a who can help Tab and
uh you can and we are happy to make sure
that you're listed there we've also in
our work cultivated a network of
organizations in New York and the
Northeast that specifically support New
farmers so it's not just extension
Educators that are out there doing this
work we have a a bunch of nonprofits we
have incubator Farms we have all sorts
of people that are really passionate
about helping people start farming um
and so what we try to do um through the
small farm program is professional
development for those
individuals to try to make sure that uh
the Educators and those that are
supporting earm development really have
connection to the best resources
information materials to make their jobs
easier so we really do see ourselves
both as we provide information and
resources directly to new producers but
then we want to cultivate a learning
community among the Educators that are
working in this area and so we have met
annually we call it the beginning
farming Learning Network and we usually
meet at the Sentry house around uh end
of October uh up in Albany because
that's actually 6 hours from everywhere
in the Northeast believe it or not and
so we uh have do um an inservice
training and I think I don't know if any
of you have been there um but uh it's
actually usually a really Dynamic and uh
fun Gathering where we're learning from
each other how to do this
work so um uh I'm just going to review
with you just quickly um some of the
offerings we have online courses these
are six week non-credit classes and we
have currently uh I think we're up to 17
classes we've had over 1300 people go
into these classes and uh uh 42% report
increasing their own Revenue in their
Farm after taking these classes and so
these are again facilitated primarily by
extension Educators who have developed a
passion for working with new farms uh
the the model that we're using is that
um people are paying for these and we're
paying Educators to help teach them um
and then it also covers them uh the
administrative management which is a ton
of administrative stuff that has to
happen behind the scenes with this for
Erica frene and um so she's been our
real um uh Shepherd for the online
courses one of our staff members uh but
we are always looking for new
instructors so just so you know that um
uh and then I'm going to take you on a
tour of uh some of our res resources on
the website um and so let me do that
right
now
um there we are
so the uh um this Pro this website
currently is separate from the small
farm program website and that's caused
some confusion the reason we created a
separate website was partly because some
of our funding we needed to have a place
to keep a lot of materials um but it
also it it has had such an energy and
drive the development of the uh
beginning farmer project and the tools
and the resources that it was a lot to
manage but I do want to give you the
heads up that we are imagining bringing
the two sites back together going
forward because a lot of the new Farms
that we've been cultivating are actually
hitting the point where they really are
more established and are going to need a
different kind of support so we are
tooling up for
that so um one of the things that uh I
just realized that I
cannot get past this little sharing my
monitor screen okay
so um I think that this question about
where do you start um well I guess
there's getting started so um these what
we have created is um this um section
called plan your farm and so this portal
and basically collection of resources is
really there to help someone who wants
to work on their own start to get into
uh thinking about is farming for me uh
what Commodities do I want to do how am
I going to do the planning uh for this
farm so it's a whole series of
worksheets that you can do with somebody
or you can send them there and say just
um start to do your own thinking and
planning and it's done using a sort of
question narrative where people can
actually go through and get some
guidance as to how to narrow down um
what do I need to know how do I finance
it or can I get a grant um and so uh
these are structured as
tutorials so for example in this
tutorial on goals and skills what's
really interesting is we complement both
the written material with videos of
farmers and New farmers around the
around the state who really have been
able to clearly
articulate um some of the um uh issues
and the strategies that have helped them
be
successful and so the I would definitely
send somebody to this planning your farm
Hub as a place to get started um and one
of the challenges I think that all of
you may face is people you know they
want someone to sometimes hold their
hand and I would encourage you to push
back and say show me what you can do and
they yeah they totally I just see a
comment from Jen that they want us to do
it and and it's um and I think that uh
you know farming as an entrepreneur is
an individualized action and starting
with information um and uh giving them
we're hoping this portal helps you say
look dig this is your project here's
where you get started and hopefully you
can use some of these um you can point
people to some of these resources that
I've shared with you to help them start
thinking about farming but what we know
is you know doing this kind of stuff
online is really um uh in some ways for
a certain kind of learner and we know we
have lots of different Learners and we
have some people that just don't even
want to do online teaching and so we um
have encouraged and support and worked
with a network of uh Educators around
the state who do these so you want to
farm type workshops and if you haven't
done one of those or you're interested I
would encourage you to go to the who can
help tab here and I and if you don't
know who else is doing it in your area
but I bet you could find somebody
locally if you're not aware of them who
is doing these types of trainings within
a several County area so um don't start
from scratch don't feel like you have to
do this yourself and if you aren't able
to find someone just send us a note give
uh send me or Erica an email and we will
try to connect you with people who can
help you um figure out how to address
this
need so um uh so these worksheets are
really meant to be a self-guided uh
process for planning uh a farm startup
but I what's become our real Flagship is
our online
courses and so we have a a whole a bunch
of online courses and we're actually
going to be restructuring the way we
present them because there's it's a bit
overwhelming and people are telling us
like I don't know which to take first
and I don't know how to approach it but
none of these have prere requisites
they're six week uh
facilitated um uh courses that help you
understand all the aspects of getting
into farming square one one of our most
popular classes is the very first class
like is farming for me you know uh what
are your own motivations um what
resources do you have um what might fit
you as far as an Enterprise these are
the kinds of questions that are
addressed in square one and and it could
be a place where you direct people who
come to like I I'm thinking I'd like to
start a farm it's like go do this think
uh go through the process take this
course um and then uh let's talk after
that and so again it's not about uh
dismissing them but trying to help them
help themselves and so we've uh
structured these classes to be
interactive um there's a tremendous
number of resources that people have
access to uh there's often two people
that are
teaching uh together um there's some
Basics about H how this class is
structured um uh one of our new classes
um that keeps filling up and it's really
interesting is Farm scale mushroom
cultivation and Steve Gabriel who's on
our staff now um has been teaching this
and every time he he's offered it twice
and and it fills up each time 50 people
and there's a waiting list so um there's
a lot of excitement and interest in
something like mushrooms um and whether
they're growing it on logs or they're
using other enterpr other strategies
with bags um this is a a class that um
if you're it's an unusual class and it's
an unusual crop uh but we do find a lot
of interest so I wanted to make sure you
were aware of
that so part another part of um the uh
online courses and something that's been
really helpful I'm just trying to find
um is our voices of experience
videos and so um again another way of
helping people learn is by is by
learning
stories uh is by um uh seeing stories
and learning from other farmers and so
we started building this video
collection in 2008 I believe and we had
some funding from USDA as well as from
Farm viability to do this and we have a
whole collection of videos on our
YouTube channel so uh it's YouTube
Cornell small farms and for
example um there's I'm not sure if you
can hear this or not but here's one from
Black
Diamond uh these videos
are uh some of them have been like this
one on cting pigs I can't believe how
many people have watched this
and so um but um these are some Farms
that are in and around itha um uh but
they represent really Diversified farms
and they represent different
perspectives on how how to do the work
and so they include um videos about the
farmer themselves sort of how they
approach different activities how they
may market and then we have a couple of
new ones at the bottom on draft horses
Don Hughes who's here uh locally has
started the draft animal power uh dap
Network and has been committed to draft
animal work and we are seeing more and
more people expressing interest in draft
animals so we wanted to connect them to
that so there are so many videos that
organized different ways um here's just
a an there's um I can't even remember
how many videos we have on here now um
but there's different projects as well
um and different videos that we've
brought in for example we have a video
here on Farm Service Agency
microloans um because there's a lot of
people that are interested in that
program to start a small operation so
understanding what the issues are um
we've also had um a program for
educators uh that was focused on
cultural competency for new farm
development and we heard from two uh uh
leaders um uh two individuals who are
leading uh local nonprofits uh small
nonprofits um and how they're addressing
issues of diversity in their programming
and what were some of the challenges
that they faced um in working across uh
difference so there's all sorts of
different um materials here on the
program but I um on small farm startup
as well as you know how to build hoop
houses and um uh just lots of different
things so I would encourage you to
explore the uh Video Collection um
farming in
action so I think then um the other
resources that I wanted to point you to
are again on that homepage um um if you
look across the top of the beginning
farmer project there's we've gone
through the uh tutorials the online
courses um there's uh also then um these
resources the videos the guides and then
we have these articles that come from
small farm
quarterly but we have wanted to collect
them together together in a way that's
um these articles then represent
different aspects of getting started in
farming and again another way who for
people who are interested in just
hearing stories and learn best by
stories and so these are written by A
diversity of individuals some Educators
some
farmers who um uh and then we have a lot
of profiles of New farmers here at the
bottom as well so I would again um
consider this another resource uh
to help you uh help people think through
whether or not getting into farming is
something for
them um and one other piece I haven't
really alluded to it in too much but
there is a whole bunch of
information that is buried in these
sites that we consider like the farmer's
bookshelf and these are linked sometimes
to online resources or how to find them
but I in both the beginning farmer site
as well as the Cornell small farm
program site you will find resources
tremendous numbers of resources that are
available in the case of the small farm
site this is where we really try to
focus in on uh resources for um
established Farmers for example in
production you can see that we have this
wide array of materials that have been
collected
together and so these aren't the only
materials out there but there just a few
that we felt were really good or well
done or easily accessible online again
something that you might be able to use
in your own work to share information
with individuals who come to you
directly or even to be able to forward
them to some of these resources so they
can explore on their own so it's both
the learning information but then kind
of the diagnosis and the support for
decision
making and I think that's the piece
that's critical for us is how do you
support good decisionmaking on farms and
so some of our online courses are
related directly to decision making for
example we have a course on holistic
management which is the entire framework
for decision making in which you really
consider environment economics and
social goals that you might have as an
individual or a farmer you can apply the
decision-making framework to your life
in general it doesn't have to be for
agriculture um but that's an example of
something that we feel is really
important it's not just technical
information it's really the how do you
put it all together and how do you put
it together in a way that feeds your
soul felds your feeds your energy and
really plays to your skills and so we
try to think about all of that the soft
skills development as well as the
technical skills
development um but this whole piece of
scaleup so um and I think this may be
relevant to to some of you is you know
we recognize that it's a real trick to
go from you know growing at a very small
scale and then wanting to really
actually change your practices and move
into something at a larger scale and a
more commercial scale so we do have some
Advanced Enterprise online courses that
are designed for supporting Farm
diversification um well the mushroom one
is one for example but we have a high
tunnel class that's starting um shortly
we have both vegetable and Berry produ
classes that are online to give people
the start or deepen their skill sets
around those two production systems we
have a grazing course um all of these
are meant to sort of help with the scale
up um and we're going to be adding food
safety um and even adapting to climate
change so these are some of the courses
that we're adding that are really meant
to help deal with scale up and um but uh
we our current profunding supports also
we we have funding from the USDA to help
those individuals who are maybe 3 to 5
years in and want to rest strategize and
what we're actually doing is um helping
Farms create what we call profit teams
and these are teams of Consultants uh
often extension Educators who they hire
to help them improve their own
entrepreneurship business training and
planning and help them make decisions
really important decisions to grow the
business and so we have funding each of
the Farms who participate get $2,000 as
a grant and then they have to commit 500
of their own funds so they have $2,500
to work with over 18 months to pay
people to consult with whether that's a
feed um a person to help them with their
nutrition plan if it's someone to help
them with their disease management plan
if it's about how do I improve the
quality for a wholesale Market it's up
to the farmer what we want to know is
that how they really feel and and all we
care is that they find the right people
people to help them take the business to
the next level so this is very much
one-on-one
Consulting um and then the other thing
we're doing is developing these sort of
intensive training programs that will be
um on scaling equipment this is
something that's really tricky to go
from a very small scale even to move
from sort of less than a half an acre to
one acre to 5 acres and then to 10 like
there's tend to be breaks there like um
well actually at over acres and then
over 25 acres I think there's like some
natural breaks in scale that suggest a
scaling up of equipment and what do you
pick and how do you pick it and what's
going to be most adaptable going forward
so our training programs will focus on
scaling up equipment and then the
wholesale Market Readiness which we
think diversifying markets is really
important as we move into this uh as we
see this growth in Local
Foods the the last thing I just want to
talk Al about and and um share with you
is this whole area of work that we're
doing right now focused on military
veterans and uh it's really trying to um
create Pathways for veterans to find
employment on
farms um or to um uh actually start
Farms so um I wanted to draw your
attention to it because I think that um
all of you are really um
uh out there and interfacing with a lot
of folks and we are getting more
veterans returning from service that we
are trying to help them integrate back
into community and whether it's
agriculture or gardening or farming we
know there's really meaningful benefits
to them to be involved with this kind of
physical work so I am going to just um
uh I can share more with you but I don't
I think I want to have enough time for
conversation um but we have a whole new
area of work that's developing around
supporting veterans and in this August
we're going to host a one-week intensive
that's called armed to farm for um
military veterans and it will take place
in Central New York this year it was
Western New York last year at Central
New York this year and then next year
it'll be in Eastern New York so if you
feel people you know people who might be
interested please uh let us know and pay
attention to our announcements when they
come
out so um as I start the close I want to
make sure you know the folks that can
help you in the program we have a really
awesome staff at the small farm program
uh Violet Stone who leads our wholesale
Market stuff and general
inquiries Erica who's provided
leadership to the beginning farmer
project and online courses Ryan Mar I he
has facilitated the educator Network um
and also is really focusing on soil
Health Management and creating
appropriate Technologies for small
farms uh Matt Weiss he's new to the
program uh and he's leading our current
beginning farmer Grant but also
shepherding the veterans work Steve
Gabriel who many of you might know is an
a his uh background in Agro forestry he
wrote the book Forest farming with Ken
Mudge and he's now uh joined our program
and he's provi he's being the managing
editor of the small farm quarterly and
Kathy pek who is brand new to the
program but is helping us dig more
aggressively into how do we help
cultivate local food systems and
networks for Farmers to really grow
their businesses in this
area so um I think that's really all I
wanted to share with you which is sort
of the program what we're up to
and well you can always reach out to me
or to any of the staff at the program
and just send us an email if you're
looking for something and you can't find
it this has been a production of Cornel
University on the web at cornell.edu