this is a production of Cornell
University and so yeah it is a real
pleasure to introduce Travis ritesman
for his defense um he was born and
raised in LA and so uh he and my wife
have always connected over being
Southern Californians and things like
that and
so uh but he did his uh Bachelors at UC
Riverside and and um in Biochemistry uh
got started in understanding in his
world of understanding bioinformatics
and genomics uh working with Sue wesler
uh who uh was
a incredibly important figure in all
everybody in maage genetics today but he
worked with her to start really
annotating transposable elements in the
Citrus genome and I think really started
forming his ideas on how bioinformatics
should be done how it should be shared
with the community and everything um he
then applied to Cornell got in here we
were excited to have him but he also got
a full bright all at the same time and
so he said Ed I don't want to start here
I'm GNA go to Germany so he went to
Germany for a year and worked with that
left viagel group and there he helped
develop a pipeline of automated assembly
and annotation of a rabbit office genome
that was really important for
understanding the strength and
weaknesses of graphs uh at the time um
he then joined us in
2018 um and he's going to be telling you
about his research there but as part of
that he also took some time off to work
with Google X and he's wearing his
Google X t-shirt today uh but I think
you know you'll see the there's a very
strong streak in uh Travis of both
public sector commitment but also want
to understand how industry has worked in
putting those two together he's uh going
to go back to Germany to do a postto in
bioinformatics and we'll uh you know I'm
sure he'll do great things but you know
every graduate student brings the
strengths and
weaknesses uh
to to graduate school but I what I
really want to highlight uh about Travis
is this perspective he has on science
and you know he was one of the graduate
students I would argue that has thought
more deeply about how Science and
Technology should be developed and you
know he really was asking fundamental
questions about what does it mean to
conduct an experiment you know how
should experiments be repeated how does
one share and repeat these experimental
findings and then you know what are
really the strengths and weaknesses of
public sector versus private sector uh
science and you know know I was kind of
Travis I was thinking about it last
night you're kind of like a science
philosopher okay
uh who thinks about some of these things
about how do we do science and make it
repeatable but he's also has that blue
collar perspective of getting things
done like plant breeders need to get
things done and it's that combination of
things that's been really uh wonderful
and so he's really been a leader not
only in our lab but across the community
and establishing rigorous methods for
Designing and setting up scientific
computational pipelines so that our
science can be
repeatable um and he's combined that
with knowledge of really the the front
of machine learning whether here or
working with Google X and um and though
although we teased Travis about his
smartphone um uh which he has an
americanmade open- Source smartphone
which probably took him about six months
to make it so he could take a picture or
something like that I mean you
know longer okay I mean took a year
before you could get the thing to take a
picture okay you know but it really
emphasizes the way he tackles problems
he wants to understand how things work
and work on systems that are you know
other people can participate in and I
think it's as machine learning and AI
become really even more distant uh and
unrelatable to people I think Travis is
really there trying to make sure that
we're doing science and apply these
incredible powerful Tools in a way
that's uh democratizing and really
available to us so Travis take it away
and tell us all about how genes work and
uh what we can do with that
knowledge all
right well thank you very much Ed um and
for the record if I allowed my phone to
install Zoom I would definitely be
presenting from it today but um
regardless that's not what you're here
to uh listen to me talk about but rather
the culmination of my uh PhD work that
I've titled for a rabbit Ops assia
learning conserves cyst mechanisms of
Gene
regulation classic uh so my PhD has been
broadly focused on these two research
questions the first is where are the
causal Loi in CIS regulatory regions and
second how do we transfer knowledge
across
species and I'm talking to a breeding
audience you might be wondering why I'm
mentioning causal Loi and the reality is
that if you want to do efficient genome
editing you need to know where the ca
ofi are to edit them and genome editing
is just the latest uh methodology in the
massive toolbox that plant breeders have
to make genetic gain so to borrow Ed's
software analogy we can see that
breeding methodologies have gone through
sort of four major software revisions
version one unconscious and and mass
selection moving to version two where we
get an idea of inheritance control
genetics to version three with marker
based methods and later on genomic
selection and now today being inv verion
4 with tools such as genetic
transformation and genome editing and I
want to emphasize here that all of these
add on to each other genome editing is
certainly useful for classes of traits
and problems but it doesn't replace
other methods um
everywhere but uh marker based methods
are known to be poorly suited for
actually finding these causal Loi and
for a number of different reasons one
there's an ascertainment bias in the
marker sets that are typically used uh
to fit these models they're a subset of
the total pool of genomic variation that
exists in in populations and further
you're only sampling the natural
variation and if your trait requires um
some novel non-natural variation then
that's not an option or doesn't exist in
these marker
sets and second uh even if you were to
sample all of the variation within a
population you still quickly run into
this NP problem where you have a lot
more variants to estimate effects for
than you have observations in your
breeding program
so the question becomes what's the right
causal Locus funnel how do we go from
for example on the order of 83 million
Snips in Elite ma germ plasm down to an
order of about 10,000 Snips that we can
start to either
edit my second question going back is
how do we transfer knowledge across
species and so why might we want to do
this well in the future we're going to
potentially need to breed thousands of
species historically breeding has
focused uh their efforts on the food
yield traits in about 10 or so species
but with uh increasing mean average
temperatures some species up to
thousands might need help being migrated
to cooler climates and we're going to
need to scale efforts in those without
investing the same amount that we have
in these food yield crops and so I'd
like to know how can we take all the
effort and data sets that we've created
in model plant species and transfer that
knowledge into specialty in orphan
crops but it's known that these
marker-based methods struggle to predict
across distant populations so we need
new methods in order to actually do this
transfer of knowledge across
species and so how do we do
that we can do that by looking at
conserved mechanisms and using those to
transfer knowledge so the central dogma
obeyed by all across the Tree of Life um
things like chromatin that all
eukariotic genomes uh organize
themselves
into and why should we use other species
to train models so first more species is
simply more training data and the Deep
learning models that I'm going to
present to you guys today require
relatively large training data sets and
this starts to alleviate the N less than
P
problem and if you can build models that
can predict in heldout species this is a
pretty strong validation that your model
is learning some biology um because we
know that functional sequences are
shared across long evolutionary
distances and it also helps you detect
when you're overfitting when you're in
poor NP regimes
and finally it helps prevent the
memorization of
retrotransposons and because they evolve
faster than their host genome they're
less likely to be shared across
evolutionary distances and this helps
prevent the common problem with machine
learning methods that sort of memorize
that retro elements are common in
regulatory regions and don't learn the
real biology about those regulatory
regions and just become transpose on
finders all right so just a quick
overview of what I'm going to talk to
you guys about today or my PhD in a
slide so we're going to start the DNA to
chromatin model move into an
expression-based model that takes in the
promoter and utr sequence go into some
bioph formatics work I've been doing to
find the functional transcription Factor
binding sites from DNA multiple sequence
alignments and finish off with a really
wonderful collaboration with the folks
at University of Washington where uh we
built a core promoter to expression
model all right so DNA to
chromatin so I'm going to go through
what chromatin is and how we commonly
measure it why is it relevant for
breeding why do I think that we can even
predict chromatin state from DNA and as
a hint we need both a concered
vocabulary and grammar which I'll get
into why are CNN's the model I'm using
here well suited for this how did I
train them and how well do they
work so we know that eukariotic DNA is
organized into chromatin and so we can
see here some cartoon representations of
histone proteins that DNA wraps itself
around and and when they're particularly
compact these even though these DNA
sequences have transcription Factor
binding sites they can't be bound by
transcription factors unless they're
more accessible and they can't then
therefore regulate gene
expression so we measure chromatin
accessibility many different ways one of
which is a tax seek and basically a tax
seek measures where a trans a massive
transpose a comes in and can cut and it
cuts preferentially in accessible
regions these cut sites can be are put
on the end of reads and you can align
them to the genome and call Peaks from
them so these blue squares for example
are binarized one or zero accessible or
non-accessible another interesting
result recently seen in the grasses is
that many of these accessible regions
across tissues almost all of them across
tissues are also DNA
unmethylated um and this is really
interesting because accessible chromatin
is highly Dynamic over developmental
time and so a lot of the Peaks aren't
shared across tissues and we want to
build models of them they have to be
tissue somewhat specific but if we can
build a single model of DNA methylation
then we can take it in one tissue
because DNA methylation is relatively
stable over developmental time and only
use one model to predict these
regions and I'm going to be referring to
these peaks of DNA lack of DNA
methylation as umrs and they're um Peaks
where there is a lack of DNA methylation
in all three context and just as a sort
of example you can see how consistent
they are in this region across leaf
Roots so why should breeders care about
accessible chromosone well we know that
they actually contain functional variant
so some prior work in the lab looked at
the heritability proportion assignable
to Snips in coding regions versus
accessible chromatin regions across
about 40 or so agronomic traits and what
they saw is that Snips within coding
regions explain almost as much
heritability as Snips within coding
regions which we already know are
important so this has relevance
so can we predict chromatin State uh
directly from DNA sequence and why might
we want to well only about 5% of the
maze genome is unmethylated and so this
would result in about a 20x reduction in
the Target space that we can mutate
within or should mutate
within and quickly why DNA based models
um specifically so first they are
alignment free and this is a common
roadblock when you're doing cross
species analyses how do you get good
cross species alignments it can be very
tricky second some samples we can only
assay with DNA sequence for example if
you're collecting from an herbarium or
other dead tissue samples it's really
impossible to do something like
chromatin as saying on those um and
nowadays DNA sequencing is relatively
cheap compared to things like attack
seek or
chipseek um also we have a pretty good
idea on how DNA behaves over Generations
so we can model reconstructed ancestors
or predicted plant bre uh breeding
program progeny and use those models to
predict functional aspects of those
non-existent
organisms and so it's this really this
grammar between the transcription Factor
binding sites that should be a strong
ratory signal from the genomic
background and it could be helpful to
think of these regulatory segments as a
DNA in general as sort of a sentence so
the vocabulary are these transcription
Factor binding sites so these colored
rectangles I'm showing here and the
grammar is the spatial relationship or
the co-binding between these motifs and
because the vocab is kind of is short
and very degenerate it's they occur
randomly by chance throughout the genome
and just one tfbs is not really enough
to say that that's regulatory but if you
sudden suddenly see a lot of them
together in a certain orientation that's
a better
signal but are these things conserved
across species we want to build across
species models we need to leverage
that so there's a reason to think from
theory that these vocab is conserved at
least across plants because we know that
the origin of a lot of these
transcription Factor binding domains
predate the plant expansion and so
therefore the motifs they bind to should
be highly conserved and common in plant
genomes and as a more concrete example
more recent work out of the lab trained
CER binding models for about 100 or so
maze transcription factors and so they
related whether or not a CER uh was more
present in a region Bound by a certain
TF and if you take all of those TFS and
you build a tree out of based on the the
relationship between those camer weights
you can get this sort of tree that was
built in Maze and what's exciting to see
is if you start to color those tips by
the orthologous transcription factor in
a arabidopsis the colors also Group by
the tree suggesting that there is some
conservation of that binding uh
vocabulary across at least the
angiosperms so going back we know that
the vocab is pro is likely to be
conserved at least there's some evidence
but we really don't know if the grammar
is highly conserved and so that's my
main hypothesis going into this work is
that the grammar is conserved and we can
use that to predict romtin state from
sequence so just an overview of the sort
of classifier we're going to build here
going from a window of DNA sequence can
we put it into a model and get some 0
to1 prediction of whether it's
inaccessible accessible methylated or
unmethylated we already know that CNN's
the model I'm using here are pretty well
suited for this kind of task what I'm
showing here is results from 2015 one of
the first CNN's deep sea to be applied
to this uh in humans and so we know that
this is a good classifier because all of
these black lines which which represent
accessibility in different tissues are
far away from this diagonal which would
be what the random classifier would be
at and a year later this other model Dan
Q showed that it can do slightly better
across all chromatin tasks that I just
showed previously um so these CNN models
seem to be
working and also much more recent work
in plants in 2011 or 2021 showed that
they also do work well with high area
under the curves close to
one so just a brief overview of what
CNN's are and how they work so you can
one hot encode DNA as a matrix
and the convolutional layer in these
cnns one of the first layers is going to
scan over in Windows and it's going to
match these convolutional Kels to each
window and over time it's going to learn
what motifs are important to predict
whatever your target is um and those
when it finds a match is going to result
in a high value that goes into later
layers and so this is well suited for
this sort of like detection of motifs
problem and I use the Dan Q model here
specifically that I mentioned just prev
prly because it also has this lstm layer
which is a recurrent layer that allows
you to learn not just whether a motif is
present in a sequence but also the
co-presence of motifs and what their
spatial relationships are and this is
exactly what I think should be a strong
discriminator uh from genomic background
to regulatory regions like I said
earlier these models are pretty large
and uh danq has about 1.6 million
parameters and it's fairly small model
for for these
days so the data that I'm going to use
to train it uh is is chromatin data
across the angiosperms from both uh
monocots and dcot so things like grape
common Bean soybean and then your
grasses like rice Ma and sorghum and I
have aack seek in about 10 or 12 of
those species and methylation data in
about 10 of them in total that results
in about 312,000 attack seek Peaks
across these species and about 360,000
umrs so not quite above P yet but in a
much better space than if we were to
just train in one of these species
so how are we going to do this I'm going
to train the model in two different ways
one within species to compare to
previous literature and in another
across species so first for within
species we'll take the Peaks under one
chromosome and assign them to our test
set we'll assign the rest to our
training set we're going to down sample
so that there's a balance between our
black and blue or accessible
inaccessible regions and just so you can
see now 3: one to one:
one and then we can get some performance
metric for that model within the species
on the test set and we can do that for
both accessibility and
methylation for the across species model
we'll assign the same Peaks to the test
set so that we can have an even
comparison between the two and then
we'll assign training peaks in the other
uh species down sample again to balance
and now we have two bars that we can
compare on the same arabidopsis Peaks
for both accessibility and
methylation and so long story short it
turns out yes we can build models that
predict chromatin State across
angiosperms so for example I'm showing
the methylation first um we can see that
generally the orange and the blue bars
are pretty close to each other sometimes
reversed but the across species models
seem to be very competitive to models
trained solely within species even
though they have to go across a longer
evolutionary
distance and the same case is true for
the accessibility if not more so what's
interesting is if we have heavy sampling
within specific clades they seem to do a
lot better than the across species
models suggesting if we can fill out the
tree a little bit more we can do even
better with across species models across
the
angiosperms and I also just want to
highlight we don't expect these Cy based
models to be perfect for predicting
chromatin State we know that there are
trans effects that come in from other
areas of the genome that can silence
these regions even without any change in
the sequence underlying them and I'll
talk about those in a
second so what I asked next was what
region does the model do best or worst
in so I divided the genome up into
either genic regions that overlap Gene
annotations uh proximal regions that
over are within 2kb of either the
transcription start site or the uh
termination site and everything else is
distal and what I saw is that generally
the model does best on accessibility in
these proximal regions and worst on
these disle
regions and it's a very similar case for
the methylation models
so diving a little bit deeper I noticed
that a lot of the accessibility errors
the model's making are false positives
so I'm summing to 100% within each of
these columns and you'll notice that
excuse me about 70% of the um
predictions of the model that are open
are actually labeled as closed in the
data so there's a high false positive
rate but I do want to emphasize here
that this is not necessarily wrong
because the attack SE Peaks that I'm
using were cons were called with
relatively conservative thresholds and
so if you have some certain Peaks that
are open in maybe half of the cell types
or less in this data set those might not
have met the strength needed to be
called in this data set and they might
be open but the model uh doesn't know
that or it suspects that but it's
labeled as closed and
true okay so some of the trans effects I
alluded to earlier um one example of
those would be let's say you have a CIS
regulatory module sitting in a
transposon which is not an uncommon
occurrence
uh and it looks like it should be a a
regulatory module by the sequence but in
reality um some host directed maybe RNA
directed DNA methylation might silence
that transposon because of its context
um and our Cy based model might not
necessarily pick up on that so how do we
help it out what if we started masking
transposons so we take in in this case
let's say 600 base pairs of sequence
feed it into our model and then it'll
make a prediction and then if it's in a
transposon we'll set that prediction as
zero and if it's not we'll keep the
original one and see how we
do and if we if we do Mass transposons
we get significant improvements uh in
both accessibility and methylation
suggesting once we start incorporating
those trans effects into our Cy based
models we can actually get to more
towards
Perfection next I wanted to look at how
well this these models do across a
number of different cell types so I
didn't mention previously but this is
leaf accessibility data so the model is
only been trained in one tissue type
across species and so I'll have one
prediction for each of these Peaks and I
wanted to see how well it does across a
single cell attack seek that has
multiple cell types in
it so going from left to right on the
x-axis here we're moving from tissue
specific Peaks to more generally
accessible Peaks and we can see model
performance follows basically how tissue
specific you are
inversely and I want to point out here
that SCA Tech is is known to be
relatively noisy and so sometimes when
you don't have many observations of a
peak in or you only have it in very few
nuclei it's hard to tell whether that
Peak is noise or a truly cell type
specific Peak so this might actually not
be uh uh predictable for the
model I also looked at genome wide how
does performance differ across cell
types and it doesn't differ that much
promisingly the best uh performing
tissue is the guard cell which is a leaf
cell type that's rate and and one of the
worst performing is tro blast or root
hair precursor so promising but there's
still not much of a difference and the
reason for this is either many Peaks are
open in in very many tissues or very few
tissues and we know the model does uh
really poorly on distal regions which
tend to be more cell type specific Peaks
so across tissues we're not going to do
very well in those regions anyways but
it does very well on regions that are
open in many tissues and that doesn't
change across tissues a lot so kind of
explains why the model is sort of
consistent across
tissues one of the common criticisms of
deep learning models is understanding
just what they're learning they can make
good predictions but what biology are
they learning if any uh to make those
predictions so how do we open up the
black box so to speak one of the ways I
did this was using a method from Peter
Cruz group called Global importance
analysis uh and it's sister method
positional Global importance analysis so
the way that works is we're going to
sample some back sequences uh just a
control for potential co-binding motifs
across um uh the background and we're
going to embed some Motif that we're
interested in so we can start testing
specific Motif hypotheses and in my case
I took a database of known transcription
Factor binding motifs and just started
embedding them in these random regions
and then you measure the difference
between those set of embedded regions
and the random background and just see
how your model predictions differ and
it's the average difference between
these that is known as the global
importance so how important is that
Motif being in the sequence to your
model for making its
prediction you can embed this Motif not
just in the middle but at any position
and get a very position specific effect
of the global importance for embedding
that
Motif and so then you can start to rank
these motifs by their effect size to the
model so in this case I'm ranking them
by their maximum positional Global
importance so what motifs no matter
where you put them in the sequence are
very important for changing the model's
prediction and we can see that for the
accessibility model which had a rabbit
opsis held out predicting into a rabbit
opsis sequence it's paying a lot of
attention to TCP family motifs and this
is cool because we know that some tcps
can be chromatin remodelers so that's
promising for Maze there are some tcps
but we also see these doth type family
uh transcription Factor motifs ranked
highly we know that they're involved in
seed and seedling development no
chromatin remodeling evidence that I'm
aware of but perhaps part of development
is is chromatin remodeling in this
case and across both arabidopsis and Ma
held out methylation models it's much
more consistent being these bbr bpc
motives or ap2 erf we know there is some
evidence for bbr bpc to do chromatin
remodeling cool um and there is evidence
that ap2 erf or they're known to be
involved in development but the case is
less
clear so in summary uh I've shown that
these recurrent convolution neural
networks can seem to model chromatin
accessibility and DNA methylation
directly from sequin and across plant
species and that these across species
models are competitive with within
species
models the accessibility a toz models uh
seem to perform best on Gene proximal
and commonly accessible
regions and incorporating trans effects
starts to reduce our models CIS based
models false positive
rates and finally uh these TCP family
motifs seem to rank highly in global
importance to the across species
accessibility models and it's a much
more consistent case being ap2 erf or BB
bbr bpc for
methylation all right so moving right
along to our expression model or my
expression model I guess um so one of
the motivations for making this model
was to try to move towards some more
efficient promoter bashing and so
promoter bashing is where you'll take um
random guide targets of stream of a gene
and just start trying to make mutants
until you see the effect that you want
and they're untargeted but what if we
can build a promoter model that can
instead reduce the space that we would
need to randomly Bash from on the order
of 2,000 base pairs to more like a 100
or
so so plenty of uh human expression
models already exist in the literature
and I'm going to test four of them here
uh the first is fnet compression which
is a relatively tiny model at 60,000
parameters hyena DN a more recent one at
450,000 Dan Q we're familiar with at 1.6
million and Informer is currently
state-ofthe-art at about 250 million
parameters I couldn't quite get
informative run on the hardware I had
available so I down sampled it to about
50 million and called it mini
former uh some previous work in the lab
also showed if you have coding sequence
going into your model then there's a
potential for that model to start to
memorize Gene family
and so in this case if you have things
that are looking like transcription
factors for example in their coding
regions then the model just tend to
think that oh if you're a transcription
Factor you tend to be lowly expressed
versus something that is more highly
expressed and not learn anything about
the cyst regulation differences between
the two that actually explain
expression so there's a couple of
different uh uh ways to improve existing
expression models the first as I've
mentioned previously with thin species
models have limited independent training
observations second if you don't mask
your coding regions then that can enable
overfitting on Gene
family it's also been seen that there's
a poor recall of these models on rare
eqtl wheels for example um a lot of
these expression models just fail to
detect even high effect eqtl if they're
not present at high
frequency and there as of today uh well
before this work there was no level
comparison between all of these
architectures so it's hard to tell
whether this model was better because it
had a different data set or the problem
was easier and so I wanted to make sure
that we can test everything on on a
Level Playing
Field and so the data I'm using to train
these models are uh 32 new uh long read
genomes and RNA seek data from Wild
relatives of Maze and this is these
genomes are really the result of
collaborative effort between Arun Cam
and Michelle Stitzer um along with
collaborators at the danforce center
Taylor and Toby who actually did the
sampling of these um species and it
spans the uh andragonia tribe of which
Ma and sorghum are a part
of and so the schema for this uh model
is I'm going to train on the relatives
of Maze and try to predict in maze so
very similar to the last Model um but
also following the advice from the
previous lab work I'm also going to do
the orthog group guided splitting so in
this case I'm going to have a holdout
set of genes that are in different
orthog groups for my training set and
also in different species so this is a
very difficult problem in total I have
about a million training observations
for these expression
models so in my model I'm going to start
uh at the translation start site and go
one kilobase pair Upstream of the
translation start site and try to
predict the uh expression levels either
in specific tissues like Leaf stem or
flow or the maximum expression across
tissues or the binarized form of that
onoff expression in any
tissue and I want to highlight that the
within Gene performance is not
necessarily equal to a cross Gene
performance and a cross Gene is
typically what's been shown in the
literature excuse me what I mean by a
cross Gene is if you take a look across
all the genes in the genome and all the
species that you have in your training
or test set if you can correctly set
separate the highly expressed geneses
from the lowly expressed genes it
doesn't mean that you have the ability
to distinguish between for example
closely related orthologues so it's
classic Simpsons Paradox situation where
you looks good between groups but then
you start to go within groups and your
correlation levels
drop so first just to compare to
existing literature the across Gene
regression results are about equal to a
within human Benchmark what's cool to
see is one of my best performing models
on one of the best performing tasks
maximum expression is about 0.52 and
it's Dan q and the within human data in
former gets to about 0.57 so we're
almost there not quite but these models
are predicting across species in this
case I also compared it to the previous
work from the lab that did this within
maze so for the onoff expression model
uh one of the best models is fnet
compression at an a rock of 77 and this
is exactly equal to the model that was
trained Within in maze that took in only
promoter regions and I want you to
notice there's also a slightly better
model that took in both promoter and
Terminator and we'll get into that a
second but first the within Gene
performance dramatically drops uh once
you start looking across orthologs
within maze so I was showing cross Gene
correlations of on the order of
0.56 but within genes across different
orthologues
the uh average correlation drops to
about
and there's not really much difference
between even or models of several orders
of magnitude parameter difference and
it's only slightly better on average on
the maximum expression
task and this agrees with the same
Benchmark that looked at this in human
on Informer the current State ofthe art
um in
pattern so looking at one of my best
models Dan Q again uh just sort of
emphasize that how poorly it ranks these
orthologues by abundance I'm looking on
the x-axis here the predicted expression
change by the model between any pair of
orthologues on the log 10 scale and then
we're looking at the observed expression
chains and generally it's just not doing
well for anything except things that are
more towards the Tails so until you get
to about a hundred or a thousand uh
times x expression increase it doesn't
it's not able to differentiate perhaps
the model's overfitting quickly on these
huge expression differences and never
really gets a chance to uh finally
distinguish expression
another thing that might be going on is
the previous work in the group showed
that really it's the three prime ETR and
the Terminator uh that was needed to
distinguish between at least ma
orthologues
um and so potentially what the model
needs is to also include that sequence
but I also want to emphasize again that
if if we do this future work really
needs to make sure to mass those coding
regions so it doesn't memorize Gene
family I also looked at where the uh Dan
Q model was paying attention for
predicting expression levels in the max
expression task and what's cool to see
is it actually highlights the core
promoter so note I didn't give the model
the transcription start site I started
at the translation start site and I've
sort of manual manually aligned these
important scores for you to the
transcription start site and it
highlights across all the maze genes the
core promoter which is we know is
important for expression
yeah okay the other thing I looked at is
it's a common refrain in deep learning
that we need more training data more
data better models um and I wanted to
know if that was actually the case
because that data doesn't come for free
um so I took various subsets of my
training data starting at very small
fractions of it and gradually increasing
it to the 1 million uh number of
observations and I do see the
performance between the 500 and a
million is still increasing suggesting
there is a need for more training data
depending on the price point at which it
costs to acquire
it so in summary it seems the current
genomic deep learning architectures
perform well across dently related
species and this agrees with human bench
within human benchmarks in both pattern
and magnitude and it has nearly the same
performance as maze models without
seeing any maze
sequence they don't seem to be sensitive
enough yet to rank closely related
sequence which agrees with wi the human
Benchmark as well perhaps we need three
prime utr but I also think it's
interesting to think about if the three
prime utrs uh region that Evolution has
happened to favor to find tune
expression or if it is actually needed
to find tune
expression so in the third point is that
the models do seem to recognize the core
promoter as important across all genes
that's a good
validation uh and it seems we do could
use some more training data uh to
saturate the performance of these models
all right so moving on to a more
biomatics focused approach looking at
multiple sequence alignments to predict
functional transcription Factor binding
sites so why functional transcription
Factor binding sites well compareed to
an accessible chromatin model if we can
actually find the the real uh binding
sites that would be even a more
efficient editing Target because not
every base pair an accessible region is
necessarily A binding
site and I kind of alluded to this
before but Motif scanning if you just
take known motifs and scan them across
the genome there's a high false positive
rate so if you look at any random
promoter Upstream you're just going to
see a lot of hits and they overlap and
there's there's a lot of them but how
many of them are actually functional
which ones are functional and this is so
bad that uh these authors kind of uh
exasperatedly conjectured in 2004 that
this futility theorem means that about
100% of your predicted binding sites are
nonfunctional three orders of magnitude
difference but we can use other
information to filter down these methods
such as evolutionary conservation so if
you do your Motif scanning as usual and
you detect a region of the genome that's
more conserved over time it's more
evidence that these are actually doing
something and this has been known for a
while as philogenetic
footprinting but why use phalogenic
footprinting now what's changed so first
there's new aligners on the scene like
anchor wave that can handle these plant
energenic regions much better uh than
previously this is important where a lot
of these non-coding uh in these
non-coding regions there's a lot of
regulatory regions that we want to study
their
conservation also I mentioned we have 32
new highquality long read antropia
assemblies and we also have 400 new
short read anagon assemblies to even
increase the depth of these msas
further and so all of these assemblies
came from uh the NSF pan and Grant which
collected about 800 anagon samples
worldwide as I mentioned previously
colleagues at the Danforth Center Taylor
aashan Elder and Toby Kellogg uh run
around the world and collected andon
from fresh uh tissue samples or either
went into herbariums and silica
collections to get these
samples and so if you build a tree out
of all these samples and you Sum along
all the the branches in that tree they
sample approximately on the order of
about a billion years of evolution which
comes out to about 30 to 5050 mutations
per base pair so a very powerful data
set to measure
constraint and so if you look at these
short read assemblies which are thanks
to the efforts of twe and cinta for the
sequencing and Amy and Charlie for the
assembly um if we look at the bootco
completeness of these assemblies
generally they seem to be fairly
complete and if the genes aren't
complete they're at least FR uh present
in a majority uh fragment so fairly
contiguous
and so as part of the long read assembly
work a collaborator Armen uh Sheen took
the long read assemblies and used the
cactus genome aligner to build a
multiple sequence alignment between them
across all 32 and then he used fastc
cons to do that philogenetic put
footprinting I talked about earlier and
find the conserved non-coding sequences
or CNS and in maze there's about 95,000
of them that he
detected so now now my work comes into
adding in those short read assemblies to
see if we can get further depth in these
uh alignments so starting with a species
tree that contains the non-ref which I'm
referring to the short read assemblies
as and the ref the long read we can
align the non- reference Contex to the
nearest reference assembly so we can
avoid some of the reference bias and
then use that Cactus alignment to lift
over all of these alignments into the
same MSA space and get msas of these
conserved non-coding regions that have
hundreds of anon assemblies in
them what I noticed looking at some of
these CNS regions is that only about
60,000 of those are widely covered
across the an bergonia there are a
subset of them that are only present
across a number of the long read
assemblies and we uh sampled heavily in
the zeia clade for the long read
assemblies um and I wanted to focus this
analysis on things that were present
across everything so I decided to filter
out to this upper right CL quadrant here
so that brings me down to about
60,000 the next thing I did was use the
Jasper transcription Factor database to
scan for those motifs with the Fimo tool
and so looking at a real example of an
alignment within one of these CNS
regions we can imagine that there are
some Motif hits within it right here and
I'm going to use fast so the same set
that contains fast cons to test whether
these motifs as a region are more
constrained than the bases around them
and I'm going to do some very simple
filtering to get rid of these uh very
gappy
columns and so when I do that and run
the the test I get about
56,000 uh transcription Factor binding
sites in maze that are constrained uh to
the bond coron correct Bond foni
corrected P value across
panand okay so the next thing I wanted
to do is look for binding preferences in
these across these motifs and so to do
that I did an all byall alignment of the
constrained motifs that I detected also
along with all the Jasper motifs from
the database and so since some of these
motifs are shorter or longer than others
I took the longest Motif and I slid the
shorter one across in all possible
positions and took the minimum of the
ukian distance between the two and used
that as the alignment score and it has
to be ukian this is a common Motif
comparison metric but also remember
these motifs are actually matrices and
they represent frequencies of bases at
each position and not a single
base so at the end of this I have about
58,000 by 58,000 distance Matrix uh with
all the constrained motifs in Jasper and
that can be a little hard to visualize
so I used umap to reduce the
dimensionality and was actually very
pleased to see that they cluster by
class and family according to the Jasper
labels so that's a good validation that
the alignments actually worked and are
doing something um and so let's see if
they have some specific binding
preferences within
them so I looked in one class in family
in this case the bip group B's and I
clustered them uh according to their
motifs and I see that there is this big
cluster here that has a Jasper Motif
within it um but there's also two
clusters down here the pink and the red
that don't have any annotated Jasper
Motif which is cool suggests some novel
binding pattern that we haven't seen
and when we look at the motif
preferences when each of these clusters
there are actual differences for example
between the pink and the red there's a
CA strong CA preference versus a strong
CG preference or a strong uh G
preference in the red versus a very weak
t or a preference up up here so
certainly interesting to see but I'd
like to get more validation and so I
looked at how these subcluster presence
or absence correlates to expression or
explains expression variation so I'm
doing a very simple linear model for
this expression uh testing so the Y uh
values are going to be TPM or
transcripts per million a measure of RNA
expression log 10 transformed and the X
Matrix is either the presence or absence
of a motif from that subcluster and it
is it within 100 KB Upstream of a given
Gene uh which is well within what we
know CIS regulatory regions are capable
of interacting with uh the core promoter
and so uh I have about 5,000 genes that
have any one of these motifs upstream
and there's about 1,600 uh Motif
subclusters and what I'm going to do is
for each of these columns for each
subcluster column I'm going to randomly
permute and measure the change in r s of
that model and I'm going to do a couple
replicates of permutation and measure
the average change in the models r
squared by permuting that
column and so uh Focus on the right side
here every row is a replicate RNA seek
experiment and we have multiple
replicates per tissue and generally the
r squ values don't differ very much
ranging from 0 2 to 3 and along the
x-axis here we have those different 1600
Motif subclusters and I've normalized by
the r s of each model the Delta so that
we can compare across rows now this can
be kind of hard to visualize so let's
zoom in just a little bit to the again
the bzip factors and the C c2h2 zinc
finger factors and we can see some cool
initial patterns so for example we have
this subcluster that seems to explain a
lot of the variation in endosperm uh
tissue expression and it shows up across
both tissue replicates so that's a good
sign we have some subclusters that seem
to show up in anther tissue as well um
and then some subclusters that don't
seem to be specific to any tissue in
particular
so for this uh uh section to summarize
I've seen or identified these
constrained maze transcription Factor
binding sites and they seem to Cluster
into subfamilies that have very specific
binding preferences some of them are not
annotated in known TF databases so novel
motifs and the Upstream presence or
absence of these constrained subfamilies
seems to be important to tissue specific
expression
patterns so to close us off I'm going to
talk about uh just a wonderful
collaboration with some fine folks at
the University of Washington where we
built a core promoter to expression
model I've talked a big game about these
models saying that we could use them for
genome editing but let's prove if they
can actually work or
not so what Toby and Jackson did in
Christine qu's group is a star SE gas
and glazing over a lot of the molecular
biology just you know that you can
synthesize any 170 base pairs you want
put it Upstream of a reporter Gene put
it into either tobacco leaf or Maze
protoplast and measure the relative
expression to some baseline and what we
did in this work was take 170 base pairs
Upstream of the transcription start site
in a rabid opsis Maze and sorghum and
I'm calling that the core
promoter the good news is star seek is
replicable within the expression system
so looking across replicates one and two
in tobacco leaf the same promoter agrees
with an R skirt of about 0.91
when we look in the Maze protoplast it's
a little bit less at R square to 79 but
still pretty agreeable across uh
replicates and what I want to emphasize
here is if we start to compare the same
170 base pair promoter across Maze and
tobacco uh systems they only agree with
an R squar of. 31 really emphasizing how
much of the variation expression depends
on the trans the cellular environment
versus the Cy promoter
sequence so my contri ution to this work
was building this bidirectional CNN
model to predict core promoter strength
so what's bidirectional about is
typically these convolutional neural
networks scan along your input sequence
only in One Direction They Don't
Understand DNA strandedness so a
modification I made was to have the
model automatically flip the motif into
its reverse complement and scan it along
the other strand all at once so that it
can use the same kernel to learn both
the forward and the reverse strand
instead of wasting two and that's great
because it results in a more efficient
use of parameters which is important if
we're Limited in data
quantity and in one of the most exciting
moments of my PhD we found that these
models actually work so we took both
three Snips suggested by the model or 10
Snips suggested by the model and
actually put them into tobacco or Maze
and show that they increased expression
level significantly and this doesn't
matter whether you're in tobacco or maze
or if you have a 35s enhancer Upstream
or not it increases expression in all
cases and not only that it the model is
able to predict the degree at which
expression increased so they do seem to
have the ability if you can control the
trans environment to predict across
different alals uh very closely related
alals so in summary the CNN models seem
to be highly effective Learners of Cy
promoter variation if you can control
that trans environment and the suggested
edits from these models actually work in
planta um and it seems that these could
be the way towards more efficient uh uh
promoter
bashing so bring us all uh together
again uh the DNA to chromatin model we
saw does work across species and also is
um comparable to within species trained
models so great for the promoter and utr
uh expression model it does does work
well across species but it still
struggles to predict across different
orthologues so I'll give it a yes and a
no sort of success
there there's still some more work to be
done to validate these subclusters in
the transcription Factor binding site uh
work but it's showing some
interesting patterns between subcluster
presence absence and
expression and finally the core promoter
expression model not only seemed to
learn the relationship but also then
predict edits that could make changes
and actually those changes reflect what
the model predicted so I'll give that
two checks for super
success um and with that I would just
like to acknowledge my funding so from
the NSF and the grfp specifically for my
first three years of graduate school and
USDA AR for the rest I've as you can
imagine had to leverage a lot of
different compute across the years from
exceed in the TAC cluster uh to the
front system and more recently on the
USDA sin cluster and bio HBC thank you
very much of course my committee at Amy
and Eric for your advice and Cornell for
having me I'd also like to thank X for
just not only giving U making my
internship very valuable experience but
just playing fun um my co-authors which
out whom of course I could have just not
done this work the bucker lab and
synapsis for both the support and all
the good times over the
years and finally thank you to all the
open source software developers and
packagers who have probably spent
countless hours making the tools that we
rely on um and also the packagers for
making them just easily installable for
us so with that I'm happy to take your
questions yeah you can go back to your
your p on a slide there yeah so the the
upper right hand corner
is um I guess you you're when you're
you're trying to predict within or you
can predict the the amount of expression
across orthologs pretty well but not not
between genes within orthologs right
yeah so I'll I'll be a little bit more
precise with my terminology there sorry
so when I say orthologue in this case
what I mean is across one gene in maze
across different OES in the N population
so not necessarily two paralogs within
the maze genome so sorry if I was clear
about that and the training that you
have is the the total expression
of that Gene across many ortholog right
uh it is either the max expression of
that orthologue across all tissues that
I have data for or just one single uh
tissue expression value could you could
you try to train on the deviation
within within a within so so for a it's
deviation from the mean for that Gene
does that make sense yeah yeah you could
absolutely do that and and pre the
previous work I didn't highlight what
they did there but they did exactly that
they they put both orthologue uh
sequences in the model and tried to
predict the expression and it does does
really like the expression change and it
does
well but not it doesn't like for example
take a difference in DNA sequence it
takes both in the in the input
yeah yeah I do know roughly how
differentiated those two orth logs are
from one
another yeah why the was bur approach is
is easier than this one no I don't know
a sequence the sequence number off the
top of my head you know yeah so they're
about 8 million years Toge oh I
see so it's it's that's an easier
problem than this right differentiating
one snip right causes an expression
difference so in their case orthologs
were across Ma and sorghum um in my case
they're across
like b73 and mo
17 are there any questions online I
can't really see the chat no
cool yeah did you look at
transferability across tissues for the
DNA Caron model and model
transferability across ti so I did show
like sort of the perform you mean
performance across different tissues
like the single cell work well like if
you train in Leaf how well does it
yeah that's a great and if I had the
data set to do that I would have but at
the time I did the model I only had the
leaf accessibility across that vast
number of species um so no I think it's
an interesting question but I didn't
have the data at the time to test that
yeah
call she come to my defense now um so
yeah I've just been sort of roughly
saying core promoter like anywhere from
50 base pairs to 150 base pairs Upstream
promoter is such a wide number I've seen
up to 2,000 base pairs from a Jee be
called the promoter um so yeah it's it's
a very loose term and I'm abusing it
sorry H sarin I think
yeah yeah
yeah it's I mean it highly varies based
on really genome size so like in a rabid
opsis things on average are going to be
a lot closer together than in bigger
genomes like maze where things are
pushed out by a lot of this transposon
activity over time and So within the
grasses that can tend to have larger
genomes that range can get up to 100 250
KB um on average so it really really
seems to depend on genome size
yeah oh John
Mo
um you you train these models on data
yeah and sometimes it's accessible or
not methylated or not conserved or
not but but it like you had a comment at
one point where it seemed like
accessible or not it's actually not
binary in in biology right there's uh
some continuous nature of accessibility
yeah so it's it's a general question
about statistics maybe of like what do
you gain and what do you lose when you
convert something that's in some ways
continuous to something that's binary
for for training a statistical model
yeah I mean that's a great question and
part of what you what you gain is a high
false positive rate uh but I mean it's
something that we that's a loss right
do you like my phrasing
yes um and yeah I so there there's more
as we get more and more single cell data
we can ask that question like train a
model on the proportion of a given cell
type that's actually this this peak is
accessible and in and you know we had
the data we had at the time and I think
nowadays we can certainly make a more
quantitative uh model for accessibility
yeah because I totally agree biology is
not in this case your answer suggests
that usually if you convert to Binary
you lose something but I you had a you
had a a a sort of scatter plot where I
think it was also within the promoter to
expression where you said oh maybe it's
overfitting on these things that are
massively expressed that have massive
fold changes yeah uh and that made me
think oh why don't you just make that
one binary and then it won't know which
ones are or yeah have massive bu changes
yeah which that might be a case where
you gain something but maybe I'm wrong I
mean comment no I think that's
interesting and some some potential ways
to think about that is is first training
a model on pseudogene or not pseo when I
say pseudogene things that are expressed
or not expressed in any tissue and then
have a model that fine-tune some sort of
expression level so you don't get have
to learn both any expression all at at
the same time as you're trying to learn
uh expression fine tune and I think
another problem uh why I emphasize the
tals is sort of overfitting is because I
used the mean squared error as my loss
function maybe that's weighted much
higher in my model uh and just learns
that
so thank you yeah sure Sam
doel
improveing architectures you think it's
problem of data um I think it's a lack
of not only data but sort of well
replicated and controlled data sets I
mean I tested uh model architectures
that had vastly different orders of
magnitude uh differences and they just
really didn't show much performance
differences uh so yeah from what the
evidence I've seen I think we just need
better data more controlled data sets
and if someone has a really cool
architecture they proposes the best and
tests against that data set just like we
have these uh Casp comp competitions for
protein folding and that's how we knew
Alpha fold was one of the best
performers because it didn't see any of
the data beforehand so I think having
these sort of
holdout uh well curated data sets is
really essential moving forward
so Travis I was wondering when you're
fitting your uh transcription Factor
binding site models you're only using at
the end 5,000 genes why why is that
rather than like the 20,000 or 25,000
genes yeah so good question in this case
I only I only chose genes that had at
least one motif of the subclusters that
I identified Upstream I could just I
could certainly add in the other 20,000
that don't have any but there would be a
lot of
zeros so there was that many gen without
a without a
constrained Motif uh that I could detect
with my msas
Yeah question
okay asking more
questions well thank you very
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu