this is a production of Cornell
University hi I'm Frank Rossy um I'm
going to introduce myself as an urban
grassland
ecologist for the purposes of this um
like this the Earth is warming it's our
fault uh we are as we've seen and Grant
showed moving into cities at rapid rates
which is a good thing because then we
only mess up small amounts of area every
place we go we tend to uh mess things up
as a population and one of the things
that we know is as we move into these
Urban environments and I know my
colleague Nina basic has been barking
about this for 40 years and hardly
anybody's been listening but it's very
important to have plants and green
infrastructures in these uh systems as
Yoshi said very well to start us off
today uh not growing food but supplying
us in different ways so it's really
important uh that we have these green
infrastructure rues there the problem is
people can't be trusted to take care of
them they mismanage nutrients they mow
improperly they uh don't Steward the
Water Resource uh exceptionally well um
there's enormous amounts of emissions
associated with their use they don't
know how to deal with uh organic waste
let me uh never mind their adherence to
Pest management principles so these
improper practices are uh all lead
leading to a reduction in ecosystem
services and that really is
fundamentally what is no longer a let
net laughing matter how these Landscapes
provide and regulate and support and in
my perspective are offer all these
cultural Services the human well-being
the recreation that uh Urban grasslands
pen provide so our research is focusing
on Diversified plantings mixing C3 and
C4 plants in lawns in hopes that it can
be a little bit smarter when the water
comes and goes that's one approach the
other is to take the people out because
in my opinion they can't be trusted is
to automate those Landscapes and we have
as the $6 million man who's old enough
you know anybody my age would remember
that television show we have the
technology to do this now it's a matter
of making it work and systematizing it
so that works on a smartphone and so we
have an array of robotic mowing
Technologies and an array of irrigation
moisture sensing Technologies the
ability to hand the keys of the mowing
over to the robot which will be better
than a regular person Mowing and turn
the keys of the irrigation system over
to the uh soil moisture sensors after
they're calibrated so that the water can
be applied properly and in conjunction
what that will then lead to you know is
sort of like driverless cars right the
roads are going to have to be a little
bit different the uh roads will be used
more efficiently and will all be quite a
bit safer when humans aren't driving and
in My Hope just like it might be illegal
some day to drive a car I hope it's
illegal to mow your
lawn this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu