this is a production of Cornell
University uh the topic of my talk today
is USDA Apple grape and tar Cherry germ
pling collection um I'm only going to
give you kind of overview of what we do
at Geneva so if you have any specific
question uh about any on my talk or you
have any question about the collection
please uh contact me
later first very briefly about some of
history for the national PL ger plasm
system uh President Lincoln established
us Bureau of Agriculture current day
USDA and also signed two months later
signed the morale Lang gr col act in
1862 uh and then in
1898 uh the section of uh CM plan
introduction was established uh and and
the first Pi which was uh
cabbage uh from Russia was introduced by
neilis Hansen also at the same year in
1898 uh also in 1898 uh the federal plan
introduction Garden which is the first
one uh which is a current day uh
subtropical Horticultural station uh was
established uh in Miami Florida in July
the same
year and uh later in 1904 uh another uh
plane transction was established at
Chico California in Northern California
later in
1919 uh two other one one in Savannah
Georgia and one in Glen uh Maryland was
established uh in
1946 uh the research and Marketing
Act uh allowed to establishment of four
additional Regional plan introduction
station that including the northeastern
project we call the ne9 at Geneva New
York in jly July
1948 which is become currently the
vegetable crop repository in
Geneva uh here just showing you a
diagram this diagram is a little bit old
but basically uh give you some idea of
uh the center of orange or uh Center of
fruit for a lot of uh fruit we consume
Uh current day uh except some of the
small fruit uh is native to North
American North America otherwise
majority of the food that we consume
actually come
from other part of the world for example
Apple uh is actually should be more
Central origin in this area uh is from
Central Asia and that's why we need to
uh conduct exchanges also exploration
trying to collect a lot of ger plasm
from other part of the
world uh here are some of the pioneer
that involve with the plan roduction uh
the first two person on the top is David
fch child and Walter swingo they are the
two gentlemen in their 20 actually
established the section of plan
introduction in
1898 uh neilas Hensen is the first plan
Explorer uh he introduced the first Pi
back into the US and uh famous Frank
Meer uh spent a lot of year in China
doing a lot of exploration uh was and
popy uh he is actually avocado playing
Explorer uh spent a lot of time in the
Highland of Mexico and guadala and later
in Central America and Caribbean
interesting part is he also aspired for
the National Security agent during the
World War
II uh later in the 60 Professor omo uh
viticulture department at UC Davis
collect a lot of variety from from the
Mediterranean region of course Dr
Charlie rcks uh Mr tomato uh spent a lot
of time and the and is collecting all
the wild um tomato ger plasm a lot of
those material actually also have a copy
uh at Geneva current
day uh here's just a diagram showing
some of the
location uh for a lot of ger plasant
stations throughout the United States um
you can see we basically have a lot of
different location uh unfortunately we
used to have a location in Palmer Alaska
and that station due to the budget issue
was closed down 3 years
ago uh some of history about how the
Geneva Colonial repository came about uh
basically in 1974 there was a American
society Horticultural science workshop
on the topic of conserving fruit and not
crop was held in Gulf Ontario Canada in
1974 and later books and the Barton uh
based on that meeting uh they describe a
plan for colal repository that they
argue that really have a different needs
uh than those than the common sea
repository uh therefore from that
discussion and planning uh in 1983 Bill
surmac who is a supervisor for fun
operation was hired and came on board
and uh a year later in 1984 Phil Forin
who was the first curator was also came
on
board uh for the Apple the malice and
also Coral hotti grape the vitus uh
propagation actually started in 1983 and
the first planting was uh was in
1986 the tar Cherry collection was
originally actually housed at the Davis
repository in California but it was
moved to Geneva in 1995 for better
growing
environment uh in the USDA uh our
Research Unit actually uh divided into
different unit uh we have two units at
the Geneva uh first one is the plan
Genetic Resource unit uh under that we
have uh three different uh project plan
the first one is a sea crop all the
vegetable crop uh second one is the
coral crop apple cart grape and tar
Cherry the third is actually Apple Roa
breeding program uh leading by Genero
fossil uh then the other Research Unit
is the grave genetic research unit the
ggu uh they working on Grape genetics
and also genomic of
grape uh here just showing you some of
the picture of the colonal collection uh
throughout the year uh this is a view
from uh 1985
uh we basically uh it's about 2 mile
from the Geneva campus uh this part of
the marcari farm we are occupy McCarthy
South and this is about 50 acre uh you
can see that picture taken in 1985 there
start some Nursery operation over there
uh
20 22 year later uh this you can see at
the same location but uh just from
opposite direction uh the picture was
taken uh we basically have a lot of
grape and tarch area all the way in the
back and also a lot of
Apple uh the slide below just showing a
lot of different picture diversity of
material for the malow we have in your
collection and also some of the vitus
and tarer they just have a gorgeous
color during the Four
Season uh the mission of the colonal
repository basically throughout the
entire system basically a four basic
Mission that's a similar mission for all
the repositor first is trying to acquire
second is trying to preserve and the
third is trying to characterize and the
fourth is trying to distribute all the
ger plasm we have but each repository is
a little bit different uh for our
acquisition uh we basically we trying to
get materials through exchanges and also
exploration uh basic on the worldwide
basis uh for our preservation purpose uh
we have a field collection of trees and
also we have a coold storage of a seed
most of wild wild g g plasant seeds also
we have we use acquir preservation of
dor and bwood at the USDA National
Center for genetic resources
preservation unit uh for colum Colorado
uh from here on we'll call them the four
column and also for characterization we
use a morphological method or genetic
method trying to study all the assession
we have and all the information uh from
our uh study
uh basically a store at the ger plasant
resource Information Network database we
call that
grin a new version of the grin should
become come on board uh this year
sometime it's called grin Global
supposed to have a better function uh
but it's quite a learning curve trying
to change into the new system uh for our
distribution purpose uh that's the major
difference between the clonal repository
versus the C repository uh basically our
main distribution material at the dorant
bwood but we also distribute summer
bwood but for research purpose we also
distribute pollen fruit uh flour fruit
sea leaf and also a lot of DNA sample in
recent year basically free to all the
stakeholder and researcher both in the
United States and also worldwide also
another very important uh function of
the distribution is trying to in
increase the public awareness of the
value of the genetic resources we
Preserve
from the ear early on uh the basically
the establishment of the collection uh
because the location at Geneva so for
the Mal collection basically we just
knock on a door uh of Dr Roger way that
was the Apple sign breeder at that time
uh we got all the donation from all the
Geneva uh Apple breeding program uh
basically been going on for over 100
year at that time I got a lot of
material from Dr Roger way at the same
time but we also get a lot of material
from other breeding program in the
United States such as the P program that
stand for the Apple breeding program uh
among the three campus Purdue University
rockers and also University of Illinois
we also get a lot of material from other
campus and also from agricultureal
Canada we also get material from England
National Collection at the long Ashton
research station and also material from
several different other countries uh for
the vitus collection BAS basically we
started by donation from the also from
the Cornell great breeding program at
that time was Dr Bush R who is still in
charge of the program we also get some
additional material from UC Davis
University of Minnesota South Dakota and
several other
places uh today I'm only have time to
talk about more about uh the malos wild
ger plasm
material uh here is a diagram kind of
map showing uh worldwide where the Mal
of species distribute uh as you can see
there are four different species in
North
America uh there's two species in Europe
the sylvas malastas also malos fortina
there are two wild malos material in
Central Asia the males oralis and also
sasi and as you can see in Asia
basically most in China also some in
Japan and other places they just have uh
more than probably close to 40 to 50
different species and the hybrid species
over there uh basically in general
that's a
consens consensus that malas actually
originate from Central and southwestern
China and then throughout history
especially especially through the srow
material actually able to reach Central
Asia eventually went to
Europe and the how the material came to
North America actually was believed in
ancient time during the during the Ice
Age actually there's ancient land bridge
between the North America and Asia so
the material actually came the other the
the other direction came to North
America and the common modern Apple uh
we consume is a Mal domesticat it's a
deploy species with the SAT chromosome
34 um it it is strongly believed that
the origin of modern Apple actually came
from mother
Mali uh there's also some parentage
involved with maybe orientalis uh maybe
some sylvestris uh the question still
being
debated the next phase of the malice
collection uh at Geneva was I consider
was expansion phase of the collection uh
especially through a lot of exploration
activity from the from the late 80 into
the 90s uh the first expiration was
Professor Weeden of conal University he
went to uh the West Coast uh of North
America to collect a lot of Mal of fuska
in
1987 uh later the uh graduate student uh
Elizabeth Dickinson uh for her C's work
uh he she collect a lot of material in
eastern US also in the
midwest uh three different species angap
Foria coronaria
Andes uh from 1989 on Professor herb
alko once again together with uh
Elizabeth Dickinson and also with
curator Phil Force sline they went to
Central Asia four different country to
cide
Mali uh four different time uh then in
1997 uh Professor Alo to get a field
Force line they went to collect seven
different Malo species in China uh in
the southwest China The suan
Province uh later uh in 2001 Gabel from
Germany went to the same place to
collect similar material uh there were
extensive exchange material between the
two
exploration uh in 1998 uh Field Force
line together with
uh uh Professor Amy arizoni from
Michigan State University they went to
Russia to collect a lot of material
including malas orales also some other
materials such as tar cherry and some
other Cherry
material uh in 1999 Professor aleno
together with Fi forine they went to
Turkey to collect malas oralis later um
in two uh in 2001 and later um Joseph
Postman from Koval uh repository went to
Armenia and Georgia collect a lot of
different species including malos orent
Talos
again uh the malesia exploration in
Central Asia has a very long history
a lot of Russian scientists they studed
the wild Mal G plasm material in that
region as early as uh I can find out was
1796 all the way into the
1900s uh the famous PL geneticist uh
Nicholas ivanho vov of Russia he first
explored the wild Apple forest in
Central Asia basically in
1929 and in 19 also 1929 uh West over uh
who was a planning for was sent by USDA
to uh Alma at alata uh Kazakhstan uh
translation means the father of the
Apple uh also in 1929 met up with uh
Balo and explored the material over
there and uh in the 1990s uh Professor
Dango uh of kazakstan Academy of Science
with uh his colleague they explore all
the wild models G plasm material in in
aazan uh from the 1950 all the way into
early
2000 there was a extensive review uh was
written in
2003 here's a picture from 1929 uh this
is West over who came from USDA uh this
is uh vov and they met up in in Elma uh
basically uh in kazakstan looking around
the Mal sesia material in that region
and then BAS basically 60 years later uh
another group of USDA scientists from
Geneva went there to collect the
material also something interesting I
dig up a little bit uh vavo actually
came to gen uh came to IA in 1932 for
the sixth International Congress of
geneticist genetics he was the vice
president for the society at that time
there is basically who is who in
genetics uh both animal and plant
genetics were all in that meeting
including barara MCA
uh also in that trip he also went to
Geneva he actually um presented two
painting of wild Apple from kazakstan
and Quan uh to Professor Willington of
experimental station also in 1932 these
two painting actually still being
preserved at the Lee library in in
Geneva I just wonder anybody recognize
the building on campus uh maybe he's
still there maybe not
so uh quickly I want to make a pitch uh
why do we need to collect also preserve
wild germ plasm material uh from the
wild because a lot of wild ger plant
also native habitat a loss due to
Agricultural Development also uh also
changes in agriculture change uh
practices also a lot of Urban
Development issue uh a lot of animal
grazing environmental deoration is a
serious issue such as a Sol erosion
reduction in water Supply and quality of
course the climate changes such as
Greenhouse Effect and
deification also a lot of wild CH plasma
material also is is being threatened due
to new p and diseases also a lot of time
also invasive species into the native
habitat also a lot of time plant
biodiversity also being reduced because
agricultural intensification also
agricultural Comm modernization for
example uh for the worldwide avocado
trade uh basically 95% all the trade
just rely on single variety the has
avocado uh similar uh for when you go to
most of the supermarket outside in New
York you probably only find about 11
apple variety uh you will commonly see
that in the
supermarket um Chen from the uh CH oh
excuse
me Chen from the uh uh Chinese Academy
of Science uh they did a survey in 2009
they basically compare the native range
of
maloi in in Shin Jang China uh compared
with the survey was done all the way
back in
1959 basically it found out in
comparison between the two uh in the in
the time frame of 50 years 80% of the
Native habitat of malesia was lost uh
due to Agricultural Development animal
grazing a lot of overh harvesting of the
wild fruit also a lot of top work of the
Native species into a modern variety and
also uh new Apple insect problem uh in
that region uh here's picture showing
this insect able to attack the m ofi in
the wild population and also this is a
picture from the uh Apple expiration all
the way to the left to the right to the
left uh when they did a exporation in
Kazakhstan they actually see a lot of
sheep Grazing In the wild Apple Forest
over there uh the picture in the middle
is not Apple uh but Aron trees in from
Morocco but you can see um the Sheep
really like the Aran tree over
there just trying to make a point here
okay uh here's a map showing the uh
plant exploration of malesia in Central
Asia by the pl genetic research unit uh
in the late 90 in the in the late 80
into the '90s
basically there are 12 major sit uh most
of them actually in kazakstan but
there's also s site in kazakstan us
bakan also tajan uh here is actually
China this is actually shinjang area uh
the survey uh did was about Native
habitat was actually right here in this
region here's a summary about tremendous
amount work on the exploration for
Mali basically there were four trip
together 12 our major site and based on
the phenotype they observe in the field
they actually select 44 they call
malesia Elite they got the bwood and
they bring back to the United States
they also collect over uh 894 SE a
session of Malicia from the while that
including basically over 120,000 seeds
together and over 30,000 of those seed
was actually distribute to all the
researcher worldwide and uh about 30
over 39,000 of the sea actually still
being store at the for colon and over
50,000 of those seeds actually store at
Geneva uh in the last couple years we
also have to collect over 50,000 open
pollinated seeds from malesia seeding
block at
Geneva uh we call this the Bony of
Desire seed uh for routine distribution
uh a lot of you probably read the book
by Marco pollen B your desire and uh we
got actually very routine request from
the reader uh because in the book
mentioned that field Force line is
willing to give out the sea so we
constantly actually get inquiry about
Mal seeds and that's the SE we don't
give out SE from here the original SE
from the wild collection we actually
give out the OPC uh so for the routine
distribution to the
stakeholder uh in the last few year we
actually see an increase a lot of
inquiry actually from European country
uh England Germany France uh most recent
was actually from
Finland uh here just show you some of
the picture from the exploration uh back
in the
1990s uh they basically uh throughout
the several exploration sometime they
went back to the same location at
different year to collect the material
uh Professor dangal is the major Co
cooperated cooperator uh for all the
exploration he actually came to Geneva
in
1992 and then the team went back in 93
95 and
96 uh this is Elizabeth Dickinson uh at
that time she already graduated uh but
she came back to join the
exploration uh sometime they also found
very nice phenotype in the wild and uh
they will collect the bowwood uh they
call that micia Elite bring back to the
United States a lot of places they went
to actually is really remote therefore
the only way they can get to is actually
to helicopter
right here's some the picture from the
1997 exploration in suon China uh before
the exploration Professor Lee uh who was
from the southwest agricultural
University uh he was a leading Authority
on wild Mal material in China he came to
visit in Geneva in 19 1996 then the team
from Geneva went there in 1997 uh
professor aleno over there um every
exploration is a little bit different uh
one thing stand out in that particular
exploration was uh there was agreement
that American were not allowed to
collect the fruit in the wild directly
only the Chinese scientists allowed to
collect the fruit from the trees then
the American able to participate in
processing the
material um the location they collect
the fruit was actually next border to
Tibet so it's a very high altitude so
you can see Professor Alo trying to walk
up the hill to look at the Yaks that's
the elevation about 4,000 meter that's
over 12,000
ft here's on the picture from the 1999
exploration in
Turkey uh basically you have to do all
kind of thing when you're on the
exploration trip some of them are
found
uh here basically the route they took uh
in Turkey they start with the city in
ismir uh near aanc they first they went
up north cover several location and then
they double back once again through the
north coming back to
air I mentioned sometime we collect the
B from the W and to bring that material
back to the US uh basically for
importation of Mal J plasm the B
material all the material need to go
through from foreign country need to go
through the
USDA a quarantine process before the
material can come to
Geneva uh every year we basically we
receive between 10 to 20 session from
Avis every
year in recent years on the material we
got uh uh from AIS uh that including
Mali uh Elite from the exploration also
some of the cider apple from Northern
Spain that was introduced by Professor
Ian meran uh also a lot of different
variety from different country uh you
can see basically from all over the
world uh sometime most of session when
it goes through the AIS quarantine
process they take about a few years but
there are some extreme cases especially
this case one of the Malia Elite from
Kazan uh was collected in 1996
exploration trip it only released by
Avis to us last year after 16 year in
the
quarantine uh that just uh provisionally
release so we have to wait for
additional two to three year before its
permanent release to the public so when
it's all set and down probably will take
between 18 to 19 years before this
material can be released to the public
why was that one so long in quantin
sometime baby just have some disease
issue say they need they need to clean
up again go through thermotherapy and
the
reindexing uh some sometimes just take
some time some material very
difficult uh now I want to swi switch
gear talking about the preservation of
the colal collection at Geneva basically
all the variety and the species we have
we preserve them as the life tree in the
field most of them uh for the malas and
punas each of the session we have one
mature trees we start with two tree but
in general after several year only keep
one trees for the vas each session we
has two mature fine in the field uh for
the wild malice and the vus g plas and
all the wild sea collection from the
while we store them store them at minus
20 cold room uh we have one cold room in
Geneva also one in four colum a lot of
dor and bwood for the malas also the
punas uh they under long longterm backup
storage using choir preservation
basically store them in liquid nitrogen
at 4 colon
Colorado uh we also have a block
material in our collection we call this
uh the cor males core collection that
including 250a assession uh that's
including majority of the common malus
Uh current day uh apple variety but also
other material from 42 other species and
species hybrid
I want to do a Rubio here get some
water uh for the collection we have in
Geneva we have over 80,000 ession total
uh for the Mals collection we have over
6,600 assession that including over
5,000 uh fuel assession also over 1500 c
assession um in the field we we have
several different block we have the B9
block that's the mes core collection we
also have two other larger block uh the
M7 and the E7 block that's all the
material we consider a part of our
permanent collection we also have a K1
block that's the Kazan Mal sesia seaing
block they are on their own Roots uh
it's different from the material in the
three other block they actually on
dwarfing root stock but for all the wild
material they actually on their own root
uh own R system we also have another
block we call that W3 block actually a
several different wild models material
uh they come from Armenia China Georgia
kazakstan Russia and
Turkey we also have one block of
material that including five different
uh F1 uh population from a cross between
Gaya apple variety cross with five
different model ofi all these five Mali
they actually been shown to have a
different disease resistance system so
we consider this more like a
pre-breeding population or can use for
mapping population for different
purpose for all our permanent collection
in the field uh every single tree in the
field and every single Vine in the field
we have a tag associated with each trees
uh basically will tell you which row and
trees and uh what's the pi number uh
what's the species number also the
variety Cove uh for the seaing block
material we usually have a tag for every
10 trees or
so uh here just show you some of the
picture from the Mal CI wild collection
uh wild species collection uh this is a
picture uh from 2004 both the W3 block
and also the K1 block over here in
2004 uh here is a similar view uh in 200
uh s uh three year later this is a model
subi uh different species here is all
the
maloi from kazakstan well a little bit
wild Vitus different wild species on the
corner there uh here's the view from the
uh Kem K1 Block in 2012 last year uh
because they are on their own Roots uh
they are not on dwarfing root stock the
material basically are now over 20 ft
High here's picture of uh Field Force
line the first curator together
Professor
hero looking at the micia material in
the field they spend a lot of time on
those
material here's some of the pictures
showing some of the interest stuff
interesting stuff we have in our
collection for example uh we have some
of the large fed malos orent talas from
China uh it could be hybrid uh we're not
100% sure uh this material they are very
large food so they have some ornamental
potential uh we also have have uh uh
some material called malice transitoria
they also from China they are very dwarf
material also very spreading very
different from most of the wild
species um this is one one of the Mal
hybrid material called Butterball it's a
beautiful ornamental material uh it
tastes terrible
though uh we also have a small M Nursery
we use for our propagation purpose
purpose uh in our
collection uh basically uh this show a
very standard uh uh malice material in
our permanent collection uh we planned
uh over 150 new session last
year um we also have a small stew for uh
roostar propagation uh here is a very
interesting material uh it's a very
thorny juvenile material from the wild
malus hopenes from China you can see all
the thorny material usually will never
see that in commercial Apple uh this
things can puncture through the tire
basically uh for the vitus collection we
have uh basically uh most of the
material we have they are wild species
also a lot of species hybrid that means
between v vus v cross with different
wild species therefore they have a cold
tolerance able to stand the weather in
Geneva uh most of the vus V material
that's the common um wine grape table
grape and also some r and grape those
are all house at Davis repository
because the weather is better over there
we have over 1,300 a session in the
field and about over 80 C session in the
cold
storage here just another few uh of our
basically main uh Fighters collection in
the field with all the models collection
uh in the background uh here is also
another material we have in our
collection is a vus hybrid uh it's a SE
material all the best tasting material
we have in the field usually by end of
the season it just
disappear uh here's another interesting
material it's a wild species actually
from China uh Vitus p
uh PC Zaki Zaki uh this material is
actually very unique Leaf morphology
it's a very deep wedge material that's
only in two species among over 60
species actually have this type of
morphology
for tar Cherry collection is actually
relative small collection basically uh
tarer is a deploy species actually it's
a it's a hybrid material from Sweet
Cherry cross with uh some the wild tety
tetr material for example the fukus uh
the punas
fosa uh we have 130 uh session in total
tarer is actually a very small industry
owning $40 million in the US
compared with the grave industry is over
3 million um Apple industry is over
sorry two billion uh 3 billion and2
billion dollar in the US uh most of
tarer actually uh originally from
Central in the Eastern Europe and also
from Russia uh majority of the tarer
assession we have actually came from the
Michigan State tar Cherry breeding
program that's in charge by Dr Amy
arone uh we done a lot of
characterization for the con collection
we have uh basically all the assession
pi number all the species number uh
species name the varietal name uh the
general description of the material The
Source history uh the pedigree if
there's available also a lot of digital
imaging actually all store at the grin
database uh we also carry a lot of
phenotypic also genetic
characterization uh also some other work
such such as a chemical composition de
poity measurement uh disease resistance
gross habit morphological trait and the
phenology trade uh some of the
description about the production also
micro salary marker some of the
information we have all store at the
Grand data base uh in the future
hopefully uh we have more GBS
information the genotype by sequencing
marker data also more food quality data
also the sequencing data in the future
all the information basically searchable
at the G database
website uh for the uh I want to talk
about a lot more about the wild mest
material a lot of evaluation we have
done in the last 20 years uh tremendous
amount of disease evaluation work has
been done in the last 20 years uh
evaluate against different fire BL scab
uh the blue mod uh post Harvest Decay uh
also a lot of work on mapping of uh
resistant genes in the uh from the wild
sources uh also a lot of work on drw
Resistance evaluation also cold
hardness uh also a lot of genetic
diversity study population study uh also
using the genetic marker trying to
determ uh the core collection also using
genetic marker trying to identify
interpace hybrid also duplicate in our
collection uh we also have uh a lot of I
mentioned before uh some of the mapping
populations that could be used for
mapping different kind of
tray here I want to give you one
specific example uh about uh disease
resistance evaluation against Blue mod
uh this is work between
um the appalation fre food research
station uh of USDA at the curing spell
West Virginia together with researcher
in volcanic Center and the
pgru uh this particular session uh
actually is been shown to be resistant
against the blue Mo and they came from
kazakstan
uh in 2011 and 2012 we collect fruit
from 101 individual from this F1 mapping
population uh then we inoculate the
fruit with a penicillin expension and
then we measure the legion size 7 Day
sometime 5 to 7 day after the
inoculation there's a huge environmental
difference from between 2001 and 2012
but the disease rating across the year
actually highly
correlated uh the qdl mapping for the
bloo resistant actually being ma the
resistant to uh linkage group uh number
four here just pick showing a picture
we're collecting the fruit uh last year
in the field for the inoculation
experiment here to show you example of
11 fruit uh from uh two one susceptible
and the one resistance uh progeny you
can see uh basically after 5 to 7 day
after inoculation uh there's significant
difference in the legion side between
the susceptable material versus the
resistant
material we also use different genetic
marker uh in this particular example we
use nine microad marker to study over
1900 mes a session we have in our
collection uh we're able to identify 238
Mal domestica and also 10 other uh model
succession they actually share the same
genotype based on N SSL marker with at
least one other malice domesticat
assession in our collection uh once we
find anything with a similar genetic
profile we also trying to look into the
through image trying to confirm the
genetic study
result uh in this case we able to
identify total of 23 sport family that
including
1004 session uh in the
collection also there are some mistake
we identify also some duplicate we're
able to identify from this
study we also carry out a lot of
horiculture and food quality trade
evaluation uh in the early year uh our
unit actually devote a lot of effort
into choir preservision method
development for the malos and the punas
and also together with for Colin they
did a lot of study on long-term survival
rate of the cryo preservation uh B
material uh also in the last couple
years we focus a lot on dig digital
image of different the fruit the leaf
and flour we upload a lot of image into
the grand database we also involve with
uh polyphenolic and also antioxidant
capacity study of the vus also we're
working on the malus and the torer right
now also uh juice quality and some
specific example like the ref flesh uh
apple and also through Obsession rate of
some of the M obession we have here just
show you know different uh Digital Image
we have uh for different material in our
collection uh sometime we still have
some Shadow we're trying to improve the
quality of the photo in the near
future here just another example of a
genetic study of a red flashh apple
apple in our collection uh this study
including over 100 session uh basically
they have different kind of red flash uh
you can see for the different pattern of
red flash uh they have some some of the
ref flash actually uh localized in the
KX area some of them actually associate
with the vascular bndo uh some of them
just throughout entire cortex but not
including the core some of them just
focus on on the core region and some of
the material actually throughout entire
entire fruit so uh there's a lot of
different color different pattern also
different intensity among different
assession uh we also look
at uh the trying to use a PCR trying to
identify the myid 10 which is trans
transcription promoter uh that prey has
been mapped to linish linish group uh
number nine uh that's strongly
associated is a refresh fuit among all
the genotype but this particular uh
promoter is not uh neither sufficient
nor requireed for all the refresh uh in
all the genotype expression uh also uh
nearly all the refresh material were
able to test it actually all could be
traced back probably a single variety
isasi Anna actually is a well
potentially probably a wild material of
malici from Central Asia so all the
refres available right now it's actually
all could probably Trace back to this
single
variety uh last year we also upload a
lot of Ploy information based on flow
cytometry also some of the information
based on historic information available
from the grin we upload uh
682 uh malus domesticat and malus hybrid
PL information into the grin uh that
including uh 554 deploy material uh 17
chimeric uh 91 triplo and uh 20 tetrol
we also have flow cytometry information
for over uh
664 uh while Amal session uh from 53
different species uh deploy is uh a
little bit more different uh some of
them uh they have deploy triplo p uh
tety all the way into pent Ploy within
the same species also we basically we
have a micro satellite marker data for
for basically all the permanent
assession we have in our collection so
in principle we should should be able to
infer deploy level from the SSR marker
in the
future uh since last year we also
initiate uh the malos uh genotype by
sequencing effort uh for our malos
collection uh in this study we including
uh over
1,950 material uh from our collection in
the study that's including over 15 uh,
1400 mod
domesticat uh a lot of different wild
model
species uh all including in the study we
use two enzyme uh for restriction uh we
have 21 play in total and uh we're just
in the beginning uh stage of the data
analysis uh for each play uh we have we
able to obtain between 100 to 100 Mil
Millions G Ray per play so basically
we're doing a lot of sequencing
information uh from this study uh in
some of the initial analysis we done we
using Golden Delicious genome as a
reference genome for comparison in
analysis uh in that particular study
comparison about 40% of the sequence uh
uh actually could not be U mapped back
to the Golden Delicious genome actually
40% of the sequence we identify
I found a GBS study actually never been
known
before uh also in the future we're
trying to make comparison without any
reference genome so we can we're not
going to create any bias against
especially the wild models
material uh hopefully in the future we
can use the data trying to study a lot
of different question uh domestication
issues still there's some debate over
there the breeding history gene flow the
evolution also Gene uh trade assoc
negotiation I hope something we can do
in the future and also other issue
relate to the malice
genome next time to switch gear a little
bit talking about distribution uh for
the Colona collection every year we
update our catalog for Apple grape and
tar Cherry that's available online uh
basically all the distribution of free
of charge to the stakeholder uh here
just summary table of some of the the
number of sample we distribute in the
last 10 year as you can see back in 2007
and 2008 uh in combin with distribute
over 11,000 sample in those two years uh
in the last two year uh we distribute
over 9,000
material per year in the last two season
so that's a lot of work a lot of
material here just a picture showing
we're collecting dor bwood from the s
healing from kazakstan for Drought
resistance study we're cooperating with
uh this is about 3 weeks ago uh believe
me it was very cold in the
field uh as I mentioned earlier before
one of another purpose for the
distribution I see is actually trying to
pre promote the value of the ger plasm
material we have in our collection
therefore we carry out a lot of Outreach
education event also a lot of tool
coming to a colonal collection uh
basically during the springtime the
summertime also in the fall season uh so
far not too many people come in the
winter time uh every year for example
the print plan breeding courses um they
will come to our collection in the fall
they will come to Geneva I think when
they come to our collection they
probably have the best time uh they all
very happy they carry our food back to
uh so they all very happy to come to the
collection uh last year also the summer
scholar student at the station also came
to look at the collection uh we're able
to have Dr H bro actually talk with
student about all his exploration
experience we also carry a lot of Dr
Plaza exchanges and also visit with
other je Banks throughout the world for
example this miss yunyang her uh she is
the great curator and also molecular
Genesis for the South Korean Jin Bank uh
she's spent about 3 months with us last
year uh she's back in South Korea uh in
the future hopefully we're going to
start exchanging material especially the
wild Vitus material between the two two
Gene
Bank uh here's kind of in the summary
basically uh the shortterm goal we have
for the colal collection in the next
couple years uh first of all we like to
continue Digital Imaging of the
collection we can always uh taking more
photo uh also we are trying to finish
the evaluation of Vitus phology we
already have two-year data we're going
to do that for additional two years also
we're going to start the the malus
phology evaluation uh hopefully for the
next three years uh we're continuing on
on the food quality also in nutritional
evaluation for the malice and tar Cherry
uh the work we start started since last
year uh we also going to carry out a gap
analysis for the malus also Vitus ger
plasm material using different G uh Geo
referencing data the climate data also
genomic data when it's available uh once
we're able to finish the Gap analysis in
our collection uh we intend trying to uh
begin collection for uh more
systematically uh for the North American
vus
material uh uh which we think we really
should focus on for the next couple
years uh also potentially will probably
trying to collect additional material
from the North American and mil species
uh we have four different species in
North America I going to continue trying
to apply the GBS marker uh for the malis
and also tar Cherry genome
analysis uh probably more tra
Association analysis and also probably
potentially a Leo mining for a lot of
wild Mal and also the V Mal and tarer
material we have also we cooperating
with with a lot of different people we
continue on
uh evaluation of all a lot of wild
material of the malus also the vus
material uh based on those evaluation
result we're going to trying to select
some of the material to be included in
our permanent uh collection uh in the
next 5
years uh some of the long-term goal we
have for the colal collection uh first
of all we hope we can carry out genetic
study among our genan bank together with
Gan Bank in other countries uh hope that
will lead to Future exchange of material
in the future also trying to uh exchange
and exploration maybe the wild malus and
also virus material especially in China
uh potentially in turkey and other
places we like to complete the long-term
backa storage for all the malice and
tarch area session and trying to develop
a a very good reliable uh long-term
backup storage method for virus which we
don't have right now also additional
genotyping and phenotyping of all the
Wild G plasma material we have in our
collection we like to reduce the disease
level in our field
collection uh hopefully trying to uh
look into longterm trying to develop a a
new strategy uh for long-term
preservation of the colonal material we
have uh because we probably facing
facing a potential limiting space issue
also resources issue in the
future uh finally I want to acknowledge
all the people involved with the program
for the last 30 years especially a group
of guys I work with every day uh we call
them the 18 uh they are four guy that
actually work on a collection day in and
out basically doing all the work and
also other people from the pgru and also
uh former curator Phil forine Professor
alen Co Plant Pathology Department uh L
Robinson Jan fio of our unit and also
Folks at uh
kingville uh gvoke Chris Richard from
for Colum other people at for colon
involved with the long-term choir back
backup storage and also all the folks at
pgru and ggu and also the field Research
Unit of a conal University at the Geneva
Station uh throughout the year they gave
a lot of help also all the folks at
konal University and finally the funding
support from the national three project
project and also the inai uh Regional
experimental station founding thank
you
[Applause]
uh the question uh was has the Apple
genome be sequenced uh how we in that
case uh how I refer to Golden Delicious
how how we're going to use that uh yes
uh there's a published sequence uh based
on Golden Delicious uh that's what we
use for our comparison some of the
material uh the GBS data we have but I'm
not an expert in the area but the
discussion is um uh because throughout
the domestication history if you simply
use Golden Delicious genome sequence as
your reference genome uh we do have a
lot of wild malice material that's
probably not involved with domestication
of the Golden Delicious the malice
domesticat so if you use Golden
Delicious as a base for comparison
you're going to be biased against a lot
of wild material so we're going to try
to use gold Golden Delicious sequence as
a comparison uh but also we're trying to
do other comparison without any uh
Golden Delicious Golden Delicious genome
sequence so we're not create any bios
we're still working on that a lot of
other issue involve for example uh Tri
Ploy is a very serious issue uh poly
Ploy is very difficult for GBS analysis
right now most of the methodology my
understanding is is developed for deploy
so we have we do have a lot the polyol
material and also especially the trio
material that can create a lot of
problem so we're still working on
that uh do we have a problem with foser
disease yes we do in the field we do
have different disease that's always a
concern um but it's very difficult
because it's open fuel collection so
it's never been
clean
um and we don't really have a resources
to testing material all the time uh so
it's always a issue I do mention that um
for the foreign distribution all the
material we send out have to go through
the quarantine process of the receiving
country but in the United States uh at
least for the M that's not the
case uh the question is yeah uh the
question is if any uh plan for
mutagenesis analysis of some of the
collection uh there are some research
involved with for the vus material by
the ggu folks uh they are doing some
mutation uh to qu looking for certain
muton they are looking for that some of
the material uh but not for malice
now uh yes you're right the main disease
problem we have is a fire blight uh
potentially uh of course right now we
rely on chemical
control but that's already always
difficult chemical control and also plus
the pruning hopefully potentially we can
look into some other strategy
maybe uh cover crop for example that's a
possibility trying to hopefully can
reduce the disease level in the in the
orer but it's always a balance between
um how much resources we have what how
much we can do uh we're pretty much uh
stretch everything right now uh for the
work we have to do
so always appreciate more
help this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu