this is a production of Cornell
University the title of my talk today is
variation in Winter survival mechanisms
of wild and cultivated grape vine and I
just wanted to point out that I don't
like to work with grape Vines when
they're ugly green and filled with fruit
but I prefer to be out in the field in
the middle of the winter when it's
really comfortable and the vines look
like they're
dead but before we get into
into the actual research I wanted to
give a little bit more of an enhanced uh
introduction to myself uh as was brought
up my background is in molecular biology
and plant biology in particular but my
graduate and post-doctoral work was
mostly in population genetics and
population ecology and I worked with
cultivated and wild rice and then as I
moved on in my post stock I worked with
Bentgrass and canola and so I've had a
lot of experience jumping around in
different plant systems and always from
a population biology standpoint so I
like to understand crops and their wild
ancestors and the traits that we've
manage to select from the wild and then
use uh for crop
Improvement throughout my studies I've
always been very interested in
adaptation and the evolution of stress
responses in Plants I just think it's
particularly interesting that plants
can't remove themselves from a stressful
situation they have to adapt or they die
and so in the past I've worked on a
number of different uh stressful
conditions from the plant's point of
view including aluminum tolerance in
rice and herbicide resistance and
drought resistance in canola and B
grass the other thing I wanted to uh
make a point of is that in jumping
around in these different systems and
looking at population genetics and
population
ecology I tend to also move between the
lab and the field frequently and so i'
I've got a good set of molecular hands
but I also tend to do a lot of
experimental work out in the field and
in uh green houses like our pictur down
here on the bottom right um to set up
stressful conditions and try to model uh
how the climate might be changing and
affecting plant
growth so then I just wanted to also
introduce um the USDA ARS ggu or the
grape genetics Research Unit uh we're
based up on the Cornell extension campus
uh in
Geneva inside ggu we have two major
research programs uh which are titled up
here we have a a research program
looking at improving grape root stock
and Scion Pest and disease resistance
and a second program called the genetics
and genomics of grape growth development
and quality this is the program that I
work
in inclusive of these two programs there
are five research scientists with
Associated support staff uh gang Jong is
our research leader and he focuses on
functional genomics Lance kale Davidson
uh focuses on biotic stress genetics
particularly powdery mildew and Downey
mildew of graap Vine Chris Owens focuses
on fruit quality genetics Angela Baldo
is our computational biologist and as um
was pointed out I joined the group a
year ago and my focus is abiotic stress
genetics with focus on cold tolerance
but also dabbling in uh drought
resistance and solinity
resistance so just as a perimeter in
case anybody isn't familiar with grap
Vines um vidis venro cultivated
Grapevine is one of the most important
Horticultural fruit crops that we grow
is consumed as fresh fruit dried for
raisins or press for press for juice or
fermented in wine and actually about 71%
of the grapes that are grown are grown
for wine
production um gra Vine is really
interesting from a population genetics
and population ecology point of view
there are thousands of cultivars grown
across the world but many of them are
ancient they there was something perfect
about growing conditions thousands of
years ago
that farmers vegetatively propagated a
certain set of cultivars time and time
again and now those cultivars are grown
across the planet in a number of
different environments this is really
interesting from the point of view of
abiotic stress
adaptation we also have um a sequence
genome that allows us to start applying
molecular and genetic tools towards
understanding how traits are inherited
traits are
expressed from the population biology
point of view there are three different
Gene pools in the genus
vidus in Asia there's approximately 40
species there's about two European
species vidus Fifer is the cultivated
grape and its wild ancestors also
considered European and in North America
we have roughly 20 species and these
numbers change a little bit depending on
who you talk to but this is the general
layout of wild
vidus at the USDA in Geneva we maintain
the cold hearty grape germ plasm for the
United States I think we have roughly
1600 different genotypes uh of which we
have all the cold hearty uh varieties
I've listed some of the species here in
the bottom right and these are species
names that I'll be using throughout the
rest of my talk vus estal scaria
labrusca riparia rupestris and vulpina
and to give you an idea of the
distribution of these species I've
placed three of them on on the board
here um vus RAR is in the top left
corner and if you can see the the lime
green is a county level distribution of
where you can find rip records of
riparia so you can see it's really
diverse in the type of uh climates that
it could be inhabiting in the US all the
way from Southern Louisiana to Manitoba
and Quebec and west to east from
Colorado and Montana to the Northeast so
you can imagine a lot of different
climate gradients exist in that swath of
geography so there's a lot of potential
for wild um grap possessions to carry
unique adaptations to some of these
abiotic stresses that I'm tasked with
working on
I also put up uh Vitus labrasa and V
estal just as another comparison and
that almost all of these wild species
have a very wide Geographic range so all
of the different species have the
potential to be mind for important
traits I wanted to mention that cold
stress response and hardiness is a
really complex topic there's lots of
different traits that could be playing a
role and lots of different time points
throughout the the growing season that
cold stress could be
important it's important to note that
cold stress is tissue dependent if you
look at green tissues versus dormit
tissues what the plant perceives as a
cold stress could be very different um
Roots versus uh chots perceive uh
temperature cin drought all very
different so you have to kind of dial
down and figure out which traits are
going to be
workable there's also a vast array of
mechanical and molecular mechanisms that
contribute to cold hardiness if you can
uh remove a damaged um plant organ and
avoid uh cold shock it's one potential
way to get around uh Dam or sustained
damage or you could have an army of
molecular Sheron that help stabilize
membranes and proteins when the plant is
undergoing a cold
shock uh down on the bottom of the
screen
is my uh attempt to draw a growth cycle
which what I'm trying to illustrate here
is that as the plants go from Winter to
Spring through summer to fall and back
into winter there are different points
in the growing season that cold can
affect uh the plant survival in Winter
uh we could have very sharp drops in
temperature that kill dormant tissues
and in the spring after Bud burst Frost
unseasonable or unseasonable throst can
damage green tissues the same thing can
occur in a fall prior to plants having
enough time to acclimate and go to sleep
before the um uh the coming
winter these sort of stresses the tissue
dependence and the difference in defense
mechanisms are shared across perennial
species and there's lots of variation in
what tactics work for different model
systems but in one General theme are
these cold binding Factor genes which
are transcription factors that seem to
be activated by cold and drought um
stress and
create a molecular Cascade of Defense
responses the whole point of cold
tolerance in growing tissues is to
prevent ice formation from forming
inside of living
cells and so this is also my personal um
attempt to draw what cold damage looks
like I don't have an art degree um this
is a plant cell on the left with a um an
attempt at thids mitochondria nucleus
just imagine there's lots of different
uh plant organs or cell organs inside as
the plant perceives freezing stress it
tries to export water to prevent uh the
chance of ice forming inside the living
cell water can freeze outside of cells
and not damage the living tissue and
so um this is called the high
temperature exotherm where ice freezes
and doesn't cause lethal damage
but as temperature continues to
decrease the ice creates a uh water
gradient that causes water to
continuously be pulled from the cell and
so the cell starts to uh be stressed by
dehydration and if dehydration becomes
uh extreme you can start having
membranes fusing
together at some point the molecular and
mechanical mechanisms um that or
defenses that are mounted to prevent ice
formation within the cell fail at and
you have ice crystals form within the
living cell causing lethal damage and
this is called the low temperature
exm if you happen to avoid this say it
gets warmer water can re-enter the cell
as the gradient is Switched and if your
membranes have fused together you can
have lethal damage even though the the
plant tissue didn't freeze solid because
as the membranes re-expand they rip
apart and so you lose cellular
function so there's a whole list of
potential mechanisms to
prevent this Cascade from happening
there's avoidance mechanisms like um
super cooling transporting the water out
of the cell uh formation of sugar
glasses to keep membranes apart uh
tissue barriers as I mentioned before
there's also uh mechanisms that are
typically called tolerance mechanisms
where membranes may change their
polarity there may be chaperon imp
placed inside membranes to prevent them
from fusing with one another cryo
protective proteins could be produced to
help stabilize protein function and
compatible solutes could be produced to
uh increase the cell's AB or the plant
cell's ability to hold on to water even
when there is a water
gradient this is what it looks like if
you try to put it into molecular terms
the whole process of coal and
dehydration stress as you can see it's a
big mess green arrows uh are promoter
arrows those red repressor signs are
genes that function as repressors what I
wanted to just bring up was that you
have cold or changes in light or
dehydration some sort of external
stimuli it leads to a transcription
Factor Cascade that culminates here in
the CBF regulon remember I I mentioned
the cold binding Factor
genes these genes activate a whole
series of Downstream genes uh called
core genes and kin genes many of which
we don't know what they do other than
they lead to the production of
cryoprotectants and um compatible
solutes sometimes soluble sugars all
which are thought to help with that U
prevention of lethal dehydration and Ice
formation within the
cell so there's many different aspects
of cold stress and
hardiness there's dormy and reduced
deacclimation so how the plant perceives
winter is coming how it goes to sleep
and then reactivates in the summer or
the spring midwinter Bud survival is
understanding how buds can survive lower
and lower temperatures without having
that internal Ice uh occurrence and then
survival against spring and spring and
fall
Frost but one thing that pops in my mind
is maybe we don't need to worry about uh
coold tolerance if climate change is
occurring and global temperatures are
rising we just need to wait a couple
more years and then Winters will be 70
and there's no reason for me to have a
job
but if you think about the way that
climate uh change is predicted to occur
there are supposed to be more and more
erratic weather patterns and so there's
the potential for rapid changes in
temperature exposing green tissues to
freezing
conditions and this is an example of
what hap when that happens uh this is
pictures from space in uh 2006 if we
look at early April what the phenology
of the United States looks like versus
20 days roughly 20 days later you can
see that there's a lot more leaves a lot
more Bud burst in those 20 days my J
this is from space
but this is what it looks like in April
of the following
year after they've had a very very warm
month of March so phenology is Advanced
by several weeks and this must sound
very similar to what we had this past
year so phology gets Advanced a month
early then we have a return to normal
Cold Spring temperatures that wipes out
uh early green tissues and so you can
see that the the dark green has been
completely reset uh to the lighter green
showing you that there's been a lot of
damage and it's estimated that this
particular Easter freeze caused
somewhere around two billion worth of
Agriculture and Horticultural damage
impacting lots of our our standard crops
wheat Rye barley and corn and then all
of our fruit crops which they're listed
down here at the
bottom so this is the sort of climate uh
Swift changes in climate that we're
worried about as far as cold tolerance
goes this is why I should keep my
job so green tissues are very cold
tender and they can't survive long bouts
of
freezing and on grapes this is uh
important to note because grapes are
primarily fruitful in the primary Bud
the infloresence Marist stems are laid
down the year before and so whatever
bursts out of that primary bud is where
you're going to get your fruit and your
Harvest from so if you get a killing
Frost in the early spring that kills off
the first Bud the plants will usually
survive because they'll push buds from
secondary and tertiary buds but they'll
be far less fruitful if they produce
fruit at all so this is really bad from
the farmers's point of view and this
just illustrates what that sort of frost
kill looks
like so that's the end of the background
I was just going to now tell you about
three sort of preliminary studies that
we're conducting to try to get at
looking at Cold uh grap fine cold
tolerance so the first one's going to be
looking at dormy chilling and de
acclamation and wild grap Vine then
we're going to look a little bit at midw
midwinter Bud hardiness and finish up
with a little discussion on osmotic
mechanisms that could be contributing to
midwinter
hardiness so to start acclamation and
dorcy and I apologize if this is a
little too redundant I'm not sure where
everybody is on cold tolerant so
um as far as uh dormy goes from the
prospect or from the point of view from
the plant there's several different
stages during the growing season basil
buds are thought of as being parad
dormant which is right here where apical
buds are suppressing the growth of those
buds through hormone
control as the uh plants enter fall and
they start receiving lower temperature
cues and light temperature cues you have
a change in molecular and metabolic
status that tells the plant to start
going to sleep so this is called
endodormancy once the plant's gone fully
to sleep but we really haven't gotten to
the middle of winter here the final
stage of dorcy is Eco Eco dorcy this
occurs after endodormancy has been
fulfilled by currently some unknown
factor and the plant is ready to grow
the only thing keeping it from growing
is the fact that it's still winter so
the environmental parameters of growth
are not favorable
when those are lifted growth resumes in
the spring and so this is sort of what
the curve in dormy looks like uh
pictured here on the bottom
left uh acclamation takes place over
several months the deepest hardiness and
dorcy occurs in the middle of the winter
and then as you enter spring
deacclimation and resumption of growth
occurs at a much faster rate than the
plant took to become apped in the
beginning in the beginning of the
year
the amount of cold that the plant needs
to experience to fulfill endodormancy is
important because if the plant doesn't
achieve that magical number when you
return to growing conditions in the
spring buds will not burst synchronously
so you'll have growth occur on Grape
Vines but they'll it'll be a spotty one
bud here one bud there desynchronized
bud burst leads to very desynchronized
flowering and desynchronized fruiting
desynchronized ripening and so farmers
don't want to be harvesting grapes at
multiple time points in the fall they
want to go through and get it all at
once so it's very important to have
grape vines that are able to satisfy the
endodormancy the chilling
requirement prior to the growing season
depending on where they are so this this
leads us to this idea of a a dream grape
vine so if you're growing grapes in a
warm climate you want a grap Vine that
goes to sleep in the winter but only
needs a small winter because you only
have a small winter
and that will leading to gra vines that
will them burst synchronously in the
spring in cold climates we don't mind so
much how long the chilling hours are
because our Winters are plenty
long what we want is a grap Vine that
comes out of dormy and kind of takes its
time slows itself down because otherwise
you end up with what we ended up last
year you have grap Vines pushing in the
early spring followed by a sudden Frost
and we lose part of our crop so it
depends on where you're going grap vines
on what sort of of traits you're looking
for so what we do to assess chilling
requirement uh in Wild grap Vines is we
go out to the germ plasm uh in November
early November and take cuting right
after the first killing Frost the one
that the frost that knocks down the
leaves we collect a whole bunch of canes
and put them in a cold room at 5째 C 5째 C
is sort of The Sweet Spot for the cold
clock in grae as long as they're held at
5째 or lower they start counting towards
the end of that endodormancy we then
take the cuttings out of the cauld at
several time points during the winter
and put them in forcing conditions and
see if they're ready if they've
fulfilled that endodormancy time limit
this is just on the picture on the left
here is what the experiment looks like
it's just a bunch of cuting in a growth
chamber and we go down and assess
whether or not they're
growing this is what the data looks like
from one of these experiments pictured
here is results from the cultivated grap
Vine Cabernet svon and we have sort of a
um randomly chosen time point to assess
when endodormancy has ended and that's
at at four weeks if 50% of the buds have
burst after four weeks in uh forcing
conditions we consider endodormancy to
be fulfilled and so you can see here
that for Cabernet svon we don't really
call um the 50% Bud burst
until uh I oh yeah Geneva can't see my
pointer I keep forgetting that uh I
would say around a thousand hours of
cold so if you look at this graph the
far right line is the darkest red line
that's zero hours in the cold we cut it
from the field put it in a growth
chamber and then as you step back in
lines and in uh more and more pink color
these are time points where the the
cuting have been in the cold room for a
longer and longer period of time so you
can see that it takes about a, hours for
Cabernet soone to be ready to burst and
the other thing I want you to note is
the longer that you keep them in the
cold the faster they burst and the more
synchronous they burst so there's a
couple different clocks going on here an
ultimate clock and then one that you can
speed up over time so Jason what was the
preferred the preferred was to have
50% say that again that's kind of the
that's kind of the journal level cuto
off for endodormancy is 50% Bud burst at
four weeks in forcing
conditions that it could be a little
subjective
though so I'm not going to show you tons
and tons of graphs but I wanted to show
how we have variation within the germ
plasm samples that I'm evaluating from
the field we have genotypes that require
very low amounts of chilling so on the
top of the the slide here we have reing
and then uh wild species vidus raria
from Manitoba and you can see for both
of these cultivars that they satisfy
their Endo dorcy with very little
chilling and they um with increased
chilling you actually have with the uh
riparia from Manitoba they don't require
any start at seven days they've burst to
completion so they're very fast out of
the gates after a certain amount of
cold we also have genotypes that require
high amounts of chilling and here's two
wild species vids full pin on the left
and vidus repus on the right and you can
just see by looking at the distribution
of the lines that they require a lot
more chilling in order to satisfy that
bud burst
requirement this is another way of
looking at the data um if you look at if
you take all the cuting that were placed
into the growth chamber after 500 hours
of chilling this is how how many days
they require before they burst so it
gives you an idea that there are there
are some varieties that will not burst
at all 60 hours actually means never
burst and in this experiment so these
buds though they're totally viable don't
burst after 8 weeks without chilling so
they need this chilling in order to get
that counter going over time you can see
that they get better and better in
bursting with um increased chilling the
other thing I want you to note is that
there's a big difference between in this
example amurensis on the bottom which
requires very little chilling and bursts
faster and faster and faster and volpino
which requires a lot of chilling and
even after 2,000 hours it's increased
its chilling time but it can never
really match the speed of amurensis and
so there's got to be some genetic
control over the clock and the speed of
that
clock picture on the bottom is uh three
sessions of vidis vulpina and three
ession of vid scaria just demonstrating
to you that we have variation within a
species for the response as well and in
vulpen you can see that all three
varieties start out together the same
and then as they accumulate chilling
hours they start to diverge in their
ability to hit any particular U Bud
burst
speed scenario is kind of the opposite
in that with very little chilling the
three varieties are very diverse in
their response but then as they
accumulate chilling hours they Converge
on a set uh in this case it's three
weeks to Bud burst after 2,000
hours so this is um just to illustrate
some of the Phenix type that we're
trying to understand um with dorcy and
Bud burst rates in Wild
germplasm we want to also understand how
this might relate to midwinter Bud
hardiness this is the trait that's been
the focus of the majority of um
Grapevine breeding for cold hardiness
and grape vine breeders have typically
used vidus riparia from northern
locations in breeding programs and it's
been very successful in uh conveying
midwinter Bud hardiness and I've placed
up here two examples Mar p and front
both of which are able to survive to
temperatures of 36째
f um the problem with this may be that b
riparia sessions can be very prone to
early Bud break and I put down here
again the Manitoba sample that I showed
you before that after a long winter
they're able to break bud after one week
so in a situation where we have a really
warm March and then a very cold April
something that carries a lot of riparia
background might be more susceptible to
frost uh damage
so we want to understand how genotypes
differ in midwinter heiness in order to
um make good breeding
decisions so we assess uh midwinter
heiness using uh digital thermal
analysis which is looking at that low
temperature exotherm that I pointed out
in my cartoon the temperature at which
the water freezes inside cells signaling
lethality we do this by uh excising buds
from the field putting them in this
Nifty programmable freezer uh lowering
the temperature over time and as the
water inside the bud goes from liquid to
Crystal and it freezes there's a small
release of heat which is registered as a
change in voltage and we're able to
observe at what temperature buds die and
so here pictured um in the graph you can
see two strong Peaks here these are two
primary buds from two Bud cuttings as
the temperature U caused lethal damage
and then a very small Peak afterwards
which is probably a secondary Bud that
was still attached to the cutting
secondary and tertiary buds tend to be a
little bit
heartier so we can track these hardiness
values throughout the
season this is what last winter looked
like these are daily Min and Max
temperatures uh with the freezing point
Illustrated here in the horizontal black
line um I do apologize I flip between
Fahrenheit and Celsius frequently
um sorry about that I didn't realize
until he uh practicing this just go with
relatives we're always below the
freezing point in these graphs so what
you can see with our winter is it was uh
pretty warm in November and December got
a little bit chilly then around New
Year's we got a pulse of very cold
weather then another few days of very
very cold weather warmed back up and we
had a super warm March and if you were
to see this go you'd see our April come
crashing back down the other
side if we look at uh the DTA results
for Vi ifra cab Fran and reing um these
are the values from this past winter
this is the lt50 so if the temperature
had dipped down and intersected with one
of these lines we would expect about 50%
of the buds on that plant to have been
killed you can see good news nobody had
that problem this
winter I I should also mention that this
is all data that's been collected in
collaboration with Tim Martinson who
runs the extension on the Geneva campus
his group does all the colle ction of
the buds uh and the DTA runs and then I
do some Downstream
processing this is what it looks like if
you look at uh hybrid varieties Concord
and no you can see um a similar pattern
to the vena and that they decrease with
temperature over time uh but then they
get much more
responsive to switches in temperature so
dips uh in low temperature cause dips in
the uh DTA so conquor and Rari are able
to respond to that cold signal better or
faster than the Venera
cultivar this is what it looks like if
you overlay them just so you can get an
idea now mind you none of these cultivar
experience damage they are all plenty
Hardy but it's still interesting to me
that the hybrid cultivars are able to
respond at points when the vener cannot
respond or or chooses not to does not
respond and so I'm interested in
understanding if that is a trait that
correlates with the wild germ plasma and
if that's something that we can select
on this is a example of the data that
Tim martinson's group puts puts up for
Farmers so farmers have access to this
data throughout the winter so they can
make choices about their pruning
technique whether or not they need to
account for damage to their Vines and
you can see in 2009 2010 cab Fran and
reing uh well well below the hardiness
line needed
if you look at kug go white and Concord
to hybrid varieties you can see that
they're much more responsive in the lt50
curves and then if you look in the 2010
2011 season at again at Concord you can
see that's very reactive to
temperatures so I'm really interested in
understanding what the control is of
that ability to move the other thing I
wanted to point out is that these
changes in LTE are temperature
responsive it's not like a age over
winter it's resp responding to
accumulating cold temperature pictured
on the left of this graph graph are
riparia cuting one kept in the cold room
one kept one collected from the field on
the right is voleno same situation cold
room and field and you can see that with
the field exposure to cold the uh LTE
values for the field riparia and the
field vulpina are much much harder much
lower than if they were kept in the cold
room under those dormy uh inducing
conditions
so I want to understand what promotes
the change in hardiness and what the
physiological mechanism is behind
it this is the data from this year uh
looking at LTE values obtained from Wild
germ plasm and you can see the uh
vinifera and and hyrid genotypes are
pictured on the right hand side of the
graph in color all the black um graphs
are or bars are wild germ plasm and you
can see that it far exceeds the ability
of Vena at this early point in the
season I've colorcoded uh riparia blue
and vulpen pink here so that you can see
that there's wide variation in the
ability to uh get increased cold hardtin
within species within riparia we're
seeing six degrees difference between
the samples we're we're looking at and
in voleno we're seeing a 4 degree
difference and I'm wondering if
midwinter hardiness and deacclimation
right can be pulled apart this View
raria on the right hand here from Iowa
represents this
-7.6 level of hardiness the one on the
left from anoba represents thetive -
23.5 so the question is if you're super
hearty does that make you always de
acclimate quickly so are these separate
modules that we can select apart or or
is it one adaptive complex that's been
transmitted through time and so we got
to we're working on figuring that
out the last thing I wanted to tell you
about about was um trying to get at the
physiology behind what could be in uh
increasing the bud hardiness and so we
looked at whether or not sugar type or
concentration uh could determine cold
hardiness in these four varieties um
that Tim martinson's group works on we
have a lot of data from other perennial
systems and also from grape that
suggests that cold hearty varieties tend
to have higher sugar concentrations and
that dormant buds um
at least with uh grape tend to
accumulate higher levels of rapanos in
uh hearty buds than in sensitive buds so
we looked at the sugar levels in those
four varieties Concord no C Fran and
reing to see if there's a correlation
between their but hardiness and sugar
throughout the whole
season so the four sugars we look at are
pictured here at the bottom uh glucose
and fructose monosaccharides sucrose is
a disaccharide of of glucose and
fructose and rapanos is a sucrose
molecule with galactose added on um and
so these sort of represent a
carbohydrate pool that could be moving
back and forth uh between trisaccharide
and monosaccharide States and so we
thought maybe maybe one of these sugars
will tell us something about hardiness
but it could be that it's the flux
between the four that actually have
something to do with
it so this is what it looks like if you
look at Sugar concentrations in those
four
varieties Cabernet Fran and reing are on
the left side con and no are on the
right and what I want you to notice is
that sugars oscillate greatly throughout
the season this is the same winter
season that we just looked at but Hurtin
so they go up they go down um they
always seem to go up and down together
so there doesn't seem to be a pool
tradeoff where we have sucrose
decreasing and then glucose and fructose
increasing but that all the sugars seem
to more or less be moving together the
other thing I want want you to notice is
that Concord and R tend to have much
higher sugar levels uh for all sugars as
well as total sugar than the uh to
Vena so if we look just at glucose and
rapanos um you can see what I just
explained that Concord and no Noir have
much higher sugar levels throughout the
entire season and that resling which is
the more hearty of the two vinas also
tends to have more
sugar so it looks like the sugars are
correlated with but
hardiness um but we wanted to test this
by looking at 33 different wild
varieties to see if maybe this is just a
cultivated phenotype or if this is
something that occurs across the whole
genus because what we don't see is the
sort of correlation that you would hope
to see between sugar and uh DTA values
so pictured here on the left is Concord
on the right is reing um the the the top
colored line is total sugar and I've
just collapsed all four sugars together
because they cycle together and so it's
easier to look at one line than it is to
look at
four um so you can see how sugar total
sugar levels cycle throughout the winter
pictured behind the sugar is the daily
temperatures and then on the bottom is
the lt50 for Concord and so if sugars
were playing a direct role we would
expect then as the lt50 decreases in
Concord that we see sugars increase in
opposition if they're the the driving
mechanism we do see that the coldest
point in Concords
hardiness uh correlates with the highest
point in sugar but it's pretty arbitrary
difference between the high points if we
look at reeling um we see something very
similar lots of oscillation without
changes in hardiness and no dramatic
increase in hardiness that correlates
with sugar level so it doesn't appear
that the sugars are Dr driving
hardiness it does kind of look like
sugars are cycling with winter
temperature and this might just be
because I stare at these all the time
but it looks a little bit to me like at
least in the beginning of the winter
Here Concord seems to be cycling it
sugars along with changes in highs and
lows after our first real cold freeze
the sugars kind of depart from that
pattern and I don't know that may have
something to do with fulfillment of
dorcy or some other physiological mark
that we haven't covered
yet um so right now we're looking to see
if the sugar level correlation falls
apart when we look at lots of different
varieties with lots of different
hardiness levels um and we also need to
make a point of noting that there could
be some other environmental parameter
like our winter maybe our winter was it
was awfully warm and perhaps these
correlations start to fall apart in when
you have less severe Winters there's
lots of other parameters that we haven't
considered
yet the final thing I wanted to leave
you with is that these are all
characterization and phenotyping uh
research projects that we're getting off
the ground to try to understand which
traits are the good ones to go after for
breeding we're also taking a genetic
approach to mapping some of these cold
hardiness traits we have several
segregating populations between hybrid
varieties and wild varieties um and
we'll be screening them for chilling
requirement budburst LTE and osmolite
level
and pictured here is just an example of
what we've been able to look at so far
this is sugar level in one segregating
or one population pictured in the two
blue arrows in the bottom left corner
are the pr the parents of this cross so
you can see that the two parents produce
almost essentially the same amount of
sugar in their buds but their progyny
produce this huge transgressive array of
sugar concentrations and so we're we're
hoping to look into this some more and
see if we can and figure out if we're
starting to pull traits
apart so I was just going to wrap up
with that cold stresses um cold stress
and cold hardiness is a suite of traits
it's really complicated and we're
working on trying to pull things apart
into manageable bits the wild germplasm
that we have access to uh carries
variation in these traits and we need to
draw on those um traits in order to
improve grape germ plasm you could see
from the cold heartness that cold
heartness of Vena that
both reing and cab Fran kind of go down
in the middle of winter but they table
off so there's a lot of opportunity for
us to improve uh
Grapevine the mechanism of cold
hardiness really isn't clear at this
point sugar level might have a role in
it but it does not seem to be the driver
at least with one year's worth of
data and please stay tuned this is the
first year I'm hoping to come back
several times and tell you more and more
as the story progresses and thank you
for your attention I'd be happy to take
questions well so not with the four that
we're looking at TH they were all moving
in sync it's possible they're being
hydrolized from starch reserves we did
not look at starch um but that's the
only place that I know where they could
be coming from no that's a great
question and a great point this hasn't
been corrected for anything like that
and the the investigation into the
responsiveness for hardiness that we
just initiated that this year so
hopefully I'll be able to give you a
little bit more input on that after this
year the uh the samples that were
running include both male and female
Vines um but as you pointed out the our
germ plasm is not run like a Vineyard we
we don't control crop load we don't
control Vigor at all and so really I
need to team up a little bit more with a
viticulturist who could give me a hand
with understanding that um we could
probably deploy some things with fruit
removal in a in a Vineyard setting and
see how that affects it
but right now I don't have the answer
for you
though so the reason we kept them at 5
degre C is because that's the the
temperature of our cold room but the uh
literature on chilling requirement is
the chilling portions that perennials
tend to count begin below 7째
C and stop at zero so we want to keep it
in that sort of sweet spot for uh
chilling
fulfillment so we could definitely try
uh treating at zero over the long term
um I don't we would have to make sure
that the plants were acclimated
sufficiently so they could be held below
zero
for you know 2,000 hours but um but it's
it's a good
comment okay yeah we could do that we um
the dry weight just to give you some
background on the me method there uh we
tried processing these buds fresh what
well fresh from the LTE experiments and
found that when we tried to process them
mechanically process them and grind them
up and they were wet that we got less
sugars
extracted because of the way that the
grinding was working so we've been
freeze drying them uh in order to make
polarization easier but your point it's
good and it would be easy enough for us
to take fresh weights
um yeah I much change water content is
during the winter yeah it's it's
probably pretty slight give because
these buds are very tiny and they weigh
very little to begin with but it makes
sense that if they're increasing their
osmo lights yeah I think that's very
interesting question I don't know if um
root stocks impact Scion hardiness but
it would be neat to try maybe graph the
same s onto a bunch of different root
stocks and watch
um based on based on what we expect the
buds to be going through in Winter
they're they're more or less
physiologically sealed off from the cane
um hopefully they're responding on their
own and if that case if that's true then
I guess you wouldn't expect root stock
to contribute much except for root socks
could be contributing much through the
growing season
so we could definitely test
it yeah no I I think you're right it's
it's another trait we could be looking
at and having an impact on it I haven't
looked on it um mostly because I don't
know a whole lot about wood physiology
and it's a I'm a work in progress but um
it it makes sense that if you had
greater capacity to transport
carbohydrates that perhaps you could
elevate that level prior to Winter and
come start off at a hardier level um the
only thing I would say is that we expect
that the buds are not drawing on the
cane tissue so much throughout the
winter once they've once they've shut
down the parader has moved through the
leaves of siness we're not expecting
there to be a ton of
communication metabolically or uh
molecularly going on but we don't know
so I'm hoping for that sooner rather
than later um I don't know when the I
don't think it's so much the price point
um it's
untangling how messed up the genetics of
grap Vine actually is so if you look at
VRA it's super
heterozygous these are combinations that
were formed a long time ago and
preserved in a state um so when you
compare between varieties we run into a
lot of problems um just mapping known
genes because they move inversions
deletions this sort of thing when we
move move to the wild species you know
it just gets crazier from there I can
tell you that we're all the whole ggu
group is interested in pushing forward
um sequencing in these wild species and
we we've been working on it trying to
get some of the wild species as a
reference genome so that we can when we
do those mapping populations we need to
be able to mark U map the markers and at
this point we still lose a lot of
markers because there's no reference
location for them in Vena so we're
working on it I certainly hope it's in
the next years or
so we did the the Iowa ripar is in there
and then we also um we had one from
Quebec in that study as well that's not
South but I thought our experiment
wasn't working when I got that data um
because the Manitoba rip areia went so
quickly um we have collaborators in
South Dakota who also work with this
riparia and there riparia takes 1,500
hours our experiment it took nothing and
so we we kind of put our heads together
and thinking about that and one thing to
note is that there's chilling going on
before we get the cuting it's not a not
anywhere near 2,000 hours but every
night it gets cold it's that clock is
going they're counting so depending on
how your fall transition from Summer to
Winter is how steep that transition is
that can really change what that zero
point is and so what we came up with is
in South Dakota where you the rapid
transition it's hot hot hot shortfall
deep into
winter it counts a lot slower because it
can only count every time that comes
back above zero 0 and seven you know so
takes a lot longer under that climate
here we have a lot of cool nights so it
starts counting way before we can
actually go to The Germ plasma and make
dormant cuttings so that's what our
thought is with why something so
Northern would appear to not need
chilling at all I think it really does
need chilling it just starts that clock
much earlier than we are able to measure
so this year we've got we're counting
chilling hours prior to our zero point
to see if that changes our scale at all
um and we're doing it a across a much
wider uh swath
zero yeah yeah November 7th was was when
we did it because we we need to wait for
the plants to go dormant enough they
drop their leaves that we can go out and
cut cuttings from our germ plasm they
drop their leaves earlier than Iowa some
rip areas are are very
photo if they're if they're clock well
that's if the clock if the photo
receptor clock is tied into the cold
clock in that case and some rares are
very photoresponsive and they drop their
leaves well in advance of the first
Frost and others hang on to it and I
don't think I have that data from our
germ Plasma in this year in this year's
study we expanded the riparius to
include we have one population from
Texas so we've got excuse me Texas and
Iowa and Manitoba and we're hoping to
see things start to pull apart
there I saw it this year too uh our
Asian varieties amurensis bursts very
early and so they were all leafed out
when we had that uh that scary Frost and
the veneros were still quiet they they
were safe but I did see a lot of burning
on the stuff that had burst in our um
germ plasm and I agree with you
completely in that within a Vine you
could go out there and it was almost
like like here it took out all six Buds
and this whole Vine over here is totally
fine and then in the next Vine over it's
every other bud and I don't I can't
think of any reason that there would be
sight to sight location differences I
suppose there could be something along
the lines where certain buds incurred of
non-lethal amount of damage through the
winter which makes them more susceptible
to frost in the spring so they're just
weaker bursts and to us they look fine
um I do think the microclimate is a
possibility if you get um an Eddy or
just a local drop of a few percents of a
degree it might be enough to cause that
lethal um symptom so
yeah I'm not
sure we would have to C we would have to
categorize it right yeah
there may actually have some Clues yeah
that's ultimately what want what I would
love to be able to say I deployed was
grape vines that have green choots that
come out in the frost in the early
spring and it doesn't matter what Frost
you get they have a greater capacity to
shrug it off
so that's going to take a couple more
years
though thanks
Jason
thanks this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu