this is a production of cornell
university
thank you for coming here to hear about
the vegetable
germplasm conservation
and research at the plant genetic
resources
in geneva new york
i'm the vegetable curator for the plant
genetic resources unit at the usdars
the usda is a pla
ars national plant germplasm system
includes uh
germplasm repositories across the
country
all the way
pullman
to miami
geneva
to riverside and also we have at hilo in
hawaii
these include the original plant
introduction stations
various colonial repositories and crop
specific
collections and also some
genetic stock collections
the national plant germplasm system is a
national
or network of people and organizations
conserving plant genetic diversity
it includes both federal state and
private organizations
the coordination is by the usda ars
while most of the funding is federal
funding there is also funding from
state and private organizations
for example
the project at geneva has funding from
cornell through the
northeast nine project
and i also have different uh companies
see companies i work with like newnames
out in oregon who help with uh
regenerations of onions
the major
objectives of the national plant
germplasm system which is the same for
all the different plant introduction
stations colonial repositories
etc
is to acquire germplasm
to preserve the genetic diversity that
we have
to document and catalog this both
passport and characterization and
evaluation data
to evaluate this germplasm and most
importantly distribute the germplasm
the germplasm collections are not museum
collections but they're living
collections which are used
we have two
uh sites that are national in scope
the national genetic resources
laboratory operates the genetic
resources information network
this has all the data available from
collection
environmental data word material was
collected past
characterization and evaluation data
and this is available anywhere in the
world through the internet
we are releasing
shortly beginning october 1st a new
version of this
database which is easier for users to
access where they can actually download
large quantities of data through excel
sheets the other
major activity of this laboratory is the
plant exchange office they make all the
uh handle all the issues for germplasm
exchange internationally both germplasm
coming in the u.s
and germplasm leaving the u.s
they also arrange for collection
missions because now
with the
national rights for germplasm has come
up in the convention on biological
diversity there's many issues of getting
permissions
and handling benefit sharing for
germplasm
the other activity of the national
genetic resources laboratory is also
very important is the crop germplasm
committees
these are groups of users and other
researchers who meet with the curators
of various crops
to set issues for example what should be
characterized
what should be
brought into the collection and deal
with issues such as duplicates and
developing vulnerability
statements we also have the national
seed storage laboratory in fort collins
colorado it's a part of a larger
national center for genetic resources
preservation
but they maintain base collections of
all the germplasm across the country
in fort collins at -20
as far as seed they also do research on
new techniques for preserving germplasm
especially with the clonal repositories
right now
the major clonal collection that's
preserved is the apple collection
they're trying with using dormant buds
and liquid nitrogen vapor they're trying
to develop techniques for other
clonal crops
that would be as successful as this
technique is with apple
and they also maintain voucher samples
such as the pvp samples
and also some black box collections
where we're just maintaining them as
black boxes with no access
about the plant genetic resources unit
the national
research and marketing act of 1946
authorized four
regional plant introduction stations
geneva is one of these the others are at
pullman washington ames iowa and griffin
georgia
in july 1948 the northeast regional
project 89 was started
this was developed into the north
northeastern regional plant introduction
station
also in 1984 the apple repository was
established as a part of the pgru
it had been established several years
earlier by cornell university
and was transferred to the plant genetic
resources unit as a federal collection
and this the two of them were merged in
1988 to form the plant genetic resources
unit
so in 19 and since 1984 we've just
added
coats
hearty grapes and tart cherries to the
clonal repository
our objectives are to conserve and
regenerate plant genetic resources
accessions in the gene bank and in the
field as far as the clonal repositories
to ensure its long-term availability for
research and crop improvement
we are working to strategically expand
the genetic diversity in the collection
but also to expand the information both
passport and characterization data that
we have for these collections
we're working to both genetic do
genotypic and phenotypic
characterization
and evaluation of this germplasm to
increase the utilization efficiency
um we've started recently both
vegetable and fruit germplasm working on
quality
nutritional traits and traits that have
a health benefiting effects
but our major as with the whole
germplasm system major objective is to
distribute this germplasm
both nationally and internationally
this shows the vegetable genetic
resources conserved at geneva new york
as you can see we have a total of about
five hundred 12
eighty
half of this collection is tomato
we have both cultivated and wild this
sixty six hundred includes about six
hundred accessions of wild tomato
our other major collections are cold
crops or things such as cabbage
cauliflower broccoli etc
and onion
but we do have large collections of
squash and radish and smaller
collections of tomatillo or hus tomato
celery etc
uh most of a large part of the tomato
collection is backed up
overall 71 percent of our germplasm is
backed up and this is like i mentioned
before at fort collins colorado
our vegetable collections are basically
seed propagated collections
most of our crops except tomato
are cross pollinated many are biannual
and again except for tomato
what we actually use to produce seed is
not the product
so it's unlike other crops like
agronomic crops
we have the problem that it's not the
product that's used for the seed
production
our germ plasma acquisition
is from germplasm collection missions
but more and more
recently has been from other germplasm
collections
and some breeding programs both public
and private
but our acquisition is more targeted now
specific regions
for specific crops or specific traits
are
certain types of collection
like we have
integration populations for tomato that
we acquired from
israel that are available
and our collections are our germplasm
acquisition is user directed
again one of the major ways we do this
is through those crop germplasm
committees
they meet an average of every year to
year and a half
at various other meetings we'll have
this meeting
also we look at the pattern of seed
requests we see what kinds of
crops are being requested but
what type of traits are being requested
uh
and
this is what we're using to
direct our acquisition efforts
just wanted to show
here is the u.s
and this is
origins for various vegetable crops
you can see that this shows the
importance of the germplasm collections
that we do have in the u.s
and one thing you need to point out
especially in this area
and some of these areas
it's very difficult to obtain access eve
to collect germplasm
are to get germplasm back to the us from
other germplasm collections it's very
difficult to access this germplasm now
with the convention on biological
diversity so this stresses the
importance of what we have and
maintaining it
this we did have a collection since i've
been here in mexico
you can see some of the genetic
diversity here with tomatoes tomatillo
and some beans
our collection this is a cultivated crop
i had previously been involved in about
35 collections
when i worked at jakarta
working with food legumes but the
principles the same oftentimes you go
with cultivated crops to the field as
they're being harvested to collect so
you know where the region is
but sometimes you go to local markets
which are higher probability that the
crop that's being sold is from that
region
so if you go to a local market in mexico
like puebla
you're probably getting uh crop it was
grown real locally but if you go to the
mexico city
if you go there to a market that that
crop could have come from anywhere in
the country
just an example here with tomato how
germplasm
the tomato originated in brazil
i mean in the andes area
it went to south america in the 1500s to
europe
the original tomato
germplasm in the u.s came from europe
not from the center of origin or where
the crop was domesticated
and then in 1930s
usda collectors and then later cm rick
at the tomato genetic resources center
brought a lot of wild species germplasm
into the u.s and this has been
integrased into the populations
for various traits such as disease
resistance
and other
pest resistance
again
some of the geographic origins of
brassica here are where you see the
leafy vest the leafy ones
cabbage
down in italy broccoli and cauliflower
and some vindications of early
domestication in the mediterranean
region eastern part of it
here is an example of a very uh
difficult
to accomplish but we've done it
germplasm exchange with china recently
we received
actually just about one month ago 84
accessions of
chinese cabbage radish and buckwheat
from china
this is our first official exchange
since the early 1930s with china for
germplasm
and this is a direct result we had sent
broccoli and cauliflower
to china in 2012.
uh
and they were very excited with it and
they led to them inviting myself and the
research leader
dr zhang
to visit them at their expense in
september last year about this time of
year we had many discussions there
with the head of germplasm exchange at
the caes
about bilateral
germplasm exchanges
and we've also recently sent germplasm
of radish in the tomato core collection
to china
and in about 10 days we expect to have
the
vegetable curator from the institute of
vegetables and flowers in beijing
visiting us in
geneva new york
and they want to discuss further
bilateral exchanges of germplasm the
discussions are also going on for the
fruit germplasm but we've already
brought in
vegetable germplasm
this is myself and dr zhang we are here
with the head of testing laboratory
testing
at the chinese national gene bank in
beijing
we also went to honshu this is the
they're growing out here as you can see
this is the broccoli and cauliflower we
sent them
they were very anxious that we go down
and visit that
and they're
asking us to come back in the spring
of next year because they hope to have
this in the breeding program full blown
in their breeding program
uh it's about two or three hundred
kilometers from the honshu in the same
province
this is uh close to uh
hong kong
so we've collected uh
we're
increasing in the exchange of germplasm
the lady here in the red blouse
her name is dr mia tao
she's very instrumental in getting the
germplasm that we did in the u.s
and we're working out protocols with her
that
once germplasm is brought into china
once
that they're going to be maintaining it
and when i receive a request for the
same accessions
i will transmit it to her
and then they will do they won't have to
go through quarantine they'll just
distribute it from the chinese national
gene bank
and they were very
open to this type of distributions
and so
she said that if they get a request for
what they've sent to me from the u.s
they will do the same
so we're hoping to expand this germplasm
exchange to other vegetables
one several concerns we've had with our
collections are gmos
they're difficult to put in the
collections because first of all it's
not one patent there's a series of
patents and it's very difficult and we
don't want to keep track of all the
different patents and what's still in
place
because it only takes one patent to make
it
non-distributable the other
even more important is the concern about
contamination of
gmo and non-gmo accessions
to the point that we had an inspection
in the office of inspector general
vis we had inspectors come to us several
times
and go through all our list of
accessions and actually go through the
gene bank itself
looking to make sure that we didn't have
gmos
the other concern we have is problems
with ipr issues
because these affect what will go in the
collections the mtas
and they may reduce uh to less germplasm
mentoring
intellectual property rights
and i'll give you a small example of
this
darth dr martha mutchler has double
haploid onions
she was done with them
she really thought they should be
available for other people to use
and we accepted to put them in the
collections
but then
cornell's
ipr office got involved
and we had a lot of negotiations
but the mta they wanted
was too much for us to be able to follow
up we don't have the resources to do
that
and so i was told by the national leader
program leader that we could not accept
this type of mta
so the germplasm
we have our finite resources
and staff so we cannot put it into
something that we can't really freely
distribute
and this is going to happen
more in the future
even though she really would like to see
it distributed and be a part of the
collection because of that mta
was not a type of mta we could deal with
it's not going in
again these mtas affect our
freedom of distribution
the convention on biological diversity
is affecting collection missions and
getting permissions
the plan exchange office i mentioned has
a lot more work nowadays for germplasm
collections
we're worried about uncontrolled
uncontrolled growth of the collections
we have a finite resource for storage
for regeneration for characterization
we're trying to avoid duplication
both regionally locally not
internationally
but
because of the problems it's becoming
more and more difficult to distribute
germplasm internationally
because of uh intellect uh
property rights
also be uh
i didn't mention before quarantine is
becoming so restrictive in some
countries
that
it makes sense to have duplication so
that you don't have to go through this
quarantine
because they're in some countries like
australia i worked with when i was at
icarda
they gave me a hundred and twenty
thousand dollars a year to work with
fava bean germplasm to screen it for
disease resistance because it cost them
about eight hundred dollars in accession
to bring it in
so it was cheaper to pay us to
to go through the whole collection and
get the score so they only brought in
what was needed
and they provided pathologists to help
so quarantine issues are becoming very
important for germplasm distribution
also
our crops are stored in geneva at minus
20.
so we maintain our collection at -20
which helps a lot in maintaining the
viability it's also backed up at -20 in
fort collins
our crops as i said before are mostly
cross-pollinated and many are biannual
so we use cages
and we have bee hives for pollination
this shows here a cage
the cages we use this is in brassica
here
beehives we use the cages we've rented
we just use rented highs because the
economics worked out much better for us
we do do some hand pollination
when we have
squash
with small numbers of plants it's easy
to do it with hand pollination
just an example this is some broccoli
and tomatoes from this year this
broccoli here actually is one that we're
working with thomas borkman this is
actually his his uh population he's
working with with this scri grant
again brassica
we we plant cabbage
about the beginning of august
then in november dig it up
store it and then in early fall set it
out for seed production
again with some of the vegetable
leafy type
brassicas we will have to actually take
them to the greenhouse
our poly house after the
have been grown in the field because we
can't store them over winter
another issue short day onions
here's what short day onions look like
grown versus long day onions in geneva
new york
you can't get them to really bulb
and if you brought bulbs in here
they wouldn't flower
because of the need for short days so we
have an agreement with new mexico state
university
and provide them funds to assist us in
regeneration of the short days
the main concerns we are concerned with
with
regeneration
is loss of genetic diversity and loss of
genetic identity
we're also concerned about producing
disease-free seed
and also
our brassica and allium is one of the
main reasons we went to minus 20 because
their shelf life is much less than say
squash or tomato
our major another major activity is
characterization of germplasm
this field is in charleston uh south
carolina
well we we work with breeders a lot with
collabora uh in collaboration for uh
characterization i've worked
many agreements with philip griffiths
looking at radish broccoli and
cauliflower for example
we have a minimal descriptor list we use
for these crops
highly heritable traits and we're
working to increase the
efficiency of utilization of the
germplasm
and increasing
we have an increasing importance of
quality in the past five years
again cg we have this minimal
descriptors list have been developed
on the advice of the cgc's we're working
with
and we've implemented this as part of
our characterization
one other thing
as part of our regeneration
and also regularly now we take digital
images
that was a strong recommendation from
all five cgc's i have
again we do molecular and
quality evaluation
this is a type of
image that we take for onion bulbs
this is what was strongly requested by
the allium cgc
again a
different type of image done with tomato
this one just happens to be one of the
stuffing tomatoes we have
some of them
look like a red pepper bell pepper when
you see them in the field and people are
surprised when i cut them open
that they see
tomato
the quality characterization has become
more and more important
uh we have already
put quality as part of our
characterization within our regeneration
process for tomato
i've i'll show you later a tomato core
collection and we've worked on
multi-year
multi-site evaluation of quality for the
tomato core collection with a number of
collaborators
and we hope we're starting now our next
five-year project plan
and we're hoping to expand this to crops
such as onion
and squash
just the nutritional characterization
a standard preparation of samples which
are stored at -20
for later evaluation
for we have an automatic titrator here
for uh
titratable acidity colorimeter for the
lycopene
we measure vitamin c with the kit
we also have worked with the
chemist at the ars in albany
california
for his samples with secondary
metabolites
instead of this they're doing the prep
of the sample on liquid nitrogen in
liquid nitrogen at a cryo station
our core set as i mentioned i won't go
over each one but they're basically
different land races heirlooms a group
based on
the geodiversity
fruit shape and then we have
50 we call obsolete varieties these are
where we could
we tried to trace them down to the 40s
50s 60s
70s and 8 80s and 90s where we had pvp
certificates or information other
information that they've released in
these decades
again
we have something from ohio state tomato
analyzer to look at the
various morphological traits of tomato
it measures a number of traits
this is uh with heirlooms
several quality traits
and we found two lines fonzilla
and this one is something called avr
avrd6
which stood out for
several of the traits compared to the
other accessions
and the same there were duplications
geodiversity land race heirloom they
don't add up to 184 because some are in
several groups
this avrd6 was in another group with the
geodiversity
you can see it it's high for all three
traits
and then again
that we found
significant
genotype effects for
these quality traits
one thing that we did
was look at the different decades
accessions from the 50s 60s 70s 80s and
90s
we did find a fairly strong with bricks
a trend of reduced bricks
from the 50s through the 90s
and some type of indication for vitamin
c
very small indication with titratable
acidity
so there has been a reduction
for sure in bricks and vitamin c to some
extent
we took the 10 we have more data for the
10th and the 1990s
and what we did was canonical
discriminant analysis and what we had
here was two
years that we grew them
so for the morphological traits
that
the ten
gave exactly they
were right on top of each other for the
morphological traits
the morphological traits were very good
at distinguishing these varieties from
each other
and while the quality you can see
they're not right on top of each other
they were fairly repeatable
as far as the quality traits for these
ten varieties
we also did a discriminant
and what we were looking at here was
bells gourmet and red bear stick out
from the rest of them
and the reason they do this
is for the morphological was
size
traits
they were very different between the red
pair and the bells gourmet
the bell's gourmet
you get fruit that are like three pounds
it's really
huge
the red pear is a very small
tomato
whereas here with red pear and belle's
gourmet looking with the quality traits
what we noticed the difference was
the different acids
the red pear was double the acid content
of the bells gourmet
we were just trying to see which traits
and that's what showed up here
for the quality factor analysis
the first factor was traits the sugar
the second factor was these
acid traits citric acid malic acid
titratable acidity
joanne lebate the molecular biologist
looked at these 50 populations that we
had
for
18 snips
and what she did was divide them up
differently she divided them up into
private breeding company
varieties and public varieties developed
by
universities
and basically there wasn't much
difference between the two populations
it was
there wasn't much difference whether it
was public or private they showed the
same
values in the snips
another
uh work that we're starting on a new
project plan is the gis or geographical
information system
and what we're looking at with there are
a set of species
new species the the new
monograph on tomato
salanum peruvianum
has been divided into four species
including peruvianum arcanum
carnellomerlii and julia since
and we were trying to see
the geographic distribution of these
species
and also to see
how it could we distinguish these
species with markers
and she used some uh snips some
genotyping by sequencing
i had uh 14043
snips
and what she did was took the red boxes
this is distance geographical distance
and the
vertical axis is genetic distance
and what she did was uh intra specific
so that would be like
a saline saline improvianum and a slant
improvianum excessions two accessions of
the same species
whereas the blue ones are
two accessions of different species like
peruvian and arcanum
so what you see here with the red ones
the further they are apart
physically there's not a relationship
with the genetic distance
but you can see there is a relationship
of genetic distance and geographic
distance
for the
inter-specific pairs
so this shows as this the species get
further apart
they're more distinct from each other
and
this is shown when you try to
taxonomically key these out which we
took all 200 and did
we ran into problems and i think you can
see that if they're close to each other
in geographic distance they become
more close in genetic distance and it
becomes more difficult
she looked at him in a with a heat map
basically
some species are easy to tell apart
peruvian and arcanum
so here the this is the frequency of one
species or canon and this is the
frequency of the allele
and uh uh
peruvian
so the darker this is the number
the greater the number
of alleles
so you can see a pattern like this
so it's
these two species are separate are
easily easily more easily separated
whereas peruvianum and cornell myrlie
which is what we saw in the field was
very difficult to tell them apart
you can see with the snips
that there's not this pattern which
would distinguish them from each other
as far as allele frequencies
again she used
the same data
here is our canon
fairly easy to separate it from the rest
and then the rest of them were up here
except
julia sense
we had a number of these that we could
tell right away
but some that were more difficult and
that was these
so the species taxonomically
that the taxonomists have made
you run into problems with certain ones
and it's probably because of gene flow
between the species
actually telling them apart
again with characterization
and evaluation we're concerned about
importance and heritability of our
traits and reporting disease scores
consistently
replication both in time
and environment
also we have like with tomato we have
multi-location multi-year
evaluations and comparisons
and again as i mentioned
with not only at geneva but at other
plant introduction stations repositories
there's concern about quality nutrition
and health benefit traits oops
two
we work with outreach and training and
germplasm conservation and regeneration
with markers and seed production and
seed storage
for characterization and evaluation
and we do have outreach efforts in c
production for organic production both
processing and actual control
pollinations
and we've worked with demonstrations and
field days
we've had three projects the public seed
initiative
which was ifas funded
and the organic seed partnership and the
northern organic vegetable improvement
collaborative novik
those have been funded by the
orei the first two were with dr molly
john
the novik the last one has been with dr
michael missouri
as a collaborator
the novik again is uh cornell is part of
that oregon state with university of
wisconsin washington state
also uh ngo the organic seed alliance
and ourselves the usda
this northern organic vegetable
improvement collaborative
is working as you can see here we're
working with seed production
seed processing
also we're looking at testing of organic
varieties on farmers fields under
organic conditions
so that they can grow varieties which
perform best under their conditions
and the breeding programs have been
working on uh
besides disease resistance also
extending uh the season
like with sweet corn making developing
sweet corn which is more cold tolerant
at the seedling stage
here's uh at pgru working with some
people with uh training and seed
cleaning
we've this is a public seed initiative
we were at a the organic field day here
at freeville
two weeks ago
my staff and i were at the organic field
day again in freeville
we also go
regularly to the common fair grou ground
fare
showing different aspects of seed
production
and providing information for different
uh for producing seed not only
processing but pollination control and
so on
we'll be going there thursday this week
again
here is a student who had recently
graduated from rit
an adult student who had finished
recently
and had further training with us and
two weeks ago
she was hired at a laboratory in
rochester
finally the distribution of the
germplasm
is worldwide both to the u.s
and to the internationally
35 to 40 percent of all the samples i
distributed are out of the u.s
so we do a large amount of germplasm
distribution outside the u.s
we try to do it for breeders other
researchers where there's a valid use
for the germplasm distribution
we distribute to non-profit
organizations other institutes and
universities
just the example a large amount of our
germplasm is tomato as you can see here
look at these totals we start 2008 35 15
in their
last year 14
and with sequestration
and not being able to fill positions
this has been very difficult
dealing with these uh distributions
uh
and there's not just
small distributions there have been
we've provided south korea with whole
collections of our germplasm like the
whole tomato the whole onion collection
larry
a question
in the last four years it
has gone up like four holes
yeah
so what what was it like before 2008 was
there i mean what
it was around three to four thousand
every year before 2008. so why has it
grown so much been in the last four
years well one thing was and we cut it
out some of it was these non-research
requests
we were giving that to them and saying
we won't be able to give it to you again
but we've had a number like nunum seed
has asked for our whole onion collection
and whole tomato collection
and i told them why do you need it now
they said we're worried about access in
the future i said i just can't do it
you're good and so they provided me
they came themselves and helped take the
seed under our supervision
so they came and actually did it
we've been repatriating germplasm to
places like south korea where they give
a list of stuff they think
originally came
then they uh
there have been companies doing
large-scale screenings like onion for
irish yellow spot virus resistance so
these have what have increased our
distributions
some of our problems is the
this germplasm is distributed freely but
there are
increasing numbers of non-research
requests does that mean farmers
we don't provide to farmers
well we get a lot of gardeners
and private individuals saying they're
going to do research
and what we've done is basically
telling them where they can find
seed that's more appropriate to them
we used to a lot of the sites in the
germplasm system used to say okay here's
some of what you asked for please don't
ask in the future these are where you
can go
now we've taken a very hard
stand that if you're not if we if i
don't consider it invalid use we send a
rejection letter
most people accept it
uh some complain
and then of those probably
one out of ten who complain i'll re-look
at it and give it to them
other issues are our costs for shipping
and vital sanitary certificates have
really increased
and we've been requested to provide
certification as gmo
genetically modified as being
free of that
because of national policy i cannot
provide that
i cannot provide a letter that says that
we certify as gmo free i cannot provide
a letter that says to the best of my
knowledge there should be it should be
genetic
gmo free that's national policy it's out
of my hands
and then requirements of certification
is disease and virus free
because of the way we're multiplying
stuff every year we have 400 plots a
year for seed i can't do that we don't
have the resources for field inspections
roguing and testing
it's just too much
we ask them to get a research exemption
if they want that
and then again our intellectual property
rights is always an issue with
distribution
so in summary we can serve
regenerate
characterize evaluate and distribute
germplasm
of our fruit and vegetable crops the
degradation of environments where the
centers of origin is making our
collections more important
also the lack of access to these centers
of origin
and centers of diversity are making the
collections more important now
this germplasm is you needed to maintain
and improve crop
tolerances and resistances
we keep getting more and more crops
we're asking for
quality traits not just tomato but
they've started asking for onions for
fructans for example quercetin
and we're using the gbs the molecular
biologist
and then gis
to our characterization and evaluation
i'd just like to acknowledge the staff
in the plant genetic resources unit
joanne labait
is the molecular
biologist geneticist
bill garman is our farm manager
jonathan spencer works with our bees in
characterization paul kisly with the
greenhouse
sherry tennis handles all the
database work and
paperwork for seat orders nancy consoley
works with us recently she takes care of
all the seed orders and seed
packaging and so on
suzanne scheffer in the green
laboratory and now field
characterization
suzanne zweiker is a was a trainee that
worked a lot with the tomato
characterization
i worked very much with philip griffis
with different characterization projects
and with michael missouri not only with
novik but also with characterization
and previously with molly john
mark farnham is the ars brassica breeder
who hasn't been involved in the
characterization andrew
brexa worked with us with the
secondary metabolites characterization
for tomato
christopher cramer is the onion breeder
short day breeder at new mexico state
has helped out tremendously
with short day youngin regenerations
jim myers heads up the novik project at
oregon state
dylan panthey has worked very much with
us
along with esther vandernaap
in the tomato
core collection quality characterization
so
thank you very much
this has been a production of cornell
university on the web at cornell.edu