this is a production of Cornell
University anyway uh I think everybody's
aware of the importance of the lakes to
the
Landscapes I think that most residents
are clear that what happens in the
watersheds is reflected in what goes on
in the lake and uh what I want to do to
today is summarize about 40 Years of my
experience with it we've got some
problems with
units and I guess I better try to get
some of this straightened out first the
volume of the lake is
about 10,000 million cubic meters if
that means anything to you it's kind of
up there with national debt and stuff
like
that if a tornado sucked all the water
out of the lake it would take 10 to 15
years for the Lake to
refill the deepest part's about 400 ft
so that gives you an idea of what we're
talking about now we're going to talk
about we're we're looking about
concentrations of phosphate which
instead of one with lots of zeros now
it's a lot of zeros in a small number uh
most of the times we talk about a parts
per billion of phosphate that's 5 * 10-
6 G per liter or it's about 5 * 10 - 3 G
per cubic me meter but please note that
most of the nitrate is talked about in
terms of parts per million which a
thousand times more concentrated than
phosphate one example that we'll see
later probably if you put a cubic meter
if you had a pallet here with a cubic
meter by the way is about a cubic yard
if you put that in the lake and
dissolved it you'd increase the
phosphate concentration by about 3 to
five parts per billion that's just where
chlorophyll concentrations commonly part
per billion micrograms per liter and if
you look at what goes on in this early
spring chlorophyll concentration
increases as a parts per billion not
equal parts per billion of phosphate
carbon content of the algae is sort of
50 to 100 times the chlorophyll
content okay one of the things that's
important to think about is the
biological activity in kugula depends on
the photosynthesis by the Aly and that
is that energy from the
photosynthesis is an
important source of energy for all of
the biological activity in the
lake uh most of the things we're talking
about the chlorophyll and the phosphate
are measured using standard universally
accepted methods all of data is online
are in two very important thesis at
Cornell so I I None of well some of this
data is mine but an awful lot of it
isn't what I really want to do is look
this is the theme inputs of streams
determines phosphate in the lake deep
lake which determines phosphate in the
cace water in the summer or spring and
that determines the alal proliferation
in the summer and we measure it by
chlorophyll so we're going to you're
going to see that couple of times 5
years ago I decided to assemble the
stream and like data from 1972 through
2011 uh since uh 1972 I'd collected
about 2,000 water samples about 2,000
Lake samples were available I had a lot
of professional interest after I retired
and I wanted to challenge my brain and
believe me this has been a good
challenge for my
brain in 1960 to for history
Environmental Quality became a major
concern at the University agriculture
kind of realized food production
Agriculture and the environment were all
tied together and the late Bob Young
assembled a team of professors Sports
docs grad students research staff etc
etc and I happen to be uh one of those
uh people and during that period 1972 to
77 it was a very very active group we
produced several thesis scientific
Publications a book a bulletin major
emphasis on the lake streamwater
agricultural economics animal science
manure management guess what rural
sociology but the whole theme was to
integrate
it we uh produced a
book and uh these are the project
authors now integration of every thing
was a
major purpose the group met for at least
two hours every second week for six
years and we had a lot of discussions
and all of everybody had to go if they
got money and Bob Young watched he no he
didn't
take take ascendant but he was really uh
a really just an incredible leader uh
there are two people here I want to talk
about one is Ray O's and of course
myself but Ray was the lake person and
we had to start early on okay so how am
I going to analyze water samples and how
is he going to have analyze Lake samples
so that once the water gets in the lake
there's not some big you know Cliff or
something like that we spent a lot of
time on that we
exchanged uh Labs samples between labs
and so on so I want to really point that
out because later it's going to become
important the other person I want to
point out is Keith Porter helped uh uh
edit the book and all of that uh Ed goad
is sitting back there Ed stand up can
you he was the guy that went out on
weekends and nights and whatever and
took water samples during
storm so anyway he's I'm glad to see him
here okay uh if we start with kind of
the conclusions from the
1977 uh thing the levels of algae in the
lake are determined by the dissolved
phosphorus present in the lake in the
early spring and the other important
issue once you get enriched algae you
can get rid of it by just getting rid of
the phosphorus inputs real question is
that consistent with 1999 to 211 and all
I want to do is just throw this up there
don't pay much attention to it you see a
lot of later I just want to see okay
here's the phosphate in the spring
chlorophyll in the summer and yeah
there's a lot of noise but it's surely
clear a clear relationship the two the
question is how did we get to phosphate
in the spring so let's start with C the
lake and its watersheds and uh this map
defines the source of the drainage and
the lake surface area is about uh 10% of
the water shed
area now we adopt it as our model
Watershed Fall Creek
for several reasons first of all it has
a mix of agricultural and Forest land
uses which is fairly typical of the rest
of the watersheds so what we're going to
do is look at what happens with Fall
Creek and we're going to extrapolate
that to the rest of the watersheds via
this idea the other important issue with
we had USGS flow data from 1926 to the
present this will turn out to be
extremely important second thing I
sampled about 100 ft above the USGS
station I walked over the sampling site
on my way to my office in the morning if
I took a sample I just put it in my
laboratory or did it did the processing
myself and that's all close to my office
and uh watersheds about 20% of the
watershed area now this is a just a
brief map of the watered itself notice
that they two BR two main branches at
Freeville it contes on North from
Freeville and then to the east it's
Virgil Creek we did other small villages
uh and population
densities
uh basically uh I think it's reasonable
to say that it's a pretty
good uh representation of most of the
waters here's the bridge at Forest or
Forest Home put
of
uh next to Forest I'm
sorry Pleasant grow Road see okay but
anyway what's important is you see the
pathway along the edge of the bridge
that's where I took all the samples I
stored my sampling tools in the
superstructure of the
bridge uh and here's uh where I here's
where I sampled from and notice it comes
through there and it's pretty well mixed
uh here's a nice winter scene a low very
low flow uh ice and snow are accumulated
in the Watershed we get a a thaw and oh
all sorts of funny things happen notice
how dark the water is there's a lot of
sediment in it there's a lot of
phosphorus in it and it's very very
important to take these samples from
steams like that here's another one this
is a summer storm uh
uh this is a picture of the USGS uh
control uh stream on a nice summer day
uh here just some Landscapes notice
agricultural land Woods in the
background uh more agricultural land
notice it background buildings and
diversity of crops and more Forest
here's a just a view across the valley
and
again uh Landscapes and uh Woods here
here's the creek above free Veil uh
notice the Abundant vegetation along the
stream notice the little Stones flat
stones that are there these streams are
pretty well uh
stabilized uh notice now that there's a
stream in the background in the middle
of this slide but look at the uh
buffering between the stream and the
agricultural land it's like at the top
of the creek here's the Fall Creek
before Lake comoo again notice the
buffering this is a Virgil
Creek and one of the things I want to
emphasize here don't worry about the
nitrate thing it's also a source of
phosphorus okay so let's get to the
data what I have here
is uh a summary from 72 to
2008 the log concentration the log of
load which is float times concentration
so that's the amount of substance or for
this case
phosphorus
uh taken to the lake versus the flow and
flow is always a convenient way to to
summarize the data uh what I want you to
notice though really is to look at the
difference in the color of the St sample
points uh the black ones are 72 to
75 the red is 2 6 the green is
2208 n what I want to conclude from this
is the loading has not changed
appreciably in the period
1972 to 2009 now statistically I presume
you might think of a model that would
enable you to do a good statistical test
my attitude is hey you know I'm not
going to go there I look at these so
make up your mind
uh if you say oh forget about it I don't
believe it but anyway we'll see this
later so how do you do well the one
thing I do want to point out here notice
the variability in loads versus one
given flow and you think oh my goodness
this is sloppy laboratory work that is
not sloppy laboratory work we've done a
lot of samples in which you take
consecutive samples within a few minutes
of each other and take them to the
laboratory and there's very little
variation
if you wait a few hours and take another
sample you get into that variability
that you see there so how do we deal
with that variability the first way is
look at load versus flow and usually you
can do some mathematics of that and you
can either Lo use a log or a linear
scale the big deal is take lots of
samples samples all seasons and years
samples storms low flow and everything
else because it takes that many samples
to really uh get what you need to know
now I did a here's another way to look
at the
data uh this is a concentration now it's
not the quantity it's the concentration
per unit
volume and instead of doing with with
flow I've done it with uh flow ranges
and these different boxes are 0 to 50
CPS 50 to 99 Etc all the way up to, 1500
to 2,000 cubic feet per second and the
last one is over 3,000 Cub I don't you
you probably looked
at box plots before I pulled one one
little thing out and pulled it over to
the left and that bottom of that
box is at the concentration that
includes
everything below that
concentration or that's the 25% of the
samples are below that concentration if
you go to the median 50% of course the
top of the box is 75% and the whisker is
90% so this is a convenient way to
summarize and what I finally did was
just do a regression of average
un uh average of the different uh flow
so this is our equation
that converts flow in cubic feet per
second to concentration of soluble
phosphorus in terms of per unit
volume you'll see this later well okay
now we've defined the load and the
concentration for Fall Creek 1972 to
2008 next we extrapolate to all the
watersheds first approximation one thing
that's pretty well documented flow per
unit of drainage area is the same for
all water sheds uh area of Fall Creeks
20% of the total area of the lake lake
shed so five times Fall Creek is equal
to
uh in input into what of all the water
sheds well you might expect an
approximation okay we're going to also
extra at the load from Fall Creek to the
whole
wed well we've Dev developed now the
loading from watersheds now we turn our
attention to how to relate this to
phosphate in the lake and algo
production now there's two things about
the lake that are pretty important to
understand the first one is and I don't
think there's any controversy about this
fall and winter the lake
cools reaches four degrees
it's mixed thoroughly by March the
dissolved constituents and the lake are
equal north to south east to west top to
bottom etc etc now during the summer
things are a little different because
the surface water warms up and water
floats on top and that's where the solar
radiation is and the algo begin to grow
and they proliferate primarily in the
surface
layer so now we conclude that the
phosphate in the Deep cold water in the
lake is an integrated average of stream
inputs over months and years and recall
that Lake deeper than 60 mters does not
mix during the summer with the warm
surface but it does in the wintertime so
now the deep water changes slowly over
years and it turns out we have a really
really
good set of data on the deep water in
the lake first first of all the research
in the 68 to
74 uh by Ray Oglesby and John
Barlo sampled the lake all the depths
all the year since then the lak source
cooling people have taken samples of the
intake for the lake Source cooling which
is deep water 60 plus meters so those
two things we know what the
concentration in the lake water has been
or something wait a minute there's a
missing slide here where is it oh here
it
is the graph on the left is the
concentration in the deep
water and the xaxis is here notice in
the upper left hand
side there's the 68 to 74 data and then
beginning 25 years l later in
1999 the concentration has dropped to uh
somewhere around four to three to four
to five and then it gradually increases
as we go from there so why this large
difference between 74 and 99 it's about
eight if you
compare
uh uh 99 and uh 210 and it's if you go
later it's about six parts per B
so why
well we go back to we go back to our
1972 to 77
data and if you you don't recall
probably uh the uh phosphate and
detergent was banned beginning in
1973 so we had spent we spent a lot of
time in all our deliberations from uh 7
2 to 77 on the impact of this on uh the
phosphate in the lake and it turns out
that detergent P this the phosphate in
the detergent was a very large fraction
of the total phosphate going into the
lake from sewed population as a matter
of fact the two together are about a
half a kilogram per cap per year
Now by
2005 100% of the detergent P has
disappeared on top of that the lake
Cornel or the itha sewage treatment
plant has removed on the order probably
a little more than half of the excreted
P so this is a if you look at just the
SE population which of course that uh
the output from the sewer plant was
going directly into the lake it was
about 40 4,000 kilos per year for the
whole plate for the 40,000 unored about
11,000 kilos P per year and the total is
about 55 now obviously these are kind of
broad
generalizations but if you look at that
10,000 million cubic meters of Lake
water that's equivalent to about 5 to
six parts per billion
decrease in what you would expect to
find in in the
lake and I think it's it's well docu I
can document all of this uh if you want
to find out about it you can read the
book uh anyway now we're back to looking
at this uh difference between 99 and
2011 which is documented by The lak
Source cooling data and notice it does
go from somewhere around 5 to somewhere
around 10 in that period of
time and so the question is what
happened well again we're back to the
lake it's very large annual puts the
water sheds varies between in 10 to 15%
of the lake volume so now if you're
changing the amount of phosphate going
into the lake in a given year you're not
going to see that right away you have to
wait in at least uh 5 years 6 years 2
years whatever what is it how can you
how can you do that well I puzzled over
that for a while one of the real key
issues is in
1972 uh the chloride in the lake had
increased to about 100 parts per billion
and uh Steve eer and his
group uh noticed that that had started
the choride started to go down once they
quit putting that uh uh the fines in the
Blake for from uh the excess of mining
it's about 100 parts per million in
1970 by 1976 it gone down to about 60
parts per million and you can see that's
kind of a gradual decrease approaching
probably the current chloride steady
state in the lake of around 55 parts per
bit so that tells us right off hand oh
okay that Lake's big and chloride said
we got problems so oh okay here things
get now we start looking at Stream
flow and this graph is 1963 to
2010 the green things are
yearly uh loading well no this is full
yearly flow data notice the black line
which is fiveyear rolling average and
how that goes through episodes of high
and low flow so now we say oh wait a
minute how are we going to average this
over
years if we sort of say hey the amount
of flow determines the amount delivered
to the lake okay so here's the here's
the approach we first of all on the far
left graph we've you've seen that before
that's chloride in the lake as it
decreases over time the second graph is
the delivery of water that flow into the
lake fiveyear
averages the next one is the
concentration versus
flow we're going to combine those the
two midal ones and then we have to see
if what we can do to get
that to finally see how that
impacts the phosphate in the deep
lake so we've got all of that together
uh and how many years no no here's where
things get a little messy maybe so look
I know what the flow is for this
history uh the concentration box plot
tells me how that concentration is
distributed as we go through flow
regimes there are 750 samples in that
box plot now we're going to say ah we've
got that that's good data so now we
start our our uh Matrix the First Column
we list the uh let me go back I think
maybe be a little clear if we start the
first column in that no I think not it's
hard to get this all tied together the
first column we list the concentration
of the de leap Lake that's for each year
1999 to
2011 the next column is the amount of
flow
are the load the preceding year the
second column is the average load over
the two preceding years third
column
is uh three years Etc it's said all the
way out to 10
years so we got that so
now here's a just sort of a piece of
Matrix got a year Lake P first year Tech
Year all out to 10 Etc
okay now we take we look at the we put
this into correlation coefficient
Matrix uh I little there little small
but let's say so these are the
correlation the the second column in is
uh uh
the correlation coefficient between the
phosphate and the lake
and the stream average input for the
first year second year third year fourth
year Etc and if you look at the
correlation coefficients first one year
forget about it uh second year it's a
little better third year is better still
finally you get to six years you get a
correlation coefficient of
089 my interpretation is
a that's the key issue is summarize
Stream flow
our stream inputs over six years and
that should be correlated well it is
correlated obviously with the phosphate
in the deep lake and I want to call you
your attention to the right hand column
which indicates the number of days in
that average now
remember the
concentration the the boxplot with
concentration for flow regimes for flow
uh
uh rate
essentially well we've used the USGS
data we know what the flow is every day
for how many years you want in there and
it's about 2,000 days go into that
six-year average so if we've done a good
job of getting an unbiased sample of
flow regimes based
on uh our 750 samples all we're doing is
just taking samples of that out and
applying it to 2,000 days so I think
this is this is this is a pretty unbi I
think this is pretty
unbiased the whole problem may be biased
estimate of how to do it but in terms of
the loading of phosphate from the stream
I think that's a pretty unbiased
estimate so we've okay we've got the
Stream inputs averaged over the previous
six years is about the best
concentration of deep water in the
lake so now there are about four
variables that we pick as really
important and this is correlation
Matrix 2000 to
2011 10 degrees of
freedom okay the first the six-year
business that's the sixe
input from the
stream the eff is the deep water
measured in the effluent from the lake
Source cooling system the lake El LK uh
APR is the measured phosphate in the
lake in April which is part of the lake
Source cooling data all the Chlor all
CHL is chloride for the whole lake or
chlorophyll for the whole
lake uh well the Corr 1% probability
correlation coefficients
68 uh obviously the chlorophyll and the
other things is sort of okay uh
particularly you want to call your
attention to the six-year correlation
with the affluent that's the measured
deep
concentration the the uh Lake phosphate
in April is not the best uh all the all
chloride in the summer is not bad and
anyway uh I think those are reasonable
correlation
coefficients considering this is kind of
40 years of experience from lots of
different uh sources of samples etc etc
uh
uh so we pretty well it's so here's my
summary of the relationships we started
out and I think that the correlation
coefficients pretty well say well yep
that's not too
bad I just summary here's SRP in the
lake in the summer versus that's the uh
phosphorus in the lake in the summer
versus uh six-year average from stream
inputs summer chlorophile sixe average
of stream
inputs there's obviously a lot of things
to be done there here's just four of
those things kind of put together all
right let's get down to the general
summary uh okay so what have we learned
the phosphate concentrations varied from
4 to 15 micrograms per liter 1974 to
2011 concentration of phosphate in the
spring is correlated with the six-year
average of phosph fate input from the
streams chlorop fils increased and
decreased in Phase with the variation in
phosphate but there's a lot of variation
that's not explained by the phosphate
this is a
multi variable problem most likely
things to look at more carefully is
temperature solar radiation wind etc etc
well I looked at that a little bit and I
decided it was beyond
my ability to deal with it I didn't have
the data I thought
anyway the second one chlorophyll
conservation has varied from 4 to 10
micrograms per liter and within the
period 68 to
2011 and I would
argue that we have covered a lot
of history of the
lake if we want to look for the guide to
the future I would say uh you could look
at the chlorophyll concentration
but uh since you go to uh other things
you can look at the deep
lake or six years or
whatever there's a lot of variability
but that's going to happen one of the
things that I I think is very very
important a lot of
people I think at least my scuttlebutt
is they look at the lake and says oh it
looks terrible it must be all that
phosphorus that went in it's all that
chlorophyll that's really far far from
the truth the reality is there have
loudest suspended silin that are
consequence of all those siment all the
settlement that's gone in with all the
storm
and that's all mixed up with chlorophyll
and if you really look at chlorophyll in
a very clean
Lake uh this the uh Lake's very clear
and it looks clean etc etc so I think
that a lot of misinformation and
whatever about the way the the lake
looks is not necessarily just chlorop
it's partly chlorophyll but very often
if you look today I don't I haven't
looked today but last two or three days
you see a lot of stuff in the lake right
that's sediment from
storms in Spring chlorofil is almost
zero and during summer concentration
varies widely believe me it's not sloppy
lab stuff they're real variations in uh
chloride a chlorophyll during the summer
uh the other thing that I think is very
very important the phosphate dissolved
in the water has no important influence
on macrofit that is the so-called weeds
those big
things uh they're usually restricted to
the shallow water less than 68 MERS in
depth so a lot of people sort of think
oh that must be phosphorus in the
lake water that's influenced in the
proliferation of those micrites well
some maybe but mostly they get their
phosphate from the
sediment so if you want to predict
future chlorophyll and algae
growth uh you can look at the phosphate
in the lake Source cooling water and I
presume Cornell will continue
to uh sample that water and we've seen
from past history what that deep water
concent ation of phosphate will do in
terms of chlorophyll in the lake so you
don't have to do all this stream
sampling uh just rely on Cornell to keep
monitoring the phosphate in the affluent
from course school if you don't like
Cornell data John hman atart William
Smith has collected and published
several years of data in far more detail
than the lak source cooling data so if
he continues his work we need Not
Duplicate
it with the future consultants and DEC
are will develop Lake and Watershed
models by 2 217 so they say there will
be a tmdl total maximum daily load
model I am the opinion that currently
the quality of the lake is very good to
excellent but the great challenge is
invas invasive species do we know how to
manage them oh very good thank you any
questions
comments this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu