this is a production of Cornell
University okay so my training is as a
plant systematist and I'm speaking on
ethnobotany and I guess I will just
preface this talk
saying I have some credentials in the
ethno part of this since I have an
undergraduate degree in
anthropology and I crossed over and
through ethnobotany and tooty became
totally confused by all the plant names
and uh made a career out of it and later
in my career I had some opportunities
being in Oklahoma and collaborating with
paleo ethnobotanist and other
ethnobotanists to do some research so
there's a lot of serendipity in research
and I I really like this project it was
very different than other things I've
done and I I think it has some Merit and
you can be the judge of that so we're
really f
focusing on three tribes which I'll make
a case for as being uh a good window to
look at an overall view of ethnobotany
of the Southern Plains so we're trying
to reconstruct in many respects
traditional knowledge so that's a
difficult task and with each generation
more and more information gets lost so
it's very challenging in many respects
okay just to start off at a general
level ethnobotany defined it's just
interactions between cultures and people
plants and people however you want to
Define it uh and Richard schulties a lot
of you should be familiar with that name
is often called the father of modern
ethnobotany and there is an Oklahoma
connection if you're familiar with
schulties so and this is my shout out to
undergrads here's Shelties on the end if
I can't see where this thing is okay
he's on your left that's the end of his
junior year going into his senior year
at Harvard he did a three
month uh senior thesis research with an
anthropologist in Oklahoma where we
spent time with the CA and at that time
nobody had made any kind of inventory of
plants used by the caiway oh they were
buffalo Hunters end the story well lot
more complicated
uh and then obviously that led into an
incredible career as somebody who
basically defined the field of
ethnobotany he spent 12 years in the
Amazon if you're more interested in
following up on this the classic book by
way Davis One River uh is a good
depiction of that time spent uh based on
his journals a lot of his photographs
are in the book called The Lost Amazon
also uh put together by Wayde Davis and
then there's a movie just the only
cinematic uh portrayal of shulties that
I'm aware of uh Embrace of a serpent
it's a film from Colombia uh nominated
for best F film uh at the Academy Awards
so a very
interesting uh individual and really
significant okay so let's get back into
the Southern Plains we're not in the
Southern Plains here unless I click my
heels
together uh anyway
ecogeographical setting the Shaded area
from an Eco pers uh region perspective
this is South
Central uh semi arid prairie
ecosystem uh geographers often have a
cut off of the central Great Plains and
the southern Great Plains are mostly
concerned with the southern Great Plains
and you can see basically where the
plains Apache the kaiwa and the
kamanche fit in that Geographic and
ecogeographical scheme what's going to
be particularly significant unlike many
of the tribes represented in
Oklahoma the casa as they are often
referred to Kwa Kami Apache uh this was
their native territory so they shrunk
their territory and other major changes
happened but they weren't transported in
here like the Cherokee and other South
Eastern
tribes whoops okay so let's look at the
cultural
landscape so what we have here is a
little
map uh and the tribes in red were
basically pneumatic hunting and
Gathering tribes so they hunted bison
but they did more than hunt bison they
gathered plant materials and other
natural resources The Agrarian hunting
economies are in blue so really in the
Southern Plains it was really a CA the
kamanche and the plains
Apache and you can see a hatched area
taking in the panhandles of Oklahoma and
Texas was their original reservation of
course that's much too large so two
years later they shrunk to resz and then
you had the small area and then 1901
they basically eliminated the
reservation uh some of our early images
are by George Catlin and you can see an
image of kamanche Bison hunting there as
well as a Kwa
encampment so I maintain and I'm that's
my thesis that the KCA
are an ideal group to study the Southern
Plains ethnobotany for several reasons
they've been geographically contiguous
really for a couple hundred years they
had a similar economic base which was
basically hunting and Gathering they had
a close Association since euroamerican
contact and they actually confederated
politically Under The Medicine Lodge
Treaty of
1867 so from a cultural inog geographic
and economic strategies they were very
similar and there was much intermarriage
now these were very disperate tribes
linguistically so to put these in a
linguistic context each of those tribes
their language is in a different
language
family so how did they communicate of
course they many peoples living in
different parts of the world learn
multiple languages unlike Americans this
is part of their growing up because they
have to interact with people well they
also use sign language quite a
bit which came in very useful on one of
my field trips when I was with a 96y old
aache Elder who had no hearing and his
son communicated by sign
language so they have a shared cultural
heritage 1700 the plains Apache were
closely allied with the kaiwa which
they've kept up all these years that's
where a lot of the intermarriages
particularly between AA and Apache in
fact for decad
the Apache weren't even known about they
were just assumed to be some group of
kowa and then they called them the kowa
Apache uh and more H correctly referred
to as the plains Apache it is a dialect
different from some of the other Apache
groups uh 1806 the KYW Kam kamanche made
peace 1885 they are actually forced to
settle a familiar story in American
Indian history
1867 they became confederated and then
it was like there's another tribe in
here so became a KCA reservation in K
KC uh by 1886 the American Bison was
functionally extrait and this is
significant because by being restricted
and being basically forced to become
ranchers or Farmers which they were
not uh their economic base evaporated so
that's one way to destroy a culture is
to destroy its
economy uh the dolls Act was uh enacted
later which eliminated a lot of communal
lands which mean families were given
individual plots which left a lot of
leftover land which was then open for
settlement uh and the reservation
dissolved in 1901 so these are very very
significant and of course if you talk to
any of these groups uh I'm not doing it
justice and just uh going over in such a
short period of time
okay so let's look at the reservation
area and there's in red the outline of
the reservation which they were in until
1901 and this is where most of the
tribal peoples that haven't relocated
actually are today and that's where
tribal headquarters are so they were
forced to settle on the reservation home
territory
restricted they were restricted to
family allotments so a dramatic change
particularly when they weren't Farmers
or ranchers uh there no bison and it's a
very sad point in their
history very proud people have to fight
for scraps thrown off the back of a
wagon
basically and traditional knowledge of
course lost in every generation a
familiar familiar
story so let's look at the objectives of
this this is really more of a meta
analysis where I've taken data and then
tried to assemble it and then do
different analysis with the data in this
case the raw data are plant lists use of
plants so I wanted to reconstruct their
floristic and ethnobotanical resources
they get that kind of Baseline look at
their use patterns in a floristic
context and in an ethnobotanical context
like how many plants did they use I mean
what percentage of the floor how does
this compare to other groups Etc and
test them hypotheses on recorded versus
potential economic plant resources Under
reporting of economic plant use and loss
of traditional knowledge these are
difficult things to get at but um it's
something that Anthropologist social
sciences and ethnobotanists have to deal
with but I mean in some respects we're
reconstructing things in scientific
research we try to get data and we try
and make inferences that are consistent
with that data and propose
hypothesis okay the methods compiling
the economic plant data from the few
surveys that are out there from some
direct uh communication with some of the
tribal
members uh and other scattered sources
in the literature sometimes uh almost
anecdotal and that's the trouble with
any meta analysis you can have different
kinds of data and you kind of have to
stand I it and bring it in and try and
figure it
out uh reconstruct floors for the South
Central prair Eco region as well as for
their reservation and a lot of this
relied very heavily on the databases
listed at the bottom so we can't
underestimate the the value of some of
these databases and
it's uh invaluable I could not do this
kind of work otherwise and as most
people who use databases and those
resources uh the Native American
ethnobot database in particular was very
useful for looking at tribal and plant
resources okay now I was fortunate and
this also kind of initiated the study in
that there were
three uh important surveys of these this
group in particular the plains Apache
you'll notice Judy Jordan published a
book in
2008 and I was instrumental in working
with her she had done her work in the
early 1960s three Summers of intensive
fieldwork and was granted a master's
degree uh if and her master's thesis was
signed out by people all over the
country why this woman did not get a PhD
is a sad
story but anyway and she lived less than
a mile from where I lived so
I hooked her up she got her notes
together and she published it so I was
very pleased with that but there's sh's
book so three months going into his
senior year ended up with a critical
publication and really the best summary
of plants used by the
Kwa a comman a group out of Michigan
they had a Michigan archaeological
summer station there onlyy Jones was the
bnst I believe those vouchers are at
Michigan Schult ones are at Harvard and
Judy Jordan are at
Oklahoma so let's get into some of the
summary of the data
okay so I was able to pull these
data
and quantify it so if we look at the
kaiwa we can verify about 88 species
were recorded the Kaman is much less 68
uh and so I spent more time looking
through the Michigan vouchers which were
actually not in the Michigan herbarium
but were in the anthropological
collections uh and luckily I was able to
uh Identify some of the vouchers but
some of the vouchers were fragments of
wood uh and I did not Identify some of
those and the plains Apache which
actually took place over three years at
a much greater number so there's some
lessons there in terms of fieldwork
terms of informance Etc because Judy had
multiple informance male and female over
multiple Summers from different family
groups uh as opposed to one or two male
informants during a three-month
period so let's look at the totals I was
able to look at the species present in
at least one tribe about
175 and species recorded for use among
all tribes so we have three ethnobotanic
surveys only 17 of those are reported in
all three tries so a lot of these data
only appear in one
survey most of these are native to the
Southern Plains 94% 164 five were native
to North America but are found outside
the region and mostly through trading
they were significant plants from the
south or west
mostly and there were also some Exotics
species not native six species
so I like this graphic and other
individuals have as well because I think
it visually
portrays uh the effect of an obviously
Related Group that shared a lot of the
same knowledge of their
resources uh and how little overlap
there was from independent researchers
doing these surveys so here's the number
of species or the ca the Apache and
kamanche here's the 17 that were shared
and then you can see some are shared
between the Apache and the Kwa some are
in surveys in the kamanche and CWA and
then 35 between the Apache so by
portraying it this way you realize that
a lot of the information really
just surfaced in one ethnobotanical
survey which means a lot of that
information which was probably there was
not was forgotten by some of the
informants or was not recorded or
whatever sometimes it's proprietary in
in the case of healing plants
Etc let's look by category so there's
lots of things you can do once you get
these kind of data so these are species
used in at least one tribe out of the
175 a large portion of that are
Edibles that makes sense this is the
major supplement to the protein source
being primarily bison me not exclusively
ritual or medicinal plants also a major
major category this is not surprising
this is through most ethnobotanical
research uh a large number again used
for material culture this is quite
important as well personal care and
adornment uh it drops off quite a bit as
you might suspect but most of the many
plants had multiple uses they could be
edible could a component or a different
plant part could be used medically some
of it could be used
materially so edible plants and in this
category I'm keeping it with broad
Strokes so we have food stuffs beverages
mcatories additives 91
species uh a lot of these have
underground Parts uh another major
proportion more than half used re
productive Parts fruits
seeds uh and 20 species saps stems
leaves Etc and two common ones which are
familiar with as well here would be Rus
gabra which is widespread and new Fara
as well which is
widespread material culture is very
important uh and if you don't think it
is see how well you survive out there
without not just your iPhone everything
else that we purchase construction
materials dyes fibers resins
miscellaneous products a major major
category fibers glaa which is also
multiple use and a lot of that was
edible as well uh the young stems which
are kind of like asparagus as well as
the blossoms are edible and then the
fibers and uh a rough Leaf Dogwood which
is common in that region uh which often
produces a lot of stems from a crown
that are equal diameter so they make
good Arrow
shifts and ritual medicinal plants many
of these are quite well known uh used
such as eonia widely widely used not
just in this region
peyote uh peyote's been in use for
thousands of years uh and remember the
kamanche were part of the KCA and they
were really WID spread I mean the kowa
too with the kamanchi roamed all over
from Mexico up to the Northern
Plains uh and a lot of what they did is
take bwood and other things and they
would trade uh but they got exposed to
poot introduced it in the Oklahoma so
the Oklahoma based tribes the KCA as
well as the Chey and arapo were very
critical in introducing peyote and the
development of the Native American
Church White Sage brush which is also uh
well known here is widely
used personal adornment personal care
not so many species mon artif fistulosa
this is a mint remember AC uh commonly
used as a
perfume in those hot Southern Plain
Summers a perfume could be a good thing
if you walk through this it's very very
aromatic with lots of volatile
terpenoids escal Bean
this is actually a psychoactive plant
but a particularly dangerous plant it's
a legume you can see a lament there like
a peanut uh but these are very toxic and
it's very difficult
to uh modulate the amount taken without
it being catastrophic kind of like
gimson weed very
similar and sidey O grma
balua uh very interesting in the sense
that the the sand or all inflorescences
on one side of the stem look very
similar to warlands and it was very
common as an ornament particularly in
ceremonies many of these had multiple
uses two of the most common ones would
be the cacti ortia which are abundant in
this region edible material
culture ritual
medicinal as well as black walnut plenty
of black walnuts here there's another
species of Walnut too the small fruited
Walnut microcarpa edible material
culture ritual medicinal multiple uses
for these
plants so I just want to go through a
couple plants and then we'll look at the
data from a couple different
perspectives so some of the
representative plants the
junipers and juniperus
virginiana uh people are familiar with
this is the structural material for a
lot of uh TPS and things of that nature
you get away from the Rockies you don't
have Lodge Pine it's the name Lodo but
you can use the Cedars but there's a
western Cedar on Limestone that pops up
and I'm particularly pleased with this
one because I found this out by really
talking to a couple of the elders in the
Apache and they took me to a spot where
they had a different Cedar with a
different
smoke uh obviously a different turpenoid
composition and a different colored
fruit the be you know the cones uh and I
went there and as soon as I saw it I
knew it was Pinchot ey so we were able
to actually add that to the list and
that was on a sacred Mountain so I felt
very privileged I went there with the 96
year
old uh ex chair of the tribal
council uh who couldn't climb the hill
but he wanted to see it one last time
because he only lived three months after
that and he was the last native speaker
for that dialect but the museum at the
University of Oklahoma has a very active
program of
recording uh languages and stories by
native speakers and so there's quite an
audio library uh for that plain's Apache
dialect because his son who I knew knew
songs and knew some plants but had no
idea what the songs meant or what the
plants were used for so that's a good
example of just one generation loss of
traditional
knowledge uh B dark or if you're from
Texas bow
dark oage orange this is a member of the
mor RAC malb family this is the
preferred W wood for bows particularly a
mixture of the Heartwood with the
sapwood that
interface uh you split the wood radially
and this was the preferred bowwood
throughout the plains
region walnuts little one black the
microcarpa as well as
Jans uh and very widely used and they
appreciated its beauty as well it is
arguably one of the most beautiful
native North American woods and here's a
kowa cradle board that's quite
spectacular as well as being
functional White Sage Brush very very
well known including in this region
emesia Luda visana
uh there's a plants database
map I guess you don't have it if you're
up in Alaska but other than that widely
widely
used and I guess Alabama people are
missing out on
this I won't comment on that
further okay Indian breadroot this is
the last of these I'll show very very
critical plant uh it's still fairly
abundant in the Northern Plains so a lot
of the Sue uh have these plants uh and
include them in their ceremonies but uh
it's getting much more difficult to find
in the southern PLS very important
edible but there are six plants not
native to North America wormwood
dandelion Water Crest Sweet Clover
Johnson grass and yet they were used H
quite a bit so when plants became
introduced and the native peoples found
them if they knew of a use that
knowledge spread and they Incorporated
it into their
repertoire so and a lot of these have
been around a long period of time so
they were
significant many of these plants used by
the KCA were also used outside of the
Southern planes usually um it depends on
the the natural distribution of the
plants most of the KCA plants are going
to be uh plants found in the North
American Prairie and the southwestern or
Sonoran floristic Pro
provinces but so yaka GLA as you can see
which is mostly Midcontinent has a
Midcontinent tribal use pattern Western
soapberry much more
Southwestern uh you pick up the popo as
well as the KCA and Rose glaver is used
by a multitude of tribes reflecting its
distribution now if we look at the
archaeological
record and a lot of these records are
from the flotation method a lot of these
are
charifi uh you have 75 plants from this
Great Plains in the archaeological
record and for those who may not be
familiar it's generally divided into the
Paleo Indian basically 10,000 years and
older the Archaic
Period to about 1,000 BCE Woodland and
then the plains Village merging into the
modder so that's your scale and if we
look at some of the KCA species that are
in the archaeological record most of
this data these data are by genus only
it's very difficult to Def to identify a
lot of species that are charcoalified
uh so 47 uh appear in the archaeological
record if we go back in time Plains
Village Woodland archaic paleo you can
see you drop off the number of plants
but there's five plants
still used that have been in use for
much greater than 10,000 years that's
pretty impressive the other thing that's
interesting is there's several species
in the record that don't show up in the
KCA record so if we look at goosefoot
chenopodium uh that is a KCA
plant carbonized and sumpweed in the
sunflower family IA anua very widespread
throughout its range
historically in the Paleo ethnobotanical
record no record for the KCA but that's
true for many cultures it seems that
once corn came in they dropped a lot of
these grains that were more like famine
Foods so these are the five plants that
have a greater than 10,000 year record
which I find pretty impressive goosefoot
Choke Cherry caly which you may not be
familiar with remember of the mow family
uh Sun flow as well as a
potia so if we summarize the
botney the in an ethn graphic context
we'll see that there's a wide variety of
plants used okay they are a lot more
than just bison monolithic bison
Hunters uh and a lot of the plants used
are used by other tribes so there was a
lot of communication shared
knowledge uh which makes has good
survival value it makes perfect
sociological sense there's a long
history of usage for many of these
plants thousands of years in the region
even with the E and flow of different
cultural
groups so I'm proposing that the
combined data particularly given the
nature of ethnobotanical surveys
resulted in a much more complete view of
the plants used by the individual tribes
and probably is a more accurate
reflection of their
Collective knowledge base of plant
resources so of course once you get this
there's a lot of other questions how
many plants did they use how thorough
are some of these surveys I've kind of
partially answered that question and the
real tricky One how can we estimate loss
of traditional knowledge uh other than
saying traditional knowledge is lost in
each generation which it obviously is
but it's difficult to kind of quantify
some of these or get a more
robust uh
hypothesis so I reconstructed the floor
of the KCA resz uh this is where the
databases come in and came up with 1,89
species for this uh sount region in
Southwestern Oklahoma I was mostly
concerned with the
natives so that's a fair number I also
went in which was a lot more challenging
and tried to reconstruct the native
floor of the southern south central
Great Plains Eco
region the floor of the Great Plains was
of limited use because of the region
that it covers and incorporates the
Northern Plains as
well uh so I came up with 28 39 native
species there 12 89 native species for
the res uh and then looking at those
reservation plants with economic uses
elsewhere in North America 8 are
recorded So almost two out of five
plants on that reservation had some
documented history of use by Native
Americans two out of five now there's a
lot of grass species in there a lot of
leum species a lot of astery species but
two out of
five uh are useful and that's pretty
remarkable now not all of those were
used but that's the potential resource
so in the south central plains you see a
much smaller percentage about
6% and I'm sure the N the numbers were
much larger but with their range
restriction uh a lot of that extra
reservation Flora was probably
forgotten uh and they used 164 native
plants that I can document out of 1289
that's 12.7% now that's the figure
that's actually very similar to well do
dou umented ethnobotanical surveys
elsewhere in the world but it's hard to
get that kind of data because the tribal
whatever group you're studying just part
of a larger region and they don't just
have a floor that close to this example
would be a Pacific island where you have
a discrete floor and a discrete culture
and you can look at a percentage of that
floor and we're getting pretty close to
what other people have
recorded um but still there's only
onethird in the plants 164 four out of
508 uh that are
actually uh used or at least recorded
for
use so again potential economic species
almost
40% uh actual if we combine the data
from KCA you see we get a
12.7% which actually most ethnobotanists
feel comfortable with but if we just
looked at individual surveys you can see
the numbers they're much reduced 6.4 4.7
7.8 because of the close ties again
going back to my original argument uh I
think this we're getting closer to
having an accurate
reconstruction of the ethnobotanical
base so getting into the summaries key
points of the use
patterns uh about 12.7% almost
133% that's actually very similar ilar
to the floor of South Africa totals
where they've looked at how many plants
were used based on the floor as a whole
but of course there's many many
different regions in South
Africa uh and that's the
RSA people have people have that sound
like Donald Trump up here
uh uh talking to ethnobotanist who have
done field work somewhere around 10% is
often a number that they uh come up with
in terms of a ballpark percentage of the
floor that's actually used but only
onethird of the native plants or
potential useful plants are actually
used and 40% of those have been used by
some
groups so getting to the
conclusions what kind of evidence do we
have for loss of traditional knowledge
and again we do the best we can with
this uh low usage of economic plants
within the floor of their historic
range uh there are other factors
complicating these but that's certainly
a contributing factor uh only 30% of the
species recorded for use uh of potential
plants are actually used so it's most
undoubtedly an underestimate what we're
coming up with obviously like in any
culture
transcultural uh dispersal of knowledge
and resource use is very important let's
look at the spread of corn
if you need an example 30% of the Exotic
Flora is used
economically and then many KCA plants
were widely used among other tribes so
there was obviously much communication
motus a widely used exotic yellow Sweet
Clover second conclusion slide evidence
for Under reporting of ethnobotanical
data and I think this may be some of the
more
significant results uh of Interest ethn
uh we get very low numbers on these
individual surveys compared to
comparators uh but when we pull it we
actually get a much more reasonable
number so I think there's definite Under
reporting in some of these surveys
limited overlap among
tribes uh this gets into ethnographic
sampling questions you just can't go in
and talk to one person imagine if you
were interviewed and say tell me
everything about
America uh okay you're gonna get a very
biased and minimalist
subset
so and lastly many Regional economic
species listed are not recorded again in
the
surveys so I I kind of almost end here
with this picture of schulties again and
this is a shout out to you undergrads
you never know where your undergraduate
projects are going to take you
H here Schult signed up for a summer ah
that sounds good I can write my senior
thesis on that his entire career and it
really changed the landscape of Science
in several
disciplines so there he was probably 21
years old that's the morning after a
Peyote
ritual you notice he still has his tie
on he's been described as Patrician and
uh
he didn't wear a tie in the
Amazon okay for acknowledgements uh
certainly I want to acknowledge the KCA
tribes it's their knowledge and
uh the interactions I've had with them
and some of the representatives they've
been very happy to see
this data resurrected Judy Jordan who
wrote that book it's actually been given
an honorific title within the plains of
Pache tribe and she brought to their
attention that they forgot about it's
way back there in the cultural knowledge
somewhere will ml used to be in Hawaii
then Brit now he's independent in the
Pacific Northwest helped quite a bit
with some of my floristic ethnobotanical
analyses some colleagues at Oklahoma
Paul Menace a Paleo ethnobotanist only
likes his plants to cified I assume
that's not true for the Hort
department and a couple grad students
Dan Mormon who put together that
incredible database has been very
helpful he's retired now but he still
keeps the database active other people
will help uh Clint flanner who oversees
the anthro collections at Michigan all
these people were very helpful in
putting this together so that's all I
have uh thank you and I'd be happy to
answer some
[Applause]
questions questions
I have one Wayne yeah um what evidence
is there of any of these tribes
cultivating any of these plants as
opposed to Simply Gathering them from
the
wild well many times there is the model
oh so the question was about were any of
these wild plants actually cultivated I
mean they were mobile people but at the
same time um and so they really took
careful stock of their
resources
I'm because sometimes they almost
followed a route they kind of knew where
some of the plants were and it's very
possible they did that uh certainly if
we look at some examples it's very
common in some cultures for people
particularly like K and or whatever to
transplant plants into a medicinal
garden and some of that may have
happened particularly if there was a a
route in their cyclic Mobility so they
could come back and knew were certain
plants were so that's likely but we have
no direct evidence of that that's been a
real issue with something like sumpweed
which is really WID spread in the
archaeological record but it's not
reported among many extant tribes at all
it's like they just dropped it uh and
then it appears in such numbers
archaological right to make it seem like
they were actually it was like an
incipient cultivar in fact individuals
are actually trying to redevelop some
weed uh I have not eaten it yet but so
but I I don't have any direct evidence
of
that yeah in addition to ethnobotanical
surveys did any of the researchers
including yourself look at cultural work
such as creation stories for for
mentions of
significant
plants the actual instructions for how
to use these plants right so the
question is about whether we uh
researchers have also looked in the like
creation stories or uh that would
incorporate some of these significant
plants and I have not directly there are
several good
ethnographic books and investigations of
the
KCA uh
and I have not come across that in some
of those I tried to peruse a lot of that
literature uh and a lot of these even if
they're uh referenced in the native
language that language has at least a
English equivalent so you could check it
out uh and I'd have to ask some of my
anthropological colleagues for I mean
there's a member of the Kwa tribe on the
OU anthropology faculty for example
they teach kaiwa I mean you can do your
language requirement learning
kaiwa yeah so yeah I'm I'm not aware of
any
yeah yeah Jerry um Wayne if you look
across the range from the plants that
are best known that show up in the most
surveys on down to the ones that you
have the fewest records
for uh is that access about the
commonality of the plants or certain
types of uses more likely to be showing
up in more
lists well okay so the question was
plants that are commonly recurring
whether it reflects more that they're
very common or they have a a sign
culturally significant use the answer
seems to be more towards the significant
component if something I mean there's a
lot of plants that may be part of the
knowledge
base but they may be less desirable it's
kind of like food there's always going
to be preferred
food uh less preferred food and then
famine
food uh but nevertheless uh the plants
that really I mean there's like a dirty
dozen many times that just keep
appearing in all these surveys and
because they are so critically important
and corus is one of I mean in the Peyote
ceremony they use corcus leaves you know
the smoke
yeah yeah
you mentioned that uh these the AC KCA
tribes were in three different
linguistic groups but there was probably
a lot of exchange of knowledge on usage
of particular species I was wondering if
like the nomenclature the taxonomy that
the actual or the names that they
referred to those plants got transferred
from culture to culture and if you could
kind of come up with the timeline of you
know
this did the commanche tribe used this
plant first and that name got passed
along to the was there any cases like
that where you could make
inferences yeah so the question is about
some of the the naming used by the
different tribes particularly given the
fact that they're they speak languages
in three different
families
um I guess I'm I have not looked into
that I guess the way I approach this
topic as you might guess is as a
botanist doing ethnobotany as opposed to
an ethnographer doing
ethnobotany uh so I have not looked into
that I mean we have the names and there
are
uh experts and even tribal members that
are familiar with the language that one
could test that and that would be very
interesting to look at but unfortunately
I I have not pursued that that
aspect I think we have time for one more
question does Geneva have
questions Bill yes yeah how many
families are there represented among
these plants that they commonly not only
commonly but entirely
used yeah I I didn't include that kind
of information not on this this talk so
I have to go into my data archive in my
brain uh there's quite a large number
and my primary database is all organized
taxonomically by Family there's at least
65 families and that maybe an
underestimate I mean things like rose AC
are very common and things like fabac
are very common but there are no seeds
theum seeds that were used which and
there weren't any grass seeds that I I
recorded I expected drop seed sporis or
something like like that to pop up
because they've appeared in other
surveys so I think those are areas where
you know uh some knowledge has been lost
look at J would there be more sharing of
J among the tree TRS and species yes so
and and a lot of my numbers are going
down to the species level and sometimes
they didn't you know it depends on the
plant because different species are
often referred to as a cousin so this is
a
cousin of another
prunus uh and they leave it at that so
there is some information that that's
you know there's a little bit of error
in that data in the sense that they
often did not
discriminate uh so the the
genus and that's an interesting point
that you all to or directly elud the
genus is actually very very critical
element in a lot of
nonwestern
taxonomies but depending on the on the
plant this this species can be important
as
well so I want to thank Professor
Ellison for a fascinating presentation
thanks so
much this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu