this is a production of Cornell
University uh so yes I'm going to talk
about uh one of our most uh favorite uh
plant types today and uh as I go through
this what I'm going to try and get you
to do is to think and and I I'm going to
uh put some things on here that
basically might change your thinking
might solidify your thinking uh but I
want you to to think more broadly about
weeds because I think a lot of this has
to do with some of our preconceived
ideas and and maybe some of the things
that we've learned over time
um but I will just get into this and um
this might be familiar to some of you uh
not sure but um you know this guy out
here he's he's not real old uh he's he's
laying down on the job but can see he's
he's quite frustrated and uh you know
asking him about this new frontier are
you kidding me this is no new frontier
this is the same old thing that I've
been doing uh you know for the past few
years of my
life so our attitude towards Weeds now
I've I've put this into I'm I'm just
giving broad terms to conventional
thinking and sustainable thinking now
these are not good or bad this is just
how we sometimes tend to think so in
conventional type systems you know
typically you want 100% weed free uh we
know that they negatively compete with
uh available resources so eliminating
weeds is is number one priority and
there's obviously there's a relationship
with economic uh losses associated with
those systems in more sustainable
systems or sustainable thinking uh you
know often it's it's density thresholds
how many weeds are out there can I can I
get by with and are they really having
an impact that I need to work with uh
also plant diversity so that thinking
more broadly you know there these are
plants they're adding diversity to the
system and also are they providing an
alternative cover whether it's a mulch
whether it's you know something else
that allows these um allows them to um
remain in these
systems but the impacts of weeds um and
through the literature uh various
studies
good or bad okay and this is somewhat
conflicting and again it's based on kind
of your thinking and and and and what
you're kind of geared toward but we can
think of weeds as either they compete
for resources or they contribute to
resources through you know biomass um or
or competing for available resources
they inhibit or assist operations
whether that's Harvest you know uh
clogging up your Harvester or or or you
know providing a mulch um Harbor insects
and diseases or support
beneficials uh
increase uh agronomic biodiversity but
maybe lower uh diversity in our natural
systems where you see invasive plants
becoming
monocultures uh there's kind of you know
this div biodiversity issue and then
also increased production costs uh or
are we increasing the environmental
benefits if you think of a weed is a
plant that has some um desirable
characteristics so this is a bit of a
conflict um and I don't think it's been
resolved
completely but if we look back so
historically we're looking back because
we want to know what what have we gone
through what have we worked on so weed
is defined as a plant out of place I
think most of you have heard that
definition but uh Ralph wo Emerson has
has defined as a plant whose virtues
have not yet been discovered so instead
of looking at the glass is half empty
he's looking at it as half full so over
time now I've I've put this um this time
scale uh back in the early days all the
way up to here and you can see that and
this is basically relating to weeds um
you know whether we had the firstand
implements then we get into horse drawn
um U mechanical uh the chemical era
begins with the first herbicide where
for the uh 24d
herbicide um some you know internet was
invented in 1973 okay why is that
important to weeds well I'll get into
that as far as
technology um we have the first
herbicide resistant Ry grass resistant
to to um uh seven sites of actions so if
you're familiar with the herbicide
resistance uh scenario or or issue
there's there's different sites of
actions with the different modes of
actions and this Ry grass here is is is
pretty major uh and this occurred in
1982 uh if we look at certified organic
systems was certified in the US in
1990 uh the executive order any
everyone's familiar with the the Clinton
error when they uh declared invasive
species as uh something that we need to
start managing or they made it an
executive
order and now we have climate hubs
developed in
2013 and uh the most recent research
that I've seen is the development of an
automated weeder by some folks at UC
Davis so these are kind of some of the
events that contribute to what I'm going
to talk about um but in addition to
those changes we've also had you know
ecological the theory has has advanced
over that same time period and we've
also seen some practical application in
our management so that's changed whether
we're talking about hand implements all
the way up to an automated weer okay so
we're seeing a lot of changes over time
time that I think also contribute to our
our Viewpoint and our
thinking but weeds and
ecosystems they're either resilient or
they're
pesky and this is based on kind of
perception but in in these natural
ecosystems semi-natural or Urban
ecosystems weeds tend to be survivors
they tend to persist um they're very
prolific in in either producing seed or
producing biomass and in some ways you
could view them as opportunistic uh they
look for niches and I I'm giving them
kind of human qualities but niches are
what they take advantage of and and
that's really what we see especially
when you look at a lot of these um in
our managed system there's a lot of
disturbance going on there so there's
opportunities that are created for
weeds so I'm going to talk about kind of
three main areas and this is related to
the things that I have done research on
or what my interests were uh prior to
coming here um and I'm going to just
talk about these three things just to
get us thinking about uh more broadly as
far as weeds and invasive plants so
super Weeds now super weeds is a very um
it kind of uh gets your attention
whether it's at the emotional level or
or whatever you've probably seen it in
the popular press um associated with uh
genetically modified crops
um so this article by um uh by kogan in
in 2005 talked about super weeds are
impossible to kill well they're
impossible to kill if you're using one
herbicide and if it's glyphosate you're
going to have a glyphosate resistant um
uh Gene that's either
transferred uh to uh the weed or the
indiscriminate spraying of glyphosate
onto resistant GM crops
you're basically uh providing selection
pressure to uh allow for a resistant
weedy plant okay
so herbicide resistant are they really
super weeds well we you probably don't
maybe you've seen this graph but this is
from Ian Heap and his weed science um
website basically we've seen a dramatic
increase in uh herbicide resistant
weeds and for those of you who don't
know uh Palmer amaran
in the South uh in Cotton Fields has
been a huge uh issue for them uh to deal
with and it's actually forced some
Growers to even go out of uh growing
cotton but it's a nice you know poster
child her herbicide resistant weeds
again these characteristics uh
contribute to its success in these
cropping systems so I'm going to take
you through
a a time lapse if you
will in 1989 the first uh Palmer amaran
uh resistance was identified in um
Tennessee and Georgia if my geography is
correct so South Carolina thank you
we'll get to Georgia so
91 93 94 95 97 98
2000 and I'm just going to go right
ahead and just you can see that
continually we're seeing these plants
2012 and again this is uh from the
herbicide resistance website but you can
see that in each of these states at
least one individual or one population
has been identified resistance to
herbicide so is what is what's going to
happen you know onwards is there going
to be just uniform
resistance um we hope not but I'm going
to shift gears so there's the resistance
issue but also um in my work I was
especially interested in extreme events
and what we're seeing in especially in
the midwest was significant drought and
significant um impacts of drought on
cropping systems and so there have been
a lot of work there still is a lot of
work on developing drought tolerant
crops corn soybeans things like that um
but for as much for what I know there's
not a real interest or there's not a lot
of work in drought tolerant weeds or
invasive plants now I know Tony has uh
written some things and there's some
folks that are working on it but as far
as the real um focused effort um it's
not it's not a lot of work has been done
on that
but just to kind of Define it a a delay
in Lethal
dehydration usually it's related to the
physiology or Mor morphology of the
plant and uh we see a phenotypic
plasticity where the plant either uses
less water it loses less water or it
gains access to water through root uh
penetration through the ground and then
there's also the genetic adaptation
where over time if there's it's it's
another selection pressure that um is is
creating um a change in the population
and this depends a lot on the intensity
and duration of that selection pressure
so as I indicated um in
2012 we saw this chart uh from the US
drought Monitor and this central part of
the country was either red or brown for
most of the
year and so I looked at frag mighty's
Australis which I think you folks have
some of that out here uh either good or
bad um but looking at frag mighty's
common read and its tolerance to Drought
so we looked we had a greenhouse study
we set
up basically we had the these large
tanks where we um uh transplanted uh
frag mtis and then we submitted or um uh
Expos them to different uh stress
periods and this we had a low stress
medium stress and severe stress and
basically that was uh related to the
number of days that there was no water
in those uh misac cosm and so for our
low stress we had 19 days of no water
which in addition there were four days
where it was at greater than 80%
available water was depleted so we're
getting down to very very dry conditions
essentially and so our medium stress was
36 days with no water 20 days at at
greater than 80% and then our severe uh
stress basically a month of of no water
and out of those out of that 60 days
there were about 44 days where it was
significantly dry so what did we see um
in our low stress
treatment where we had uh s this is Day
70 so on on Day 70 we added water back
into those tanks and you know looking at
this you'd say well that plant is either
dead or it has gone dormant well it was
actually dormant because 25 days post
drought it had started to Green up now
this is just the low stress I was
convinced that the severe stress we'd
killed those plants I thought they're
dead absolutely well not the case
because 25 Days Later those plants were
starting to Green up and you can ask
well did you get all the water out of
that soil we had soil moisture sensors
that were basically reading zero and I
know there's you know there's probably
could have been pockets of of water in
those systems but um very much an
indication that this plant is is very
tolerant to Drought condition conditions
and maybe some of you are familiar with
that have worked on this particular
species um shifting gears a little bit
uh cardu newans which is
musle uh we looked at in an invasion
study uh into cool and warm season
perennial grasses and we had simulated
grazing for two years uh we also
introduced musle in the first year in
the spring of the first year and part of
this study was very interesting in that
we had normal precipitation one year and
then we went into our drought Year in
2012 which was um the the worst drought
that they've had on record so it was
really nice for our study it was
horrible for people that were you know
cropping and and and that part uh but it
worked out really well for us to to
compare that so I'm just going to go
right to the results
um and then again along the um uh the
x-axis here is the the the dates so
April 2011 all way up to November 2012
and then here's our volumetric water
content uh these represent the the
various treatments whether it was Barr
musle by itself warm season grazed warm
season non-grazed cool season grazed
cool season non- grazed but basically
this shows you that in the second year
where we had
our um uh must and I realize these lines
are not really easy for you to see but
where there was not basically
non-grazing
so our non-ra
treatments um we had there was water
content but where we had our musle and
and anything where there was grazing if
I'm reading that right uh had depleted
water down so we saw a difference in
water content between these two
treatments and this is a really great
graph especially if you're um tired and
and you want to uh go to sleep really
easily um and and I pardon me for the
the busyness but
along here the XX these are all our
treatments uh and this is basically
looking at light penetration into the
canopy over May June July and August of
2011 and then the same thing in 2012 so
so what I want to highlight is at the
initial part of our study we had um good
plant cover so if you think so if you
see a high bar that means
um there's a lot of light uh penetrating
into the uh to the soil surface if you
see bars that are low that means there's
not a lot of light reaching the soil
surface so looking at and I'm just going
to point out a couple these two
treatments are warm season non-grazed
musle where we added it and warm season
um where we just added uh musle by
itself or sorry warm season non- gra
without musil so you can see in
2011 it's doing a good job at shading
out the uh soil surface
but in 2012 now these are perennial
grasses they should be growing robustly
you know providing some good shade in
2012 the drought was affecting um these
grasses where they had now were allowing
uh light to penetrate the soil surface
and you say well why is that important
well for mus thisle it's very important
and once it gets access to light with
enough soil moisture it grows very well
again here's the same thing this is just
looking at populations over time so in
2011 2012 I'm just highlighting this our
warm season non grazed where we
introduced musle so you can see here
early on it started to establish but
then in August it disappeared same thing
in 2012 it started to establish by July
those plants were dead so what was going
on in 2011 we had great soil moisture we
had normal
precipitation uh we had very nice
establishment of musle in our grazed
treatments in our non-grazed plots in
2012 this is basically musle emerging
and then it would die without producing
a flower or any kind of seed head and
just for comparison here's our uh
beautiful Barr plots of musle which we
did get a lot of attention by people
driving but this is right by a highway
and they would drive by and say you need
to control that it was you know cuz it's
a noxious weed and we were trying to do
research on it we we were we were um we
bagged all the the seed heads so just to
let you know we didn't let all the seed
just go everywhere we were we were
bagging the seed heads and then the
second year we we chopped all this down
and I I did actually get a chance to
operate a shovel and uh take care of any
uh remaining so um but this is just to
just a little bit of an uh kind of an
introduction of of where we're seeing
this um tolerance or not tolerating uh
these dry drought
conditions so uh does tolerant or
resistance make it super well we also
know that there's there's weeds that are
tolerant to mowing they're tolerant to
to dising or disturbances it's really
dependent on intensity and duration and
it's not super but they're actually
resilient so phenologically or
genetically it adapts to environmental
stress whether you know an example is
drought uh it these plants are able to
evolve um as far as their defense
mechanisms uh you know and this is a an
example of herbicides and they're also
able to access spatial temporal
resources whether that's light water
nutrients now I I'm saying this related
to weeds but again they're just
plants they're not you know some for
formidable foe that is that is that we
can't really deal with and I'll talk
about that at the end as
well so
bioenergy uh we going to shift gears
here a little bit bioenergy research uh
this is just a map of of where some of
the regional um uh uh projects have been
conducted across the country and this is
a little bit dated it's not uh really up
to date um but just to show you and I
think everyone is aware of of the
bioenergy research that's going on
there's several resources there's
several um things that folks are looking
at obviously corn corn residue uh
switched grass perennial grasses uh
there's been some interest in miscanthus
uh
gigantis biodiesel soybeans canola Cam
camelina and others um I just want to
point out there's uh even within this
group there's folks looking at um grass
bioenergy but there's also been some
interest in uh invasive plants as uh
bioenergy
sources and if you look at these three
photos the thing or sorry for my math is
not working real well um you can see
that there's high amounts of biomass
right that's that's the big interest is
how can we create a lot of biomass to
you know create ethanol and and provide
some
fuel
well like we discussed for Palmer uh
invasive plants have some similar
characteristics they're fast growing
High biomass relatively few pests they
create these dense monocultures and
there's few inputs to kind of keep them
going but on the flip side of
that they that is a great scenario for
Invasion and there's there's a lot of
potential with these plants some already
you know some have already are already
doing their invasive
work the weed risk assessments is it
anyone familiar you fam with weed risk
assessment so assessing a plant for its
um it's uh invasive or its ability to
become a problem um most of these
assessments on these plants are positive
they're it's they're highly um
problematic or they could be highly
problematic peer-reviewed position
papers uh these are just two of many
papers that have opposed uh this kind of
a you know use of these invasive plants
as well as public land managers I mean
when you say hey guess what we're going
to use these for Bio energy they say are
you crazy uh because it's it's a it's a
thing that we're always managing and
then somehow you want to protect that uh
to create a a fuel source well a a new
approach I think is is important here
and this gets back to what how do we
think about
this and if we're harvesting existing
populations and the focus is on control
and
restoration I think it's a little bit
different uh scenario and also if we can
uh co-mingle these uh sources with other
resources uh you address the
sustainability
issue so there's a paper in uh Frontiers
in uh in
2013 they basically looked at bioenergy
that Sports ecological restoration and
they were focused on these two U
invasive plants Russian olive and tamask
in Washington state they had a 52 acre
restoration site and this is this was
all a model they did this by modeling so
there wasn't actual you know it wasn't
an actual field study but they looked at
you know all the the available tamaras
Russian olive kind of assessed the
biomass and found out that um you know
there's there there was a significant
amount that could be produced per year
and they estimated for decades so they
compared their data to National
estimates and basically what they came
up with
was that they said we could they could
expand restoration activities and
biomass supplies which would then uh um
create Revenue um well so it would be
supported by revenues from the uh sale
of the invasive uh tree Woodway so
basically you're supporting that that
that restoration effort by the sale of
the invasive plant biomass so you're
you're trying to create this uh system
that supports
itself
so I'd seen that I'd already been
thinking about this and I I've submitted
numerous proposals uh with other
colleagues uh different disciplines uh
you know just an example of some of the
proposals we submitted we've submitted
to numerous funding sources requesting
up to $15 million with zero uh funded so
if anyone is interested in this if you
want to pursue this I'd be happy to talk
to you about it um but just realize what
you're up against and um then and and
I'm going to show you some of the
barriers of why okay so it's an
ideological you know how are we thinking
about this there's environmental risk we
already know that there's a weed risk
and even if you're transporting this
stuff there's potential that okay you
could distribute it you know in the in
the pathway somewhere economical I've
I've run into this over and over you
know these plants are not sustainable if
we harvested everything there wouldn't
be enough to to supply the energy needs
that we're looking at you know so it's
not a particularly energy dense
material um there's social issues
conflicting of national agendas so the
depart Depart of energy says Hey grow
this stuff yet the USDA says no we need
to control it so um you know you can't
it's hard to go to them and and propose
something when there's not really
agreement between agencies so we're we
we're going through all this we're
having this really good discussion
meanwhile the invasive plans continue to
spread because they don't really care
what we think okay so but this is just
some ideas that that I've been thinking
about and working on uh in when I was my
pre previous location so the last thing
I want to talk about is
Automation and just to to preface that
so in
agriculture uh looked at you know some
of the trends that are occurring and
we've look we've seen that uh land use
in EG has dropped from 54 to 51% so
that's you know kind of holding
steady uh labor declin 30%
um while agricultural prod productivity
increased 50%
larger Farms 97% family-owned um I I
guess I'm I'm not going to question I
mean this is a a report by the USDA but
the thing I want to really point out
here is the increased adoption of new
technologies and that's really what
we're seeing in some of our cropping
systems but in addition to that we're
kind of we we've got these challenges
that we're trying to address whether
they're limited resources water
nutrients energy um we have uh
conditions that are that are continually
we're dealing with whether they're pests
diseases disasters and now we're seeing
you know climate change extreme events
but there's also challenges to
Innovation the application Logistics as
well as the uh one we always like to
work on is
funding but what is the available what
is the technology that's out there what
are you know what is kind of the new
thing that that is on the horizon are
actually being um
developed well in our our human health
system our human health
area they now have cameras that can you
can actually
swallow and uh they can look inside you
different you know find different things
that are right or wrong I I don't know
if that's good or bad uh you can you
they can unlock your car from space
now uh we've all gone through this one
where you're going through the airport
and and they can see
everything um and then this one with the
you know they can determine if you've
washed your hands uh because there's
sensors that that show uh what What's
actually been done uh so that you know
could be beneficial if you have a two or
three year-old and you tell them what to
do and they don't always do it um and
then here is the one for all you Gamers
out there that just you know uh like to
get in these now these games are getting
real interactive and you can actually
play you know across Geographic
locations and
um but this is the kind of technology
that probably is nothing new to a lot of
you and and there's even other things
going on but I just thought um this um
this uh a new biology for the 21st
century they point out that um you know
computational sciences and Engineers are
part of this biological research that's
going on this this emerging Trend and
this is a quote from Bill Gates back in
2008 on the uh special edition on
Robotics and basically says when or even
if this industry robotics will achieve
critical mass if it does it may well
change the world well we're six years
later and I think we're seeing some of
those changes uh Even in our cropping
systems here's John Reed uh director of
production technology at John Deere and
they're saying that uh uh opportunities
to follow a different path to higher
productivity one that involves
automation control and Robotics so
you've seen their 48 row
planter but they're also looking at um
uh very small individual Ro robots that
move in the field and and and that's an
area that that these companies are
looking at as
well so what is the idea with this
automation stuff well if we've got weeds
in our cropping system we want to
produce this we want to support these
people but we also want to maintain our
our natural resources our economics but
we don't necessarily want to revert to
that so how do we do all this and can we
you know use automation to uh help in
this process if we talk about integrated
weed
management
uh a lot of treatment factors that that
contribute to the decisions that need to
be made and I'm not going to go into
detail on these but selection method
application amount timing plant
conditions Environmental conditions
these are some of the the factors that
are considered in integrated weed
management and then you think about well
if we're talking automation we've got
machine factors that include
Logistics uh if we're working real time
uh and then also guidance if you're
talking about something that's that's uh
autonomous so targeted recognition and
application systems actually are
possible and I'm going to show you some
examples of research
if you look at the the literature on on
engineering they're really working in
this uh weed science area more than
maybe some of the weed scientists so
they're kind of doing this work and I
think there's a real opportunity for um
overlap or collaboration uh between
these two Fields so if we talk about the
spatial temporal identification and
management of weeds basically predicting
uh where the weeds are based on
environmental factors we're really good
at predicting not always versus
treatable based on location and plant
characteristics so I'm going to focus on
this one uh just in the uh in the in the
next few minutes so based on
location so locating the weeds and and
there's some uh I think there's been
work done you know where are weeds in
the field how do we find those do you do
you go through and uh you know do it by
hand you you do it with uh sensors or or
or computers uh but you can create these
maps and this is a comparison of maps
created either um by uh manual weed
mapping so going out and mapping those
by hand uh semi uh automated weed
mapping uh kind of a hybrid between hand
weeding or hand um by hand versus um
using technology and then on automated
weed mapping and you can see that um
they're they're pretty close there
there's some relationship there and what
they found was the uh weed
density uh in in most cases the
difference was due to Leaf occlusion so
when you've got overlapping
weeds it's it's hard for the technology
to identify well this is a weed and this
is separate that just looks at it as one
weed so that's part of the the issue
with why there's not a real nice um
relationship between those two but if we
we talk about loc so we know okay we
look in the field where are they what
about plant characteristics can we look
at some of the characteristics of the
plant to help us
Identify some of this and this early
work was back in the 1980s uh looking at
um sunflowers and soybeans and basically
looking at near infrar
photography but we've obviously we've
Advanced uh from from that from that
point on in the early 1990s they've
developed these commercial spot sprayers
uh basically looking at if there's green
foliage or brown soil so when the green
comes up that's you know an indication
to spray um but we're we're getting
beyond that now we're we're getting to
where we've got some a knowledge-based
ma Machine Vision system and it's kind
of based on on these principles you
could you know view this as a decision
support
um tool but uh visually you know uh
finding where the plants
are and then through a series of steps
identifying those plants and then even
going to the species classification and
population and then we can develop a
weed map that's very specific and and
allows us to have a strategic
approach this right here is the hard
part you can find the
plants but
getting to individual leaflets looking
at Leaf shape vation texture analysis
species
classification this is uh the the
problem with this particular um approach
so here's an example this is um from the
Norwegian crop Institute uh and they
tried to do some of this work looking at
plant canopy that was um uh
photographed uh and doing this on the go
as well so this is not a stop you know
View and then Mo it's a it's a realtime
uh system because trying to get this to
a practical application is is going to
require us to go at a certain
speed so we've got a knowledge-based
machine system and application
system um and this is again some the
work by the the group at UC Davis and
basically this schematic shows
you that traveling in this Direction
with this camera um image processing
computer and then connecting it to a
microcontroller where okay we've
identified the Weeds now can we spray
those based on the information that we
collected uh going through the field and
they've showed some success uh
especially where they can distinguish
tomato from night shade and and pigweed
foliage so it's very right now it's it's
very
rudimentary um but they're really making
some uh good nice progress in that way
so here's another um uh you know looking
at it again looking at the
shape but also now adding the visual
color um looking at you know what are
the differences in the color of the
plants can we use that to to help us
identify it and most recently um this
group uh has been awarded a grant to
look at um doing kind of what they said
here is is is modifying the color of
that plant to then allow them to
differentiate between the weeds and the
plant now what is this going to what
effect is that going to have on the
production of the plant I don't know I
that's yet to be seen but but just you
know changing this color um you know
using in this case a
a a a gene that could be a way to help
uh
kind of identify our our desirable
plants versus
weeds so true integrated weed management
I think we have an opportunity to
actually you know pursue this now now
that we have technology so we have
sensors that can locate individual weeds
in the
field weeds can be identified based on
their characteristics or using a
database and then the a decision support
system determines the best
treatment now the the part that is
is important is is as we're working at
the micro scale and this is again a
little bit of a conceptual um Challenge
and it's not for a field that's just
loaded with weeds that's not the intent
it's the intent is where you've where
you've got some weed management
challenges and you can have a a robotic
system go through identify where the
weeds are if there's a known herbicide
resistant weed that computer can
identify it and apply a different
treatment whether it's a you know a
cutting treatment a burning treatment
but again it has to be at the micro do
um
level
so advanced technology can account for
spatial temporal
variability and since we have all tools
on board they're available at any time
and any location in the field so you're
you're bringing integrated weed
management to the field you're not
waiting for different seasons you're not
rotating crops not that that you
shouldn't be doing that but those tools
are there in real time so conf
conception to the field these are some
of the things um this is a a swarm
technology right now I don't know if
some of you have heard about that they
have these individual kind of um spider
looking robots that that kind of uh move
throughout the field and they have a
little area that they they
manage um there's also some of these
automated um machine that that they're
looking at where the weeds are and then
they they have actuators that that move
um you know within the row these are
used in in row crops um so you know
question are we still at research grade
I think we still are there I know
there's some startup companies in
California that are actually uh you know
working in this area and they're
actually making some really uh nice
advances but in general I think we're
still kind of uh looking at okay how do
we make this thing work how do we do it
efficiently so I'm just going to wrap up
here with um just some final thoughts so
I think I think what was needed is kind
of a merging of attitudes not an
emerging but
merging and so what type of thinking do
we need to have and I don't really think
it's conventional or sustainable I think
it's outside the box thinking I think
just a different approach and be
thinking broadly uh not like our second
photograph
where the young man was thinking are you
kidding me this is not a new frontier so
you know I think our mindset needs to
change about how do we view weeds and so
what do we need to be thinking about
weeds are plants you know some and some
happen to be very resilient so what can
we learn from those
plants are managing weeds when is it
necessary for complete control as
compared to when can we use thresholds
is there a time when we we can allow
weed or or does it always have to be you
know
annihilated advanced technology is part
of our society how can we enhance our
tools in the uh integrated weed
management toolbox I think some of those
things are up and coming and there's
either even other things that I didn't
mention um that are that are applicable
and we all know that weeds are
ubiquitous so what ecosystem services
are some weeds providing and how can
those services not the weeds be
exploited you know so what can we if if
they're here we're dealing with them are
there some ways that we can actually
incorporate them into our system in a
way that doesn't become detrimental to
our economics and our environment in
other ways so that's all I have and I'd
be happy to answer any questions I think
we have maybe a few minutes or
[Applause]
so that's a that's a very good question
in fact one of the things that I was I
was working on before I left uh UNL was
training livestock to eat invasive
plants so there's a person in Colorado
and maybe some of you familiar but she
has trained uh cows to eat weeds just
Google it and you'll bring up her
website but in Nebraska beef is like the
number one commodity in in Liv you know
in animal systems so you've already got
him out there why can't you just train
him to eat the things that you don't
want and she showed that you could do
that now I had some there was it was not
as simple as it sounds but I I that's a
very very good you know idea whether
it's um genetically modifying them or
just training them to eat uh these these
plants that we don't necessarily
want that that's a very good question
and it's a good segue to my presentation
that I will be giving uh in a couple
weeks to the Department of Natural
Resources on invasive plants and ecology
so when I was at UNL I had to basically
balance AG agronomic weeds invasive
plants so I I kind of generalized for
this audience it's the agronomic side
but the invasive plants you know are
very much obviously like you said
they're less intensively managed so how
do we address that I just had a
conversation with um with Carrie the Two
Carries before I got in like where do we
say okay you know am I am I making any
difference here making any progress on
especially at large scale and I think
that's where it really comes down to um
defining what your goals are especially
when we talk to land managers you know
is is it a problem across your entire
landscape do you have patches do you
have satellite populations where you can
you know focus on those and I think
that's where we're we're really looking
at removing those and and and gets back
to that restoration study by those the
folks that you know in front years and
but that's that's a maybe an equally as
large or bigger question but it's a good
point all right well time's up so let's
thank Steve once
again good job
Steve this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu