this is a production of Cornell
University well thank you very much um
Don for that nice introduction and um
this afternoon I am going to go back to
hodon uh territory and talk about the
three sisters as a cropping system um
well known uh with
the with the iroy um but this is a
cropping system not only present here in
the Northeast um it is a a cropping
system all over the Western Hemisphere
and as uh Carl Sawyer um wrote in 1962
it's a symbiotic plant complex of North
America without an equal elsewhere um
for the iroy uh William Fenton has
indicated that it is the foundation of
ir oi subsistence um enabling them to
develop institutions of sedentary
life well the three sisters in terms of
their origins in in the Northeast uh
until quite recently um most
archaeologists and anthropologists uh
thought that these three crops arrived
in the Northeast as a as an intact
cropping system and that they came here
sometime between
1,2 1200
BP but recent work by the paleobotanist
John Hart Who works at the New York
State uh museum at Albany um has put
forth a much different
um um you know story first edible squash
has been around here since 3000 BP maze
by 2270 BP and beans a much more recent
introduction 700 P or just um in the uh
you know couple of hundred years before
Europeans arrived so Hart says that the
three plants as a at the as a crop
complex were not all here at the same
time until around 700 BP J can you just
um mention what BP oh before present
right so it archaeologists use this I it
doesn't make any sense to me because
pres is was changing why would you do
that I don't get it but the
archaeologists have a reason for it and
I'm trying to be a good archaeologist
someday so I use what they use
right well the three sisters in iroa or
in hodon areas um territories um have
been Central to our cultural identity um
in our oral text such as the creation
story and the words that come before all
else um um in all aspects of Social and
um you know political institutions and
in um subsistence and of course um women
were the farmers in IRA and um women
controlled most aspects of agricultural
um work um in the the top right you see
a a a watercolor painting by Ernie Smith
a Asen artist in the 1930s
um portraying a a very typical iroy view
of the plants they're portrayed as as
members of a family as women um and the
difference between the plant and the
human beings is not discernible right
they're they're they're one um we also
see another painting below by By Ernie
Smith um showing uh this one was called
corn gathers um another one of his
paintings showing women bringing corn in
from the field
and the the drawing on the left was by a
Jesuit up in the
um 1600s who was uh along the St
Lawrence with iryan um Villages and
Farmers up there and this was one of uh
the drawings that he made of women
working in the the field with handheld
hose in terms of the agronomic
characteristics of the the three sisters
they're typically planted on mounds and
this is a you see there is a a photo
from early 1900s um in eastern um in
Western Massachusetts and this was
thought to be an old Indian um Planting
Field the crops were usually planted as
a polyculture but not always there are
indications that there were sometimes
corn monocultures or bean monocultures
and sometimes I think even um pumpkin
monocultures there were no Plows in this
cropping system it was hands hand to
only it was continuously cropped meaning
this was a permanent agriculture not
shifting cultivation the primary reason
for that is where most of this
agriculture was taking place um which is
along the the center of New York State
present day New York State and this is a
band of ferti of Alphas sols which are
highly fertile um this is where most of
our best agriculture is even um now so
the continuously cropped means that
these were on very highly productive
fertile soils um when we think about
shifting cultivation that is a a
management strategy for um acid INF
fertile soils and so not applicable here
um at this time in terms of the
Agricultural productivity of this system
uh historic records provide uh a very um
extensive um record of firsthand
observations that date all the way back
into the 1680s even earlier um
indicating that uh IR Corin agriculture
was highly productive people were amazed
at the types of of um crops that they
were seeing but no one took any yields
so we have no measures of um corn
bushels of corn per acre which as a
agricultural scientist that's what I'm
always interested in so um back in the
middle
1990s um decided to do some field
research and to get some numbers so we
carried out some experiments at the
Musgrave research Farm up in kuga county
and on a private Farm in Tomkins County
and as much as we could we used crop
varieties and agronomic practices
similar to what the iroy would have used
in the 17th and 18th centuries I'm going
to show you some quick crop yields um
this was at Tomkins County averaged over
two years and these are the three
sisters meaning the wrong
way
no not liking
that
okay so these are
the the three sisters the crops corn
beans in squash corn and green bean in
in Orange and pumpkin yellow corn by
itself Bean by itself and pumpkin by
itself so that's what happened in in
Tomkins County over two years
um in kuga County it looked quite a bit
different the three
sisters almost no corn almost no beans
or pumpkin um higher yields the corn
monoculture about the same Bean
monoculture pretty Dreadful and pumpkin
monoculture equally Dreadful
all
right what agronomists do one of the
problems with yields like this trying to
compare pumpkins with corn is uh you
can't do it um it really doesn't make
any sense so what agronomist do we use
something called land equivalency ratios
and what we do is we simply look at the
ratio of each one of the crops in the
polyculture and compare it to when it
was grown in monocultures so for example
the corn yield in Tomkins County in 1993
was
1874 in the three sisters and
2231 when it was grown as a monoculture
meaning that we basically got 82% of the
yield in the three sisters compared uh
to when it was grown as a monoculture
we' go down and do the same thing for
beans 132 in the in the three sisters
versus 1096 we only got 12% of the yield
if we look at the pumpkins
14,46 to over 40,000 we got about a
third what we do is we add up those
ratios and we get a number
1.3 that's the land equivalency ratio
and anytime the number is over one what
intercropping people say is that it was
an advantage to have planted it as a
polyculture if the number is less than
one it says you should have stuck with
monocultures right so we can look at
Tomkins 1994 1.08 kuga 1997
1.16 much of the um polyculture
intercropping you know literature will
show results like this although
sometimes the yields are less we get LS
less than one but in this particular
examples they're all over
one all right I've just been talking
about crop yields and
the title is what did they eat right so
I'm interested in food values and I'm
focusing on two things energy and
protein and the reason for this is that
subsistence farmers will first ensure
that they can actually feed their
families that their families won't
starve and so what they do is they look
to produce energy their next priority
after they're making sure people aren't
starving is to increase the quality of
the diet um by adding protein so as a
consequence of this most subsistance
farmers will plant a grain like wheat
maze rice for energy calories and a
legume like Bean Pea or lentils in order
to add
protein but I'm back to this question
again because before we go any further
we have to be clear about what we're
talking about here what did they really
eat now I've given l lots and lots of
workshops to little fourth graders all
around Tomkins County with my kids and
then with lots of other people's kids
right um and almost every time after we
do a workshop on the three sisters some
little kid will come up and grab my arm
and say but what did they really eat um
because they're thinking corn sweet corn
and green beans and pumpkins and it's
hard to
imagine making a real meal out of that
so always the question what did they
really eat well it is confusing because
corn we can Harvest it when it's
immature green you notice the socks are
green the the husks are green and if you
pull back the husk that kernel is going
it's if you pinch it it will squirt milk
into your eye and we call this sweet
corn right so that's one way corn Zam ma
but we also have Zam ma that looks like
this and this is mature corn right um
notice it's brown the stems are brown
the leaves are brown notice the ears the
hus are brown and notice how different
the kernels look right they're hard this
is grain corn
right we can do the same thing for beans
this is fasolis bulgaras kidney
bean we can Harvest it when it's
immature green the leaves are green the
pods are green slice open the pod right
we see a little tiny seed in there but
we're eating that whole pod but we could
leave the plant in the field let it
fully mature notice everything's turning
brown now we Harvest a pod but we take
out the seeds inside there and we eat
those no longer interested in that pot
well
the this has major effects on the
nutrient content of these Foods so for
example
sorry if we eat ma if we Harvest MAA
sweet corn 75% of it is water it has 86
calories and 3 gram of protein but if we
wait and harvest it as matured grain
it's only 10% water 3,650
calories and N gram of protein what
happens with green bean is even more
striking Harvest it when it's green 90%
water 31 calories 2 gram of protein wait
until it's mature we call it a kidney
bean 12% water 3370 calories and 30 g of
protein so you can guess if you're a
subsistance
farmer when you're going to harvest your
crops um predominant particularly if
you're worried right maybe you don't
have enough you're going to be
harvesting mature grain and mature beans
so corn grain and um and dried beans all
right but now we want to go from a crop
yield to a food yield and it turns out
this is a fairly complicated process
it's not so easy so I'm bringing back
this this data from the field
experiments but now I've averaged over
sites and over
Years and we're looking at crop weights
at Harvest weights not dry weights more
or less at Harvest weights
and the Maze is at 10% water the beans
at 12% pumpkin flesh at 90 pumpkin seed
at 5 noticed here now I've divided the
pumpkin into the Flesh and the seed so
now if we look at these crop weights at
Harvest we see um the three sisters
these are are just weights over the the
years but look at this pumpkin right I
mean if you're just thinking about
weight you'd say wellow we should just
go with the pumpkins there's more of
that than anything else but the problem
is that most of that pumpkin is water
and water has neither calories nor
protein so if we're interested in its
food value we've got to figure out a way
to get rid of the water and fair it and
compare it more um more fairly so we
convert the Harvest weight to energy and
protein and the ways that we do this is
we look at the
USDA nutritional database which gives us
the amount of
calories in
maze this is when it has 10% water so
we've got maze 3650 kog per calories per
kilogram and 94 g of protein per
kilogram Bean very similar to maze but a
lot more protein about the same amount
of water pumpkin flesh only 260 calories
10 gram of protein and an awful lot of
water right pumpkin seed whoa
5,590 calories
302 of uh grams of protein and only five
of water well now we're beginning to see
some differences in how we might um
begin to uh compare these different
systems so in in this graph what I'm
showing is the three sisters here and
this is the total calories coming from
maze the bean pumpkin seed and pumpkin
flesh and notice the amount of energy
there um it's actually more than what we
get from ma monoculture it's way more
than we get from Bean monoculture and
it's a lot more than what we get from
pumpkin but note also that a huge amount
of the pumpkin calories is coming from
the seed right now you might want to
remember the land equivalency ratio and
how that even with just the weights
showed us that even
with the three sisters we got an ler of
slightly over one compared to the corn
monoculture right um so we know that we
can we can do better and the energy
reflects
that I just brought this up to show you
and remind you again right we'll go on
we can do the same thing with protein
right so this one we're looking at
protein in the three
sisters in maze monoculture in Bean
monoculture and in pumpkin monoculture
right and notice the significant
contribution from the beans and the
Pumpkin both flesh and seeds and notice
that it is now quite a bit higher than
maze monoculture and still higher than
the bean and still higher than pumpkin
but many of you are saying but wait a
minute plant proteins are incomplete so
those how can you really be measuring
the proteins because we know that plants
don't provide all of the essential amino
acids that we need right so they have
different amounts and that is absolutely
true let's look at the the um the maze
the bean the pumpkin seed and I've put
pumpkin flesh up here too these are the
essential amino acids and what we will
notice is that four of
these isoline lysine 309 and
tryptophan corn in particular is low in
these and bean nicely complements where
the maze is low and surprisingly the
pumpkin seeds are really strong in some
of those areas as well you probably
asking but these numbers on the pumpkin
flesh they're so small why why do you
even include include them well there's a
lot of pumpkin flesh and when you add up
all of those amino acids they can
complement the amino acids in the other
plant Foods or from other Foods whether
it's fish or or nuts or um deer they can
be part of the protein contribution even
though the concentration is so small
I was also interested in looking at
calcium vitamins A and C and nasin and
these again are um taken from the
USDA nutrient database what we see that
sorry what we see down at the bottom is
a recommended daily allowance so for
example for calcium we need a th and
when we look here we see we're not
looking so good right um not very good
numbers here for any of these these
Foods if we look at Vitamin A oh ma and
beans are Dreadful but pumpkin flesh
whoa we need 5,000 and when we get 8,500
and 100 milligrams vitamin A is not
going to be a problem right vitamin C
however uh we need 60 and we're pretty
low right and niin we need 50
and this doesn't look so great either
all right we'll come back and talk a
little bit more about
this this wonderful word
nalization um it's a word that means
it's a way of preparing corn corn grain
um that it is soaked and usually cooked
in an alkaline um water a solution in
iria we cook it in hardwood Ash right
nalization does a number of really neat
things the very first thing is it
dramatically reduces cooking time
because the alkaline solution attacks
the parac carp of maze um which is very
very hard and it begins to hydrolize it
so that water can get in much more
quickly um and so it dramatically
reduces cooking time but the other thing
that um nalization does all of those
ashes have lots of calcium and what
happens is the calcium gets attracted to
ma starch grains and so the calcium
content of the of the corn or the maze
increases 100 to
400% the nization also improves protein
qu quality and it does this remember the
the amino acids and I showed you a bunch
of them that Co horn was really
deficient in that's lysine tryptophan
histadine methionine and 309
so it increases the relative amounts of
of these amino acids so the end result
is it's it makes corn a higher quality
protein meaning it doesn't have yes do
you know if um when nalization is done
with lime as done by the indigenous
people in Mexico and Central America
whether it has the same impact on
calcium content exactly the same yes
exactly the same it's just a difference
in what you're doing what you're using
to make the alkaline you know solution
so
um so when we nixim malize corn we
actually improve its protein quality
because we balance out some of or we
increase the amounts of some of those am
acids which are very low but it also has
another impact in that it increases
nasin which is part of the vitamin B
complex preventing pgra plra is a really
ugly terrible disease that was uh
rampant in the Southeastern Us in the
early 1900s it is still widespread in
parts of Africa and Asia and it comes
from um
primarily a diet that is almost
exclusively corn and the problem with
the corn is
that it's low in tryptophan and
tryptophan is a precursor to forming
nasin right so when you nalize you
increase the
tryptophan and that increases the nasin
right before colonization there was not
a single documented case of pelra in the
Western Hemisphere it was only after
that pelra came and much of it has to do
with the process of
nixtamalization because when the poor
folks in the southeast United States
were eating corn they were mostly just
grinding it and not nalizing it first
and they were so poor they had no beans
either and the same thing is true in
parts of Africa and Asia it's this is a
a disease of poor people who do not have
the technology the nalization um or any
kind of legume in order to um increase
the quality all right so we've talked
about all these comparisons and I've
told you how wonderful the three sisters
is compared to monocultures of of um
Maze and and bean and pumpkin although
I'm sure many of you are
noting this mayze mind on culture um in
both energy and protein maze is amazing
right it really is hard to beat maze out
yields every other grain crop it
is just pretty spectacular as Margaret
Smith here is nodding away um um but so
I've been I've been comparing the three
sisters with a maze monoculture a bean
monoculture and a pumpkin monoculture
and what I am implying is
iroy Farmers would choose um to plant
the three sisters or no we're not going
to plant our field to the three sisters
this year we're going to plant a bean
monoculture there's no way that would
happen it's not a choice between
planting your field um to the three
sisters or deciding just to plant
pumpkin I mean they know that's not
going to work right I mean it doesn't
make any sense right um you're not going
to
decide between three crops and one crop
for your entire
field right rather you're going to take
your field and I couldn't make this into
a square right so so pretend that the
the the field is is a circle right so
instead of planting the three sisters we
might decide to plant 1/3 of the field
to Corn 1/3 to beans and 1/3 to pumpkin
right so instead of having the three
sisters over the entire field we divide
it into three parts and put one crop
here but it's still on the same field
right it's still let's say one hectare
right so 1/3 of the hectare is corn 1/3
is Bean 13 is squash right or we could
decide seeing how productive the corn is
I'm going to put half of it half of the
field into corn and I'm going to put 25%
into bean and 25% into pumpkin or I
really say that corn is looking awfully
good I'm going to put 80% of the Corn of
the field into corn and only 10% into
bean and pumpkin right this is a much
more realistic comparison of what people
would actually choose the decisions that
farmers are making so now let's look at
monoculture mixtures versus the three
sisters so this first one and we're
looking at energy um so this first one
says we've got a third
right we've got a third of these crops
and this is how much each one of these
the maze bean and pumpkin um contribute
to the total energy
right it's looking not so great right if
we look at the one that's 50% corn and
then
10% um 25 and 25 being in pumpkin we can
see the we're doing better but it's
still not great when we put
80% into corn we're doing better if we
plant the whole field to Corn we're even
better right forget the pumpkin and the
Squash and the beans right just plant
corn but now look at the three sisters
right when we plant the corn and we add
the bean and pump
we get a jump in the amount of energy
that's the land equivalency ratio that
we saw in the yield as well but we see
it in energy too right we see that yeah
there's a good reason why these farmers
are planting the three sisters because
it turns out that we get more energy
from this than anything else we can
look at the same thing in terms of
protein but it looks different right
first of all
um we look at the 1/3 1/3 1/3 and we can
see we're we're getting about a third
from me from Mae a little bit more than
a a third from the pumpkin and something
less than that from the beans but the
total amount is still less than what we
get from the three sisters and every
time we increase the amount of corn we
increase the amount of protein right it
goes up and we get right up to there
when we go all corn but notice the
significant impact of the three sisters
on increasing protein now I would argue
that this is the major advantage of the
three sisters um not so much in terms of
energy it does give extra energy but
it's really the protein so all of these
are on the same piece of land right and
we've just varied um whether it's three
sisters or the others Mario and what's
the
mixture this one oh the the mixture um I
mean these are all this is It's the
standard thing right um
I when you're asking what portion of
this um most of the yield is coming from
the corn whether it's protein or energy
but it the fact is that this is on one
piece of land
so exactly where it comes from doesn't
matter right I mean you you plant three
kernels of of corn in the hill and two
or three of beans and you plant the the
pumpkin in between what you're
interested in is what comes out right of
what the yield is in terms of energy and
protein
right all right one last question that
I'm interested in is well how many
people I and I'll tell you how I got
started on this I got called by the um
Museum of the American Indian in New
York City the national museum but not
the one in in in Washington it's its
Other Side in New York City and they're
doing a program educational program on
the three sisters and they wanted to
have a a a cropping game in which young
kids in their families would plant
different amounts either as polycultures
of the three sisters or as monocultures
and they wanted to make it real and they
said well how many people could could it
feed you know like an acre of the three
sisters right and I said oh well I'll
have to do some calculations and I did
some quick quick back ofth envelope
calculations and I I realized it was a
very interesting question about how many
people could
actually eat off of a Hector of the
three sisters right and so um in order
to make this kind of calculation you
first have to determine well what are
the um daily requirements of an active
adult for energy in other words how many
calories do we need and what about
protein so on a daily basis 2500
calories per day is pretty realistic 60
gram of protein realistic you just
multiply by 365 and you come up with
what one person would need for a year
close to a million calories right to
provide Basics and 22 kilogram of
protein right and then I just go back to
the data that I just showed you and kind
of divide it
out so people supported by monoculture
mixtures the ones I was showing you
before and the Three Sisters in this
case the energy is in the lighter kind
of tan and the protein is in the the
darker color and what we see is that on
the everything in a third we able to
feed um probably seven people per
hectare um in terms of energy Supply
that um in terms of protein we get over
10 right notice that is each time the
corn goes up each of these numbers
increases so we're up to with with the
uh monoculture of corn we're up to about
12 and a half people fed per hectare um
in terms of of energy and about 13 and a
half in terms of protein but once again
the three
sisters in terms of energy we could
supply for about 13 people and in terms
of protein about 15 and a half um just
for comparison to think about it and I
have these figures and could actually do
it but I didn't think I would have time
today if we looked at European Wheat
Growers in the same time period um
wheat farmers in Europe were struggling
to feed even three or four people per
heor right and so what we see here is a
cropping system that is multiple times
more productive and able to support more
people all right so what are the
conclusions here first that intercropped
maze bean and pumpkin is highly
productive um and it certainly could
have been counted on um to largely
satisfy hodon dietary needs there are no
indication that they that they used only
these crops in fact many many other
sources of food um in in this area very
very productive ecosystem with all sorts
of other
plants um you know wild plants lots of
animals and fish um but certainly as the
foundation for um their diet it was
doing a a great job um one of the
reasons for this is maze um it is the
anchor of the system and with its very
high crop yields it produces really
enormous amounts of energy and a lot of
protein um the three sisters as a
cropping system provides more energy and
protein than individual crop
monocultures and more than monoculture
mixtures of these um three
crops the pumpkin and the bean and
pumpkin seeds um increase the total am
amounts of protein and improve protein
quality the pumpkin flesh provides lots
of vitamin A and Maze nalization
decreases cooking time increases calcium
100 to 400% improves protein quality and
increases nasin preventing um pagr if
we're looking at how many people we can
support three sisters um ah and I have
to qualify this these are based
on yield from field experiments right
and the
amounts the maze yields I am absolutely
confident in these are very realistic
maze yields in either the polyculture or
when planted as a monoculture these are
very realistic yields the beans and the
Pumpkin much less experience in only a
couple of sites and and um years so I
have much less confidence in the beans
and pumpkin but it's pretty clear to me
that even with relatively small amounts
small yields of beans and pumpkin um the
the three sisters does a great job
because even those small amounts boost
things enough um to significantly
increase um energy and and protein so in
terms of energy enough for 13.4 people
per hectare per year and in terms of
protein almost um 16 people per Hector
per year so with that I'm open to
questions the explanation for the
overyielding mostly the nitrogen from
the beans or not no I mean I would say
that the contribution of of beans in
terms of nitrogen to the coof system is
very minor and the reason for that is
that people eat the beans which are what
contains most of the nitrogen there are
small amounts of nitrogen in the stems
leaves but majority of the of the
nitrogen in the beam is in in the beam
right and once you eat it the only way
it gets back onto the field is if you
put human waste back on the field like
we do with with with cops right so the
bean contribution is is relatively
unimportant I think the reason for the
extra for the increase productivity at
least what you know literature on
intercropping tells us that it's just
increased um efficiency of the entire
system in other words the three crops
are collecting more sunlight and more
energy they're Gathering more water
their roots are gathering more water and
nutrients underneath and as a result of
that we're seeing um small efficiencies
that result in somewhat greater
y can you say anything about how these
Foods were prepared and eat in terms
ofas
lots of different indigenous not
tortillas um the the corn and and beans
primarily in in soup and in bread um the
person to look for that um two um two
major sources one is Arthur Parker um
iry uses of Maze and other food CRS and
his contemporary wall W Au u h um and I
I think it's just called eord grps and
both of those were written in the 1900s
and get very um extensive
descriptions Jane the cucurbit that you
spoke about was pumpkin was that the
sole cucurbit type that the H use now
there was indications um uh particularly
at the time of San's campaign that there
were lots of different types of con
curbit and con curbit are a bit of a
nightmare in terms of their complex
and I barely feel competent to even say
what I know is that um the one that I am
looking at and and the the nutrient data
that I've taken from um is
curita mar you got it right got it right
so um and those are crops um that have
brightly colored flesh um quite firm
right so it looks like a pumpkin or what
we would often think of as a winter
squash but the acorn is in a different
place right even though Acorn we think
of as a winter squash the acorn is not P
it's peopleo overa I think or something
like that anyways but there were other
cucurbit that were much more similar to
like melons um and things maybe even
cucumbers that the English might have
known about out because they seem to
during Sullivan's campaign kind of give
them names that sounded like so they
might have been growing lots of other
things too right but I focus for the
food value on the on the pumpkin or the
winter squash because it is the
most in the process of
mization I'd expect some nutrients to be
lost in the solution but they're also
picking up calcium you have any
information of well the one thing about
nalization that I did learn which
surprised me was that the total protein
actually decreases on the corn uh the
total amount of protein of nixed corn is
less than
uned um but the reason but and I think
some of that may I'm not even sure how
that happens but uh the protein quality
increases substantially right so that
more than compensates right in terms of
other things that might be lost in terms
of leeching I didn't see anything and
I've read a a number of papers on
nalization and I don't recall them
saying um that things were lost other
than protein went down total
protein um I know that t originates in
Central America do sashing be also come
from Central America um yes uh short
answer yes although squash was um
domesticated at two different times um
in the Eastern woodlands in North
America um and in you know Central and
South America um but the first squashes
that were domesticated were inedible ORS
and so then there the there is a
um when as far as I understand the
edible um you know squash comes in quite
a bit later right but again
at I'm not sure of that the edible
squash may have been only domesticated
in in Central America and then moved
forward because what was domesticated in
the Eastern Woodlands was an
inevitable second part of question do
you see the three sisters
elsewhere like such in as in Mexico with
the than absolutely okay as Carl Sawyer
said it's across the entire Western
Hemisphere at least up into kind of
Southern Canada um and goes all the way
down I'm not sure probably not Peru yes
yes Peru too okay so it's all over
sometimes they only use two right um but
most of the time there are
three um with the same with the three
sisters being grown in the same place
year after year um did that that system
require fertility additions at any time
this is a great question and I will send
you an article on this it says yes I
mean they were not grown indefinitely
because IR coin Villages were moved
frequently it used to be the standard
um kind of rationale given was that the
soils became completed
um that's not true the soils did not be
become depleted primarily because the
uroid did not use clouds um and they
were starting on very fertile soils
Alpha soils the major loss of fertility
in agricultural systems is not from crop
UPC it's from plowing which causes
oxidation of
nitrates and most of those nitrates
leave the the soil system only a few are
captured by the crow when you plow
continuously Which Europeans and US
settlers did for a couple of hundred
years you
will see a dramatic decline in soil
fertility it had always been assumed
that the reason for that was these crops
were just grabbing out all of that
nitrogen but that's not true the major
reason for the decline in fertility was
the continuous
plowing so the fact that the uoy were
growing crops starting with very fertile
soils alas Sals typically will have
unplowed 4 to 5% nitrogen if you don't
plow them the only thing that you are
losing then is what's taken up by the
crop small amounts when you're digging
out there with your hoe don't get Capt
by The Roots but the decrease in soil
organic matter and in nitrogen is very
very small right so from what we can see
the iroy were
not you know cutting down trees and
looking for new Fields every year once
they had cleared a field and formed
those mountains they probably stayed
there for as long as the vill Village
State and the village moved not because
of soil fertility decline but because of
trade needs of defensive needs of um the
long housee was infested with fleas
right I mean whatever they reasons to
move but it had nothing to do with
declining soil
fertility what about um like insects and
diseases were they all brought by
Europeans or there any any of any of the
major in diseases like
I mean certainly
European few
others or any other disas no I'm sure
that they had you know diseases would be
maybe a reason for
one I mean I my guess is that the squash
plugs would will accumulate wherever the
squashes right um they don't have a hard
time finding it um I mean the the thing
that I would think would be the biggest
um pest would be weeds right um and the
the weeds we could never grow the three
sisters at the muser farm or any place
else without doing an awful lot of an
weat um the re two reasons for this one
is because we are in we're using plows
and so when you use plows you're
constantly bringing up the weed seeds
and encouraging weeds to you know
germinate um um and second a lot of the
weeds that are most um you know
Troublesome now in New York state are
imports from
Europe
so thank you so much Jane
for this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu