this is a production of Cornell
University
so my title today is messages from a
maverick
model microbe and
what I realized is how much I believe
you enjoyed my pathology this morning I
was grateful that I had the opportunity
to think about this seminar and
lecturing today instead of other things
and it was about very grateful for that
obviously the model microbe is
phytophthora infestans and we know how
order to say also this photo which I've
seen many many many many places without
ever any attribution was from Vaughn
chains from my lap about 30 35 years ago
um we know that are tough infestans is a
model micro because soak in commune and
31 and it's very closest friends have
said so it says so in this publication
sage advice Ellen I don't think so
that's not what actually you and I would
just say some of the reasons why I
cannot
first of all
I'm an introvert and
for those of you who are introverts
moves an introvert yeah okay so we don't
even buy so easily it's really hard and
you heard
finish finish finish
yes
absolutely crazy what's up I'll be
talking like this oh
and also you know my career
really did not have a special plan it
just sort of happened so i have to say i
have had no special career goals so
there's nothing I can say that would
provide any miracles to anybody
but I have wanted to do is be a
professor in a small University I got
the professor part right never quite
made a small University and life I think
some of you my first years in the in
graduate school were sort of tough I
wasn't sure that I shouldn't be in
technology and it was interesting to to
go through that experience
and I suspect that I'm not alone in that
and I think that that's
okay I have subsequently come to this
absolutely
really enjoy the subject is I find it
just really really exciting and really
lot of fun
so I have messages from five top 35
states and three categories and
since i'm not giving advice what i'm
going to do is sort of relate some
things that I've learned during the last
several years
in these categories first love
epidemiology and population genetics of
phytophthora infestans
short segment on humanity and a short
section on host-pathogen interactions
for I think I'm going to illustrate sort
of the Maverick qualities of this
organism
but I need to provide some context for
all of this and
this is me as a diligent graduate
student
some years ago and you're probably all
thinking that I'm just looking but I'm
thinking very hard
disappoint notice also that I do have
brown hair at that's
be probably thinking that maybe I was
thinking about
phytophthora infestans
but actually that's not true
when I was in graduate school I was
essentially a lab rat I which the Queen
house once a year and I never got to the
field and
my thesis action was really very
interesting i discovered a new enzyme
that
was typical of pathogens of silence any
plans some plants produce
cyanogenic glycosides a new brightest to
HCM on infection ACN is running quite
toxic and
but it turns out that many pathogens of
these plants produce an enzyme that
converts how to cyanide too far behind
and I was really was really proud of
that accomplishment
but I but there's another message here
in this one and that is
that your audience really matters
it turns out the audience for cyanogenic
work in plants and very small as well as
stated here my first phytopathology
paper on xen that must be 19
okay
cyanide tolerant since I'm feeling low
tide
since 1971 has had 15 of citations my
first paper on Fatah confessed ends of
1975 and
7 950 which is interesting three or four
and last six months which is also the
most impressive paper
certainly with HD and I published was in
archives and falconers from of physics
and it's had my
citations again nothing the past three
or four months
my most highly cited paper on fight off
infestans is this one in 1994 but we
just started a global distribution of a
single from a lineage in campus with 437
citations and 20 in the last seven
points which is different so the message
here that there was an audience for my
pudding excellent working sun identity
but there was an audience for work on my
top ten pheasants I have to say this
paper yeah I know demonstration
the obvious then yet was it was
picked up by
ok so I was hired and saw this picture
for was hired to
teach Disease Control and you
appropriate research and with my
background in the plant physiology and
biochemistry that seemed like his
stretch and it was I really know put in
the world I would be going to do
so I thought long and hard about it it
has started the
position was actually here and
what I decided to do was too focused on
late blood for a variety of reasons
first of all it was a model for
secondly it was important in New York
State
it was possible to me to do field
experiments and there was expertise in
department warrant credit
when credit digs Thurston who was
remarkably generous with
advice and help
during the early stages and
he had been working with phytother
Festus but required some time I thought
he was old at that time
but he was pretty very helpful so that
was the reason I chose it all right some
epidemiology and population genetics
studies when i first started work at
secret do you think that i would really
have to do some few experiments
management my first field experiment
occurred in 1917 tubes a total boss
we've got drowned out from Hurricane
Agnes our second field experiment was of
a lunar month later in the same year
there was absolutely no disease and I
realized that this is not easy as
packaging in the world to work with
subsequently moved to frito and did
learn how to do field experiments with
white tough investments this is narrow
photo of those plots and it's a false
color infrared photo and
the healthy tissue looks bright red
diseased tissue gray or in soil sort of
three so there were really significant
differences in these and listen buddy
actually found an interesting to do
these kinds of experiments because
there were almost analogous to doing
enzyme assays just how many people have
ever done enzyme assays artistic a
couple of us old folks right and we
that anymore but I did and the
kinetics were very interesting and aziz
development is one of these plots had
kinetics that work in use and there's
really good really develop over time in
kinetics were really quite important
so what we knew about the epidemiology
of phytophthora des des was really quite
a lot and
Jack Brown in 1981 published a paper
describing a simulation model
cartoon of it you listed here and clean
enough to put this too
after it which was a really interesting
accomplished a person to run this model
took hours and hours
actually first time we get up is on
punch card to the mainframe
but we use in two experiments over the
weekend and come back and we have a
simulation experiment to do the same
experiment today takes less than a
second and
Jorge entrada
refine the model in 2005 and illustrated
that really works pretty well in these
various epidemics the
observations are in the open circles and
the prediction is in the straight
continuous line and you can see that the
prediction fits the observation pretty
nicely in most of these and that model
has been the basis for decision support
system that we've subsequently produced
students this paper by in small from
last year in which we named and use the
white pro decision support system and
that's really kind of cool
it involves host resistance
password future whether such a side a
pathogen strain and pathogen proximity
all together in helping growers make
management decisions and what's really
important i think is that all this is
done in absentia so it's it's a it's a
very nice tool
what we didn't know at that time
was what caused
unexpected disease control and
we wondered about whether the University
of the pathogen population might
contribute to that and
so we began the question looking at
population genetics and photos and
festivals and when we started this
we knew that there were a 2 and a 1 many
types in Mexico what topic of Stanton's
head without so there are too many times
he wanted nature and
only a one mating types had been found
from the rest of the world
so two people coming to lab would
already had wonderful tools totally
brought allozyme stir that followed by
Steve good one who developed here rflp
fingerprint for DNA fingerprinting I
slits prior to this time the only
markers that were available for mating
type and morphology no diversity in
mythology so we only had meeting type
essentially single market and that
because you just been joking about
populations of plant pathogens from that
these these two games a
possibility of looking at population
structure and disorganization in other
locations so we so requested Isis from
people around the world some
culture collections and
analyze those isolates using both
markets and we felt like Paul Dooley and
markers developed by Steve good way
in Mexico what we learned is that indeed
the a1 and a2 mating types were present
proportions when we applied the dusties
do they think creativity's what we
learned is that the population of rivers
and with this slide illustrates these
these numbers real estate those three
individual
individuals the DNA is in this lady's
cup with restriction fragment
restriction enzyme and then probe with
our fee 57 and what you'll see is that
these individual states are really quite
different from each other which is
consistent with this being a sexual
population in central Mexico
what we learned from everywhere else was
something we need to management and
so does affirming US Canada Peru Ecuador
Colombia the UK Netherlands going to
pantalon Philippines can under wanted
all had the same paper which was a
really interesting with occupation
we termed this
photo lineage the US 1 formal image if
you saw it first in the US and s are
everywhere else it's all it would maybe
type in one type of mitochondrial DNA of
the Allison's lurkin 112 had the same
DNA fingerprint and as always pop out
pretty to this paper doll talk about the
panworld with mr. grade distribution of
a single
linning to flip out that residents
how can you explain that kind of
situation
nobody can explain it for sure but one
possibility is that this organism went
through a severe bottleneck and when
somehow to northwest europe in northwest
europe there's a very vibrant seed
particular trait or secret a toner sold
all over the world to South America
Africa Asia and
this organism most very happily
tubers another possibility is that it
came first to the United States and in
fact make life appeared in the United
States before it appeared in Europe and
then maybe from the United States it
went to Europe and then subsequently was
distributed throughout the rest of the
world so those are some possibilities
but we continue collecting knife slips
from people around the world and
linda Spielman made a really interesting
discovery
she said look there's something else
happening in these locations around the
world and so sure enough there was
and what we suggested is that there was
a second worldwide migration and
population
this is some of the most exciting work
that ever been associated probably some
of the most important i wrote a
spectacular proposal to the best
traction
which is really interesting so it seems
like some of the most important and most
interesting projects to still make it so
that the
reviewers where he didn't like it
and they didn't believe that this could
be happening but in fact it did
it made the news in the early 1990s
there is an article from New York Times
and
this is what actually happened in the
1970s us one was disputed essentially
all around the world by 1997 those
populations have been replaced you can't
find it anymore locations can find that
particular video it's been replaced by a
different population of veterans which
is highly diverse in those locations and
actually there's sexual reproduction
occurring in in the Scandinavian
countries and
we do know how that happened there was a
shipment of potatoes from
Mexico after the 1976 season because in
New York there had been a drought in the
1976's a very short potato crop and
Europeans desire to allow Mexican
potatoes into Europe so that we use
exclusively for
you can't forget people who buy potatoes
store from planting and I'm sure that's
what happened and that's what brought in
these novel strains if I talk they're
testing and then they were
substrate from
northwestern Europe and it happened
really fast he didn't have Isis in the
Netherlands Germany and Poland we could
cut the deck and we can demonstrate that
this there was this introduction of the
new strings and they displaced
the old spines that had been and so this
message I guess is that with this
organism
vibration and population displacement
are really cute
and it didn't happen only in Europe it
also happened in the States here's an
example that is particularly
impressive to me and this concerns a
lineage that we've called the u.s. 800m
lineage we detected it in 1992 and watch
new computer
season at the invite season we had a
sample from Maine which also had that
which gives him astray before because
we've sampled from Northwest Mexico and
found this exactly
president in a Northwest Mexico and then
in 1994 you covered the entire
eastern part of the US and by 1995 could
colonize all of the western part of the
u.s.
so one of the things that we've done is
to look at the population structure over
time and this slide prepared by Giovanni
Johnny's illustrates that us eight was
the dominant strain from 1997 to 2008
replaced in 2009 by us 22 now they just
wondered throughout that and then you
can see that after
2010 that US 23 has become the dominant
strain and this turns out to be really
difficult for fight often festivals is
that there are these waves of
predominance and disappearance and it's
not is to not only in
the US but also in Europe and these are
data from people who illustrates that
the
u.s. one strains present 1982 were gone
by 1995 and then these a one stranger
present until about two thousand five
and starting in 2005 there was dominance
by destroyed here which of blue 13 or 13
a2 and that
and
so the take-home message concerning
epidemiology and population turns to me
is that all non Mexicans Mexican
phytophthora infestans populations are
recently derived from outside
this organs we just goes in lots of
places I've seen reports where people
have suggested that we have an Irish
stringing a fight off Manchester what
they don't say so we've been there for
10 years and prior to that it was in
Mexico would you say there's no way that
there is such a thing as an Irish
straight there's no way that there's
such a thing as the US as a nuestra
they're all recently arrived from
okay
so my next topic is about humanity
I took this picture in early August
[Music]
1994 and this is a potato form and this
is a potato field and
its ground because it was destroyed by
that light and
this is a sprayer right here in that car
engine spray two or three times a week
to
suppress lately so I talked on the
grower
this is always difficult to say
about where you could
and he said every Thursday night the
growers in this county pitfield in
Crimea
and that's because I think we're other
customers i think this strain would you
just relax all
spin dramatically more aggressive
you just wrote on a customer
so that was Sir my first
introduction to the damage and human
impact that this disease
it's a picture of Irish happened he was
a blower in Madison County
and in nineteen metaphor he lost his
problems
these are dead he said illustrating but
late blight 1990 94 in 1995
bankruptcy and a clean nurse later he
died
we 2009 of similar story having this
really fascinating Kevin Myers in my
life took this picture at our local
Lowe's to this picture and gene 23rd
these are explained of transfers to be
sold to local garters and they are
infected with Python third persons and
what happened was what happened not only
in our Louis but New Jersey and
Pennsylvania in Connecticut in Maine all
throughout the Northeast
and a visit to this organic farm I think
forget of july in
2009 and this was the lat plenty of
tomatoes and they would be deterred by
the lake life as well and i received
this letter
which i think Bob's me I am an organic
gardener in Amsterdam New York with 63
heirloom tomato plants and 23 different
varieties they're all gone I was growing
very rare varieties blacks being oranges
whites I'll purchase from a very
reputable brands of Harry can I have
believed home as my husband pulling that
you all 63 plants I have a her percent
loss we know on 10 acres I inspected
every day and it seems the black took my
defense in a matter of hours
I was hoping to sell them for additional
people so on this
as I chose late blight to work on as an
academic
convenient system to use I've heard
about all this snow from the Irish
potato famine at all but to experience
is really really quite significant and
this side was given to me by san jo
Illinois it was an example of a 2014
lake in west bengal in india and
what happened there was that in 2013
Melvin's significant overproduction at
mid to low prices and centaurs could not
be the motorcade in 2014 there was a
devastating Lakeland epidemic caused by
in Europe
there were term Eliza's economic and
social amend farmer suicides and then
some toys particularly disappointed that
the government or he is limited exports
to other places because that sort of
distorted future markets for the growers
of our communities
so my lesson that I've taken from this
one is that light line
okay next on to host-pathogen
interactions is my third topic
message and
label this one of the fryer lab failures
and
is their failures because
we've been unable to see phenotypes that
other folks see
the first one concerns on purified
Osment in which according to the pnas
article confer resistance
so we've received the
developers of is we're happy to send us
transgenic potatoes that were expressed
in PR card
we put them in the field this is an
experiment where we had different
potatoes genotypes and
unfortunately the plants with pr5 we're
not at all resistant just completely not
so that's you know we just could not
achieve the same result that the folks
at Purdue energy
and then a year to later conversation
colleague in Europe and she said I've
created resistance to lately I said wow
that's great
the company and they were going to
create transgenic potatoes that were
resistant to late life and unfortunately
were able to do a test which confirmed
that experiment and this is a picture of
that field experiment there's some
people to know who were part of that
experiment and remember it well
and by this time I've learned how to
kill plants inflate boy and
although the company would never come
across or convinced that what happened
the concert had a pathogen specific
promoter
with an arching and a navy argue so that
upon our NOC ulation of leave with quite
often pest hands we make hypersensitive
response and
resistance and I think that's what they
saw in their experiments of Europe so
this is a just after we had an
occupation and this is what we saw after
the progressive turns out there was
indeed diversity in the transgenders
someone more resistant somewhere less
there is nothing associated
that was diversity so one of the things
I really don't think this is that if you
put potatoes to a palace reduce the
laughter's summer funk very much and
that explains the person that you'll see
the question is why why do some people
see these
these phenotypes that week and
I wanted that for some years and then
just in the last couple of years I think
I think I actually know and I think the
answer is at sporangia from a culture
are not the same as spread year from
leading colleges and people inoculate
the growth chamber with Sturridge of the
culture an epidemic in the field
so
the reason I think I know this
comes in part with work from
headquarters in routine
water was this his approach was to his
goal was to look at how sensitive my
toughest had spread to our to solar
radiation and
you he had a terrible time he was one of
her happy register for the summer
because every time he did this
experiment you take the spreadsheet from
culturing expose them to someone
absolutely no surprise
finally a desperation when he didn't
have a culture available he took some
spreading from the leaf and long before
they didn't
copy conditions 87 survived for hours
mm-hmm under sunny conditions which is
illustrated here most of their dead
within 60 minutes but they survived 15
minutes installation so clearly
the sporangia from this culture army
which don't survive at all spend you
from the juicer god they're pretty
different from each other
they work with then closing we had
another insight into this dan was
working on arachidonic acid and where he
demonstrated that in fact retreat plans
of arachidonic acid to become more
resistant to phytophthora infestans
which is just great and here's an image
of that here is a leaflet that did not
have our economic acid applied to it and
you can see nice lesion here's a leaflet
that did have our epidemic acid and the
is a very small regional population but
we tried to repeat that experiment and
the same
and then I realize the reason we didn't
get that phenotype is that we were
taking our
spray get from papers and
inoculate so if you take a scrounging
from a leaflet and you put it on to
plants treated either treat not treated
with arachidonic acid or treated with
our economic acid um
again it's this exact same pathogen one
comes from leaf the other comes from
so one of the questions that Shawn
parties was asking is is there an
effective dist pathogenicity and
he did a field experiment in which he
took sprang from the culture two
different isolates and
inoculated plants in the field and
leaflets in moisture and you can see
that he did get disease
different amounts of disease from the
two isolates if he took sporangia from a
leaflet
both in the field pots for both isolates
you've got a lot more disease the same
numbers branch then he did
if the ISIS came from culture and that's
particularly true with the disease on
leafless
in moisture
so our goal is to try to understand what
what is happening and one approach is to
use our NAC to determine first of all if
this branch are different from each
other and secondly to see what's
happening during the infection process
those materials are still at while
they're going to come back we don't have
them yet so in
lieu of having the RNA seek data Sean
did some one day in real time pcr and
what we know is that infamous elicited
by talking to us today that's a protein
if you put it into tobacco it's a
hypersensitive response
we know that that
smoothie indeed elicited is
downregulated in
Infante oh
there is an RX lr that which is an
effector from photographer investor from
previous studies we knew that one to be
upregulated in
in tissue and so what we did was to
compare the expression of these two
genes in spreads that came from the
leaves or from culture and what we found
was that from culture info on which
causes hundred
the are XLR which is an effector
was definitely so what Ron did was to
look at the ratio of inform the
expression of if one to the expression
of our XLR between spreads that came
from culture or sprint to the king from
leaflets and what he found is that for
these two isolates there's about a more
than a 50-fold difference in expression
of those teachers and our suspect that
that difference in expression can cause
a different phenotype if you're using a
strange infant culture person system
so the pathogen clearly is different
what about the host but that is in
different environments and it turns out
i think that the host also be different
we did this experiment
last year right now
2000 one or two thousand or two dozen
three something like that and chris was
heavily involved in this one we were
looking at the differences in resistor
between two
closely related tomato compressions but
we did find a QTL for resistance and
what was wrong about this
he's at first of all we could get fairly
expression and without a whole lot of
noise which mr. interested we used micro
thomas is old technology that
but one of the most interesting to me
discoveries
for plants that were not inoculated just
growing together what we found was that
the top 34 of the top 200 most variable
we're all defensively
and what I'm wondering is are they in
fact divest really are they just are
they just perturbation
in destroying in the field over here
exposed to all kinds of things and
the top six included catalase which is
the first one and then five PR team
concluded the most
variable strains of arabic genes in this
experiment
we also found a significant differential
expression of genes in the two different
two different genotypes of planets and
we found that we were able to science to
of about thirty two they were
upregulated in il-62 but not i may need
to get maybe two of us and more
susceptible when we silenced those two
it reduce the resistance in il-6 to
the conclusion i come to is that field
expertise of field studies of gene
expression are entirely possible and
there's not a huge amount of noise you
don't have to
always get a huge amount of very sore
throat
and i'm just going to suggest that if we
really are interested in post per second
version that's happening sort of a field
that is a whole lot more efficient to do
this kind of experiment
so the third message I have concerning
post-crescent interactions is that may
be at least r500 distance and its host
the
interaction can be specific
so finally
the three messages to me are there is no
such thing except in Supreme Mexico the
native
african fest and
late blight can be absolutely true and
we also get with it can be specific to
the environment
now this is a maverick micro I'm on my
good friend Cindy McNabb
developed this Limerick
phytophthora infestans is freaking
prototypical also quite speaking its
maverick waves cause eyebrows to raise
in theories turn porous and linking
sometimes it textbook quintessential
exemplary so elemental that's when it
conforms to microbial norms a model
that's quite providential
sometimes it's in freakin weird a
renegade has reappeared starts breaking
rules making us look like fools
conclusive results disappear this model
that's this micro that's model and
maverick exemplary and enigmatic we must
understand learned by both and eccentric
yet paradigm
so I'd like to thank you also to
recognize this group of people through
my work I
don't have pictures of everybody
this time but i would like to Lisa
Christmas in the audience now
over there oh
if I'd my wife Barbara is here she works
in the lab and has been a big partner so
I think with that homeless and there's
already questions of being happy to try
to dust
[Applause]
so you found that things like sporangia
or resistance or variable
parameters
uh
that's I think the matching the model
does need to be recalibrated what we
learned is that different isolates have
different parameters
most models are constructed on the US
for money
the
capability of those models is very not
known at this point to
how useful they are I think what we saw
was sort of a qualitative difference in
terms of
in terms of the
field versus the
greenhouse type of direction but this
problems intestinal exclusively or not
specific a lot in the field so I think
that has helped us a lot
so your take-home message number one is
that all the isolates that we know of
today came from Mexico if they're all
moving about we're giving these new
epidemics with new genotypes presumably
you get different mating types that move
out and then you could get
geographically specific isil's right
when do you think that's you think it's
already happening yeah it's happening
there's um there's a sexual population
in Scandinavian countries and probably
poland i still need Olivia western
Russia
and whether that will develop into
something dramatically different all
right ah in many places it's still
hiding from
traumatic apologists like it is in the
United States the all of Africans that
way
India Asia are that way
South America is that way
so there's there's its initiative
actually I mean there is sexual
reproduction in that part of the world
including the step
but most other locations have
clonal lineages and someone said the
same one like this blue 13 which is
found in Europe is now dominant in China
and
so just as the follow-up to that so for
places where the populations are clonal
quarantine issues seem to be
key
you're not going to get a diverse
population there unless you unless you
allow entry of new isolates right right
but this pathogen
travels on potatoes around the world and
it travels in the air as well so I think
there will be there is migration quite
quite
sexual
so I'm in actual potatoes were not
ground commercially and potatoes until
the nineteen existence prior to that
time it was on wild species but now
there's a hell of a lot of time decided
to use one commercial potatoes
so
stint little in tune with the value some
actually doesn't because of such a
diverse population it doesn't to look at
any single
but elsewhere pretend oh USA we saw in
the Los Mochis very similar state
forensic officer
anyway so I'm curious about the
transgenic AVR our gene potatoes nice
all kind of go down did that look like a
typical disease or to DC signs of
autoimmunity or a temperature it look
really typical like life
we thought there was no fee associated
this is so cool so when is it puts up
with the future so Jonathan ours on the
state of the jonathan Jones one time you
saying that our teams have you need the
very best thing since sliced bread and I
got before that and said they're never
gonna work
so what what what's really cool is that
if you combine the effect of an arching
with the fungicide that will make the RG
a lot more durable and
Simplot company is doing that you know
they have transgenic plants with our
genes they want those plans to receive a
little fungicide because as Michael
Milgram has demonstrated if you suppress
selection then you delay the demise of a
particular RG and what way to do that is
to use a small amount of thunder second
edition so I think I think it's going to
be integrated management and I think
that's what's gonna happen
if anybody
amazing your elders in Geneva have
questioned
to do we don't have
anybody else here
bill will help please go ahead
are you know
so sexual recombination
creates new genotypes and
mutation is the source of those of that
diversity so we know that my toddler
changes the law for example in a single
lineage there can be a whole bunch of
diversity for effectors that are
recognized by
but what we do see is you do get
tremendous more genotypic diversity in a
sexual population than and a central
partners
but we have honey clonal populations in
most of the early
well well we want to recognize you and
thank you again for really else
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell edu