[Music]
so first why breed cover crops uh when
we when the cover crop breeding Network
first started doing its work back in
2015 2016 we carried out a survey of a
little over 400 farmers and asked which
traits they felt were important for each
of the crops we planned on working on so
over winter cover crops
so the most commonly mentioned trait was
nitrogen fixation which we've
investigated and found correlates quite
highly with uh biomass accumulation so
biomass is a goal in and of itself
um because in combination with early
Vigor it helps with lead competition and
all those soil soil health benefits that
come from having a a big mass of biomass
to decompose um winter hardiness is a
big goal um obviously because the
without that we don't get any of those
um those benefits of uh biomass in the
spring and we didn't ask on this survey
but we also know that breeding for a
seed yield uh can help bring seed costs
down and and make cover cropping a
reasonable economic Pro proposition for
Farmers so in all of our crops we're
breeding for biomass bigger Winter
survival we also have some crop specific
goals and we'll talk specifically about
cold tolerance and winter PE today for
the three legumes and Rye we start with
um breeding nurseries like these where
we can note and select single plants so
crimson clover hary vet and Rye are
outcrossing species so nurseries start
with 1,00 to 1500 plants we select 5 or
10% of those and all the plants left in
the nursery share pollen with one
another and we end up with one
population coming out of that
Nursery in cont
uh wintery is a selfin crop which means
it doesn't naturally share pollen with
its neighbors so to create genetic
diversity we have to cross uh the pollen
from one plant to the
stigma right here the sticky stigma or
the the female reproductive part of
another plant um so we start with
segregating populations from this two
plant cross and then select uh usually
individuals to increase and advance to
the Next
Generation so for these crops once we
select good-looking things in nurseries
the next step is Advanced line trials in
multiple locations nationwide so these
uh plots look a lot like the ones that
you have on your farm right so there's a
15 foot row of the focus crop in our
case winter peas blanked by trale and we
do this to simulate the competition that
um the legging would have in a in a mix
that legum grass mix is commonly used
and we know that survival is generally
better um with
um with the protection and uh snow
holding ability of uh of the
grass so for the for the legumes in the
cover cut breeding Network we have about
six years of data which has allowed us
to make some pretty robust conclusions
about how these lines do over space and
time this year we're adding uh National
cover C variety trials which are plot
sized so these are uh four and a half
foot wide plots by 20 feet um with five
varieties per species replicated um
across 12 sites these are the iterations
we have at preville New York our
research Farm here um and this allows um
a next size larger plot to um to compare
the best of the best across uh time and
place so to sum up there are two sides
of our breeding process we've got uh
germ plasm sourcing germ plasm
development then selection and breeding
nurseries then Advanced line trials the
15ot rows that we run in uh several
locations across the country then these
uh larger
plots concurrently we have seed yield
trials on smaller plots and then larger
plots so that we can make sure that we
weed out lines with poor seed yield or
put more focus on lines with really
promising seed yield and then finally we
get to release and
commercialization you all come in right
over here so the On Prom trials are
meant to supplement the knowledge we are
gting from our V fine trials which
because even if they're in a dozen
locations across the country that's only
a dozen and you guys are 69 locations so
that's a huge advantage to be able to
you look at a trait like winter survival
which ultimately is a yes or no there's
a lot of nuance in there but it gives us
a lot more um nuanced perspective on uh
where and how these things
survive so our original goal and still
our goal with these trials is to have
you all trial cover proper Network
experimental material we had some issues
with seed availability up until now so
we started this year with uh commercial
material um to get our methods down Etc
but starting this fall we should be able
to let you trial some um CCV material um
and I guess the good part is that if you
find something you really like out of
what you have um you can go buy it for
your
farm so um this is an analysis based on
six years of uh Advanced line trial data
so you see the number of times each
thing was trialed right here in the
observations column so we've got quite a
bit of data so you know 25 different
environments for this first um first
entry here
um we compare everything to the best
check in um in our trials which for us
is W winter for the balance of traits
that we think are uh beneficial for
cover cropping so we see quite a bit of
progress for fall Vigor and spring Vigor
and biomass so there're a lot of things
that are better that are as good or
better for those three traits not a ton
of progress in um in Winter survival
although we're we have comparable Winter
survival to the best um to W
winter let's see um this is an index
that I make to be able to balance um to
to waight the traits that are most
important um I can say more about that
if it's
helpful one last thing to say is that a
couple of these with the Stars um are
we're hoping to make available for
release
the top one um this was selected on Mark
dudas Farm who was on the call with us
today so Mark I would love to talk you
more if you're able to hang on um about
some details about that because it's
really shown excellent performance
across time and space so that's exciting
to see that there there is progress to
be
made um these are the lines the three of
the four lines you have in your trial so
w winter is our best check it's been
trialed in five seasons we got a lot of
data on it uh survivors also look really
nice um it's a little more compact of a
plant it's a little later to flower but
it's done really nicely we only have two
years of data so far so um we know it's
a it's a good-look pretty reliable
variety so we put that in there Blaze
some of you have is a semi-leafless
variety um it doesn't put on as much
biomass because the type of PE it is
we'll talk more about that um but it has
great Winter survival we kind of put
that in there for uh can can
um if if there are places that Blaze
survives that the others don't we know
that those are really key places to
Target for uh studying and selecting for
which are Sur
upful so this is where you come in um
your plots are small scale plots to hope
to I think we have accommodated a lot of
um I guess this is good for home gardens
um um for veg farmers who are growing on
beds already things like that um you
have 69 participants 43 of you have
submitted results which is honestly a
pretty good ratio about what we were
hoping for it will give us a really
great Baseline of data we obviously are
using the seed link platform where you
are collecting data on an app like this
and we have interactive results like
this which I'll share with you
today um we've taken data once in the
fall we'll take it twice in the spring
um and we have a rubric to make sure
that each of us are um
generally um having each number of the
rating scale mean approximately the same
thing these are photos from Reeds Farm
um mapping the trial out planting it and
um having the seed in the ground so
um this is what you all found for
germination and emergence um germination
I guess the trade is called germination
in seedlink we're really measuring
emergence we're measuring what we can
see coming out of the soil um we had 28
to 34 reviewers per variety and
everything was in the the three to five
range so um generally better than 75%
emergence which is which is pretty good
um Blaze did a little a little more
poorly which is interesting um all of
the lines tested at 93% germ or above uh
before we sent them out
um for fall Viger uh same general
Trends so everything was everything was
at least acceptable at a three um with
canid went Survivor moving towards
strong
growth and part of this difference
noticing owes to the the leaf type so
there is a gene there there are three
genes in P that control leaf leaf and
tendril distribution and shape
um varieties like Blaze that are semi
leafless have two recessive copies of
the Aila Gene um so they will put on
tendrils where their terminal leaves
would otherwise be for grain production
this type is really beneficial so the
uh these types uh stand up kind of hold
hands and they are much easier to
harvest they don't Lodge as much
um so most of the grain peas uh produced
now are these semile leafless types um
and like I said we put blaze in because
of its exceptional winter hardiness not
necessarily because of its biomass but
I'm also really curious if any of you
like that type better for manageability
reasons or anything else
um and the other three varieties are
normal leafy types so they are more
indeterminate and Vining and they're the
the're the pee plants you might be more
used
to um let's see I see a few things in
the chat let me just check
that oh hello Glenn good to see
you okay the next thing we asked you to
rate
um was flavor so we um coordinated with
our friends at Blue Hill at Stone Barnes
to think about um tasting uh peas since
peas are unique and that they can be
both a functional cover crop and H a
tasty uh peas shot or greens Pig greens
crop
um we we'll chat afterwards about how
many of you evaluated flavor fewer
people did
um like 15 to reviews uh per variety we
got for flavor and generally we got in
the range of I'd eat it again but I
wouldn't seek it out to happily eat
again for Survivor when you look at the
comments that some of you left um it's
really all over the board so there are a
lot of environmental factors that can
influence how um or what what flavor
compounds come out in in pee or in any
uh crop so for Survivor um across space
this fall we got everything from very
bitter overpowers any sweetness to
really good green pea flavor um to very
sweet very
pleasurable get a similar assortment of
ratings for
texture
um and yeah that's just I think one of
the one of my favorite things about
studying flavor is that everyone's right
like there's no objectively good or bad
flavor um different ones of us have
different assortments of taste buds we
also have different experiences
associated with Foods so the very same
food can uh
legitimately taste or have a um an
overall experience more positive or
negative um even if it's grown in the
same place then you throw in the
variables of where is it grown how much
moisture has it had how much uh heat as
it had all these things um and yeah the
same variety can taste a lot of
different ways but it is interesting to
see if we can find
Trends
so what are we talking about when we
talk about winter
hardiness um when in our uh Advanced
line trials we talk about um Winter
survival is just a ratio of the spring
stand to the fall stand so what percent
of what came up in the fall was there in
the spring um it's a bit of a blunt
instrument but it's it's pretty relevant
and it it lets us um it certainly lets
us differentiate among varieties
um as all of you know um let me
see oh nice thanks re for the props
too
um winter complex right so it's not just
temperature it's also snow cover wind
soil moisture and then the uh rate of
change between different temperatures
and um snow cover and no snow cover and
certainly ice um so it's it's it's more
than just cold temperature but when we
talk about temperature specifically um
acclamation is the process of um the
plant's biochemical adaptation to cold
temperatures and then de acclamation is
the reversal of that process so when
we're thinking about things that we want
to uh keep some cold hardiness when we
have more temperature fluctuations gets
really cold but then we have some warm
days and it gets really cold again uh so
that's something that we are hoping to
be able to select for just by selecting
in um the conditions of a change in
climate what makes a PE witer hearty so
there's a gene called the HR Gene that
confers high sensitivity to day length
so the P stays in its vegetative stage
where it's putting on uh leafy biomass
but not putting on flowers yet and in
the vegetative stage it is less
sensitive to Coal so by delaying
flowering until those longer days in the
spring um that gives it a a critical
mass of
uh of um cold
hardiness cold hearty peas also have a
higher photosynthetic rate and they
accumulate more sugars which you can
taste um so it's finding peas with first
of all that capacity to have that higher
photosynthetic rate to make more sugars
um and then to have those functions
upregulated when the temperatures drop
so there's variation in those things
like do we have the capacity genetically
and then does that capacity get dialed
up uh at the right rate when
temperatures get
cold those um going back to probably
high school chemistry that we did um
when we put solutes in water it will
will uh raise the boiling point and
lower the freezing point and it's
lowering that freezing point that we're
interested in here um and preventing the
cell tissues from drying out from the
um from from losing that
uh osmotic balance between different uh
parts of the cell increases more anti or
um more antioxidants are produced cell
wall uh uh
composition is changed slightly it's a
lot of detail it's pretty complex but
that's in general what's
happening we know from our advanc line
trials that there's kind of this sweet
spot where we have
um we don't have complete winter death
we don't have complete Winter survival
because neither of those scenarios tell
us much or are much good for selection
because we can't tell which varieties
are any worse or better than others so
that's where we ically placed uh on Farm
nurseries like the one at Mark's Place
um and have gotten some really nice
selections out of those
environments uh one of our
collaborators in Minnesota is doing some
growth chamber work so subjecting P
plants to um a cold acclamation then a
Sub-Zero acclamation then a freeze drop
and then a recovery and seeing how they
do so anywhere from not being damaged at
all after that recovery to being
completely dead he's
found um that okay so this is a
generation of selection here so the F3
families in the Next Generation that he
selected so in the first generation
there were
um many families with complete death or
a high proportion of complete death and
um very few families with no damage and
then in just a generation he's got a lot
more families that have no damage and
fewer that have complete damage and you
can see in these scores uh keeping in
mind that lower is better um that he's
make he's moving the needle on uh freeze
tolerance with this growth chamber uh
procedure we're doing some similar work
here at Cornell one of our grad students
has a growth chamber or freeze chamber
protocol of her own um seeking to um
both identify or refine previously
identified genomic Losi or qtl um that
have to do with uh cold tolerance in p
uh and so those genetic Losi would drive
those biochemical mechanisms that I
mentioned so future
opportunities um things that are
happening we're going to do un firm
trials with some CCB Network varieties
starting this fall so would love to have
um as many of you as are able um
participate in that um and then eten who
maybe still on the phone is running some
interesting um on-farm evaluations of
existing cover crops that you're going
to plant anyway and or a variety trial
of uh commercial varieties that will
correspond with our um National
covercraft variety trial so watch this
space meaning the ceiling feed and the
emails that I send to you for more
details on those things um I also would
really love to do some onir breeding
with some new material some crosses that
I've made um variable populations
ascending from those crosses and have
those selected in a lot of your
locations so that's still pending
funding but fingers
crossed um and lastly for those of you
who are even
remotely of vicinity we're going to have
a cover crop and soil health field day
on April 24th which is a Thursday in the
afternoon you can see our breeding
material in the field uh the New York
soil Health Group will have their
trailer there to do some demonstrations
about cover crop uh uh water
infiltration
and all manner of things uh we'll have
various demos we'd really love to have
you join us this is a production of
Cornell University