This is a production of Cornell
University.
Welcome everybody to our sixth year, huh
Carl, of of Howling at the Moon uh as we
started out early on uh in the pandemic
days. And you know, we do it for a very
short period of time and now it's
starting to come together in clippings
podcasts. So, if those of you I haven't
really I'll draw attention to this some
other time, but uh for those of you that
uh are interested in listening to some
of the podcasts that we've taken from
the show over the years, we've got an
ACE undergrad communication specialist,
Jake Sakowski, who's turning our
previous shows into little snippets or
clippings uh of really informative
stuff. So, hopefully you'll uh pay
attention to that. And I think Carl
promoted it through the email just a
couple of weeks ago. Okay, without any
further
ado, I think opening day should be a
national holiday. Carl, what do you
think? And of course, the Yanks and even
the Red Sox are tied for first place.
Hopefully, it's the last time uh that
happens. I've got to put up with with
Red Sox fans, but you know, the the
grass is green, the ball's flying
around. Uh and now till October, it's
every day. I just love it. Carl hates
this. Okay, so let me get my uh let me
get my cursor. And in in light of that,
Greg Chvervis and the guys at Soerties
already at it getting those infields
ready. Big differences between upstate
and downstate. And we'll talk about the
weather uh as we get going. Um but for
sure, you know, working these infields,
this is why a lot of fields have become
synthetic because you got to have people
who know what they're doing getting the
clay ready this time of year. And this
is why Greg's facility hosts so many
games, so many op so many tournaments is
is the envy of communities far and wide
and something you just don't see as much
anymore with this deep commitment to
baseball uh in particular. And of
course, it's a multi-use facility. But
big shout out to Greg and the guys in so
at canteen memorial that have been good
supporters of the show over the years.
And Carl, without any further ado, I
know you're going to take a different
tack today, but as I said earlier, you
were con you were con you were a
convivial uh pleasant guy hanging out
with Dave Hicks, winning your uh mid-
amateur championship a number of years
ago, and I know you've got something to
say about people in general today. Yeah,
we're going to talk about golfers. Um,
you know, I I we're going to talk so
much about uh sort of evidence-based
turf management, best management
practices, what the science tells us.
We're going to spend all these these
next 10 weeks talking about that. And I
sort of put this uh you know, it's a
little bit facicious, but does it even
matter that we can produce good grass or
bad grass sometimes? Uh, you know, this
is an example for those watching. If we
fertilize this, in this case, it's
perennial ryrass in Wisconsin. If we
fertilize it a little bit, we get less
weeds. Great. We know how to do things
really efficiently. Maybe you don't have
to use herbicides as much, but uh the
product or the grass sometimes does not
equal what the person using the grass
feels as their experience, right? And
and this is most known in in golf
courses. A person is going to play a
golf course. It's not just how good the
golf course is, it's the customer
experience. And we looked at this a long
time ago with our New York State Park
golf courses. Uh this was not an
efficient way to do this research. I
went through thousands of online
reviews, Google reviews, Facebook, Yelp,
Golf Advisor, and I would manually input
how many stars the review gave it. And
if there were comments, I would keep
those comments, and then I would sort of
categorize them, especially poor
reviews. Okay. What were they saying
about the golf course that they didn't
like? And we could basically bucket them
into four categories. I wor conditions.
Yeah. No, you're good. And a pace of
play, right? Golfers want to play really
fast. If it's really slow, they don't
like that. amenities, things like is
there water to drink on the golf course,
are there bathrooms, and then customer
service, and we did not expect what we
found, uh, which was that over 50% of
the reviews, 51% uh, of poor reviews
mentioned bad customer service as the
reason they had a poor time. And I think
this review just uh, encapsulates it so
well at one of the State Park courses.
When you check in, it's got a DMV feel
with attitudes to match. That's not
great. You'll then go to a starter who's
as friendly as shingles. Okay. Where
we're 0 for two. Uh after the TSA like
procedure to begin your round, you'll
have a rectal exam. Once you're on the
course, it's great. You'll soon forget
about it all. And this was a poor review
that says, "Hey, the grass was really
good. The product was really good. And I
gave it two out of five stars because I
spent five hours there, but my five
minutes interacting with people somehow
screwed that up." And and that's really
frustrating. I think for the
superintendent listening probably is is
a relatable experience. And and this
isn't just state parks. Th this is
pretty much true. Like whenever we say
this to people or I make this comment,
Carl, in a meeting, everybody's head
starts nodding and they say, here's what
they said to us last week. People in the
front of the house don't start out like
this. Golfers do this to them. This is
what they said. Remember? All right. But
it's not just golfers. It It turns out
this is not just golf. And and I'm going
to highlight Maggie Ryder's blog post
here. Maggie's doing some really cool
blog posts, not just lawn and landscape,
but also some sports turf stuff. I'm
sure she'll do golf stuff. She did a uh
she she built a code that did this all
for her. So she scraped all these
reviews from a Austin, Texas landscaping
company, one company. She did sentiment
analysis. So the code looks through all
the words and the comments and sort of
groups them into these categories. In
the positive reviews for this company,
uh 66% of the time, the most often cited
topic for for a good review was
professionalism. The tech the
technicians were polite, professional,
and friendly. That was the number one uh
often cited thing in a review. When you
go to the negative reviews, uh that's
when you start to see the the poor
results showed up. So 64% said, "The
reason I'm giving it a poor review is
because I didn't get results." But if
you look at all the other things on this
list, Frank, 39% of the time missing
appointments, that was why they didn't
have a good experience. Billing 23% of
the time sales price. So this is also
saying like, hey, sometimes good reviews
can be driven by customer service. And
that's the interesting thing here is you
might not pro provide the best product,
but if you're nice, thank you, you're
welcome, hey, anything you need, uh,
that can make your customers really
happy and probably get return business.
Uh, and I think it comes back to this,
Frank. I know you've said in the past,
you're not uh you'd rather not be around
people. You'd rather just look at the
grass. We don't need golfers. Can I just
grow the grass? It comes back to it's a
people business. And sometimes how we
treat people is just as important, if
not more important than the product we
produce, the grass we produce. And I'd
say this, Carl, we often say this on the
golf course. It's like, you know, a lot
of people know how to grow grass. Yep.
Right. But, you know, staying at a golf
course, meeting a golf course
superintendent for 30 years is more
about growing grass. There's an
assumption that, you know, how to grow
grass. There's no magic to growing
grass. This is what's been interesting.
The changing climate, the increasing
pressures on the turf, the lack of
investment in infrastructure up until
recently, I think, uh, made it harder
just to permit that bare minimum of
having decent grass. And I think your
your your data shows that. Listen, you
got weeds all over. They're going to be
pissed about that. Yeah, you got dead
greens. They're going to be pissed about
that. But if you meet this minimum sort
of bar, right, and you've talked about
that, what's an average lawn got to look
like and what do we do? Because we get
paid to do it, especially in the lawn
care business where you're only really
getting paid when you apply something or
mow something and and and you're not
really paid for sort of producing that
landscape as a whole. But I'm going to
continue in the vein, Carl of Grass
being a people business, but deflect it
a little bit. These are these old guys,
Piper and Oakley. They wrote this book,
Turfer Golf Courses in the 20s. And the
first line on the first page of the
book, ever, first book ever written
about golf courses, this good grass is
conditioned by two great factors,
climate and soil. The latter can be
modified. The former must be accepted.
So, let's start with what we've had to
accept. We had a proper winter, as my
British friends would say. a proper
winter with good cold temperatures, uh,
adequate but still not excessive
snowfall. I mean, even snowfall along
the lakes, uh, you know, they got dumped
on. I I think it snowed every day on the
Tug Hill Plateau. Those poor people got
like 12, 13 feet of snow and there's
barely a hill to ski down it. It's just
flat farmland on the plateau that just
gets buried in snow. And then you had
the cold temperatures and then uh
freezing and then thawing and raining
and freezing again and so and then you
see ground heaving everywhere. So I
would just say we had last year uh we
had a proper summer and a proper winter.
Now coming out of the proper winter we
got that annual blueg grass in some
places. Not everybody but some places
are definitely showing. Now, this is
good if you know if you're trying to
kill it like we're trying to do it on
our sports field and you made a couple
applications of prorass last year uh on
your ryrass uh even with a little bit of
bluegrass in there. We we smoked uh
Chris was able to smoke the annual
bluegrass on our on our game field out
there and you know you go out it's like
wow is that snow mold? No, it's dead
annual bluegrass. Okay, back to the
weather. You can see in this monthly
departures from normal in Ithaca, right?
Uh it was warmer than normal. Look at
January, February, March, April. You're
looking at, you know, two to almost
eight degrees above normal month after
month, last winter, right? Last winter,
2024. Then you see as we got through the
summer, June and July was warmer than
normal, a little bit cooler in August,
warmer in the fall. This is the story,
right? Warm fall. And then as you can
see at the end of the top chart and the
beginning of the bottom chart where
you're cooler than normal now we've been
on the cold side. A little bit of a
roller coaster but certainly warm in the
fall. And the other thing about the fall
that persisted was the incredibly dry
weather right annual departure from
normal. You're looking at two inches
below normal October, November and
December. This was the story and it has
persisted. We're in the, you know, some
people in the 50 to 75% of normal, more
in the 75 to 100. So, we're starting out
the season on the dry side. Last fall,
it was so dry, sparks were setting off
landscapes. Prospect Park had a a fire
that's going to cost a quarter million
dollars or more to replace just the
natural landscape from uh, you know,
homeless people in an area barbecuing.
spark goes into the woods, boom, 10
acres burned up. So, it's a a pretty big
deal. Now, from as far as what got
smoked from last year, I'd say towards
the end of the year, the crab grass came
on and really took over. You know, we
had a dry season. Lawns really started
to suffer. Many of them are not going to
recover well. But if you see crab grass
skeletons out there, my opinion right
now, just go in there, scuff it up, and
throw seed. Don't go for the
pre-emergent yet. get some grass growing
there. Right now, as we've learned in a
recent paper, and we're going to talk
about this as we get going, grass alone
there doesn't stop the crab grass from
coming, but it does slow the
emergence. Okay, just a note about if
you're heading out to spray your
pre-emergent or you want to go out and
do anything, we've got the runoff risk
tool. And uh again, for the Ithaca area,
we're low, but we're starting to build
up as the rains are going to start
coming through next week. And you can
see by uh Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday
of next week, when when are we getting
to the 31st? Monday, Tuesday of next
week, you're going to start to have
great runoff uh potentials in certain
areas where the rains are coming
through. So, check the runoff models.
It's a very important time of the year,
and I hate to say, I see a lot of
farmers running around spreading manure
at this time of year, and it's just not
a good thing.
Okay, late grub damage still obvious
this spring. In fact, Kyle Wickings has
got my head spinning a little bit that
if they're feeding late, maybe it's
cranefly. But this is some damage I saw
in October in Central Park uh with some
grubs there and trying to look at the
anal slit and seeing what it is. Not
everybody's favorite job, but we were
able to see that it was uh I think it
was oriental beetle uh at this location.
But you know, the grubs themselves, the
turf's looking fine. The grubs are
everywhere. The only problem with this
area is the vertebrate damage, and that
remains the problem. It isn't
necessarily the grub pressure as much as
it's that. All right, let's talk about
getting the season going here. Um, soils
are barely in the 50s. They're still
frozen. Walt Nelson's probably got he's
can't get out his front door. There's
still snow up north. We had a we had
just a dusting yesterday uh of snow when
we were having the conversation. So
barely creeping into the 50s all the way
down into Delm Marva. So we're a we're a
slow start to the year uh for sure here
in March, right? And and this past week
was cooler along the coast. Uh warmer by
the lakes, a little warmer inland, a
little cooler by the coast. Uh and of
course, Carl, I don't have to remind
everybody, but the growth model is
there. And and you know, the grass isn't
growing very much. We're just, you know,
it's Chris has got people playing on the
soccer fields. We got golfers playing on
the golf course, but it's important to
keep in mind the grass isn't growing.
And I got a question for you at the end,
pal, about how to reconcile this. Okay,
so what about moisture? Well, in the
last week, uh, we got a good dump along
the coast. Uh, on the left here, you can
see we got a pretty good dump along the
coast, but pretty dry inland, right? The
rest of us have been a bit on the dry
side, but definitely wet along the coast
last week. And it looks like uh it's
going to be a little bit of the
opposite. It's going to get dry along
the coast. Uh we're going to start to
see some uh drying out. Uh but to the
north, we're going to start to see some
rainfall. We are into seed head
suppression right now. Of course, if
you're really serious in the golf
business about suppressing seed heads,
you're making that proxy application
with your snow mold application in the
fall. And so that's become pretty much
the standard since Sean Ascu started
doing that work a number of years ago.
and that followup application is due uh
in a lot of places uh which seems hard
to believe. Uh but uh certainly the
models have been pretty consistent about
this, but you want to keep in mind
you're spraying a growth regulator at a
time where you want the grass to get
going. So you've got to reconcile that
sort of dissonance in your head that oh
well I want it to grow but I'm spraying
a growth regulator. Okay, Carl, I got a
question for you. I'm gonna set you up
here. We got about 15 minutes to have
this chat because I know you're a golfer
and I see this bubble up every once in a
while and I want to see uh what you
think about this. Give me I'm going to
make a pitch and then I want to hear
what you have to say. Yeah, it's green
and open early. This is a golf course
superintendent in Morristown, New
Jersey. Uh posted uh on on uh
Turfet uses covers, gets the greens
going. Here's my question. Green and
open early, good deal, bad deal. All
right, here's the impact covers have,
right? You can see here, you know, when
you put covers on, you warm that system,
right? This is what we're talking about.
You get that warmth going, you get soils
activated. Once you heat the soil mass,
right, it's it's on. Plants are growing.
Up until then, you're staring at it. You
can see on the left, the arification
holes are filled in. On the right, you
can still see them very clearly,
especially if you're doing late
arification. I'll just make a note that
heavy blankets of sand worked very well
this year. I saw it on our golf course
and a number of other golf courses this
year. Heavy blankets of sand worked
really well for getting things going. Uh
and then capitalizing on maybe using
some coarser particles, maybe even airy
a little bit, getting them into the
profile. All right, Carl plays up. It's
a good time to be in golf. We're record
round numbers as we look at annual
rounds. You know, we've gone talk about
a roller coaster. We're having a ball
right now. All right. It's the sun is
shining and everybody's happy.
Everybody's spending money on golf
courses. We see a lot of infrastructure
projects. I sit in a room of
superintendents that I'm speaking to. I
say, "How many people got projects,
bunker irrigation?" 80% of their hands
are up. So, golfers, you know, people
are playing, somebody's got money,
they're spending it back in deferred
maintenance. This is a very good thing.
And a lot of this has to do with remote
work, Carl. This is what the remote
worker looks like nowadays, right? I
talked about this with our state park
guys. You know, the National Golf
Foundation has found a 25% increase in
weekday play since the pandemic. We knew
this. Now we got data. There was a
workday study that was done recently
that I stumbled onto work from home
study about the it was a really long
presentation maybe 80 90 slides. In the
middle of it is this golf effect. the
fact that you look at cell phone data in
an in a community, right, where there's
golf courses, right? Cell phone data
tracking where people are, right? In
2019, on Mondays, uh 12,000 people were
heading or at golf courses. In
2022, 24,000 people. Look at the
increase in play on Monday through
Thursday through Friday and you don't
see it as much on Saturday. They're
still playing on Saturday. They're still
at the go, but now they're at the golf
course all week. Uh not just on uh
Saturday and Sunday. In fact, the data
also shows they're taking the early tea
times. So now you used to have a little
bit more time in the morning except for
the deuce sweepers. You're never going
to get ahead of those guys, right? So
you let them go and then the rest of the
people are coming. Now you got a whole
pile of people coming early. They want
to fit it in before they start working
remotely. They're not working on Mondays
in the office and they're not working on
Fridays in the office anymore, Carl.
They're there. They're only there
Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday. So now
Monday maintenance days might have to be
Tuesday maintenance days. And how does
that make it look come Friday, Saturday,
Sunday for your weekends? You don't have
four days to recover from a vertic cut
in sand. You got three days to recover.
All right, Carl. Here's the question,
brother. Here's what I hear. We should
open and play whenever we can to
maximize. If you got a private club,
Craig Courier never closes Glenn Oaks.
The flags are always in. If if if the
grass if you can see the grass, you're
playing out there. Uh access. And if
you're in the business of golf like our
Elm Tree brother, you're you want rounds
and revenue. Okay? So get out there. And
then there's these other people that
say, "Oh, no. We got to stay closed as
long as we can to preserve the golf
course for the season. Opening now will
hurt us later in the season." You could
have this same argument for Ben Palmer
could have the same argument in on play.
Oh, why can't I use this field? Oh, oh,
you know, you're gonna do damage. Okay,
Carl, where are you? What do you think?
I did it to you, didn't I? I did. Yeah,
you've you've put both sides there and
and I am split, too. As a golfer, one of
my favorite things to do is in March and
I keep track of every year my first
round. It's always second, third week in
March, I go up to Elmry and it's just
one of the best experiences of the year
is I get out for the first time. I get
to see the ball fly in
2025. Uh it's sort of like, you know, it
creates this inertia momentum for the
rest of the year. Oh man, I want to
golf. Like, that was so cool. It's 50°
out. It was sunny. I'm loving this. Uh,
and from an operator perspective, it's
it's the most money you can make with no
cost. You don't have to mow. I don't I I
put I can put temporary TE's out there.
That's a really good option, I think.
Don't don't beat up your tea services.
If you got artificial mats for part 3es,
I think that's a really good idea. Um,
but you're making basically free money.
You just need one person in the pro
shop, take the cash, and go out and
play. I don't have to do anything else.
People will come and play. There will be
a 100 rounds in central New York. Okay.
On March 15th. Okay. All right. All
right. Now, and then if I'm a
superintendent, I I'm saying exactly
what you put in that slide there, Frank.
There is no growth happening right now.
And when I have traffic plus no growth,
I'm going to have less turf cover as we
get close to the season that actually
actually matters, you know, in April and
and throughout the growing season. And I
do worry about, okay, does do we get
some weed encroachment there? If we're
if we're trying to keep poa out and
we've got ball marks early in the season
on greens that aren't growing, man, are
we going to get some poa infestations
there. Um, I think generally I I
probably worry most about tea surfaces
where there's divoting and you are
definitely not growing that grass back
for another month probably. Um, that's
where I'd say, hey, like if you're going
to open and you're going to try and make
some money, like mats or just put the
te's off in the rough. I a lot of us
golfers do not care, especially public
golf. I'm paying 20 bucks to play 18
holes in March. You can put me off in
the rough. I'll I can tee it up in the
rough. I don't care. I'll take divots in
the rough. I'm just happy to be outside.
Like, try and keep them off the high
value tea surfaces and preserve that.
That's what I'd say if if I'm a or at
least I'm a superintendent, I'm trying
to argue for uh hey, let make less work
for me later on in the season. That's
that's maybe one option I' I'd go with.
The other thing I'd say, Frank, is when
we look at um we get data from Pollucid
uh that looks at capacity, weather
adjusted capacity for golf. How many
rounds can you play in March, April,
May, June, July based on the weather. Is
it sunny out? Is it warm out? Is it not
raining? Right? uh where we see the most
variation especially in upstate New York
is March, April, November, December. And
you can make you can get huge increases
in your potential play by 2,000 rounds
sometimes in March and April if you get
a nice March in April. And that means
you can really get ahead on your revenue
if you're an operator. Uh and if we look
10 20 years in in the future with
climate change, we're going to extend
those shoulders of the season. man, it's
going to be hard to not open, especially
public golf in those times because
that's where you can make a lot of your
money and you can be you can get into
the green as opposed to the red. Right.
Okay. So, let me throw a wrench in this
and I maybe you listen to the podcast I
did with Stuart and Jim where where
Stuart says that golfers are more like
bears than
squirrels, right? They hibernate in the
winter and come out in the spring and
want to play golf like crazy. and they
had beautiful weather in the fall and
probably nobody was playing uh the way
we normally expect them to. Why why
don't you play golf in the fall, Carl?
You know, that's that's a great analogy.
It's you're sort of tire yourself out in
the fall. And I think there's also this
effect of uh Masters starts in April.
For a lot of people, that's like the
first time they'll watch golf on TV. You
really get the itch to play. Then once
you're in September, October, November,
you've you've played if you're a
competitive golfer, you've played all
your tournaments, you've been with your
buddies, you probably had enough of them
after 20 or 30 rounds to be honest at
the end of the year. That's right. I'm
going to hang up the clubs, take some
time off. So So that's a good point,
too, by by Stuart is maybe the the
springtime is where you can really make
hay and get that momentum for Okay. So
then let's talk about this in other
arenas, right? the long thing. Let's
leave it to the side because that's
let's just assume you're looking at
that. But sports fields are a different
animal and right so let's think that
same argument that happens here and then
all of a sudden you see the clear
justification in our climate for
synthetic turf. So, um, when we get
ourselves into these pickles, how do you
reconcile, uh, these issues where now
we're seeing a growing concern, uh, and
this is something we're going to talk
about adnauseium this year because it is
front of mind for all of us and it is,
you know, presenting us big challenges
with the, you know, I think some people
would say epidemic of synthetic turf
being uh, laid down much like a land
going to solar farms. It feels like a
waste. Um, it feels like, well, in the
case of synthetic turf, maybe polluting,
but at the same time, Carl, we want the
kids out and about and playing on safe
surfaces. How do you reconcile sports
fields in your mind with with the pickle
we're in now? Because again, just like
with golf, there's you could argue both
sides of these things uh effectively.
And and and and that's of course the
world we live in nowadays. Where do you
fall on how you feel about, you know,
natural grass, synthetic at this time of
year? I I think it's there's there's a
big difference spring versus fall sport.
And we saw this, we have our data for
like a 10-year average of Itha, New
York, the growth potential. How much do
we expect the grass to grow based on an
average temper of 67 67 is about where
we want to be in the spring. You don't
get to 50% growth potential until middle
of May on average, which is the end of
our division one spring season. So,
we're playing from February through May
when we're getting basically no growth.
That's correct. And I worry about those
sports on natural grass because they're
going to we're getting no growth. We're
going to be using the fields at least
five times a year. We can expect that
field quality to decline and the
fluctuations in soil moisture,
compaction. I worry a lot more about the
safety of that field in the spring
versus the fall. Like we have uh our
soccer teams both play on natural grass
both on campus and their practice
facilities. growth potential stays high
now in the fall basically almost until
December. I mean, we can host we've
hosted NCAA Division games when it it
snows in December, but up until then,
the grass is still growing. Uh, so we
can support the traffic and we have data
on the the firmness readings, traction,
how how long the the ball rolls and how
much it bounces. And it maintains these
these standards up until the end of the
season because we have enough of of uh
of warmth and growth. So, so we're
talking to, you know, you and I are in
this project now where we're working
with school districts on trying to
figure out how to do synthetic and
natural turf, uh, you know, you know,
governance and stewardship and making
decisions and how they go about it. We
met with Tom Ferrara, the facility,
director of facilities for the city of
Syracuse school district and absolutely
incredible operation and he's quite a
professional that guy, but you know,
he's in a city. I said to him, listen, I
think you need three fields for every
one. You need three natural grass
fields, six, seven acres of grass for
every synthetic field you have. Just off
the top of my head, where you know
you're going to trash them and you're
going to need recovery. I'd almost say,
you know, if you have three teams and
one field, uh, you probably need five,
you know, one synthetic field, you
probably need five fields. Three fields,
uh, five fields in the spring, three
fields in the summer with two rest. So,
the end of the day, you're gonna need
more land. and he was like, "Yeah, I
don't have any more land and I'm
spending millions on storm water
associated with the synthetic turf." So,
for those of you in the sports turf
business, this used to be something that
was relatively straightforward, I would
say. I mean, and natural grass was
losing. I think synthetic turf is now
coming under question, but you start to
see the constraints that made synthetic
turf the best option, right? urban
areas, Frank, and we've seen it in New
York City. They want to get rid of
synthetic turf in the city and replace
it with natural grass. We love that. But
when you have millions of people and
probably hundreds of thousands of people
who want to play sports and a confined
area, that's just not going to probably
happen with and you know, and since we
know it's baseball and we're going to be
the Yanks are off today. I don't know
how the hell they take a Friday off and
then they're playing Saturday. But
nevertheless, I got to go one day
without baseball. was very happy to see
Juan Sodto strike out and lose the game
last night for the Mets. So, I was very
happy about that. But in the baseball
world, Carl, you know, it's the same
thing. We showed Greg knows what he's
doing, taking care of that dirt. But how
many school districts have anybody that
has the never mind even if they have the
expertise have the time to tend to it?
And that's another reason where you see
synthetic turf having its benefits and
options in those. Matter of fact, I
think I've said it on this program. If
you gave me one synthetic field I could
have, I'd put a baseball field in
because most of these guys don't have
the ability like Greg like Greg does or
the expertise capacity to to do the
infield uh the way it can be and man
that's a danger, right? There's this
safety thing from a broader
environmental perspective and then
there's the safety from a projectile
being hit at you at the exit vlog.
Somebody said yesterday, it's it's not
how fast, it's how many.
It's not how fast it goes, it's how many
go. It's so stupid. Some of this
analytic stuff is over over the top. We
got any questions before we wrap it up?
I I just want to point out uh Greg is on
with us today and he said he limits play
in the spring. So So no cleats, sneakers
only. We've
heard said the same thing again. And
that's a great example of someone who
knows what they're doing. Hey, if you
want to get out here, we have to limit
the the damage we're doing to the turf.
So, he says he does that. Yeah. And he
still closed, too. Or you sacrifice. You
just say, "Here, go use this. You can
use it until it's not safe and then you
got to go use that one." All right,
Carl. We're at the We're at the end,
brother. 30 minutes gone by. First goes,
the first episode always uh goes
quickly. Next week, we'll have Art
Degayano on the the real weather guy.
Good climate. The real weather guy,
right? Good climate. Learned. Yeah. And
we'll talk a little bit about sort of
the fall and and some of the trends
we're seeing with non, you know, how the
snow fell and growing degree days and
also soil temperature and model stuff,
right? We Carl's actively you're
building a lot of models, brother. And
Art is certainly Art and Ben are
certainly the brains for for you and me.
More me than you. You got the brains.
But nevertheless, we'll see everybody
next week. This has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu. edu.