This is a production of Cornell
University. Uh good afternoon everyone.
Uh it's my pleasure to be able to speak
with you and tell you uh the work I uh
the work that I have been doing. Um my
work mainly focus on plant virus uh
movement and the A15 mission.
uh you know as as you know the plant
virus is very small with a very small
genome and just encoding uh less than 10
protein. However, the virus life cycle
requires very complex activities and how
and and the virus has involved
uh a lot of complex mechanism to ensure
that uh all the activities can be uh can
be performed can be performed
performed. Um so today uh I I'm I'm
going to tell you about three gene from
potato livers
uh that red unit that
red a multi multi activity
uh that very that are very crucial for
the virus survival in plant
host. Uh the potato leaf for virus
uh is the polyro virus genius in the
family of gluty
we did. The natural host of the virus is
potato and it can also infect several
other plants such as
parade tobacco. The typical symptom
after infection of this virus is the
growing tubet necrosis and also the
chlorosis on the infected
li this virus is flown
preferred and transmitted by a in a
persistent in a persistent manner. Here
I'm showing you a picture that we
construct a virus induced gene silent
vector using the four virus. And when we
silence the TDS we can see a lot of
branch area that area that that
area
represent the the localization of the
virus. The virus is really bloom
linking. Here is the genome structure of
leaf for virus. It looks very simple and
it and it is a monopati linear signal
string RNA virus. Also the whole genome
can transcribe two subg genomic RNA
named subg genomic one
subgenomic I2.
This small this simple genome use many
translational strategy to incur their
protein it protein for example the re
mechanism ring shift liquid gaining
internal random
palite. So today my my talk will mainly
focus on the read through mechanism and
the protein included from the subg
genomic
one. Here's the subdenomic one in coded
protein.
There are several open reading frame
along the subdenomic one for the O3
being called a code protein. It's the
major capate protein and the whole
wiring is composed
with 188 code protein and this protein
has been recorded to take part in viral
transmission and movement. For the OF4
we call a movement protein. uh this
proteinate is related to virus movement,
cellto cell movement and datamic
movement in the plant
host. For the OS five there is RTD
domain named as through domain this
domain contain two part one is a very
conserved and terminus domain another is
a
very vulnerable domain with the order
sequence. This domain has been
recorded to take part in virus
transmission also take part in the virus
movement for the read through protein
RTP is the red through of the sticky
stop protein and generating a very large
protein about 75 kilo this protein uh
has been very extensively studied our
formal work on that protein fction in
chain in flow
mutation this protein is on the surface
of the structure you can see this is the
RTD
domain so here's the outline of my talk
in the part one I will introduce the
translational read through process we
discovered a downstream translation in
hunger the structure of the
translational enhancer is critical for
translation of RTP
and the uh uh the translation in hunger
and the state rich element
uh the the interaction between these two
domain is very important for do protein
translation in the part two I will
introduce the read through protein
inspection so here the proposed working
models for our stop coding when
translation happened a stop coding
the release vector will come and will
arrive in the stock coding then the D
the R will get released. So the so the
translation will get termination.
However, when forming a very complex
vector structure near the stop coding
will inhibit the release factor coming
and then the
rest the rest of stop coding will
continue and the uh that mean
translation
and so of our previous work 20 years ago
uh using a related belly yellow draft
wire. He found that there are two
domains named 15 rich region adjusting
to CP coding and translational enhancer
located within the uh RTD domain it are
very important for translation when they
deleted the two domain the RTP protein
couldn't be detected however the nature
however there there no further
information about the mechanism and how
how the
rest are uh regulated. Uh it's little
unknown until now. So in our research we
will focus on study the
mechanism between these two
regions. Firstly uh to discover whether
there is a translational enhancer in our
liver virus but serious
uh mutation was
contracted. We found that when we and
the the RTP expression was detected by
western plot by western blood using the
in using the aggro infiltrated bend
lift. When we delete the nucleotide from
the
4854 the RTP translation was severely
uh impaired. However, when we deleted
the nuclear from
4933 or from the
507, the translation was withdrawal
protein is later
affected. Also
by autobinding also by
infin deletion. We found that the
nuclear part between the
4854 to
4933 is the minimal uh
unifor translation and we these regions
are considered as the translation
translational enhancer of the
former. So to to act uh the the
translational enhancer fraction is is
determined by the
nucleite in the translational enhancer
or the amino acid encoded from this
region. So a stop coding was introduced
before the translational enhancer and
making the nuclear after this will not
be translated. RTP what was detected. We
found a trumpeted RTP indicating that
the um that the nucleide in this region
it is define the risk translation not
the amino acid translated by the
translational enhancer domain. also a
dart RTP mutant which all the nuclear
part after the CP stop coding was
deleted as this mutant was used as a
network to control as shown in this
finger we couldn't find any RTP that
with
translation so next the nuclear
alignment of homologous translation in
her sequence among several poly virus
was carried out we found that the
nucleotide similarity is very low and
it's less than
14%. If we looked the sec the secondary
structure of this region we found that
the secondary structure is very similar
and there are several double
loops in this region.
So previous work on other system found
that the double loop structure is very
important for read through or stop
coding. So to study the the stop the
step loop structure section in our res
translation we focus on starting three
step loops loop one doop two and loop
three and we started this loops
separately for loop one
um we introduce two mutant which the
will be opened up and the IDP
translation was detected by web. We
found that there the translation was uh
severely
impaired. However, when we made a
complement of the the signal here and
made this the made the term close and we
found that the RTP translation will get
reversed
translation. Also we introduced another
mutant which the loop of the W1 was
closed and the RTP translation was was
also impaired. So this dot here suggests
that the WOT str one is necessary for
RTP simulation.
We also studied the loop 2 and loop
three on the fraction of translation and
there we found
that there's no effect on it translation
after disrupting this loop 2 and 3.
Next we started on the charact
characters required for the useful
translation required for the proof one
in in useful translation. Firstly we
focus on the uh plus plastic city uh
plus city and we change the blue side by
one simpl or two inletard and the rule
translation can be detected by wing
block indicating the size of the loop
doesn't matter for the res
translation also we next we studied the
position and the sequence between the
stop coding and read through read
through translational enhancer.
Firstly, we deleted the the nuclear
between the stop coding and the
translational enhancer and
generating a 500 nuclear decre decreased
RTD mutant. We could find the RTP
translation can can be detected also
when we replaced the nucleotide between
these two region with the foreign HA
attack sequence. Although the RTP can be
detected indicating the position and
statement between these two regions is
not so strictly required for the restore
translation.
So I have told you that a formwork found
that the stage element and the
translational enhancer is very important
for related virus with translation and
we found that the it's there is a very
similar secondary structure between the
uh the two related
virus to to check whether the whether
the stage region of hourly for hours
also uh required for translation and to
see whether or not the there is a
communication between the C element and
translational enhancer and whether this
interaction is virus
specific a several chimeic mutant was
constructed as shown in this finger this
is what type for levers they could
detect the RDP
translation. However, when we deleted
the C element of the D4 virus, no RTP
could be
detected. When we replaced the virus C
reading with the related C
way element, there is also no RTP can be
detected. Also when we use this the
virus translational enhancer with the
related CD way translational enhancer
nop can can be
found. However, when we replaced both
both uh striing and the translational
enhancer with the state related
sequence, we can find RDP can be
translated indicating that communication
between translational enhancer with the
stage domain is virus specific and
indispensable for RTP
translation to Okay, next we asked what
the effect of RTP mutant on infection of
the plant. So the leaf virus titer was
measured in septemically infected
leaves and we we can find all the mutant
can get infection as early as 3 weeks.
However with with RTP translation all
the
mutant all the viral titer increase by
time. However for the without RTP
expression the vir decreased from three
weeks put in
population and for for example the dp
mutant you can see the titers always
decreased to a very low level. However,
we found there we found there are
typewriter switch using the loop one
mutant the tighter of virus switch to
increase in six or seven week put
ination with this loop one mutant. So to
see what happened on this mutant whether
or not this sequence inter this sequence
are still kept are still kept integrated
as constructed. So RTPCR was carried out
to check the sequence uh integrated of
this mutant.
Firstly, we detect the the the mutant
sequent from three weeks post
inoculation
uh leave from three weeks post inulation
uh leave and we found that all the
mutant still keep integrity and
constructed. Here is the wild type
factory structure about the
translational enhancer and you can see
all the mutants factory structure of the
loop loop one was still being
impaired. However, when we detect the
sequence
from from 8 weeks put inulation infected
plant, we found we found they all have
additional mutation and we found that a
com compensatory mutation that would
restore a studio one structure was
found.
Although the the loop structure is a
little different with the white pipe as
sher the
uh but the this door J resto develop one
structure. So to to see whether this
difference will restore the res
translation. So we we made this mutation
into the lipo virus infection clone and
infiltrated into benzim benzima le and
did then detect the RTP
translation. We found that all the
mutant can restart RTP
translation indicating that the develop
structure
uh is very important for it through
translation and also uh the the
structure is in a very strong selective
pressure to maintain the RTP
translation. Here is the conclusion of
part one. A translational enhancer
located 640 nucleot mode CP stop coding
is required for use through translation.
Develop one of the translational
enhancer is required for efficient RTP
translation. But there is plat
plasticity to it structure communication
between the translational enhancer and
sting which element is required and
fic but the length and makeup of the
sequence between them is not important
for useful translation.
There is a strong selection for mut
mutation that restore a develop one
structure that allow RTP
translation. Now that we found that RTP
can be recovered translated so it may it
it might it might have very important
function in the virus in the virus
survival. So in the part two I will
introduce our studies on the red protein
factions and we found there is the
interaction between the different uh
virus MP with the resto protein and
finally a model was rigged to explain
the RTP MP interaction.
So all the floam limited
virus after they get inoculation into
the floam tissues by a or some other
insect they have to overcome two
barriers to make sure they can establish
the successful infection
uh the the successful infection of the
entire plant. Firstly they have to get
replication in the
inuculation field. Second, they have to
move out from the the replication
site both in the cell to cell level and
also they have to
move in a in a long distance level and
they have to move to the flow and get
sentic infection and then excite from
the flow and start new infection to so
to say whether the domain has effect on
virus replication. A serious RTD domain
was
constructed which this mutant RTD
protein was serious impaired as shown in
the in the in the Indian figure. We
found that the RTB do have no effect on
fire replication both in three days post
inoculation and five post inoculation.
uh this regard uh excludes the
possibility that RTG domain has the
effect on virus
replication. As I showed you before, we
can detect the systemic infection of the
vir the RTP mutant as early as civic
indicating that absent of RTP doesn't
prevent the systemic movement of the
virus through flow. So next we want to
ask whether RTP has effect on the cellto
cell movement of this
virus. So tissue print was performed to
detect the cellto cell movement in the
in the flown tissues. Here with RTP M
with RTP expression we can see a lot of
infection for side
um in the FL tissue between the this is
the STM this is the cross section of the
limb we can see a lot of infection for
however without RTP expression the virus
is present but the the infection for
both side is very
limited indicating that the RTP protein
had some role in the cellto cell
movement of the D4 virus.
So uh the MT protein is the moment
protein of this virus and has been and
our our formwork from
that the the number of infection fosi
are although decreased in tissue
infected with the leo virus mutant that
doesn't translate that doesn't translate
MP the similar phenotype between the RTP
mutant and the MP mutant uh inspire us
to study whether there is a fctional
interaction between the RTP and movement
protein.
So first first we studied the
localization of these two protein for MP
is the movement protein. Uh it can look
localized to the plasma matter and the
30s promoter uh agro
infotrated. We can see the PD
localization of MP. When we press the
RTP and the
30 promoter, we found that RTP can look
localized to the cytoplasm and also in
the nuclear
nuclear. However, when we express RTP
with the express with the infection for
the localization of the RTP changed
switch to the plasma
uh obviously there are some other
protein in encoded from the
refriation of the RTP protein. So
because MP has the electronic property
to localize to the
plasma. So next we detect the
localization of RTP uh without MP uh
translation. We found that RTP RTP
doesn't look like two
plasma when in fact with MP deficient
mutant
uh indicating the MP protein is the
protein which help the plasma domata
help the RTP protein to the plasma.
Next we want to know what the mechanism
of of this process. How the
MP make the RTP to the
plasma. Whether there is a direct
interaction with the two protein and
then the MP drag the RTP to the
plasma. So we also detect
antin when we parall alone can direct
the RT to the
plasma
indicating only ant alone can help RTP
to the plasma.
Uh therefore we started the interaction
between MP and RTP to to support whether
MP drag RTP to plasma doesn't
matter. So the
BCA was carried out to detect the RDP
and the MP interaction. If these two
protein can can interact with each
other, we can see the yellow fluorescent
and and micro and a confocal
microscope. Here is the BC result. We
confirm the interaction of RTP and MP
and we use the CP4 virus CP protein is
the as a positive
control. So to support our idea that MP
direct RTP to the plasma through through
binding we by mutenic analysis the
reason of RTP responsible for the
interaction with MP was and was was
found out and we found that there's no
interaction between this mutant with the
movement protein. This is the posive
control Y type
RTP. So next we want to know what the
localization went. We found that the M
mutation that disrupt RTP
binding prevent the localization of RTP
to the
plasma both in the both co-infected with
the leo virus infection or the MP alone.
uh this this does support the idea
that MT help the uh direct to the
plat through binding with this
protein. So next we construct this RDP
mutant into the leaf for virus infection
clone and inoculated into the plant. We
found that we detect the virus after
four weeks post
inoculation. We found that zero in fact
loi observed in tissues that chemically
infected with this RTP mutant and this
phenotype is very similar with the the
one mutant which the RTP couldn't be
translated and corresponding with the
the the limited corresponding with the
limited infection low the title of the
virus is also very low in the septic
This result about that RTP help for
virus cell to cell movement depending on
the binding with the movement
protein. So here is the conclusion of
part two. The RTD domain of virus has no
effect on virus replication. RTP is not
impart for longist movement but it
facilitates septamic spread. RTP
interacts directly with MP binding to
the MP redirects the RTP to the plasma
domata. RTP appears to faction to
move before virus between flown
companion cells with unknown whether the
cellto cell movement requires structure
RTP or a solubable
RTP. Here is the whole summary of my
talk. After the nephro virus get get
inoculated into the plant cell.
Fortunately they have to translate it
the replication associated protein and
make the liars get replication. Although
they will
incur some protein such as AP and MP for
the RTP for the rich translation. There
is a translational enhancer D of the
stop coding and and it can form a
develop structure and through
communication with the 15
domain inhibit the release vector coming
and then the translation will continue
the red protein will get
translated. After this protein get
translate gets translated it will be
recognized by the movement protein and
at the help of the movement protein to
reach the
plasma and help the virus move to the
neighbor cells.
We still don't know whether MP move to
the plasma plasma associate associate
associated with the
wiring. Also there are some other
possibilities that the MP just interacts
with the the MP just interacts with the
the the sol the solubable
RTP and they move to the plasma and then
mod modify the side of the plasma.
When the virus come to come to the
plasma doesn't matter this modification
of the pl this modification will
facilitate the mo the virus move to the
neighbor
cells. So as we can see the virus is
very simple but uh it works in a very
sophisticated manner. they works
together both in the nucleotide level
and in the protein interaction
level. So here is the acknowledgement. I
thank all the members from student grid
lab. Thank you so much for your help in
my project and help me improve the the
talk and also I thank the collaborator
uh from Michel Mish the lab. Thank you
so much for the discussion.
Uh I also thank all the guys from the
greenhouse. Uh I especially thank for
help me prepare all the plant. Finally I
thank the funding. Without funding we
can't do anything. Thank you for your
[Applause]
attention. This has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu.