this is a production of Cornell
University yeah thank you very much for
K's invitation and J's introduction so
um because I had some misunderstanding I
thought like a full of us will share the
total eight minutes so I try to make my
slides as compact as
possible so only three slides uh so this
is the format we used for our and CR
science uh lighting talks only three
minutes three slides so
uh I would like to bring you to a
totally different scale from the the
previous two speakers and also last
speaker by Mike um my lab uh our scale
of was actually very large well the the
I usually start my talk from this two
dimension scale the in space and in time
so in space we start from Leaf scale all
the way to the globe and at the time
scale we uh our research ranges from
hourly all the way to the decadal
scale so keep this in mind uh we uh my
the the research program uh we try to
answer two fundamental questions number
one we try to understand how the natural
ecosystems and also the agriculture
systems respond and feedback to the
climate change and climate varability
and how they uh respond to anthropogenic
activities uh so uh again the scale is a
major uh SE uh in my lab so here the
second question I want to answer is like
how can we harness the best sensing
technology to monitor the um
interactions of these um agriculture
system natural systems uh with the uh
climate change and anthropic activities
and how we can utilize the stateof art
uh models process based models uh to
predict such interaction feedbacks in
order to inform plant policy making so
here in the blue fun I tried to
highlight some of those um uh projects
uh we uh conducted under these two major
seams uh so the research are funded by
Doe usaid SF USDA and Ceda and also
Cornell Atkinson and also the six grand
challenges the major two approaches
number one uh we try to use the remote
sensing observations mostly from
satellites but we also utilize ort
remote sensing uh and also uh the tower
based sensing Technologies uh so here I
try to give you this example of showing
this latest a fleet of NASA uh
satellites um all the way from 1970s uh
to uh uh 20 to beyond the 2030s so we
utilize uh different types of
observations starting from including
Optical remote sensing thermal remote
sensing micro remote sensing lighter
remote sensing and also gravity remote
sensing to really reveal different
aspect of the earth system uh like the
uh for example the so moisture um
vegetation house and also like water
availability so I'm going to give you a
few examples later the second uh
approach we use is called process based
model uh this uh one example is uh the
Earth model or a climate model so such
models have been utilized for the ipcc
climate report AV a few years so why we
use such um models because it can help
us uh uh understand the mechanism so
basically we try to put the mag magntic
understanding into mathematical
equations and put into these type of
models so such models have like
different components including land
components ocean component uh
atmospheric components and also like ice
sheet everything put together so that we
can utilize such models to simulate the
past and also simulate the future so
here
uh you know this is one typical figures
um uh which is output of such models
basically these models can simulate the
past so during the past where it overlap
with the remote sensing technology uh
this data set can be utilized to
Benchmark such model simulations so once
we gain confidence of such model
simulations we can utilize these models
to project the future to see okay under
uh different uh economic orual emission
scenarios what's going to be look like
for the L system and also for the
atmospheric system and also ocean system
everything but here my lab focus on the
again the Eco terrestrial ecosystems and
also the agriculture systems so these
are two uh major geospatial tools we use
uh in my lab of course on top of that we
also put AI uh uh uh uh to um enhance
the the capability of these
tools then uh here I'm going to give you
some specific examples of the uh
research projects uh I really like to
put uh divide my resch projects into um
this um um this metrics um so this D one
dimension is field skill versus regional
skills and Beyond another dimension is
what tools we use uh including post
observations and also process based
models so at the field skill we try to
develop sensing technology and different
observational data to monitor crop
growth and Dynamics governed by the
genetic environment and management so
here these uh two figures left one shows
this two coupled Tower systems that put
uh the a currence measuring carbon water
and energy fluxes and also another uh
system that monitors the um hypers
spectral uh and also chlorop fluoresence
measurements so that we harness the two
measurements to understand the
vegetation house and their response to
different management including
irrigation nitrogen management and also
different stress in the meantime we also
develop the Drone technologies that can
uh put concurrent measurement of
hyperspectral and also florescence
measurements that can really look at
many different targets including
different U management treatments and
also a breeding plots to look at their
uh different uh
functions at the regional scale we
utilize really many different types of
satellite data to Monitor and assess the
the uh food water
sustainability uh in both Africa and
China so the first example shows the
left figure shows okay the the uh the
two decades of depletion huge water
depletion in Northern uh western China
but this is a mystery of what was causes
for such a long-term depletion so we
look at these gravity data set which
give you information of total water
storage and in the meantime we look at
the land use land cover change they said
and also um the soil moisture and also
VAP transformation data set uh in the
end we found it was really the crop
expansion because of cotton growth that
has dramatically uh expanded in the past
couple of decades that led to this huge
depletion of water uh the total water
storage because this is a very dry area
and the the coton system really depends
on irrigation but because it's very dry
uh there's no water so the water should
really come from the ground water so
where the ground water come from That's
from the Glacier melting from tension
Mountain so very very complex system so
here we try to use the Sal data set to
really reveal what's exactly going on
and another example is like we try to
utilize again different um salite data
set to understand the impact of land
restoration program in estopia so uh
there has been a million multi-million
dollar um investment from the ethopia to
put different uh the land restoration
programs but so far we don't know what
is large scale national scale impact so
we utilize different salite data set to
uh to evaluate okay what is productivity
under uh under drought turns out that
such restoration program can actually
improve the drought restoration for
productivity so such analysis can be
done by the conventional approaches with
like a very sophisticate surveys that
are labor intensive and um very time
consuming so um also at the field scale
we utilize models so this is the
collaboration um with my Gore and K
Robins so we try to um harness multiple
remote sensing
Technologies uh and crop growth models
and also AI to inform uh crop reading so
while my students were trying to run
very sophisticated 3D radiative transfer
models that um um benchmarked by the uh
the uh ligher measurement to see what is
the best uh optimal uh uh corn structure
that will have the the best um
productivity for the future and finally
we utilize both models and remote
sensing data to look at the future uh
crop yield productivity and also how the
agricultureal revolution can impact the
global carbon cycle so one um project we
are um in collaboration with uh the unar
which is natural Center for atmosic
research trying to understand okay what
is the past uh uh driver uh the the
Revolution including the fertilizer and
the genetics can impact the the the uh
the CO2 uh amplitude uh increase over
the past few uh past five decades which
has been a mystery so these are few
projects I want to highlight but in the
meantime we also work a lot on natural
vegetation including Amon Congo
rainforest and also the uh the carbon
and water uh uh coupling in the across
the US so um yeah that's all I have
thank you
any questions
you yeah would you let us know that what
type data you can collect at the field
scale okay so uh maybe Kelly can um also
CH in okay yeah so here we uh try to the
data set we collected including liar
data that's led by my G group and there
are also uh the uh multi-spectral
measurement from UAV so lighter data was
from like rowers and also mod spectral
that's from uh from UAV and we also have
some florescence data sets uh that is
measured by UAV so uh Kelly and I were
uh just got this six grand challenge
proposal that we want to collect more
data in the g2f field uh in mrave so the
uh of course this is like AI based
project so the the the the final uh
typical data also like you know we are
looking at a lot of like of the uh
trades in in the latent space which
probably don't know what what they are
but we uh other like more um expl traits
includes uh say plan height um Lai you
know Leaf angles or those uh of course
yield so all of these different
information but we're still looking at
the data sense so yeah so that's why you
know we're interested in like how you
are trying to optimize the uh cus
structure to get the the maximize the
productivity of of
apples question second in advaning this
what what are the mix right is it
quality of the Imaging the satellites is
it the compute power is it the number of
people models is it the ground truth in
data sets or is it oh that's a great
question and a very hard to answer
actually both to me fall is everywhere
so from the sensing technology part I
think the data on certainty is really
really huge especially for Sal REM uh
because of course we do have a lot of
datas but we don't know um uh the level
uncertainties and how to trace those
uncertainties so that's something we
have been working very hard on uh to
trace those uncertainties so that we can
really link the satellite sensing signal
with the actual variable or or trace of
our interest so that that's very hard I
think for the ground remote sensing I
think we're B necked by like the number
of like the the ground labels we have uh
I think that's that that that's quite
hard to me and another challenge
probably like analy tools like what is
the best way to really harness remote or
the uh the process based models and also
um AI you know a lot of people are
talking about like we we should create
like knowledge B Mach learning but you
know there are a lot of different ways
of how to do that in a best way and most
eff way of course the once we use like
the Deep learning or AI the computation
power is always challeng so I I would
say the challenge is everywhere so a lot
of work to
do okay many thanks here
this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu
right okay there's one slide that's not
patterned correctly sorry
Jos right so I'm going to tell you guys
today our lab works on patterning
especially of leaf grasses we want to
know how leaves are initiated from the
maram and how they form these beautiful
structures such as the the blade this
Lial and the sheet we've done a lot of
comparative analyses between uh UDOT and
grass leaves there's lots of differences
in morphology I'm going to focus today
on these two the differences in the leaf
base whereas in new diecuts uh the leaf
bases are usually non sheathing and
they're accompanied often times by these
stipules these lateral derivations
whereas grasses form sheathing Lea bases
as you can see better on this slide of
real plants a you diecut this one has no
but you can see the leaf inserts and it
doesn't spread it all around the stem
whereas This Grass plant this is maze
you can see at the node the sheath is uh
overlapping it forms a sheathing Leaf
base where there's a wrapper inside of a
Tucker and we know that this happens in
the sheath anyway at at the point of
emergence so if you're looking here at
the node in this CT image this computer
tomography image this is uh below where
the leaf will initiate move up a little
bit you can see they're already
overlapping as soon as they emerge we
know this from CT analogy also from
sectors if you have a sector here it'll
Mark both sides of the sheet but not the
blade they come off the mar stem they
come off the stem already overlapping so
how does this happen so we've used a
genetic approach to understand how these
leaves wrap and a long time ago we
worked on these two mutations called Nar
sheath one and Nar sheath two double
mutations make a leaf that is very very
skinny so this is a model of how leaf
leaves are may be patterned into at
least three medialateral domains the
central domain which gives rise to the
mid rib shown here the lateral domain
which is large part of the leaf and the
marginal domain we think our narrow
sheath mutants delete this blue region
here this marginal domain which is uh
basically goes about halfway up the leap
blade and all the way down into the
sheath and as a consequence these leaves
no longer wrap they look like pseudo
UDOT morphology this is almost like a a
if you do a cross-section through this
cartoon of the marem show these real
leaves here this is the fourth Leaf from
the marem here's the marem while type
they overlap the marginal domain is
there narrow sheath removes this blue
domain and these leaves no longer WRA
they look more like a
udon and just quickly you look at the
expression this is a Sho at glan with
two Leaf
primordia about a two we old seedling if
you do a cross-section about this level
you can see the marem in the middle this
outer Leaf the second Leaf of the marem
you can see expression shown with this
dark blue area of narrow sheet at the
margins and it promotes growth from
those margins and this is actually the
P1 the margins are not yet out from the
marem but they're going to come out and
this marks where they're going to
form okay so we think the narrow sheet
provides this outgrowth from the leap
margins now in maze there's actually two
other wax genes this is genetics or maze
genetics there's four of these there's
only one in arabidopsis so we knocked
out these other two called wa 3B walk 3A
unfortunate names and we found that
triple mutations with Naros one wax 3A
make very very very skinny leaves look
at the sides of the scale bars here
compared to the Naros double mutant and
then the uh the wild type these are what
the plants look like they're very very
short and they're very very curly and we
think these mutations Nar one two
together wat 38
remove not just the marginal domain
shown here but also this large red
lateral domain all you're left with is
the central domain and these triple
mutants and the growth happens from the
upper part of the Le okay so the
question is now how do these margins
wrap what is the pattern of how they
wrap and it's been noticed that
basically if you look again here's uh
the base of the sheet there's the node
there's a wrapper and a Tucker if you do
a cross-section of a Seedling here's the
stem you see a couple leaves here notice
if if you draw a line through the middle
of the stem all the leaf margins that
that are derived from the right side of
this stem will be wrappers and all the
ones from the left side will be Tuckers
and this pattern is robust it's
decidedly non-random and and grasses we
say the same thing happens in rice and
if you look at these as colorcoded
Richie likes to color code these this is
a wild type made and
rice a non-random pattern of wrapping
and tucking all the margins coming from
this side will be wrappers from this
side will be Tuckers so the question is
are there mutations that disrupt this
pattern and of course there are I
wouldn't tell you about them um so this
one you can see everything was good
until this one made a mistake wrong side
it's a random mistake this next one
didn't really go through the Mac to PC
conversion very well but you can see
this one actually made two mistakes and
we find this in plants that are mutated
in higher order walk stre mutations so
if these plants are homozygous for wre a
and then homozygous for at least one of
the other Naros sheet genes heterozygous
for the other they'll give this random
patterning of wrapper tuck and the the
the mistakes that these make are random
they get more and more severe as you go
up the plant make more and more use
so our mutants are in charge of this
which was a surprise we didn't expect
this actually if you look at it closely
looking looking at some markers and this
is the cross-section through the stem
wrapping and tucking looking at this
fourth Leaf shown here the expression of
this boundary Gene cck two which marks
very stiff cells that are very very slow
to divide it's it's heavy in the Tucker
not in the W you think this prevents
this uh this margin here from growing
and kind contrast wa 3A a gene which
makes leaves grow from the margins it's
expressed very heavily in the wrapper
part of the P4 but not the Tucker we
think this promotes growth to make this
thing wrap
around okay so that's what we're looking
at now so what Richie is doing now a
graduate student in the lab is is micro
dissecting with our ler micro dissection
scope the marginal domains of the
wrapper and the Tucker put them in
separate tubes figure out what genes are
being expressed here doing the same
thing for the lateral
domains and the central domain put them
all in different tubes make libraries
out of them see what's going on in terms
of gene
expression okay yeah that's what we're
going to do next so I'm going to skip
this and uh I think we have time for
this weirdness so there's another
mutation we're working on the lab was
actually found here at Cornell by
Emerson person this sping this made 1912
it's called lius this as the name
suggests this mutation removes the liul
which is shown here the boundary between
the blade and the sheath it's gone so in
Wild type we have these extended sheath
margins look at these These are
epidermally derived they're non-
chlorophos to the margin we think this
gives rise to the Liu narrow sheath
removes the marginal domain so these
extended sheath margins are gone the Liu
is still there but they're gone we found
the in lious mutants and this was uh
never described before we you see topic
expression of this sheet margin
extension way up into the blade and it
always happens on the Tucker side so
it's an asymmetric signal happen so lius
one unexpectedly is also involved in
patterning this wrapper
Tucker okay now it gets really weird if
you look at triple mutations narrow
sheath which should have no margins
combine them with lulus somehow the
margins of this triple mutant are
restored they're also ectopically
displaced on the Tucker side only so
somehow if you add these three mutations
together somehow narrow can now grow
margins again so we suspect wax Trea is
being patterned patterned there to do
that and even more weirdly if you look
at these triple mutant leaves the base
of the sheath are often times fused they
don't separate no wrapper no Tucker
their fuse if you look at the uh
microscopy you can see these margins
here don't
they can't decide whether to wrap or
tuck so they're fusing they're all
confused and the last side shows a
expression of wat 3A which should be a
heavy on the wrapper so these two Leaf
margins are confused they don't know
whether to wrap or tuck and this one is
fused it's got It's like a two-headed
monster it doesn't really uh know which
way to wrap which way to tuck so there's
a lot of work to do to figure this out
in the next couple years and I'll take
any questions if there's time
yeah so we haven't uh we we could asked
that question all the time we have no uh
done any experiments to see whether or
not this rapper Tucker mutations um are
affecting yield we're probably never
going to do those experiments tell you
the
truth
y yeah do you have any IDE to like
signaling
that left right so um we know that the
first sleeve decides the pattern whether
it's going to wrap this way or wrap that
way and it's random like an arabidopsis
the spiral filot taxi is going to happen
but it may be left or it may be right so
that first decision is random we're
trying to figure out now what how walk
stre somehow in combination with lius
can decide whether or not it's going to
maintain that wrapping tucking
relationship um we suspect that the
signal to wrap and Tuck which side's
going to wrap and Tuck is sent really
early in leave primordial formation I
didn't show everything that Richie's
doing he's actually going to be micro
dissecting the fourth Le from the maram
all the way up to the second L for the
maram we think the signal happens really
early when it sends down the Plant but
that's what the big question is what is
the signal to make this wrapping tucking
pattern yeah that's a good question
sorry this kind of related question but
ever since qtl started to be detected or
or yeah people have have had this idea
of breeding by Design where we would
understand what all the genes the plant
did and then we would put the right ones
in the right places and then we would
get higher you and to me as a Quant
seems Seems
hopeless but and I think your answer to
her question sort of was similar but I
wonder what you think about that and
like like like you study these things I
don't know if this has been back we not
but but does your does your research
illuminate anything about the about
prospects for breing by Design so we're
really uh interested in basic
fundamental mechanisms of development
and I don't really don't even think
about making more corn I don't say that
in my grant proposals but I really don't
think we need more
corn sorry need lock the doors Mike
can't
leave somebody in this room right I've
collaborated with Mike or a
lot any more questions yeah my what P
you you use to identify those
three n one
two what approach do do what what what
approach do we use so um I I
deliberately most of my talks are
labeled genetics and genomic analyses
but today I just uh use genetics we're
using lots of single cell RNA seek
spatial RNA seek Multiplex and C to try
to figure figure out how these patterns
uh form um and we're doing lots of
reverse genetics so yeah we're we're
doing um trying everything we can
actually to understand the mechanisms
we're really focused on the basic
biological mechanisms
so Nar one Nar 2 were identified at
Pioneer in a breeding stock they won't
tell us what the stock was but they just
arose and then walk 3 A and B we made
mutations by reverse genetics it seems
as if walk 3B I didn't mention this
doesn't seem to have an effect in
vegetative stages and might be affecting
later so that was done by reverse
genetics net 1 and two were identified
by forward
genetics clone the conventional way the
oldfashioned
way one more
question have you seen
orap
that and does that affect uh how unfur I
as
just in some before is that related at
all to that's a great question I mean if
very well could be um the degree of
overlap varies as you go from the base
of the plant a grass plant to the tip
the size of the inter node gets much
much smaller as you go up so they tend
to overlap more in the upper nodes and
lower nodes but they all come off the
marem off the stem in the sheath anyway
overlapping the blade components do not
they R
late great okay thanks Mike and thanks
all the speakers
today this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu