this is a production of Cornell
University so today I'm going to talk
about AI facilitate the scientific
discovery from Big Data and the process
based
modeling and probably as you may
aware and the AI is a big area it's uh
you know so many different uh method
and so powerful in different areas so
today I just uh want to share the
experience my lab had have and using AI
in our research so um today I'm going to
talk about why we developed a product
which is you know as a AI modeling tool
and how we use the
to understand the mechanisms underlying
soil carbon storage and to understand
the
climatological temperature
sensitivity of soil organic carbon along
soil profile now my lab is developing a
so- called be bio uh biog geochemistry
informed neural network as another AI
modeling tool so uh in each of the
slides I have bottom to indicate the
different part of my
talk and uh probably most of us has been
influenced so much by like chat GTP
regarding AI uh AI method and a chart
GTP basically is used soal Foundation
models which is which are pre-trained
with massive data sets and then when
user
to make a question or make request to
chat
GTP and then the chat GTP will use the
new data sets relevant data set to that
particular questions to Def find tuning
before they make um you know answer your
questions so so the Char
GTP uh what there are many of those soal
language large language models available
those larg language models require lots
of data when we use it most the time we
used as a blackbox
model and you know the these kind of for
AI tools can generate results that may
not physically or biologically
consistent with our understanding so ai2
without clear mechanistic understanding
might not not effectively help us to
understand the
science and but you know last year two
Nobel prizes awarded to physics I in
physics and chemistry to do scientist to
make a great contribution to advances in
in in chemistry and physics and
especially like the the the award in
chemistry they certainly can use the AI
to advance science so it's and uh
particularly the uh know professor John
hopfield re recently made a notes that
basically he think that word is
understandable and uh he he said that
you should be able to take anything
apart understand the relationship
between it
constituents do experiments on that
basis to be able to develop a
quantitative understanding of its
behavior and uh so so how to use the AI
as a scientific tool it's a major uh
issues we have been thinking about today
I'm going to
introduce a ai2 my lab has developed a
So-Cal proda that that's basically
combine process based
modeling and the neural network and also
data assimilation approach process based
model is used a lot of understanding
about process and the neuron and the the
machine learning most the time used as a
tool for data mining and then the the
product the tool we have developed is
try to combine the best order for that
ability capability of data mining
through machine learning and the process
based
understandings now I discuss why we
developed this approach holda as a as a
tool to understanding we we try to
understand the so carbon Dynamic
probably as as many of you know the so
is so critical for agriculture and now
also so critical for carbon sration
towards the so-call climate smart smart
agriculture so so how to predict the so
carbon Dynamic and storage is a major
issue and in this figure on the Y AIS is
a model predicted the soal carbon
density from 11 models that was used in
the ipcc fifth
assessment and xais is observation based
so carbon density so you can see from
this figure that if the model can
predict a so carbon density well enough
then most of those dots supposed to be
scattered around the one to one line but
but you can see from this figure the
model basically has no ideas what's what
happening in the real
world this uncertainty in model Earth
system modeling actually propagates to
the uh through those prediction
regarding the land carbon sink and the
CL climate uh Dynamics so this is one of
the one of the three major sources that
caus that
uncertainty in future climate
prediction so my love has been try
to understand and try to
improve how we can predict so carbon
Dynamic well and in order to predict
soil carbon or any any you know anything
if we want to make a moreel more make
more realistic prediction we need a
perfect model structure perfect model
parameterization and also forcing
variables so my has examed all those
three elements and one by one first we
developed a framework to unify all the
land carbon cycle and the nitrogen and
fast for models use a
matric equations as long as those model
use so called po on the fluxes
structures so we can unify all of them
so so basically we studied the the the B
of models try to understand what's the
fundamental principles underline them
and then we discovered that no matter
what kind of model structure as long as
they use the socalled flexus uh schemes
and all the model can be represented by
these matric equations that's counts
carbon input into the system and then
this is a carbon Dynamic basically
carbon transformation in the system and
also including release from the system
so basically this is a matric equation
we have converted about four 40 models
and to into MRI form and also another
group from um M plank in Institute in
Germany they also converted about the 20
nonlinear microbial model into this
matric form so now we have the once we
have the unified framework we can study
models at different level of complexity
under one overarching Theory and uh here
is the examples and the the
national anchor National Cent for
atmospheric research they developed the
So-Cal Community Land model with carbon
nitrogen Dynamics this is probably
literally is one of the most complicated
model in the whole world they used about
nearly one thousands of pools to
describe carbon nitrogen Dynamics and
use of six you know six modules to
describe them now my lab have converted
into two equations for carbon and
nitrogen Cycles in vegetation and soil
and once we converted to two equations
this this structure become highly mod
modular and we can make much more
powerful diagnostic capacity we make the
spin up much faster faster by about 50
times so once we converted to the this
uh unified framework now we can pinpoint
sources of model
uncertainties in this particular studies
we study we used eight models and
ranging from 10 model with two pool
versus or model from France France
that's with a 100
one the pools no matter how how
complicated or
the the complexity we can all represent
the different models in one
unified frame basically model structure
is the same so once we represented all
those model struct uh all the model in
the same
framework then we we did the experiment
so we used these eight models and feed
the same same forcing and also gpp and
then we find out that actually more
under the among the models that the
uncertainties diverges as time goes so
next since now we have unified framework
now we can
standardize the parameter of eight
models and then we can shrink these
model uncertainties to zero so so what
that mean those study that means this
simulation modeling approach that has
been used by Community for 60 years so
the the
the the simulation modeling approach
basically we develop the model by G
structure and then we assign the model
at the Primal value and use metadata to
drive to predict so those simulation
modeling does not use much data to
improve model parameter parameterization
so that lead to the divergency model
predictions so next step we we use the
soal data assimilation try to understand
how model parameterization will
influence model Dynamic now many people
use the digital T to describe this data
assimilation approach basically try to
use the model mimic the real world as
much as we can so so data simulation the
idea is we are not only need the model
structure but we also use the relevant
observations through data assimilation
to estimate the parameter make the model
to predict the real world phenomena as
much as we uh you know as we can so
that's basically that's why the Dig T
came from the prediction my lab has been
doing this since about 20 years ago my
first poster I hired to do this is 203
to 205 AT Regional scales and in the
past about 20 I mean the especially
first 15 years we did a variety of
analysis use this digital TN techniques
and certainly we improved this model
prediction um very much I mean lot the
residue decreased the special
representation of the soil carbon
improved but the still the accuracy is
not ideal the accuracy CH you know
improved to like about R square of
point4 but still no matter what we do
still we not cannot improve them further
so then we analyze we thinking about
this issue why you know once we use the
data the digital TN still cannot perform
well enough so we we try to understand
the reason basically the parameter value
in those models in those Earth System
model at the global scale assume to be
constant over space and the time and but
actually this assumption may be
problematic this assumption works for
model to be used at the local scale for
short term it's fine but once we do the
longterm and the large scale simulation
it may not uh not works basically
parameter in the models is represent the
property of those processes and for
example the soil property and the
microbial dynamic in Isa in the model
it's assumed the same as in Africa or
South America so this is you know bi
biologically or ecologically doesn't
make sense but the currently model still
make those assumptions so once we
realize that and we propose that we
really need especially on a temporary
varying parameter in order to make the
digital TN works well so that's how we
incorporate the Deep learning into this
our scheme to develop we developed the
So-Cal process guided deep learning on
the data during the modeling and the
basically at the data simulation
approach we add the Deep learning so now
you can see we used about
60,000 of vertical profile of soal
carbon worldwide and put into this
product now we get the the the the the
uh R square
62 so this is uh this R square accuracy
is very close very similar to this
machine learning without any process
basically socalled soil mapping people
use soil mapping that's very use the
neural network without any process so
this is is accuracy it's a it's almost
Reach the the level that we uh so far we
cannot do much at the the at least at
the global scale so so now hopefully now
I introduced uh basically discussed the
why we used this introduced the AI uh AI
uh modeling tools to do uh to combine
the process understanding and the data
mining so first issue we try to address
the use this U method is so-called
microbia to evaluate microbial rule in
so carbon organic carbon formation and
the persistent and recently the so
scientist and uh led by mro schimid and
uh um
uh the johannas also contributed to this
paper the new framework emphasize the
the rule of microb and mineral in soil
organic uh formation and the persistence
but we still need to find a way to
evaluate the relative importance of
various process in soil so in this
particular study we first defin soal
mobial carbon use efficiency as biomass
microbial biomass produced divided by
substrate uptate and this actually
microbial carbon use
efficiency has represent the Dual rules
so one point is micob consume the soil
organic substrate for to get energy and
growth and also the M soil iob also
contribute to soil organic substrate so
the relative rule relative importance of
those two rules and might determine the
how soil organic carbon formation and
the
persistance so one hypothesis in the
floating in the literature is that the
higher carbon use efficiency will lead
to the appr of s organic carbon storage
as long as the the the microbial carbon
use deficiency stimulate microbial
biomass and necromass formation and then
contribute the soil organic carbon but
also the other ideas has been greatly
discussed in the literature that if
microbial carbon use deficiency
increased and the microbial bomas
increase and lead to more actual
cellular enzyme activities actually soil
organic carbon can
decrease so as mentioned in our B the
product we have modal structures that
represent the microbial activities now
we can test see under what kind of
conditions the soil organic carbon will
increase versus decrease with the micro
be a carbon use efficiency we find out
two critical parameters one is a
resonance time for M microb another is
resonance time for enzyme and then the
those different parameter will lead to
the different patterns so now the issue
is what the real world the observation
will tell us about those parameter so
that's the basically and then if we can
use use the real world data to tell us
then we can con can evaluate the
relative importance of those Pro those
process represented in in this model so
what we did is used as I mentioned we
used the 60,000 vertical soil profile
data and
to to to to constrain the model and then
we estimate if each of the seven
components that contribute to the soil
organic carbon
storage and then we make the evaluation
to see the their relative importance use
two type of
sensitivity and one type of sensitivity
is soall specially uh same constant
parameter versus variance parameter as I
mentioned to to as I mentioned earlier
that currently Earth System model all
use the constant parameter over the glow
now we estimate the specially variance
parameter so if we use the specially
constant parameter versus variance
parameter we can see that microbial
carbon use efficiency has the largest
impact on the on the simulated carbon we
also did the sensitivity analysis which
has been done regularly in the modeling
or also indicate microbial carbon use
efficiency is most important so we also
use the model generated relationship of
so organic carbon versus microbial
carbon use efficiency and also
observation use mod analysis to to to to
to basically to verify the model uh
predictions so this is basically one of
the study we we have done to use this
you know AI facilitate the AI modeling
tools to understand the
mechanisms so next we also use this tool
for another study try to understand the
mechanisms so another study we call the
climatological uh temperature
sensitivity for soil organic carbon to
warming so what we did is we first again
use this Global database of vertical
soal carbon and and then we use use
different layer of soil we use each of
two cm as so layer and then we get data
from this database and then we use this
uh uh at each s layer we have soil
organic carbon versus temperature we get
the temperature sensitivity sorry
temperature sensitivity and then use
those different along the different
layer we get the observed apparent
temperature sensitivity Q10 versus
depths basically this indicate that
temperature sensitivity of so organic
carbon at the surface is highest most
sensitive and then the towards the Deep
layer sensitivity is very very low so
that's basically observation based so
now this observation based gradings of
temperature sensitivity could caused by
lots of mechanisms and very complicated
so now how can we know which mechanisms
really influence them in the real world
it's very difficult to do experiment and
certainly we we need the innovation
Innovative approach to the experiment
but now we have modeling we will see
whether we can use model ai ai modeling
to help te te that part so this is
observation observe the part apparent
temperature function we use the
microbial based model nonlinear model
after the use the data simulation you
can see we cannot reproduce that pattern
and we we used the CLM model uh and
before product so this pattern also
doesn't reproduce but after we use the
produ to train the CLM and then we find
that pattering it's very very similar so
we now we can use model as digital T to
represent
observation and also we need to make
sure that actually the model the
intrinsic parameter the parameter for
intrinsic tempature sensitivity actually
relatively constant so this apparent one
has a huge depth dependent dependency
but the intrinsic one it's more or less
constant so this is a huge contrast so
now we have a digital pin to to the real
world patter
now we can use this digital Tain to to
understand what causes this apparent
temperature sensitivity why do different
from the model intrinsic temp
temperature sensitivity use this matric
equation as I mentioned that we use this
matric equation to unify the all the
land carbon cycle models as long as they
use the so p and flux structures so in
these equations there are seven terms I
mean there six terms but represent seven
uh processes now we can PE tease them
apart use processes so what we did the
first things we use the
manipulate a parameter matri a a is
basically transformation matrix that's
and another is a k k is uh the
decomposability
ma vectors so we make the globally
uniformed uh a matric and now we you can
see that once we used the uh globally
unified a it's a you know this is the
apparent apparent sensitivity this is
intrinsic now we
manipulate the a matric and then we lift
this the q1 vertical profile closer to
the intrinsic one now we unify the K
separately also make it closer to the
intrinsic one but once we unify both A
and K actually this very close to the
intrinsic one so based on this we can
see that prob
those process related to microbial
carbon
transformation and the
absorption and also related to organic
carbon decomposability play the huge
rule to influence the the temperature
sensitivity in the real world so we also
manipulate other parameter like water
scaler and the depth scaler they do have
effect but cannot match the the the the
intrinsic one well so here if we unify
all this parameter actually the
theoretically we can see this even even
temperature sensitivity could increasing
with the depth so this is opposite from
The observed apparent one so this is a
the challenge now now we can use a
digital train to try to see what you
know the potential mechanisms underline
those OB observe the pattern but the
challenge is still how to get empirical
evidence to support those I AI modeling
analysis so this is the another
challenge so so
now um
currently our lab is developing so-call
biolog chemistry ined the neural network
by a graduate student how how howy and
he's a second year graduate student and
then after he joined our lab he now he
put the matric equation into neural
network and then this uh this we find
out this the the accuracy is very high
even slightly higher than the product
the computationally much faster than
produ by 50 times and as I mentioned our
metric equation spin up already faster
than the regular model by 50 times now
this is another 50 times over the 50
times so basically now being make the
spin up faster by 2,000 more than 2,000
times faster than the the current model
so this offer the explanatory power and
we try to do the transfer learning try
to use this technique for the carbon
farming at the at the farm level so let
me make a summary you know we by 2017 we
identify the issue that's need to be
solved by AI we luckily enough recruit a
graduate student who developed a product
and he used the product to study the
microbial uh carbon use efficiency and
the soil organic carbon relationship and
he also used this study the model in
convergency and another graduate student
studed the intrinsic versus app Q now
how is developing the being and
currently we have a few postor of
graduate student Now using being to
study time course Force Dynamic and
disturbing regime and greenhouse gas
emissions so what we have learned in the
past is basically AI modeling can enable
us to discover mechanisms underly
systems behavior from Big Data and a
process based model AI is very powerful
to accelerate computational efficiency
achieve high accuracy in the model uh
data fitting is basically accuracing in
digital train now and democratize the
scientific discovery but AI is a tool
like any other tools and it is powerful
only if we can identify scientific
issues that need AI to
address and uh many people contributed
to our studies I cannot uh you know uh
I don't have time to to say each of them
we also get fund basically funding from
uh AI uh AI
Institute and uh we also supported by AI
for science the shim
foundation and uh uh s other LTR sit
spru sites funding from uh NSF doe and
the
USDA and also take this opportunity do
some
advertisement if any of your student and
at Corel you are welcome to join our
training course it's free for Corel uh
people but uh we do take a little bit of
uh tuition fee for people outside thank
you very
much yeah yeah yeah no problem uh I mean
the uh your presentation is very nice
and I'm just wondering in the data data
simulation part you mention that the
parameters are constant uh when you uh
apply the data assimilation method in
global ass simulation but uh for uh but
I know some um data simulation methods
uh which can also update the parameters
so I just want wondering what's the
difference between uh this methods and
the
product well
uh you said update probably you're
talking about like Karma filter yeah
Karma fi has been used very widely by
engineering uh engineering s
scientists professors I mean the
disciplines and uh it's true the comma
Fielder is do the time uh you know time
uh up update once you have a have
observation
uh along the time so this uh one thing
is uh this um comma field probably may
not be use for tool for carbon cycle or
broadly speaking biog chemical cycle
research because it's update the state
and the parameter at the same times once
you update the state variable sorry this
is get to very technical and then then
this become um you know the not to get
the the mass balanced so so back to the
almost all the Earth System model you
still use the constant parameter
now oh yeah thank you and another
problem is that um I'm just wondering uh
in uh in the I mean I noticed that you
use the um AI model to chain the
parameters to op optimize the parameters
but uh
uh you have to get the true value of the
parameter it's very different to get
this data so I'm just wondering how do
you get the uh the
parameters well that's a very important
a very important question and usually
those parameter is not observable in the
real world it's right yeah yeah most of
them so what we can do is we use the
socalled
OS uh this is
observational system simulation
experiment uh to test the whether the
method can be authentically reproduced
so so o OSS again this is a very
technical uh issue and OSS is basically
use the model given the parer to use the
model to produce the output and then use
the output to train the model again to
see how how accurately the recover the
parameter comparing to original
parameter so in both both being and the
uh the product we did this
experiment uh okay I understand so you
mean the parameters also be reversed and
then you'll use the this reverse
parameters to validate okay thank you
yeah thank you this a great
question sorry it's a very technical
talk yeah
ich I had a question so you had uh at
one point you were looking at the
microbial parameters and you had
identified that the residence time of
the microbial biomass and then the the
residence time of the enzymes were
having an impact yeah um were you able
to see which of those two parameters
maybe mattered the most or if if could
you comment on how important those
parameters were for your soil carbon
estimation yeah those uh let me
uh see if I can get back to the slides
and
uh you can see the different combination
of those two parameter will really
influence so for example like this one
is uh you know the
microbial uh 10 over time of micro micro
is a
five and this uh
yeah this uh that's make it the
um so let me see if uh you know the this
enzyme turn over time if enzyme turn
over time fast and then these become
negative so those are modal exercise and
then actually in once we do data
simulation we can constraint each of the
prodct
so apparently because now we get the
most relationship probably look like
this so look like probably um uh this
enzyme 10 over time I I I really we need
to check the real data but uh based on
the relationship we got after data
simulation probably somewhere around
here so so the um my my C turn over time
around one on the 1.5
probably okay thanks if you need need
the real I mean the exactly value we can
we can dig into our our results great
thanks we have a question also in the
chat from Alison so she has uh two
questions the first is what do you mean
by AI can be a force for democratizing
data well the um not uh not the data
probably
so what I what I meant is uh you know my
my La has been doing the data simulation
for about 20 some years and actually now
we find that that being it's much easier
and can do data simulation in a much
better way so so so actually this is
probably you know much easier to use and
uh you know before each if uh when I
take a new student of post store they
always take a long time to learn about
data simulation I now being probably
make the process much
easier great and the second question she
has is uh you ended with a really strong
point that AI is only powerful if
researchers are answering important
questions so how can you gain input on
what the most important questions
stakeholders need answers to and what
questions do your team thinks are the
most important to address with the eye
going forward
well this is a this is a very great
question on questions well the you know
the I guess talking with the farmers and
also uh ping scientific I mean each of
the scientists you know generate their
own questions in the different way and
uh certainly the you know like the kind
of a
seminar and the lab meeting and talk
with farmers and depends on yeah your
your own work I guess different you know
different people have a different way to
to generate
questions I I understand that probably I
didn't answer your question very
well do we have any other questions in
the
audience yeah I have one over here why
don't you go ahead and I played with the
microphone so let's see if Yi can hear
you um uh thank you for the presentation
uh it seems some of it went over my head
but it really seems like they made you
earn your tenure here really interesting
um so hold on youi can you hear him
yes um yeah uh if if I understand
correctly uh a lot of your research is
based in in force um but when changing
and applying it to agriculture um we we
have like uh like management practices
that can influence these dynamics that
you're describing in is do you see a
possibility uh of of using kind of your
work and and moving it towards like a
agricultural uh Focus focused questions
despite the complexity of like different
management um decisions on a spatial
scale like the
glob yes that's a great question and uh
certainly uh you know after I join
joined the so so on the crop science
session this is a very important uh
issues I uh we are exploring and
certainly we don't want to just you know
the walk on Forest or grassland or
Global scales but also try to make some
contributions to S on crop sections
science sections and uh so what our
thinking is probably in the towards the
end is just uh let me see can you see my
slides let me see yes for the end we um
we are you know I'm I only mentioned
very briefly we are currently do soall
transfer learning and
uh uh probably if uh uh you know you may
know that currently none of the soil
model can predict well if uh even uh you
know even we have like being or product
we still cannot apply to the individual
Farmers because this uh you know
individual F may not have enough data so
what I'm we are thinking about is so
called transfer learning so the idea is
very similar to like chter GTP Char GTP
train lot of you know to train with a
lot of data big data but when they
answer when answer your particular
questions and CH dtp borrow the
information from other data sets try to
answer your questions so this is
actually is called transfer learning so
the idea if we apply to here is if we
can train the the model I mean the let's
be or product with a lot of data at the
global scales then we supposed to kind
apply that knowledge to a particular
firm so this is the idea we are
exploring try to try to apply to the
individual Farms so this idea probably
also applicable to any uh you know any
of these subject areas for example crop
year or the we weat control and um you
know some other issues yeah nitrogen
fixation yeah so this is the kind of
things we are thinking about I
understand we
still uh haven't made uh a great
contribution to so on the crop session
for for individual Farm I mean the for
Farm
yet does it make sense yeah thanks you
we're we're at time so if we could thank
Ichi
again well thank you all for listening
and for great
questions this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu