thanks so much James um I'm Donna nouer
I'm a Youth Development educator with
University of Illinois Extension um I
work with the 4 program and other and
youth activities in Metro communities um
so I do things that are a little bit
different most of my world is about stem
and I found that climate change has been
one of the things that our youth are
concerned about they're interested in
and they have been very motivated by
some of the um opportunities through 4
through the egg innovators program some
of the um stem challenges that have been
available and that you can get these
things through shop 4 so they are
available to you
um in the last year these science
ambassadors who are all um middle school
and high school so their early teens
through High School uh go out and they
do teen teaching and Outreach they work
in some of our um underserved
communities and do large walk by
activities down to small group
activities for smaller groups the group
I have with me today have been very
active in developing an app um to track
carbon outputs and give alternatives on
how to reduce your carbon outputs um I
have ashmit Gambar uh darik mapi and
Joshua George with me they are part of a
team that was working on a program
called Blast and blast was
a u oper offered rather in naville which
is one of our um communities in my unit
which serves Three Counties in the
Chicago metropolitan area and blast is
about building leadership around
sustainable
transformation so this was a program
that uh teens took their ideas their
concerns and developed a program to get
something done so um these are three of
the guys they're my coding experts
because you need that coding for it and
then I have U another larger group of
Youth who also did a lot of research to
get the information that they needed to
use to put it into the app so at this
point I'm going to turn it over to uh my
4H team and they're going to take over
and tell you a little bit about what
they were doing how they just got to
that point and um and about some of the
coding that they've been teaching so uh
forh Team you can get in and do your
thing all right so why did we start this
project so since all of us are soon to
be computer science Majors we wanted to
have an app that has practical solutions
for day-to-day applications and for it
to be easily accessible so whether you
have an iPhone or an Android we want it
to be on the Apple and Google Play Store
so we specifically since all of us are
environmental activists we wanted to
have an app that promotes sustainability
so the three topics that we dove into
are carbon emissions water conservation
and food waste so later on in this
presentation we're going to get into the
specifics of why we wanted to dive into
these three topics and also of course
give our how we implemented these
Solutions into our app and the functions
of the app and we wanted to influence an
app that influences the long-term
generation so since climate change is an
existing problem that we have and all
and we need it to promote
sustainability yeah so here's our
timeline of our project uh as you can
see we started our first team meeting
and that was back in I think January of
2024 and like Miss nouer mentioned
before we're actually three out of eight
people that joined in on this project
and from their we actually broke off
into a different research group uh one
was carbon emissions one was food waste
and also water
conservation and from there we actually
received a grant from Apple they
provided us with iPads to actually start
on the coding processes for this project
and after that we developed a prototype
on figma this application where we can
kind of just um outline our uh program
without actually starting on the coding
so we actually started on figma first
first before presenting at blast and I
know Miss nouer touched upon that but we
were there in hopes of receiving funding
for app so yeah that was at blast and
then right now we're actually educating
the other uh people in our group on the
basics of Swift so we can actually start
on programming and our goal eventually
is to get this published and available
on the App
Store see yeah on to our first topic
carbon emissions I just have some stats
on the screen right now and as you can
see um the average US passenger car
emits about 2.7 metric tons of CO2 per
year so our goal is to try to you know
get that number down and we know we can
see that food transportation is
responsible for 19% of all carbon
emissions so along with that there's
also a diagram you can see up there and
it says that cars and bands have around
I think
48% um our biggest share of CO2
emissions and after that it's the
freight trains and trucks I
believe so how does our app actually
combat these problems so our app has two
functions on the carbon emissions part
and one of them is to input our ride
info so say if you take like a a 20
minute car ride it'll provide the output
of carbon emitted based on the time
lapsed and it also provide an alternate
route of travel
so that was our first uh first function
the second function is it'll it'll
provide a carbon footprint based on the
food packaging of any food let's say you
get at the grocery store it'll if you
input the brand and the type of food
it'll output uh the exact um carbon
footprint based on
it uh the second component of our app is
water conservation
and so what is water conservation water
conservation is using water efficiently
and effectively to prevent using water
unnecessarily and so one of the main
problem problem that stems from this is
that fresh water resources are limited
and so we want to combat that by having
healthy habits and we want to Pro we
want to promote that by using it as
features in our app and so as we can see
in the pie chart about 20%
of the of the water that we use comes
from toilets showers faucets clothes and
washer and many of these things are in
our own household and so we believe that
with our functions we'll be able to
combat this usage with our two
functions and so our two functions are
meaningful reminders and pro providing a
personalized list for the user and so
the first one the meaningful reminders
so the user will input their water usage
and we want to provide the user with
more information about how to cut down
their water usage like what they can do
and some calculations of like how how
much water they've been using and how to
prevent them from using that much water
and so our second one providing a
personalized list for the user so we
want to have P personalized things for
the user that they have inputed and
based off of their needs and so for
example for me one of the things that I
would do is I've been using a water
bucket at home to collect rain and I've
been just storing it in that bucket and
using it for daily tasks such as like
watering plants cleaning out doors and
flushing toilets and I talked to my
family about that and we found it very
beneficial and healthy for the
environment because we're not using as
much water and we're saving the water
because we're collecting it from the
rain and so some other examples are
Mulch and compost but the water bucket
with the rain that is what I found the
most beneficial and that was something
that worked for me and so we want to
have something personalized like that
and we want to use that as a function in
our
app all right so for the final topic
that we dove into is food waste so these
are some facts that I found really
interesting about food waste so I found
that onethird of the world's food goes
to waste so as you can see and on the
picture on the graphic on the bottom it
shows how 43% of homes is where our
waste comes from 40% comes from
restaurants groceries and food service
companies 16% comes from farms and 2%
comes from manufacturers so I just
really wanted to have our app combat all
these problems and have less food being
wasted so for our app function for food
waste we have three specific functions
so the first one is input inputting food
so first the user inputs whatever food
they bought and the expiration dates of
those produce so and then during the as
it gets closer to the date of expiration
the app is going to constantly send
reminders on recently bought food so
it's going to give you a friendly
reminder on when the item is going to be
perished
and then for the second app function
with the expiration date being passed
for the produce the app is going to send
specific recipes that you can make with
the expired produce so such as for
example bananas when bananas are
parished the app would send a recipe of
a banana bread that you could make so
then for our third and final function of
this app we would have location so the
user would input their location and then
a 50 mile radius would be generated to
find the nearest donation Food Center so
all these three functions contribute to
less food
waste we have many goals to promote
healthy environment and promote
sustainable habits and so we are
planning on promoting these healthy
habits through our app and so our first
goal that we have is to continue to
teach classes to other students and so
prior we have succeeded in teaching
classes as we've been going to other
schools and other offices to teach
classes using the Swift language and so
from the Grant from Apple that our for 4
group received we're given many
resources such as iPads Apple pencils
while also gting their full support
these resources were very useful for
teaching the students and we're able to
show the app that we are making with our
full timeline of events to the students
and this allowed the students to see
what our app was how it worked and what
we did to make it happen and so this was
able to inspire the other students and
they were inspired to make their own app
and it was that app that theyve wanted
to make was something similar to what
we've been making and so we spoke to
some of the students and they told us
that they were interested in making
their own apps about environmental
sustainability and that is a very big
progress step that we wanted to make and
that is like that is something that we
were very proud of as we were able to
promote a healthy change and so our
second goal is to continue working on
the app and to ultimately publish it and
so we want to have we want this app to
have a big impact and once we're done
with the coding we'll be able to publish
it on the App Store and Google Play
Store and this will help promote
positive change which is our third goal
and so we've been doing this throughout
we've been promoting positive change
throughout as I said prior by inspiring
other students to create their own apps
and so we believe that this is very
necessary to promote healthy
environmental change and promote a
positive impact people will be
conserving water better they'll be
reducing carbon emissions and they'll be
wasting less food while just making
better and healthier decisions overall
and these will all ultimately assist us
in reducing the impact of environmental
challenges that we face today as as a
world and we hope to bring positive
change day by
day thank you for listening to our
presentation I greatly appreciate your
attention in this and I I really want to
thank and congratulate these young
people they um they came up with these
ideas themselves this was not uh created
by any adults they came to me and said
they wanted to take their talents and
find ways to use it to make a difference
in the world um I'm very grateful to a
couple of the other members who are now
off at college and they're very very
busy uh doing other things they were the
one who got us into blast to begin with
and they were people who were already
into environmental issues and wanted to
take this further and we're grateful for
all the teaching that these guys have
been doing because they're
providing opportunities to youth who
otherwise would not have an opportunity
at all so thanks a lot and if you have
any questions were here we'd be happy to
answer
it so I have our questions and answers
open and interestingly a lot of our
questions and answers are just
outstanding great work it's fantastic
presentation so that's a that's a fun
way
um um
so a few kind of direct oh David has a
question yeah just I I thought this was
fantastic as as James was just saying um
I'm just kind of wondering how you all
think this you know individually might
kind of
like uh help you sort of take your next
steps in life you're work on this you
know in terms of what you each want to
move on to do after uh
this is finished and a success let's
say so we're really looking forward to
publishing this app and promoting a
positive change and so that is something
like that we've been very interested in
we've been combining this with coding as
well and so coding is like our very big
hobby for all of us as we've been like
teaching classes and we're all planning
and hoping to be computer science Majors
as we apply
this coming year and so we've been
combining two of our interests into one
and that is just something that we're
really interested in and this positive
change that we've been promoting and
that we've seen already happen so far
these results that we've seen we've
found those outstanding and we just want
to keep seeing more and we just really
love the positive impact and change that
it has
um so we do have uh another question um
have they have you considered exploring
info about the carbon Footprints of say
larger corporations or you know
Transportation Industries like Airlines
and the like to provide information in
your app for that as
well I think Josh is talking but he's
muted
yeah so I believe that we would be
looking to more larger corporations like
Airlines and I think it said yeah larger
corporations Airlines Etc so right now
we just started focusing on like the
driving aspect of it because I think um
when we're looking at users right
they'll more they'll use this app when
they're driving so I believe that's like
more in their everyday life we could and
we could incorporate something with
Airlines or even corporations or maybe
just put like an informational article
about
that and then um from my perspective a
thing that I would like to hear um a lot
of our attendees in the meeting are
practitioners similar to me or Donna and
from your
perspective what do you find has been
one of the more helpful
aspects
um I guess from like the the extension
or the 4 system as you've gone along in
this um a lot of us are trying to figure
out how to best support the young people
that we work with and so if you have any
specific thoughts on that I would
appreciate it myself at
least okay so the 4 organization really
supports us really well with especially
Miss nouer she's been supporting us
through all these all these different
activities and giving us the resources
that we need to better our app and even
our activities that we do with teaching
and um everything else so yeah just
supporting resources and um yes like
with the iPads we wouldn't have been
able to do all the Swift coding without
the Apple grant that we got so just like
putting our support putting your support
to us will just drive us
exponentially so providing that space
for you to explore your interests and
making sure you're
supported yeah that's
fantastic this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu