okay well hi everyone uh thanks for
sticking around for on this call today
about Youth and climate and I'll share
an experience about developing
curriculum with and for indigenous
peoples and there's a lot of lessons
learned with this project and if you
have any interest of working with IND
people hopefully you'll be able to learn
a few things from our own experience and
apply them as well or Not Apply them if
they were something that didn't work on
our end and we'll share both the
positives and the Lessons Learned um
that we wouldn't do again in this whole
journey so here we go in a few minutes
we'll just do a whirlwind uh tour of
that experience and I'll um I'll make
sure to cover all aspects in the brief
time we have together so as I start
sharing some background about this
project I'll just put a question in the
chat for all of you to think about and
respond to both attendees and panelists
um as I'm talking so if you could just
review that and when you have a moment
of inspiration want to share that with
everyone that would be fantastic in the
chat okay so this uh brief story is
about my experience in the Colorado
Plateau area of Utah I'm in Moab in
um just north of the Navajo Nation and
surrounded by a range of tribes
including the Ute tribe the Hopi uh
tribe as well and uh there's the Apachi
and a range of other tribes that live
still in this area and have a very
strong presence here and uh as part of a
necki initiative actually uh Patricia
Townsen in Washington formed a team and
we submitted a National Science
Foundation Grant to do this project
called climate change Community programs
and opportunities uh if you look at the
acronym of that what I just said it's C
C3PO so we had a little nerdy Star Wars
U acronym for our project and Patricia
in her project worked with let next
population in Washington and I worked
with Alaska or I worked with uh
indigenous populations in Utah my
colleague art worked with uh indigenous
youth in Alaska and uh in Pennsylvania
Melissa Cay worked with um women Forest
donors so again my audience was uh not
youth but College age students and and
so I'll just share that right from the
onset that still youth but not um not
same as 4 youth for
example okay so at the beginning of this
NSF grant our whole plan was to apply uh
already created an excellent curriculum
from the University of California called
climate stewards and
what I learned over time is that a
canned curriculum applied to indigenous
populations even if it is adaptive was
not going to work very well and it
wasn't going to be the best approach
that we had to design this from the
ground up and uh so that was one lesson
learned along the way we H we formed an
advisory Council of um professionals and
tribal members that had extensive
experience working with indigenous
communities and or living in indigenous
communities to guide our process as we
uh rolled out our game plan for
developing a curriculum focused around
climate change uh it involved over time
uh first of all we needed to expand our
timeline we learned right away with uh
with with beyond the boundaries of the
NSF Grant because building the
relationships with tribal members took a
lot longer than um even we had imagined
at the beginning and so definitely
extending timelines is an important
aspect ECT of working with indigenous
communities and that's difficult in our
academic environments with the Turn and
Burn
of and uh giving us many reality checks
like first of all our timeline was
unrealistic and uh from those talking
circles we also uh or sorry from The
Advisory Council we also um receiv
received guidance on hiring someone who
with experience working with tribal
members to help us decolonize our survey
instrument that we uh were planning to
use and we ended up moving completely
away from surving tribal members in the
end and just doing a depth qualitative
process through what we call talking
circles so similar to focus groups we
sat in circles and had conversations
around climate and those conversations
fed into our curriculum development
process we did three talking circles in
the end one at um the Red Canyon poow in
Moab one um in a Hogan down in Blanding
and another talking circle with
organizational Partners on zoom and um
and then also the Hogan talking Circle
was with participants in a program
called Native American tribes upholding
restoration and education and we did a
first talking circle at the beginning of
our uh whole process down on their site
where the program takes place in Beer's
National Monument so four total but with
uh three different audiences if that
makes sense okay so those talking
circles um again that took quite a while
to build the relationships and I won't
go into depth here because I have just a
handful of minutes but uh I will say
that we reached out to chapter houses on
the Navajo Nation to notify them of our
work and to the Navajo Nation
IRB and uh we didn't receive a response
from the Navajo Nation IRB which we were
told from some tribal members and on our
advisory Council that that couldn't um
actually be good news that there weren't
any red flags about the research but our
IRB was not happy with the fact we
hadn't received notification for the nav
Nation IRB and it really delayed our
project and uh so early communication if
your the tribe you're working with has
an IRB is extremely important and um
building that I in hindsight I would
have built that right at the beginning
of the grand application
process and um one thing that was a POS
positive in the end unexpectedly is I
had already volunteered at the Red Sands
Powwow in years past and so I had
relationship with some of the staff
there and that allowed us to conduct a
talking circle at the powwow but we also
paid to table there so we contributed to
the event financially and um then we we
conducted a talking circle on the side
of tabling an educational table so uh at
first we launched a position to
decolonize our instrument and everything
uh as latinx and Indigenous at first I
was going to look at both populations
and um climate perceptions from
both and I learned that very few people
have um depth experience with both
cultures there's a lot of differences
and so in hindsight I would have just
advertised for an indigenous Community
coordinator instead of a latinx and
Indigenous uh and then hired someone
else to do U the Latin U latinx side but
again lesson learned so we fast
forwarding through time we conduct our
talking circles we transcribe uh code uh
the results and we shared those back
immediately within two weeks with the
participants to do a reference check of
the data make sure our interpretation
was accurate and then we created a
handout that was really easy to read and
Visually attractive that we administered
at the Red Sands powow and to our
participants electronically to share
about our takeaways from The Talk
circles major results after the talking
circles we hired three indigenous
participants who had engaged in the
talking circles to co-create a climate
change curriculum with us for the Native
American tribes program at the beginning
of the Grant I had planned to uh launch
my own program and then realized that
that would be in competition with an
already existing program within Beer's
National Monument so we partnered with
them instead and just strengthen their
program through our research the three
indigenous um participants we hired we
um paid a thousand each to work with us
over the course of several weeks to
co-create our climate change curriculum
we had weekly meetings and homework
every week and then we would come back
and share our findings and our
recommendations for the program and um
that resulted in a climate change module
that was de developed for the nature
program that's a menu approach where
people can sample um and take what they
wanted to use in the program as a
speaker availability and um uh
other uh considerations were taken into
effect so for example not every year
potentially they could do a rafting trip
as part of the lesson plan but that the
menu includes that as an
option okay so um I'll just stop with
that since we only have three minutes
left but I do want to share a couple
resources if you are interested in the
work that we did um I can share looks
like I didn't see anyone weigh in on the
question in the chat but I will share
two Resources with you all one is the
handout that we gave to our participants
um to share back the data uh and the
other is that I'll share if I can share
let me see if I can share this
handout
um oh shoot I can't share but let me
just share my screen real quick and I
will just show you what it looks like
okay so this is the handout that we gave
to to um the community members and just
background on the study what was our
objective being very transparent with
what we did and very simplified results
take away from the talking circles some
key quotes connecting climate change
with capitalism Etc and then the climate
change curriculum co-creation what did
we do how did we do it and here is a
sample of what the model or mod um menu
style approach included so if you want
to
receive a example of the depth
curriculum which is this the co-creative
menu that we did with all of the
suggestions and the speakers and things
like that I'm happy to share that and
just um we'll end by saying that the one
that we developed included a lot more
activism it included a lot more
indigenous voices in the speakers and
also movies and other things that were
shared and uh it ended up with a much
more Diversified um menu of options for
the program to use especially because
it's a program that targets indigenous
people that was important to our group
so in that brief time we have one minute
left I'll go ahead and wrap up and share
it back with Jenny and with James thanks
Ros um so real quick the reason why no
one responded in the chat uh we just got
through the Q&amp;A apparently the chat
disabled for the participants or so or
for the attendees so we Dar okay thanks
yeah
um and we are getting a lot of people
interested in the uh either getting your
email for curriculum or um Jenny has
said that um we can put it uh if you
share the PDF we can share it on the um
the web uh the website for this
particular
presentation so first off thank you and
I'm getting all all of them are like I
would love to see the
curriculum yeah it looks like Jenny is
going to share it on the website so I'll
go ahead and send it to her and if you
you don't see it or um don't know where
on the website don't see it on there um
go ahead and email me and I'll send it
to you
directly and um I really do think it's
important to uh you know be putting in
perspective how we reach out to
communities I think to a large degree
we're pretty decent at reaching out to
our individual communities in a lot of
ways but it's uh really important to be
able to take into account all the
different I don't even know the proper
words for it but all the different ways
of communicating Styles as well as what
is important to our individual
communities so um I really appreciate
your
talk this has been a production of
Corell University on the web at
cornell.edu