this is a production of Cornell
University um so so when I kind of got
the invitation last year from gide and I
was like super honored but has you know
had to cancel at the last minute because
of some some unexpected healthy issues
we still kind of go through that process
um but then when I can of prepare for uh
this seminar I think is not only just a
seminar from can for the research view
is actually a pretty kind of interesting
and fun way to kind of revisit my
journey since join Cornell cuz um
believe or not um actually the first
official Cornell seminar I got invited
was from PL pass uh but dedicated in
Geneva and that's 2020 uh Kitty
mentioned you know we just started the
lab and that's the two student I have uh
one just graduated last of fall uh
actually started his own startup on
commercializing the robot he developed
and second PhD is still account of in
the pipeline and hopefully can graduate
soon sometime this fall um and then you
know 22 is really kind of a booming
stage for my lab and you can see from
three kind of people there looking at
each other most of the time just through
Zoom now we really have all of these
folks and they enjoy the inperson
activities and start to do the Synergy
as robotic sees address in many of these
Agriculture and food related issues and
last year we actually first time had
this cross lab meeting uh involving with
Kitty uh Lance and also chonun who is
also a new hire actually in food science
dedicated for technology for post
harvesting uh
evaluation um so with that I I still
want to kind of revisit that's actually
uh the the drop talk I gave at Cornell
back to 2019 and I still think this is
the kind of the key Vision we now uh not
only see that on the paper actually we
going to go through that through many of
the true products now working on daily
basis and support different uh programs
especially implant pathology um but the
basic kind of a concept is we really
want to kind of highlight using
technology as a middle layer to better
bridge between human and the
agricultural systems instead of using
you know tons of our wisdom and
knowledge and you know we can have a
technology lader to really more
quantitatively gather this knowledge and
hopefully can reserve them for many of
the future Generations in a different
way than just a writing books right and
one of the good example nowadays is like
we have all these AI systems especially
large language models and how those can
be used as a way to teach students we
Beyond cornal in my opinion that's
really kind of a passion as a
Technologies I can foresee for the
societal
benefits and then our kind of a story
really started with the food chain
solution right that's we call it a
systems engineering is it's not a
specific angle but to look at the whole
system and try to find oh what other we
weakness is there right or the aspects
to be improved and instead of putting a
lot of resources just solving a single
problem perhaps for each of these aspect
we make you know 1% better collectively
the give us not 5% but maybe 50%
improvements down the roow and and
that's really the vision there and we
kind of use the so-call multi modality
multikill sensing technology it's also
not just a ground robust where we got to
focus a lot today but we have you know
in collaboration with Lance we have the
backbird as more like a laboratory
microscopic Imaging robot that we can
gather the information really from the
web lab experiments and then translate
to the ground robot to get you know
submillimeter very high resolution
imagery and information from the
canopies of the plants in the field and
all the way to the Jone or uas based
imagery to get what the field looks like
right or what's this kind of whole
Vineyard or art looks like all the way
to how the New York State and the global
look like through the satellite remote
sensing technology and hopefully we can
also gather all this knowledge right
through from molecular all the way to
the global as well and in my opinion
that's where AI really really helpful
because we I mean as as human we have
limited power to really figure out very
complex relationships and that's really
these computational tools can help us in
the long
run and then when I kind of a look back
all right so we talk about from all the
way from breeding to pre-season inseason
post Harvest suppos Harvest Right um why
I just joined all the bottom part are
black okay so nothing there it's just a
blank page and we start fill in and in
the past four years around uh we kind of
fill in most of these major components
as I mentioned in collaboration with
Lance um and and uh in the early stage
also uh uh D garyi also from Plant
Pathology uh at Geneva uh we have this
microscopic image rubot and we actually
just um submitted a new Initiative for
USD ARS uh because the ARs kind of uh
leadership is very interested in pushing
this technology for all ARS Labs across
the country to uh do the highr
phenotyping to better understand the
plant responses to different stress um
stimulations and in the middle that's
where we do for uh not only the braiding
like we have field of Trials the
programs to evaluated their actual field
responses right to different diseases
but we also have the Drone systems that
really can be leveraged for faster and
kind of equivalently accurate sensing uh
capacity to the ground system and the
last piece actually is this new lab
scanner um G and I really work a lot
from the breeding right all the way to
how we manage the grip vines in the
field during the season and this is the
last is okay we got disease infection
for whatever reason and it the
management does not really take effectiv
this and we ended up with all these
infected GP berries and how at the last
step people can evaluate their defective
needs and really sort out the highest
quality that g still can gain the
monetary benefits rather than okay this
is a canly died one and we have no idea
how to make money from that and we just
kind of published this paper um last
year and hopefully to just continue uh
in collaboration with Terry Bas from
claro at Western New
York so that's the kind of a major thing
we have achieved but when I kind of
think about what's the vision right uh
for a roboticist to work with PL
pathology in a broader context this is a
kind of image I generated and I use I'm
a very passionated roboticist interested
in Plant Pathology question and my dream
is to help my colleague really dealing
with many of the daily scouting issues
please help me generate a figure to
demonstrate how this can be more
collaborative period That's the taex
promp it's very long but then just give
me this very beautiful image right and
that's exactly what I Vision U we still
need a lot of human pathologies in the
room to use our kind of natural
intelligence to advance the knowledge
really help people to understand this
knowledge but on the other hand we start
to have the robots to assist you as a
human
scientist again to better understand all
these interactions and hopefully to also
identify insights or any of the complex
relationships otherwise human ourself
can can not easily identify right so
when we can look at a two line of
numbers try to do regression yes we can
even manually draw the scatter P plot
and try to identify some relationship
there doesn't matter that's linear
nonlinear but when you have thousand
dimensions of the data the first
challenge to me is like okay I stop
working right the dimensionality is just
a booming and how this Ai and Robotics
technology can help us
and then there another kind of a key I I
I did not really kind of see uh B
actually would be here but I'm so
appreciate you come um because that's
kind of ir relevant also in my opinion
to a very traditional field in Cornell
called agricultural engineer and I think
many of you who are senior really know
that department used to be actually the
leader uh not only in the country but
worldwide to push for all the
agriculture
mechanization um but somehow we kind of
achieved the entries and now we're
catching up for the digital agriculture
era and one of the key thing for or
challenge for all the agricultural
engineers in my opinion is we lack
actually a solid Science Foundation to
start with okay the analog I kind of try
to compare is when you consider biom
medical
engineering versus agriculture
engineering what's the key difference
there only the study object is different
one is for human health the other is for
plant health for Plant Pathology context
right other than that this just a
similar and actually plant give us more
advantages because we can create more
samples more replicates different
genetic sources and we can leverage all
these to really Advance our
understanding about the life
mechanisms in addition to you know just
help us to U manage the human disease
which is also very important but it's
just like we have a lot of other ethical
issues that we don't want to kind of
risk ourself right so PL actually is
very advantageous um but often time the
key thing is like I don't know where I
can start with from a science point do I
have a solid science framework to guide
my engineering advancement and hopefully
use this Advanced engineering
Technologies to better understand the
science as a Clos Loop so K and I kind
of chatted a lot over the covid and this
is really the figure I want to borrow
from her because this is a kind of a
very cool starting point as an engineer
to find the Science Foundation um when
we talk about the disease many of you I
believe know more than me we have the
host we have the pathogen and then we
have the environment and somehow because
of her program entries we add the
management explicitly but I still
consider that as a part of the
environment right um from the
engineering perspective sorry Kitty um
so we started with okay let's just a
pick this three U pathogen that's a can
of a different world in my opinion and
and we're GNA just put that aside a
little bit and we're g to find some hard
time later on so this is actually the
starting point okay 2019 uh December I
heard Carell has no tradition to close
the campus Because of snow but my first
day was a heavy snow and the campus was
closed I've been told your first day
will be holiday thank you Cornell
um um so that's actually the system um
so my colleagues already used in the
field to collect a lot images and try to
better understand what's the disease
resistance response in the field and
then um we start to come up with a more
automated kind of a concept on the right
hand side and you will be laughing oh
what that small kind of a toy robot can
do but that's our starting point right
we we start to add a GPS at different
sensors and start to automate the data
acquisition
process but what is really key is two
components there right when you talk
about autonomous field scouting we need
to actually solve two problems number
one we need a navigation system right
just as the Tesla that now can drive
just on the road we need the rubot to
just derse the whole vanard or allart or
fiill autonomously without any human
interference and the second component is
how the disease will be sensed from the
images we collected so that if we put
these two together okay yeah automous
disease scouting at least as a prototype
um so this is a published work um and
here we actually use a Pure Vision u
based guidance um on the left side
that's the input image seen by the
camera from the front view and then the
the right side is actually the AI based
Det determine determine passway the
robot should go forward to derse the
whole vanard without any human
interference and surprisingly we tested
that out in different you know field
conditions it generated very well so we
collect the data actually in one Kitt uh
Vineyard in Agri Tech and we test out
that during the winter time in
California uh you different V yards in
New York and they just all work pretty
nicely okay so that give us the
confidence all right we have the
navigation capacity here and then we
build the neuron Network right um which
is a kind of a bus word nowadays uh and
to really identify where these disease
infection regions are on the images um
and we also further optimize the neural
network so that we can get it faster and
can be deployed on the robot
directly and I put in these two together
um that that's I believe oh sure why
many of you have have seen this before
while the rubot traversing through the
venard we get the input image we got
where the disease are we get the
canopies are and then we also avoid any
of the overlapping between consecutive
images right because we don't want
double count anything there and if we
aggregate them all together we can get
the uh actual disease infection
severity and the good thing is once we
have this robot right is no longer oh as
KT mentioned we need to have a group of
five or six send them all to the field
folks let's do the
scouting and after you know a week we
probably finish some kind of field
scouting and we know time is important
for Plant Pathology because disease is
not a static thing they keep developing
themselves so there are a lot of
variance there so what we found is
actually the scouting frequency is
really a right so we deploy this robot
based on a weekly basis and if we want
we can actually deploy that on daily
basis and the interesting thing is um we
oftentimes talk about asymptomatic
disease detection as the key information
for the GS to know okay I need to apply
preventive
mirors to suppress this disease pressure
right at the good starting
point and often times as symptomatic
disease detection is super
challenging um and that's really because
we have limited manpower to scale that
frequently and now with this robot can
autonomously SC the vard on a weekly
basis what we found is at the beginning
that's the map the Scot the the rubot
Gap if you can see if you can see my
cursor here and you see some of these
purple-ish blocks that's actually the
panels start to show very very early
symptom but if you look at the whole
vanard it seems like that's fine won't
really trigger any of the series
consideration but when you can of later
on all the way wait for you know three
weeks the human scouting really confirm
no you got serious disease issue and
this time window be in between is what
this rubot can really fill in right
because we don't have the limitation
because of the Manpower just deploy this
robot and you detect this map and as
early as you know just a week we we
already identify these hotspots and
hopefully if we come up with the right
management strategy we can contain them
well and avoid getting into this
situation so with that what we kind of
want to come with is let's kind of
explore further what about the frequency
of scouting can impact how the disease
management practices can be in the past
we have to wait for the scouting
Consultants coming in and tell us what
happened but now with this rubot if I do
frequently let's see push for even daily
basis what that can tell us what's the
new information we can leverage
there so the other thing I want to point
out is actually the improved scouting
sensitivity so this is a can of U
commercial vard in finger leaks region
and we are targeting to detect the g g
Leaf real virus right which has a very
obvious visual feature is like a radish
infection on Green Leaf right so that's
very kind of neat for this rubot to do
and what we found is in general the
rubot and human scouting align very well
like over 90% accuracy but for some of
the spots the rubot reported hey here if
you see this dot we got some diseases
there but human report n well interested
in oh I know the model is not perfect
and we all know model won't be perfect
but some works and then the good thing
is first our impression is not to check
all the lab note is to go back check our
database really pull out what's the GPS
information for that particular region
and then what's the corresponding raw
image look like and that's exactly we
show on the left side that's a raw image
and then we have this model inference
result on the right and we identify oh
there is a very very small portion being
labeled as jrv
infection as here and I hope the the
contrast is enough but we kind of zoom
in this region and really bring to
people and we confirm yes that's a
radish symptoms on grein Leaf so we
confirm there is
GV or can of grv infection symptom there
so that really give us the confidence
okay not only about the accuracy
absolute accuracy but also the way how
we think and how we retrieve the
information that we think might be a
surprise to our research
hypothesis and that's where this robot
can do
now so then uh we can of uh distribute
the ppb uh into different regions and
this is supported actually by the um s
Grand called vites gen 3 the third
generation uh and we have collaborators
all the way from California South Dakota
Wisconsin and Wisconsin Minnesota uh
West Virginia and of course New York we
have KY crew uh program we have madis
group uh program on group breeding and
also uh L program from the ARs
perspective um and then what we kind of
wondering is okay so we have these good
tools for our researchers and many of
them can afford that for sure right and
and we don't need to worry I mean the
only thing we need to AR is when we
going to start to get these agencies
back to function normally and we can
write Grand proposals and start to
acquire these tools for our research
routine research um but for gers the
challenge is always being around the
cost and also their return on investment
and for each of the PBB prototype uh
roughly just the building itself cost
$35,000 right and if you consider for an
entrepreneur to survive you need to at
least double that so each venor need to
pay for
$70,000 to get one
rubot I'm not sure when they can justify
the ri on their Finance balance sheet
right um but of course I don't want to
be the one to create further
disparity because of the technology
advancement that not how we've been
passionate about technology advancement
so that's a reason we just do some kind
of a brief comparison uh am of UR in
different states and we found okay
remote sensing is the only viable option
right because we have the federal
agencies like NASA to really offer
affordable or even free satellite
imageries that people can use and also
we have some other private sectors that
launch commercial satellites that will F
ultimately enable such of the thing
happening using remote sensing
technology but the question is how right
so when you consider the current remote
sensing can work largely is on one hand
we need to gather data from the air and
on the other hand we need to have the
so-called ground troops right so that
they can really build the model to
correlate the signals from your remote
sensing data set versus what we observed
from from the field and later on we can
translate or dispatch this model for the
actual uses but often times getting the
remote sensing data is no longer being
the challenge at least with all this
engineering advancement but who will be
the human power get the ground Tru
mement from the
field right you all run your field
experiments and I being very lucky have
my colleagues like kitty to run that I
know they have you know group of folks
just dedicated for ground choosing is
very tedious
laborers and no one really I wouldn't
say not really enjoy but when you
repetitively doing that then that's
where Bing starts right so our idea is
why not we can leverage our ground robot
as a source to ground troose what
happening on the ground and feed this
ground Tru data back to the satellite so
that we can build a model between the
robot generated ground tools versus the
satellite imagery so that we can have a
model but with a much affordable cost or
press tag to build
it so here is what we kind of TR um
actually last season is first we deploy
the robot in the vard right and as we
demonstrated there we can identify
different disease and generate a
geospatial map with what's their severe
there and instead of just having human
ground choosing we purely rely on this
map as the ground Cho because we know
the accuracy is pretty high and we can
confidently trust it and then we just
collect the Jone data or aircraft
hyperspectra data actually later on and
then we build a model try to see whether
or not we can use the rubot generated
ground TRS to train a model to interpret
the uev or remote sensing imagery into
disease
severity and here is what we got um the
first case is actually again a a
research vity in every teag and we use
the uev which has much higher uh special
resolution but um we use multispectral
Imaging which we have less spectral
information and what we found is
actually when the can of disease
approaching to is a peak time or end
time the accuracy or the correlation
between the human uh the rubot generated
ground Truth versus the uh remote
sensing or U signal is really high and
we can push for a model of accuracy
about 80% that would be really useful
because you don't need to really rely on
kind of a um very time consuming human
scouting in the field you can actually
bro this um model and then just fly the
Drone with the hope we can deliver 80%
accuracy quote unquote um so that the G
can really use a faster speed to know
what is happening in the field right but
we all know what is kind of not really
good for multispectral Imaging is it
lacks of certain spectral resolution
that can really resolve the signal
relevant to the disease infection or the
disease
itself so that's the reason we Leverage
The hyp spectral technology um but
before we kind of getting into build a
model what we do is first as a data
person I really want to have a very
solid statistic evidence to show yes the
DAT based on the data intrinsics they
are separable so what we do is we use
both human field scouting as a ground
troose and also rubot field scouting at
the ground shoose and then we label all
the pixels from the REM sensing data set
and try to see what's the separation
power between healthy and infected
plants and what we found is actually the
rubot is not only on par but actually
give a little bit more statistical power
in generating the separation between
healthy and infected plants through the
hyperspectral data okay to me that's a
really kind of exciting thing because
then we have the solid foundation to
build a
model and here is just a you know
highlight of that particular region and
you can see for the human the mean to
mean is almost very close to each other
and if you consider the standard
deviation that just created a challenge
for the modeling itself but when you
look at the bottom part that's where the
ground truth is from the rubot you start
to see clear kind of a separation even
between the two
means so that that give us additional
power to believe the model should get
improved so with that we just build the
model and uh of course uh we can of a
tested out on that hyperspectral imagery
uh collected by the aircraft uh and 5%
Improvement um so we are still kind of
waiting for more data for from the
coming season and try to see if this is
a solid 5% Improvement or it could be
just a variation by Nature right and it
is hard to tell at this point but at
least give us a very prom missing
results from the data analytics
perspective and of course you know with
that as we kind of uh discussed what's
the motivation there right is really to
have a skillable solution that everyone
can afford to use Advanced Technologies
and that's the comparison very easy okay
a group of four to five people do the
human scouting for this venard that's
actually a venard out in California um
takes a week and with the rubot we need
several hours to run the rubot
autonomously there I mean although you
don't need to think oh I don't need to
Traverse there how much power robot can
consume based on the current regulatory
in California and actually most of the
states in the US you need to follow the
self-driven car traffic policy for
having autonomous robot running in your
field
that's I did not get understand about
that part but that's what we've been
regulated okay so I have brought that up
to actually many of the New York
legislator lators and hopefully they
start to discuss what would be the
policy from New York to really Embrace
this technology and being like aead of
other states or even the world about
this new regulatories for autonomous
equipment in agriculture
and last is actually the the NASA
average you know data acquisition just
the whole
region and then it take seven minutes to
run the model yes you get it okay so
that's really the difference in terms of
how soon we can get and how large the
region we can cover in terms of using
remote sensing plus with all these rout
Technologies
together so up to this point I would say
okay we have the autonomous disease
scouting
uh we have the disease detection models
by supervisor learning so if you work on
machine learning this is the way like a
human need to explicitly tell the answer
what this is to the model so the model
can learn what it is okay the pen is
like we need human labels and I know
many of you don't want to do that um and
then we have a proof of concept
skillable scouting from the field to the
region levels through this ground to
Arrow branch of this close loop
analysis but what is missing there right
is actually looking at this map that's
how we distribute our rubot across the
country is actually the model
generalized capability which is also a
key for many of these AI research is the
model train on one data set whether or
not I can rely on for many of unseen
data sets in the
future and what we did is okay instead
of just rely on the image itself which
give us the V feature we leverage the
multimodal models so we use the language
as a
regulator because that's how many of us
as a human pathologies really kind of
communicating because I'm learning from
you and I'm not kind of learning from
you to point all the pixels on the
images seeing hey that's the PO M
infection that's Don M infection that's
your RV I've been told just when you
look at the p m that's a widish layer on
top of the leaf and you need an acute
angle to look at that so you can really
see it clearly that's how we really
learn and that's what we really want to
push for AI technology is why not to use
text description as a way to tell the
model what is the feature looks like in
the image so that combining both the
image as a v inputs and the text as
another inputs the model actually can
get better performance
so here is just a quick thing to show um
with this improvements U we got a much
higher accuracy as compare with uh the
Baseline model in the middle and also
another kind of a large foundational
model called Sam I think many of you
also use that maybe um so get some
improvements there so that really
demonstrate yes our hypothesis is
correct and when you try to use
additional modality or the modality
information and the overall model
performance will be boosted because the
model is really trying to learn some of
the knowledge rather than the
superficial you know pixel
relationships so then what we want to
test is not just for the New York right
um we talk about the model generalized
capability and that's our Target what
about we just pick one data set from
California and this is the totally un
that that we have no idea what's going
on and if you look at all these images
the even us using different scoring
system than what we use in New York
their training system is different and
you see each group one is a very buy
canopy and being very well separated as
compare as a panel like a whole panel of
leaves in New York right and how the
model going to
perform that's the first thing we got
just a deros shot which means we TR our
model only using the New York data set
done modeling part is done and we
directly Ed that model infer the disease
infection on the California data sets
and that's what we found actually across
two years from 23 and 24 so this is the
error distribution remember they have
the scoring system from zero to six
right a z to five six different levels
and in the middle line that's agreement
with no scaring category difference at
all and then when you look at the
overall distribution maximum difference
category IAL difference would be just a
one level either minus one or plus one
and this is very consistent through two
years of this testing and we are very
happy about that um so that demonstrate
okay these models are generalizable but
what's the next is actually Several Hard
Times get ready so the first thing we
are kind of thinking is at the beginning
from the project people are more
interested in or concerning whether or
not the rubot can detect very low
incident cases right because they are
very challenging for Compu Vision but
what we found actually from the C
California data set is no actually the
model handle those low incidence cases
pretty good I would see but more
problematic with high incidence and this
is understandable because for many of
the Breeders or even PL pathologist
after certain stret cold you g just see
no that's a useless thing I got just
give whatever score there right
regardless that
really 55% or 75% or 95% I all call them
score five right so that really being
the key challenge um but is actually
good thing because our model actually
give better percentage quantification
rather than just a
scaring the second aha moment is okay
now we have really disease progression
right is as I mentioned it's not just a
single time point we can frequently
deploy that on weekly basis and we can
generate this disease progression curve
and as a data scientist I'm lazy right
and I lack of the be honest yeah and I
lack of certain PL pathology knowledge
so what I do is really from the data
perspective that's just a WR clustering
algorithm and see what we can learn from
these disease Progressive curves and
very surprising we found a can cluster
if you see starting with adding uh four
clusters there there is a bottom Blue
Line showing consistently very low
disease infection symptoms there right
so from the breeding perspective that's
exactly the group we want to identify
because they really give a very strong
resistance to the disease in the natural
environment and that's what we really
want to kind of um find using big data
right because then breeding is a number
game in my opining the more numbers we
put in the the kind of higher likelihood
we're going to get something useful
and this is really enable us to put more
and more and more numbers there and to
really enhance our possibility of
getting the right materials for
different environment or different
desires aha moment three is
actually okay so we compare right we
have this progression curve but how that
can of compare among different years so
what we usually kind of expect is
actually the left side right if it this
is the genotype with certain disease
resistant genes kind of stacked there we
expect it demonstrate also high
resistance to any of the pathogen like
for example this is for po M right but
actually through the data analysis we
found the right side
case that particular genotype also have
a stack of resistant genes but the why
in one year is behave very normal right
if you look at the um blue and red lines
that's actually the data from 23 but
when you look at the uh black lines
that's the data from 24 it got kind of
infected a lot by par
muu right and that really give us a new
science question what
happened that's a part bring back this
chart right so we discussed about all
the plan environment management but what
we lack is what's the interaction from
the pathogen
point of view right there are so many
isolate and we know the mutant risk is
very high for this m BS right and how
that being considered so far in the
whole breeding cycle or whole management
cycle and now our new tools really
enable us to do that and actually that
right case if you look at here is kind
of overcome by a specific isolate of
ping modu only identified in California
not in New York okay but it might be a
matter of time when it can't be here so
with that um we have some new chapters
to ongoing right we have affordable
scalable solution especially now we want
to bridge the the the um closed loop
from the arrow to the ground right rubot
are very neat but they are so expensive
and how to strategically deploy them
into different places that can help the
remote sensing model even being better
than nowadays so that's our next
question and also is a economic question
now this actx sector being soly focused
in California which I understand why but
is this the right way to allocate all
the resources
there and how to strategically really
expand and reallocate these resources
both help the gers to combat their
production kind of challenges but also
help these startup companies gain
economic benefits and hopefully that can
also boost Regional economy because of
the Technology
Innovation and then of course with this
new approach we start to add passing
back in the whole thing right then we
really have four components there try to
identify their complex relationships and
we hope to review more and the last part
is a um participatory research approach
uh we talk about this Hightech but my
heart goes with people and where we are
right now and that's actually ongoing
effort from my student supported by NASA
we call it the pharmacology Network and
basically is if everyone doesn't matter
if you are a grer or not can contribute
a cell phone image with a specific
guidance that would allow us to build AI
models to better understand Regional
level thing without much of a pressure
lacking of data um so I hope to share
more maybe in the coming years or two um
but so far everyone we reach out is very
excited about this approach because they
now feel being part of Agriculture
rather than oh yeah I'm just a buyer of
the Agricultural
produces period right so if you are part
of something then you start to generate
the different motivation and passion so
with that i g to acknowledge for all
these funding agencies programs to
really support all this wonderful work
and also thank everyone in actually the
beginning you know
from the four Labs who you know made
significant contributions otherwise I
won't give the talk here today with that
I hope I still have some time to take
questions
thanks
yeah I was just curious um you said said
that the robot was around
$35,000 now I think did you compare with
how much it costs for the ground TR by
humans what does it cost for
that so
the the question is um the rubot cost
$35,000 uh and what's the cost for human
Scouting For the equivalent coverage
right and
accuracy that's a great question and we
did not really do a very precise
calculation on that kind of a category
because largely we tested mostly for the
research venur and that's being paid by
K's program I'm not sure how much
dollars you put for that but I guess
that's a kind of significant portion of
your program right being hired people
and doing that so I would consider rubot
still might be cheaper right might be
cheaper in my opinion but again
technology itself the rubot itself is
there right but so far we need the
operator to learn what is
Linux um how many of you use Linux on
daily
basis right yeah okay I I saw several
people and there are some kind of a
troubleshooting skills we need for the
operator right if what what if something
happen and and how you can really
quickly put the robot back in function
so those are steep learning maybe not
steep but at least some learning curves
there to prepare a new Workforce and
that's the reason why through my
extension actually we put a lot of
efforts now try to um distribute needed
training materials for the gers but at
the same time working with different
sectors try to lever or um create the
Synergy to build the new Workforce
Development programs especially you know
with Cornell as a so unique position
with all of these
aspects did the math real quick so for
just the training data for the whole
season it was approximately $112,000 for
like sub one acre so as soon as you're
using the robot in its current condition
over three acres you're
netting POS
and that doesn't count like
indirect oh yes was
better a followup question to bills
about cost of the robot it also relates
to resolution of the
satellite and relates also to like the
potential of the imaging technology
Precision agiculture so unless I'm
mistaken a lot of Growers are in their
fields on regular basis driving their
equipment how much of the cost of the
robot is
navigation right and relative to image
acquisition data analysis take the guts
of the robot and put it on the tractor
right and make something and is the
image analysis fast it's just a
realistic goal so that you put it on the
front of the tractor and the images are
analyzed by the time the back of the
tractor passes then this nozzle comes on
off so let me summarize your question is
like how about to translate some
components from the current rubot
prototype into the existing agricultural
machineries so that we can lower down
the operation cost while still taking
advantage of all this advanced
technology right okay great and that's a
great suggestion uh and I'm I agree with
you 100% about that and I'm not sure if
you notice when we distribute the the
robots to different places we do not
distribute the whole product type we
actually take out the the Imaging kind
of a component or model and really
distribute that part because when we
consider autonomous scouting right
autonomous is one thing that's more like
about navigation and people may not
really enjoy or like need that like a
$15,000 each navigation model but they
much more like the you know $20,000
Imaging model with analysis capacity
right and I agree with you then we can
attach to ATV tractor any of the egg
equipment nowadays we can easily find in
the venard or alard or other kind of
farms so that people can start to gain
the benefits um one thing I want to kind
of highlight is actually the the
analysis power right or or the speed or
turnaround time of getting the raw data
to the result The Growers can use or
researchers can use is getting much
faster uh and my personal kind of a
vision is to this thing is going to
improve infinitely right and even for
our current robot is running on a near
real time term which means as soon as
the camera taking one image the analysis
model finish the inference at the same
time and then you will just keep
continue so at the end of the scanning
of the robot we also start to have the
map of the where the diseases are in
that kind of a particular field and is
all Geor referen so then back to our
last point point that really kind of
enable us for many of these preceding
management practices right and then we
can use for Target spray or even you
know using the current fan base that
that still cance a lot of chemicals
which is also a concern right now but in
the long run I would see having this
rubar might also help us to manage the
soil problems in the long run because
the large egg equipment cause a lot of
soil compaction and there is no kind of
a good solution right that might be an
additional motivation and also because
of the cost if that's kind of a compact
system Growers may just a share that
unit and just load on their trailer and
walk around so several people can just
buy one rather than every of them will
buy
one yeah I hope I answer your question
you more comprehensive with yeah um yeah
yeah yes yes so are you able to
differentiate different diseases
great question that's a wonderful
question um so at the beginning we
solely focus on either Donnie or poy or
gr and last year for that kind of
sensitivity slice if you still remember
rubot is better kind of identified a
small spot that's a actually a mixture
of Donnie and uh gr RV so we will be
able to differentiate that but largely
my kind of personal opinion is is I
really use human pathology as the
standard what human can do let's don't
really kind of consider more advanced
sensing Technologies because that always
give us advantages right but let's step
back you and I just have this naked eye
just the you know uh for the visible
range to see all these things in our
world but with your knowledge you still
still be able to differentiate a lot of
these things and my current goal is how
we can push rubas and AI to achieve that
first and of course if we can achieve
that with Advanced sensing modeles with
additional information chain everything
G to be just boost
naturally I could as well so a lot of
people from my group who spent a lot of
time training a robot um in particular
my field research manager da holes who's
forgotten more about disease management
that I think any of us would really hope
to know um the robot the new model is
just good at looking at its imagery as
he is now so it's there's still room
like you know him in the field P head
like sticking his head in the vine like
being there but like looking at the
imagery they're CL I think that gets to
use point where it's like the
human you want to repeat that to the
zoom audience oh yeah for for whom on
Zoom what Kitty kind of add in is now
the rubot is as good as
her very longterm and a wonderful
technician Dave come uh with like a 30
years of experience about the disease in
grip
ones thanks so much for the
comment oh um oh yes sorry I forgot that
yeah yes and
yes is the uh the ground Imaging
dependent fair weather days or is it
restricted by very bright days like post
rain Bo overhead irrigation Two Face
limits like that yeah the the the
question is whether or not the robot
being limited by environment conditions
like the sunlight or varying you know U
conditions so uh great question so far
the only kind of enemy for the robot is
the severe weather events like a very
windy very snowy very rainy I cannot run
that because nothing is you know
weatherproof but other than that um so I
did not introduce more on the sensing
side but we use active illumination
to combat the sunlight so the camera
does not rely on the natural light to
provide the information it's actually
rely an artificial light so that only
that light provide the illumination and
that's how we really uh try to control
the data quality consistency and
actually also boost the AI model for the
generalized capability so it serves for
both purpose and it can run day and
night yes yeah U my question was about
what powers the robot and like it's a
charge like how long can it go without
beting a charge like I'm thinking if
it's in the middle of a Vineyard it
might be hard to go back and and charge
it so yeah so the question is uh about
the B battery consumption or the power
consumption and charging time for the
robot um so so far for the robot it can
constantly run about three hours for one
charge and usually we feel that's kind
of sufficient to cover he is two acres
field per charge um but of course you
know we are upgrading all the platform
and with the Improv The Battery
Technology and I know at Cornell we have
a lot of researchers on you know energy
side we hope actually to further improve
that down the
row
yes oh oh I miss that let me open that
oh there are several messages on the
zoom sorry folks just open that um first
comment from Gary very exciting PR
missing research well communicated
thanks thanks Gary for you
um second from Edwin uh I'm wondering
what is the maximum height that robot
can extend can it work on hops up to six
six meter tall um so add that's a great
question so so far so it's not on this
kind of a rubot based platform platform
we have a new one and that one can be
used for apples um although for a
different purpose not for disease at the
moment it's more like for its 3D
structure um for the digital twin
purpose um so I would say six Metter
might be okay it depends on the base
right everything is down to the
mechanical designing whether or not it's
stable and also a challenge for New York
forever is our kind of um terrain
situation uh if that's in our Washington
California with a super flat field I
would see oh yeah let's just do that but
now with New York we have all these
slopes D all these things um I I think
it's kind of a very Case by case at this
moment but I I think in general six
meter would be okay yeah hope to answer
your question um next from Luke do you
think it will be on the individual
farmer to buy into this remote sensing
technology to use it or do you foresee
that there will be a subscription
service perhaps where a company will
have a fleet of drones Rovers sensors
extra and be able to work with Farmers
to do the data capture to data
processing uh and make recommendations
on decision making uh one for question
look so that's also my feeling uh I I
don't really have a very strong opinion
either way you know um but I think both
can work and I see definitely both work
because for many of the pilot Growers
who kind of run very large vure generate
tons of the revenues their only question
is how I can maintain that right by
saving money that that's their kind of a
first priority and I wouldn't see they
would be hesitated if this is the proved
technology they going to invest on that
and then really use that on daily basis
but of course then down to small to
mediumsized Farmers that's a totally
different word and sometimes even asking
for you know $500 subscription fee can
be a glitchy question there right so I
definitely foresee both business model
could wrong and I think the best way is
let's just explore and see how these
things go naturally um because in my
opinion what we bring in for this Clos
Loop um framework is to let the pilot
and the large GRS to actually help the
small to medium siiz Farmers because
largely the training data set going to
be contributed by them
and then the knowledge can be translated
to the other group who might not be able
to afford this advanced technology at
the moment okay um last from Don hi you
for virus detection the best use for
remote sensing might be in the nursery
do you have any plans to use the robot
or Imaging models in a commercial grip
Nursery wonderful question uh Donna uh
maybe you can just shoot me an email
let's just chat after this seminar um
sounds like a very interesting use case
scenario yeah that's what I got from
Zoom all right thanks
everyone this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu