this is a production of Cornell
University thank you we thank you
everyone for joining me today to discuss
my research um and uh uh well I try to
be make it a little bit different uh
with the previous talk that I recently
gave uh at Cornell so um today we'll
focus a little bit more on applications
so at you can tell from the title
monitoring plant stress through water
use perspective using remote sensing and
cloud
computing and I think you know this is
really um nice day to give a seminar
talk is a Halloween and also a special
India F Festival day so um and for for
the Halloween we have like a check or
treat it's the same for our environment
to do treat well otherwise you know it
can get spooky right so um as we all
know that the projected population in
2050 will be a large amount of
population so we also need increase our
food production to feed this increased
population and uh when we do that we
really need to assess how the current
agriculture model Works to help us
achieve achieve both the food security
and also the environmental goal so study
is indicated as the first figure here
that with the current agriculture model
you know we could somehow get less for
the food security goal but our impact on
environment could be large and this is
not what we want to see so to transition
this from the top scen scario to the
second scenario with that we achieve the
goal for both security food security and
also environmental goal I think we
really need to have innovation in
agriculture management to help us as you
can also tell that water is a large
component from the agriculture
impact and this impact could be further
compounded by the draw
and with the draw events it's getting so
hard to predict and also the draw start
to show up in areas that historically
don't experience drot so this is the US
jot monitor on the top for the conus and
on the second panel here is for the uh
New York State um as we can tell
although New York State we don't really
have those very severe draw which is the
dark red color we do have draw and the
draw tends to happen more frequent and
if you zoom into a certain time period
and look at when the draw happens for
each of the year you can tell
that the the lines in this figure here
they are July for each year so this
shows that draw tends to happen during
the growing season and when the crop the
plants needs the water to grow so
for not just agriculture for natural
resource for natural environment water
just so critical uh because they could
eat too much water too less water both
extreme can be harmful for agriculture
and for our natural environment so with
like especially when we have draw plant
doesn't have enough access to the water
they start to be showing the stress
signal and this stress could um making a
lot of other effect to develop other
other than just a draw there will be a
disease The Pest and also this
eventually will impact the yield and
also for natural Forest it will impact
the forest e ecosystem serving functions
so for now people like with remote
sensing we can start to monitoring
General Trends um and with this this is
a USD USD Force service model that they
use ndvi to try to find the stress
signals because if you find the stress
signal then you can start to think about
how you want to treat the
stresses but one question here is ndbi
is showing like basically how green your
land surface is but when the plant is
under stress it doesn't necessary to
change Cotter or to stretch their leaves
as the first response to the stress um
so here we are really eager to look for
an earlier signal that can tell us the
stress before the leaf turns to yellow
or before the leaves start to drop so
eval transpiration this is a process
that um the water goes the water go
through the plant and return back to the
atmosphere and it uses the same path as
a stomata we is a similar pass as the
carbon assimilation so what we've think
before the we' change color we will see
a signal of water use change and which
could be earlier signal for stress
detection so talk a little bit more
about uo transporation is actually two
term together one is evaporation another
one is transporation so for evaporation
as you can tell is the water returns
back to the atmosphere from different
surfaces while the transpiration is the
more biological part of the water use
which is go through which is the B water
that P extract from the soil then return
that back to the atmosphere so combining
these two we call the we call these
processes together as U transporation
and this is the second largest component
in the hydrological cycle of course the
first one is the
precipitation um and when we talk about
uo transporation actually historically
this is a parameter is hard to measure
and it's hard to model um especially if
you consider the difference between
potential ET and actual ET so a lot of
previous studies we use potential ET we
use weight per pressure deficit um
that's uh because it was just easier to
to to calculate from the meterological
parameters however there's key differ
difference between this two um
terminology so the potential ET is the
ideal condition and how much water can
be returned back to the atmosphere so as
you can tell if we it's it's sunny if
it's windy and if it's dry you would
expect a higher potential ET because the
atmosphere just needs a lot of water so
this is the
demand which is mostly for the potential
ET part but whether we can provide that
much water to return back to Atmosphere
so that's the limitation combining both
the demand and the limitation together
is the actual eapo transporation so for
the the limitation part we need to
consider whether we have enough water in
the soil to support this and whether the
vegetation is health and the stomata is
all open ready to do the
transporation and also how rough the
surface is the soil surface and also the
canopy surface all these can impact
actual uo transpiration which is the AET
so today I will talk about the AET and I
will go through the methods that we um
we improved developed improved and also
so the product that we developed and
also applications so first we'll talk
about the
algorithm for the actual uo
transporation of course there are you
know now with machine learning there are
a lot of methods there are uh this um
process based model and it can be also
machine learning data driven model and
here what I'm going to talk about is
energy balance model so why is energy
balance think about you know like in
physics there are actually a lot of
assumptions is the balance Mass
conservation you know energy
conservation so um the energy balance
method is we assume the net radiation we
get like the energy we get on the
Earth's surface it will be petitioned to
three energy
components one is how much energy is
stored in the soil and another part is
how much energy is used to change the
air temperature like when you feel is
hot outside it's cold outside that's a
sensible heat and then the rest of that
is latent heat which is the energy used
to transfer the water from the soil or
water surface back to a waer condition
so which is the part of the energy that
is used for eaper
transporation so in a lot of this energy
balance models we actually calculate
this latent heat which is the L term
there uh as a residual of this system
because um it's just so hard to directly
estimate it um so here I'm showing you
one of these energy balance model which
is called Alexi dis Alex model and this
is the model that that have been um work
on since my postal and it was developed
by my postal weather and for this model
it actually has two components one
component is on the course resolution
which is a Lexi model the reason we have
this is because
to have this energy closure we need to
have a system that you can consider the
closure right so to consider this system
we need the atmospheric boundary layer
condition so that's the hard part to get
so that we rely on the geostationary
data which is the weather forast
satellite in the space because it's it's
course resolution but it's very frequent
so from that we can grab the information
of the atmospheric boundary layer
development information then we can have
a closed system to consider the energy
balance so for the course resolution
part one key input is land surface
temperature so this goes to the cooling
effect of Ule transporation um is I
always like to to use this example as
you know in the hot summer days when you
sweat actually your skin is cooler and
this is the same for vegetation
transpiration if you have water
transferred back to Atmosphere it uses
the energy so it has the cooling effect
your Leaf surface will be cooler so
that's why land surface temperature is a
very important parameter that we use in
the model other than that we also need
to know the condition of land surface
which we use vegetation index so we know
where the the vegetation is and where we
know the bare soil is so that we can
estimate e and t because e is from
different surfaces and T is from the
fence so that's the course resolution
and for the final spal resolution we
call it a disaggregation of Alexi so
which is this Alexi so for for dxi we
borrow this air T air estimation for the
boundary condition that we estimated
from Alexi and use that in the dis Alexi
but change the land surface and
vegetation index uh land surface
temperature and vation indexing input to
a finer special resolution satellite
data which now we use lens set eost
stress and we so these are different
satellites in the space so now you can
see this is really uh hierarchical
structure that involves satellite data
from different spatial resolution and
for satellite data normally if it's
different uh spatial resolution it's
different in temporal resolution the
temporal resolution meaning is how often
it comes back to the same place we also
call this as revisiting timee so
combining all these different satellites
together uh we can estimate eapo
transporation at different spatial and
temporal resolution normally closer
spatial resolution has more frequent
revisiting and finer spatial resolution
has a longer revisiting
time so as you can tell that for a a lot
of agriculture
applications what we need is high in
both in both spatial resolution and in
both in temporal resolution so that's
why we came up with a data Fusion method
then we can combine the advantages of
high frequency from course resolution
data and the uh High special resolution
uh observations from those satellite
that they don't have a very frequent
revisit time so combining all this we
want to get a daily field scale uo
Transportation
estimation so I will give a little bit
more about this data Fusion like
multisource data um system because I
want to guess a little bit new in new
things in my slides that I didn't talk
in my interview uh talk and also another
talks so this is a different sources of
land surface
temperature as we identified that land
surface temperature is really important
input for our energy balance model so
these are the satellite that we are
currently using which the first is G
stationary one is the go data the
weather satellite for the uh United
States modes and we is polar orbit polar
orbit means they that go through um uh
the the polar part so that's the modus
and we the spal resolution is 500 meter
but is daily risi and lset lanet has
been a really um golden observations for
us working on field scale because it
provides 30 m uh spal resolution and all
but the revision time is relatively
longer because it's 16 days but now we
have two lens set in the space lens at 8
and lens and nine so combining these two
together we can get the revisiting time
to eight days and then the ISS orbit is
the ecost stress sensor ecost stress is
a thermal only sensor so it only
measures um the land surface temperature
is on the International Space Station um
it because it is on the International
Space Station so it goes to a very
different orbit the revisiting time is
about 4
days and also considering like in the
future we also have multiple uh sensors
that is planned in the future for
example the Trish from European um and L
next which will be launched in 2030
which uh is will be launched by NASA and
hosted by USGS
so why we need all these data together
this is a simple uh like identification
of uh these different
data their frequency and this area
actually is for California California is
already clear during green season um and
you would see a more added value
actually for a cloudy area so for the
first one is lens set eight and nine
which is the key input currently for a
lot of operational product of V then
Sentinel 2 is the European satellite
which doesn't have thermal observation
so it doesn't measure land surface
temperature but we can get vegetation
index from Sentinel and eost stress is
thermal only it's just a measure lens of
temperature so combine these all
together we can see a lot of more
samples that we can get over a growing
season which can help us to better
estimate eapa transpiration because if
you don't have satellite observations
you can only do is interpolate between
the two days that you have observation
uh which is not ideal the ideal
condition is we can get observation for
um each day but there will be a long
long way to go um and also comparing
with the lanet and Eco stress this is
how many clear images that we can use
for a year this is in
2022 um with darker color is more images
over that area so you can see lens set
really have limited images and combining
with Eco stress they're a lot more so
the difference is we use eal the the
number of Eco stress minus the number of
lens set so we can get the number how
many more images we can get so the
question is okay so we have all these
satellite observations and there will be
more in the future whether you can
directly use them together
um actually not because they are so
different they the key differ is the
spatial resolution is different so as
you can tell that lens at 8 eal stress
and wears this is the relatively the
image from the sensor and it get course
and course so what we want is field
scale and if you look at the we sta you
don't really tell the field anymore so
what we need to to do is we need to
first to unify the land surface
temperature from different sensors and
here we use the data mining sharpener
which is a machine learning based method
for the land surface temperature
uh which we can sharpen the course
resolution of land surface temperature
to a field scale then we can put this as
input into our model to estimate field
scale U
transporation okay so now with all these
you know stellite method uh energy
balance what we actually want to get is
a 30 m daay evap transpiration
estimation so that we can use it for
different applications so now we are
going to start with some applications
because uh this talk will focus on the
plant stress detect I will use our vard
work at California as example to
demonstrate how we detect PL stress
using U Transportation data so this is
the gack project which is a
collaboration between NASA G gallo and
USDA so the Project Lead um is Bill
custas and uh and also Mara Anderson who
my co viser um so this is a project that
we have been working on for many years
actually um and these are the sites that
we selected they are EG Gallow vard and
for each of the sit we have observation
capabilities the instrument flux to
final Camp all this observations built
in this
sides and we evaluate our modeled U
transporation for each of the site by
comparing with the flex Tower
observations so here uh it can give us
confidence how we can further use the
model of the U transporation so you can
tell that the the Dots here observations
and the red line is our simulated daily
30 m field scale ET which performs very
well and other than just look at how it
works for these flux Tower we can also
look at the spatial pattern so this is
the ET the cumulative ET for the spard
area and start from the uh the the start
of the green season and all the way to
the peak of the green season so you can
tell how these different field they
start start to use a different amount of
irrigation over the year and also um
these are the the vineyard and there
also like the natural uh trees over
there uh so it's very uh useful for The
Growers that they can look at this
spatial map to understand how the
different water is used then how this
water use can be transferred to a stress
signal
so we actually using a very simple
anomaly method so the anomaly normally
Compares with a baseline right so if you
have a long-term observation you know
the Baseline and for each of the they
the data comes you can compare that ET
value with the Baseline and that can
give you a signal of stress but here we
are not actually directly compare the ET
value because
it changes a lot it's not just impacted
by the plant itself a lot of actually is
impacted by the weather right today and
tomorrow the plant won't change much but
you probably see the ET change a lot if
today is sunny and tomorrow is cloudy U
so we normalize the eapa transformation
use the reference ET to remove this
day-by-day difference of um the the uh
weather condition then we use this ratio
to calculate the F anomaly so this is
the index that we use to capture the
stress
um so this is the one example of one of
the venard is the on the top is this F
value um the red line is our model the
black dots are the
observations we can use these data to
look at these abnormal values and when
you compare this abnormal values with
the uh the far the the vineard
management you will see all these
differences comparing with the normal
condition uh sometimes it's due to the
drought as you can tell the California
drought sometimes is due to the
management for example this is a time
period reared that the graph and the
trimed so this is we use this um anomaly
index to help us identify what's
different comparing with the
Baseline so with this we can look at you
know the spatial pattern of water used
for different years among different
monsters and then when we use this value
to minus as the Baseline we can clearly
tell which part is not performing as
supposed to be so this is different as
of what Baseline tell use that the red
color means it's lower than the Baseline
which gave you a signal of either you
know the plant needs water because they
are using less amount of water or there
is also a signal that there might be
some kind of dis disase or pest for
those field that impacted the plant
water use then throwers can use this map
to look at to the field to look at the
field for further management so GPX is a
large project I'm a part of it um and
what is very excited is actually just uh
this Tuesday and Wednesday um the a few
leaders of the grx project visited us
and kitty gold from hotic culture um and
me we've together hosted them at Geneva
campus so as you can tell Bill kustas
Martha Anderson Joe alfy um are here to
visit our Geneva venard site and this is
also part of my new research that I want
to bring the G par experience to our uh
New York Vineyard grower
and to see under different climate
conditions with different uh uh
varieties of groups how much we learned
from gacks can help the growers in New
York so uh stay tuned hopefully next
time I will have some results for this
and we are planning a flux Tower over
one of Kitt's field site so she has the
disease measurement um and I will have
the water and carbon flux measurement uh
collectively I think we will have a lot
of interesting
findings okay so uh other than the the
the crops actually we also I also did a
lot of work for natural Forest um but
because of time I'm not going to to talk
about this in detail but we did use this
water use information to help us to
understand Plantation management the
thinning harest these are all the
signals that you can find from water use
and these are all published papers if
you're interested you can look at them
and look at Missouri Forest draw impact
um and also how the forest compositions
management impact different water use
and also the uh restoration of uh
different kinds in the Southeast area
which is a large conservation effort in
sou East and now and also Wildfire
impact over the uh west of us so these
are the The Works that we have published
so now you can tell that you know we
spend a lot of time to explore how we
can use this data and when people start
to adapt to this method there's new
issue is how we can provide people the
data because this is very compal
um resource
intensive so for a local server we
cannot estimate large aere so that's why
the ear a few earlier studies you can
tell they are just limited with small
aere because just we cannot run it for a
large area so how we can provide this
Regional data to people are interested
so this is another key project that I
also have been worked on for multiple
years and I'm super excited to see how
this project turned to so this is open
ET project it started with a a lot of
collaboration efforts from different
government agencies and
universities and actually at that
time we started to think how we can
provide this data to the end users not
just in the scientific community
so what we did is we bring we brought
our model into the cloud which is the
Google engine so we use we we integrated
six different ET models into engine then
we can directly do all the estimations
in the cloud nothing need to be done
locally everything is in the cloud and
the results are saved in the cloud and
to e to make the the accessible of the
the data we also developed a website
which is this
open.org um and you can look at the
water use from different fields and we
also developed the API that people can
directly download images and time series
do a little bit more Advanced Data
extraction so the six models that we
have is these wellestablished six models
and Alexa dxi was one of them um and we
also have a another emble value because
a lot of times users they don't need six
values especially when these six values
are all different so they want one value
which is emble so we also like studied a
lot how to get to this emble value and
we went through careful evaluation and
the evaluation results turned out that
Ensemble actually performs the best
which is also what we want to see um and
we also have published
another uh evaluation paper that was
published earlier this year um on nature
water which is also the C page and uh
from this study we evaluated our open
product comparing with different flx
Towers all all across the conus so um
the that paper have very detailed
information about the performance of
different models and the performance
models at different locations um so now
we have the ET data we are still uh like
work very hard to expand this to the
east um so now I think it we have a
little bit more but uh didn't get to the
New York state yet and and this is where
the multisource data could be very
helpful for the next stage because we
all know the EAS us is cloudier than the
Western us and we will need more
satellites to work on this and this is
the if you get to the open website you
can zoom into the website we already
have build field boundary there you can
look at the water use for each of the
field um and currently we have data from
2016 to present I think and also we have
this API there you can use it to
download data if you're interested to
explore in a certain area we are also
building this Farms Tool uh to use this
Farms tool farmers can bring their own
boundary shape file into the platform so
that they can get routinely report of
their Fields water use um so I I do see
there's limited of time um and but I
also want to show you that with the open
we are not limited to small areas we can
do Regional studies but still keep this
fine spatial resolution um this is a
study that my PhD student she is
currently working on look at Lower
Mississippi Alou PL agriculture
activities and how these activities
impact the water use so this is the
study area and along the Miss River you
can see it's a highly cultivated area
and we did we use the open data to
analyze the like for these different
crop types soybean is a green color corn
coton and rice uh how these different
crops use different amount of water um
and here we can get a very typical uh
plant water use curve so this is aage
from out cor years which agrees a lot
with what we uh observed in the field
that the yellow Lin corn it shows a
higher water use during the first stage
of the the green stage and the coton
doesn't need that much water so this is
what we get statistically from the open
data um and we can also look at how
these we can look at the water
accounting for this
region the same as you know you
understand your bank account we also
want to understand the water account how
much water we use at different locations
and how much water is extracted from
groundwater the groundwater information
is this scue bar that uh shows all
negative value the negative value is
like is always withdraw so that's also
explains why this area we see a
consistent groundwater depletion and for
these draw years we do see a higher uh
groundw withdraw uh to maintain the
agriculture activity over this area and
again we can also look at the spatial
pattern for like different area they
tend to use different amount of water
over a green season so this is the same
area starts from May all the way to
August on the top is leaf area index and
the the second panel is the U
transporation which is the water use um
so I will try to go quick because this
will be something I'll will further work
on is very high resolution ET because 30
m sometimes can be limited for specialty
C alter um like the specialty crops this
is the vard um the from KT is
field that we do need uh like finer
spatial resolution details and part of
my group's work is using UAV data so we
fly drones to collect images then we can
really get very detailed information on
the ground this is the two site fully
irrigated and deficit site and you can
see how these are input be different and
this is our U transporation estimation
the first one uh you can also tell how
different the uo transportation use for
the fully irrigated deficit they are
next to each other but they are very
different so this is a 3 meter uh evapo
Transportation data and this is 30 meter
so now you can tell how why we want to
go a little bit further is this should
be fine for corn Bel You Know Field
crops but for a lot of the specialty
crops we do need a finer special
resolution my group is also working on a
deep learning method to help us directly
sharpen the open ET 30 meter data using
Planet observations to get 3 meter ET
for the uh like the the specialty crop
management and we now like lot of
interest from different field they want
to look at like either the water use or
like plant response or in know water
accounting uh you can see there are new
ET data every day like you can see new
Publications every day using ET or try
to produce ET so with a lot of these new
effort how we can have a standard to
evaluate these
uh new data right like if I change just
change a model appli to a area can I
claim it as a new model or whether uh my
evaluation method is a standard method
there is no standard now so what I'm
currently doing is I'm leading a group
of scientists uh internationally from
different country Australia China Europe
um that we are trying to understand
what's the current stat um status of the
silite based uo Transportation product
and uh through this agu talk we will
further uh establish a working group
that will work together to get a
protocol that to help the entire remote
sensing Community to get a standard for
the ET data evaluation so with this I'm
going to conclude my talk so it's
basically the take-home message is we
spend a lot of effort to make this as a
product open to the public especially
open to the users and then I like this
data can be used for a lot of
applications water accounting plan
stress detection on Farm U
management and we are still working on a
lot more of this uh exciting
applications and I also want to thank my
founding agency
uh for all these work thank you so
much we have time
for I yeah johanes we do have time for
questions thank you so much very
impressive I'm really excited about this
um I a question about data ownership you
mentioned aspiration is and evidence for
it that it's open accessible but who the
data you're working with Google Earth
Google probably know uses the data for
all kinds of things and maybe claims
some ownership so what are the
conversations about that not that I
trust actually governments any better
especially with past potentially coming
upon us next week but um no who who can
be trusted with these very important
public goods and how do you and your
colleagues are talking about ownership
of these data for the future
oh thank you so much for this important
question the question is about ownership
of the uh I would say open ET data so um
we do have a lot of discussion um and uh
what we actually have now is we uh
trying to define a better um
intelligence property um certificate for
this data so there is like a more
computer science field there are a bunch
of the is IP certificate we can use and
later we choose one of them there's a
number I cannot recall it uh so there
there we choose one of that so that data
is open and people can uh grab it modify
it which I don't know whether we want to
see that um but for further uh actually
the open group we formed a nonprofit uh
organization um I think two two years
ago so we are um having a a nonprofit
organization that we have board member
uh we also are uh we have the capability
to respond to uh allocate the founding
between different uh science teams and
how the Google engine is involved I
don't think they really claim the
ownership but uh I do see the the tricky
part because among our like a in group
discussion we discussed a lot about when
Google's engine is going to start to
charge us and how much it will charge us
and this
is Hospital yeah and all the discussion
about open AI is is very
similar yes yeah but um well so far
Google engine has been supportive but uh
we had some discussions about that yeah
thank
you other
questions question so it seems like most
of the applications have been focused on
sort of water stress in the crops yeah
and in Upstate New York we often might
have the other problem where we have too
much water I'm specifically think about
soil and nitrous oxide loss and I wonder
if this tool could be useful for making
like field level predictions as to sort
of timing a fertilizer application or
spatial distribution of fertilizer to
try to minimize into to find wet spots
and then avoid those wet spots or wet t
yes for sure I think this will be a very
uh interesting application and actually
uh like through the last two days
workshop with gack team we were thinking
about because for the vineard here you
know not just like field crops wyard um
Apple alard they all have this uh like
more water issue um so uh we were
thinking about to explore the data to
see whether the higher ET could be
related to some of these uh like what
you talked about um the the unarm
management and could be link with the
past and dis
Yep this will be I I think something new
to to the ET Community to
explore thank
you this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at
cornell.edu