this is a production of Cornell
University thank you J for the
invitation so actually couple of weeks
ago Jan talked to me about the seminar
possibility here I'm kind of scared
because because you know bacteria and
the mammals and the plant are different
kingdoms right and I thought okay we are
different different kingdoms how that
can work here and but then I thought
okay anyway so we are all so the central
dogma between plants and the bacteria
and mammals they're the same right and
the particular also I think plants also
has ubiquity that's what feel like fine
we can do it that's something here and
uh okay here's my talk today so well
concentrate tell you about story about
how this bacteria hijack UIC system in
the host for the benefit of
infections okay so this is a bacteria
called Legion
num and you can look on
this um structure of this bacteria is
like a raw like bacteria it's a gram NE
gram negative intracellular passaging
actually it's not like a op it's not
like applicated human pathogen but
sometime it's a fresh host sorry it's
natural host is a fresh water amiba and
somehow when the people getting inhaled
The airos Source contain this bacteria
and then they will cause a disease acute
type of pneumonia disease called
legionar Puma or legionar
disease okay so now uh so this disease
actually first uh reported in uh 1976 I
guess so the the legion convention in
Philadelphia in the hotel and a big
ballroom and two 300 people in party
together and after that tons of people
get sick and eventually the CDC tsts
down what caused the disease it turned
out to be a bacteria and that's why the
Time Magazine has this Title Here
tracing the Philly killer and at that
party like 30 people died for this
infections and ever since then because
people aware of the disease and every
reported more and more cases every year
and uh there's a website actually uh all
cases reported to this website and you
can see a lot of it it happens all over
the world and every year all the time
and I remember heard you probably heard
the news too last year is downtown has a
explo kind of outbreak of the infection
too years here
um so now how they can cause the disease
so when the bacteria enter into L it
will pick up by the aviola microage
cells through the process called a
phagocytosis so the as bacteria get goes
into the
cells it has a weapon we call the type
of for secretion system so you can see
this needle penetrate the membrane which
engulfed this in circulate this bacteria
and the delivers tons of bacterial
proteins into the host the cytool and
then the magic happens basically they
just hijack VAR holster Pathways and we
can intercept vesicles derived from ER
and DEC on the surface of lcv the
secreted proteins they change the
identity of this
vacuums and then they can prevent
detections of by hosting immunity like a
Fus of endosome for degradation not
going to happen in this case because
they change the identity we hide the
bacteria inside this
vacuum and then basically expands and
takes the nutrients from the host the
back replicated inside the vacuum within
the cells and eventually it will life
the vacu life the cell and spread
infections so we do the infection in the
lab in tissue culture cells you can in
in incubate the bacteria with the tisue
culture within 24 hours almost like this
two3 of the cell c will be occupied by
this bacteria and then they will Li and
break the cells and they spread out the
bacteria so and as you can see briefly
this brief like um isogenic Pathways it
theend out if you look at it
molecularly oh sorry there too many l so
those bacterial proteins the whole cells
they are sort of a better cell biologist
than us they know all the cell cellular
mechanism cell Pathways they secreted
those weapons and they can deal with a
Hijra whatever variety of host Pathways
including lipids cytoskeleton ubiqutin
you can name it everything in the cells
in host cells the bacteria knows how to
manipulate and the benefit for their
growth
okay let's give you some example and
taste and initially we find actually
this bacteria secret this phosphatases
lipid phosphatases and those like CDP
and CDF they can specifically hydroly
those three species of the phosphor
inositide which in UK cariot maybe
implants the same thing it serves as a
like zip code for different kind of
organel inside the cell so initially the
foses have decorated with the pi3 p34 or
345 and the P3 C is the marker for
endosome so you need to get rid of three
and that's why the bacteria secret those
enzymes remove all three and eventually
also some people other people reported
as kindnesses here and they convert all
the phosph node into to pi4p which
enrich function as a marker for the uh
for G and er type of organal in the cell
and that's how they can hideen hide the
Spector inside of the vacuum now the
mimicking the host itself and that's why
they don't the host don't detect this
and just ignore this for for
degradation so now just give you another
flavor another example um to just to
show you how the bacteria is knowledge
of know that's so versatile knows
everything of the host and this is
another example they also can invade
exploit the host side of skeletons for
probably for the or or the or
trafficking within the cell after
getting into the cells so there's ex uh
there's an example here so this is the
effect called a mavage so it's very
simple protein uh it has a p3p binding
domains at Inus and and cus has a wh
like uh acting bining very simple
however when you add this liposomes
contained incubated this proteins and
also added to acting that shown in blue
here you can see this acting was
stimulated stimulated polymerization by
this effector and then you can see this
not only poly acting it also deforms
this membranes tubulates and it turn out
actually this effect Secret at a very
early time at during infections once the
bacteria make a contest with the host
and recuit actins and poly acting at the
contact size and polymer acting and
speed up the F phytosis process and
facilitate B entry into the
host so there's another example actually
which is right now actually on my lab
actually mainly focus on is that um this
bacteria also secrate numerous of
effectors they kind of muing or
manipulated host mitochondria so we know
mitochondria is the energy Hub and also
produce a lot of more metabolizes which
may be useful for the bacteria that's
why the bacteria needed to kind of
hijack or utilize the host rewiring the
host mitochondrial functions for their
benefit and we did some kind preliminary
predictions and we have like more than a
dozen of those factors probably local
secret and localized anchor to the to
the host mondra and change the function
of
mondra and just give you a little bit
example here so usually uh this is the
host MRA what it looks like in your
Carrio
and if you have some you will Express
the effector for example here the LPG
1803 it changed totally the morphology
of Metra and cause the aggregation of
Metra and another example for example
lamb 12 it also secr into the host
anchor or localized to the host and when
student studed this and he find out
actually once the this effector goes
into cells it recuit holds the
phosphotase to the mitochondri and Def
phosphor some proteins on the surface
and that's how they can inhibit
mitophagy basically stabiliz metaconda
and and inhibit myop so I don't have
detail I don't have time to cover in
details but uh this just give you a
taste of some examples how the bacteria
can can invade variety of host
Pathways but certainly for today's talk
I will mainly focus on another major
conserv pathway in you car which autop
pathway and again the bacteria secate
numerous infectors and rearing the host
Ting system and for the benefit of a
grow inside
intracellularly okay so now we'll go
this more details if you before I I give
you some background here so if we just
look at the sequences of this bacteria
genome and you can identify some kind of
sequence homology uh some effector
actually including the fbox or U Box
which are part of the liquid Nation
Machinery proteins like e liases and and
they can probably some of them have been
tested actually they can function e
liases on the other hand there some
other effectors people can identify and
actually they can serve a function of
the
deines okay and um so overlab actually
at the first also identify another
unique type of heckle E3 liases which
represented by CDC and DCA and we'll
tell you the stories about how we narrow
down this E3 liases and how the
functions in the
cell okay so because of why as J
introduced my interest initially are
interesting phosphoros lipid signaling
and functions and we started this
because this protein and a big protein
secretor and only people knows it
combine pi4p and so The Binding of the
lipids it anchored on the surface of lcv
leg gener contining vacuum and besides
that nobody knows it's just really
totally blank so I since I trained as a
X3
crystallographer and so we solve the
structure of this proteins it turn out
this protein has multiple domains as you
can see from here and immediately find
the structure we can see
the a domain which in we call name the
p4c actually combine the
pi4p oh oh
okay now you can see so at so this P p4c
domain actually has four Al helican
bundle at the top of this is a pocket
which negativ positively charged which
ideally can fit into this phosphor inide
4 P four phosphate which is negatively
charged and this actually turn out to be
very specific and we find this actually
a lot of lab requested for this
constract as a probe you can use it as a
probe to to detect tected pi4p in
cells okay so this is the bind but
anness we have no idea it is this is a
structure and as a structure biologist
usually you are uh you will search the
database and see which one is similar to
this and then maybe you can infer any
functional um clues for this domain it
turn out this structure is unique
nothing similar to this and and we solve
the structure we kind of struggled for
like almost two years I have no idea
what it is and we Sol me to publish
paper without any function so until one
day suddenly that idea comes out so come
to us so basically we should analyze
also the primary sequence to see whether
or not there any conserved amino acid
right that's normally people do but it
turn out this protein actually about the
20 30% amino acid are sort of identical
across different leg gener species but
you only see them in general you don't
see any other or species for this
Protein that's why the homology quite
High
between leg species 20% is identical and
it's hard to see which one is
important but luckily we have the
structure we can map those identical
reses to the structure see what happens
with assumption that maybe this can
function the enzy and because if the
function of the enzy then us us should
see a surface patch which has a class of
identical conserved residues and indeed
excitingly we see when we do that we
immediately see the pocket
sort of a cluster on the surface here
which contains all the
identical residues not in other places
or majority of them actually embedded
inside the protein which probably is for
structural purpose but only here you see
the patch with conserved identical
residues if you look closely and they
have a hpo hist in system and I'm
teaching biochemistry you immed I see
this I so excited okay this must be a
system based prodct or thein or whatever
transfer which you have no idea what it
is and then we suddenly we order all
different kits and tested in test tube
to see whether or not we can detect any
activity but it turn out we cannot see
any of those activity so this kind of a
science just up and down sometimes
struggles and that's one struggle kind
of another second hit for us because we
have no idea what it is then we thought
okay maybe in the test tube we not
really know the the the indul substrates
we don't know even the conditions so
when should make the function so we
should do it in the cell and ask a cell
whether the was something whatever the
something happens so and before we do
that we have sort of idea maybe it's
related to uquid so we kind of Co
transfer transfer the cells with hqu
either with a Y type or mutant proteins
and we muted the system to Aly we saw
the system must be important right and
immediately you see from the gel we BL
the rest BL with h to see theing
patterns and you can
see some band Only appears in the Y type
but not in the mutant and the mutant one
you see some band disappeared in a white
type so that immediately tells you this
effect must have something to do with
the ubiquination passway right so with
the help of my neighbor Mark smoka they
do M back and exra MP and we try to
identify what are the change what you
know to ubiqus and sub you know the
bands prot changed it turned out among
the top 10
list seven of them actually relate to
e1s e2s okay it turn out so those in the
sales you always have this your Bitcoin
charge E2 and in the presence of CDC
this pool of ubiquity chart E2 was
diminished disappeared okay and that's
why and you can see if you this part is
gone and that's why some ination was
inhibited because you don't have Supply
U charge You2 that's why some band
suppos you should have and now it
disappeared and um instead these enzymes
or affectors they hijack Ubi take over U
from this e2s and go to the cell and now
it can record its own substrates and uin
is its own substrates Now find this
diagram or hypothesis you can see this
actually function as E3 Li is hijack
host uin and do it own you
be now with this idea it's much easier
you can now you have idea you can test
you can confirm this doing the test tube
so we can SE in the e1's e2s and e3s
here and immediately you can see the
robust pration happens with this e2s but
now with this E2 and with you
you7 is so robust almost all you be
could used up within like 30 minutes and
and also other yous also functions fine
okay so now that tells you in wow this
is like a
isas and then it comes to the next
question so C should place here as a us
liase so then we ask this structure or
protein like novel how this can function
as us liase so basically we asked how
does CDC can recognize e2s because E3
need recognize E2 and take over ubiquity
and how they can transfer you could find
you to to um it's substrate or
CC so we continue the mechanic studies
with a structural Sol a variety of
structures and you can see it turn out
that there's a green domain here and
specifically recognize this E2 which
shown pink here and then through the B
once it's bind to e2s the uquid which is
shown in yellow here will be recorded to
the active side which is here and
transfer between to the eies and further
on to its own
substrates okay so now with this it it
turn out it sounds like this is
CDC or SDC the two of them actually
paralog in in the same bacteria so it
secret and and the full structure
actually this active side is covered by
the p4c domain actually so it's not
active probably so then once it's secret
and sees the pi4p and this p4c domain
will bind the pi4p and opens up the
active side and maybe and you can start
um uation some substrates on the surface
or
nearby and we'll continue this later on
before I do that I will show you another
ubiquity kind of passway here so now as
I go back to this here so now we I just
present you our kind of identification
of this heck type is leges and
um recently actually there's another
family of this like eector and uh my
collaborator ding La lab from Pudu they
find that actually this four member
family of this city family like um it
also hijack host ubiquities but it
hijack ubiquities through a through a
very unique bizarre way as you can
appreciate from next
slide okay it turn out this is CD the
domain structure and there nothing that
no you like is domains anything like
like that it instead it has a a ADP raso
transfer domain and what it does
actually it specifically recognize
ubiquity and modify ubiquity use NAD and
this process we call the phosphor
ribocation so NAD can be used as
substrate and and then attach phosphor
ribos uh sorry um ADP Rivals to ubiqutin
very specific only to one restive AR 42
very unique only ubiquity only ar42 will
be modified by this domain the C vector
and then there's a second domain called
the phoso DI domain PD what it does
actually it further modify or converts
iiz away from the ADP ribos and what
left is phospho ribos phosphate and
attached phosphate to its substrate and
basically you do this ubiquination is
very different from canonical lysing
based isop linkage here is like a fosho
eser linkage so the this ubiquity now
attached to the substrate and also
there's a f variable in brid so we work
out the mechanisms and figure out how
this enzyme can do this unique we call a
phosphor ribos ubication pration so as
you can see from here so this enzyme
cleave the phosphate and release and
then the subst come in activated by this
hising so this is sering residues attack
the phosphate and now you can see the
form the linkage so this
uquid now through the aring through the
pentos and the phosphate attached to to
the to the Ser residues on the substrate
so that's what we call the phosphor
rioso
ubicon
okay and then it it turn out that the
four of them as I mentioned so all of
them can do the similar things can do
this which called the
phosphorilation
so but if you look at the the genom of
the bacteria so there other five
effectors contain this conserve the p
so we saw okay you know you look at
sequence all the Cal component reses all
identical we thought okay this PD can do
similar thing as do the ligations as we
just show you in previous
slide so the 10 n of them can do the
ligations but surprisingly to
us it do the reverse two of them can do
the reverse the pation as you can see
from appreci from this is experiment so
we can generate this phosphor Vos
species here so this is substrate this
phosphor rosate bands when you incubate
this phosphor R rosate species with this
D B you can see all the UIC form is gone
and another mutant and similarly so this
D A also incubator you all CLE them up
use up and another the mutant so that
tells you maybe this two actually
function to reverse the fos
um P reverse pation and and it also true
in during infections as you can see from
here so we do the infections you can see
we can enrich the substrate and in the
white type infection you can detect some
P species however if you delete this two
enzymes now you can see this P substrate
really jumped high and it just
substantially
increased confirms this indeed rever
function of the dein specifically for
this phosphor your bation to this point
I want you can appreciate actually this
Legionella secrete those liases and do
this unique type phosphor we call a
phosphor uh ribos uation and they also
secret this doops to reverse the
activity to to Cle thisin found the
targets and and recycle this so just
like canical ubin you have lies in the
DS and the P has similar
Pathways to this point actually I have I
have to confess I'm so guilty for one of
my former students because we saw that
this is really unique in while we find
this in in the general species it's hard
to believe this only the nature only
created this Pathways Cycles only in one
species now in other organism or other
live species so we thought it must be
some other lives have this too and she
spend quite a long time but will never
detect any of this enzymes in other
organisms but maybe in plant they have
it but we didn't really spend time on
the plant species so this is unique it's
really hard to believe only this Legion
have this
Pathways so anyway so uh but this is not
end so on top of this cycle all this
like a Pathways cycle cyclical
Pathways um there's another layer of
complexity so this you look at the
genomes again so this is the bacteria
genome we have the A's and B's and the
C's so those are the leganes I just
present to you between the B and the C
there two other
genes nearby in between so usually in
bacteria so if the genes form a cluster
they almost the function probably likely
in the same passway right they probably
regula the same regular whatever
together um and indeed if you look at
what they are
one is a to a which is I just show you
is the
okay and another one called CJ and um
interestingly so CJ actually can rescue
the to suppressed activity of of this
ABC the leges as you can see here so
this leges when you express the yeast
and they are toxic yeast don't grow
however when you coexpress it yeah now
it regulates the toxic rescue the toxic
but now e the
control just to cut it short there too
too much storage behind this so the turn
out this here where here again we show
the pathways on top of this Pathways
this
CG you know con to another regulatory
paway basically the secret and bind host
codul activate and modify CDE and
inhibit activity of CDE so this we call
a glutamin and also there's other
effectors that can recycle this so
basically we have this pathway and on
top of that you also have a regulatory
circuit to control the activity and I
think there many labs contribut this
including ours this is really a new
pathway and that's why many a lot of
papers come out at almost at same same
time
um okay let's continue so now to this
point I just introduce you to you uh we
have U this conically Pathways and we
have this unique PR Pathways and we want
to ask whether or not this two different
pathways are they in totally independent
or they are they can cross talk with
each other the reason why why we ask
this the two folds actually because when
doing infections we do detect a lot of
UIC signals at the surface of lcv when
infected with Y type of bacteria but now
mutant and if you delete either CD
family or c c family those ubiqui
positive Vues are significantly reduced
so basically both of these two family
like is contributed to the signals at
the surface of the
lcv and also another fot of evidence
reasons why we sort the cross talk each
other because they modify similar
substrates and both for example RAB one
has been shown can be both Modified by
the pr PR Pathways and the chonic
passway too as it's showing here so you
can see when doing infections you can
see this substrate being ubiquinated you
delete the E families is reduced deleted
both it's almost all
gone okay so now we so ask if this
function together and modify the similar
substrates same substrates what kind of
uing structures or chains accumulate or
build up on the substrates so we saw
that here we come up with this kind of
model we
CDC can build up canic CH which directly
attach to the substrates and the CDE
they do this pation and again attached
to the Sim substrates and this also a
uqu molecule uqu also has license
available they can be further
ubiquinated by CDC that's why they
probably can continue build up elong
chain and this type of kind of
structures we kind of hypothesize that
maybe happens in the cell and to test
this model we now we can do this in vual
in the test table Al inil in the cells
so you can enrich or accumulate this U
substrates and then treat with a
canonical D which will cleav all the
isopeptide bond link ubiqui so you free
up ubiqui but only left this phosphor
Ros ubin attached to substrates right
and you can also treat with another enzy
D B which I just showed you it's a
specific Cleaves here be the linkage and
then if you do that now this ubicon
still maintain attached to the
substrates and then it will be released
with the different lens of
your chain so that this is the kind of
predictions and we do the experiment and
test res is true so Marina synthesize
this ubient species with both enzymes
and indeed after treated with dob you
see the mon uin which is here and some
uin is maintained which correspond to
this
substrate and then if you trade with d b
you see the mon d a little bit poly
which correspond to this part and you
have morein chain attached to the
substrate which correspond to this one
and if you certainly if you treat with
both enzymes you all collas into moning
and almost all gone so indeed so those
ubin you have two enzymes they build up
this kind of uine chain mixed ubin chain
we
call and then in the cells you have this
mix U chain and we know in the cells we
have autop machineries we can detect the
ubin and send this for AutoPage
degradation that's usually happen in the
cell and the bacteria is not that stupid
they know actually they know what how to
avoid this but how we don't know because
this ubiquity this should be recognized
by uqu adapters and it can be degraded
by the autop
pathways to to ask this we kind of have
go back to the activity of this enzymes
so this can do the like P ligations but
sometime in the absence of a substrate
and in the person of water molecules
actually do the cleavage too so now if
this phosphor was cleaved by water
molecules it will left phosphor ribos
attached to
Ubi so which means this ubiquity
probably be modified by CDE with
phosphor varibles on aine 42 and by this
modifications you may kind of a mask
uence and the block recognition by The
Host
adapters and first we'll test verify
this where not this true this uin be
modified indeed we have uin chains
synthesized and then you can use a we
call a pro phosphor protein Q staining
you can only detect the free and the
phosphate attached to the proteins and
indeed those uin chains are light up
lights up indicating in the presence of
the C SDA or C C indicating those indeed
those uin modified with phos pentos
phosphate and also it's true inval and
invit or in both is true we use Ubi
substrat and we CLE with Dot and now we
can analyze ubiqus again this uqu you
can see in the presence of a c SDA CD
which basically you can see this UB be
modified and then we also confirm the
Mach back and this is the true so
basically
oh so this uin be modified that's why
they can prevent The Binding recognition
by the U adapters and prevent Auto
degradation and indeed if you look at
the uquid binding by this adaptive
proteins U domain bind ubiqutin and
oxygen 4 42 right at the interface and
you can imagine if do 42 be modified
with ADP Rios or phosphor Rios and there
a sterical collisions here this block
The Binding and indeed when you do The
Binding assays you can see if the UB be
modified there's no binding here and you
can otherwise this actually can you pull
down by the p uh uba domains and also
when doing infections just is too
complicated just focus on the two l two
lanes here so this uin species is a lot
but yet there's no P p62 bind to this
ubin species if you deleted the CDE
family even though theing species are
being reduced dramatically you can still
see dramatic binding with
p62 okay so and this is also um
consistent with the Imaging data you can
see why type of infections no to be
recruited to the lcv and but you delete
the
C be uh pp62 positive lcvs significantly
increased here as you can
see
so okay I'm kind of speed up a little
bit here so to this end so now this
actually we understand now so B what
kind of uin sign build chains buil up at
the surface of lcv and this actually is
mixed and also m is being modified and
that's how they can prevent the host
recognition prevent Auto degradation but
you may ask why you need this if you
don't have uin not going to it's not
going to detected by autopia anyway so
why you needed this uin build up at the
surface and and then you need and then
modify them prevent recognition so there
must be some physiological functions
associated with this uquid this mixed
Ting chain here right to um uh indeed
actually when we do the infections if
you look at the recruitment of er
material or ER vesicles to the lcv in a
Y
type the M okay you can detect a lot of
sorry a lot of lcvs are positive for
those ER materials ER
markers if you delete either of the two
family of Li cases those y markers will
be reduced deleted both of them been
reduced to the almost to the do mutant
which totally block the secretion of the
effector
proteins so that tells you sounds like
you this ubiquity chance you build up
the surface also serves as a kind of a
recruiting mechanism to recruit year
vesicles to the lcv so basically now you
go that to this model so this you can
imagine this ubient chain build up and
actually ubiquity within the chain maybe
they can use up to cross link a second
substrate so this phosphor Rosal linkage
if this we can attach it to the first
substrate which anchor RCV and this one
anchor ER vesicles so now you can you
can imagine this chain SES as anchoring
molecules and Bridge up together the two
different um proteins and and breach the
vesicles recruited to the
lcv and um okay good so I just cutting
the short indeed probably is true
because we can detect those cross
linking of the two different substrate
within the same uine chain so you can
basically you can do the infections you
can pull down one substrate you can also
detect the second one and when you do
the after you when you do the Cleaves
you can release the
free um second substrate in free and
indeed when you do this AES um if you
just focus on this two lanes here so
this the uh uqu species is also positive
for the second substrat and if you do
the cleavage you can see this subsec
substrate was released from the same
material here either with do a or D or
clonic D or do B either one you can
release the second substrates from the
UB
species Okay so and certainly whether or
not this Ting change so that anchor
still need certainly need more evidence
more experiments will continue invest
investigated in uh this idea so but but
anyway I will stop here and just
summarize what we presented so far and I
told you this bacteria secret many many
factors and they can really they the
best to sale B than us and they knows
everything they they can manipulate
lipids and manipulate acting
cytoskeleton and mitochondria which I'm
still working on and to I present you
more in details about the two UB
Pathways and this two uqu passway
function together they build up um sort
of a mixed uine chains like MH work on
the surface of lcv not only they can
protect the bacteria from host
degradation but also probably can serve
as a anchoring scaffolder to record host
materials or vesicles
and okay by the end I will see some
peoples uh I Cann knowledge actually I
do see um some of the former members and
some new members and I don't have time
to go in details sorry for that and also
some collaboratives and the foundings
and I will stop here and hopefully it's
not too late and welcome any
questions question that you show
Target yeah and why is that is that
really a Target why is that a Target
like do you have any idea like why rap
teally should be degraded as like as
opposed to being a partner um and is
there any other Target for this effector
and do any of these proteins have any
role to towards
236s protos or
isulation basically only works for for
autop like as a sofr for autop not for
yeah maybe I'm not clear with this it
the turn out
um this tines are not for prote
degradation the purpose is not for
degrade any degrade any proteins around
CV totally not for degradation
um so in term of substrat we did mess
back with both ccs and sdas you will see
a numerous of effectors which many of
this actually ER proteins and some
proteins involved in membran trafficking
like rap small gdps and many others and
there's also some of the subst that kind
of a common for each leges and we
believe those there's no specificity for
those targets the only I think it more
likely the based on the geometry based
on the space the vicinity so because
those enzym been secreted it's all
localized on the surface IV whatever
protein nearby they can be modified and
the modification not for degradation
instead they probably just build up
ubing mes as a protecting shell and also
serves as I mentioned as anchor
anchoring scaffold and recuit other
proteins cross linking other proteins so
is that answer
you membran that yeah it's possible some
that's why some initial vesicle can be
recuited through other mechanism and
this you modifi and stabiliz
more tily like Co me just attachment
together yes yes
please
as
why do like why
do why they Rec materal
yeah so the the bacteria need to grow
right when into the cell initially the
the fome is very tight it's really
tightly bounded only the bacteria size
eventually as I mentioned 24 hours
expanding enormously like two s of
second occupied by this vacuum you need
membrane need materials to enlarge the
space enlarge the niche it's more like
transfer one that's probably one the
mechanism recuit year vesicles fuse them
eventually big bigger
and related around that contact site or
whatever yeah that's a good idea we
never look at it yet but maybe we have I
have no idea yet and nobody reported
that any liid transfer protein involved
in this process or not that's certainly
could be a future direction for you can
investigate yeah yes please
it has and c and the Cy are and then
degraded and that's how the cell
progress right so if ubiqutin are
hijacked are the cell arrested in the
same
stage uh I'm I'm not sure I understand
quite well your question could you
repeat again oration
pathway leads to cell arrest because
cyclings they will not be degraded oh
okay um I have no idea whether or not
interfere with other host uation
Pathways it only so far I present here
it just utilize Ubi it hijack clost to
Ubi and use it for its own build up this
meas work the cell know the cing or
other Pathways during infections I don't
know whether or another they
to what degree the impacted by this uine
lius is I have no idea yeah and also the
infection cycle is quite short like 24
hours you're down and I'm not sure can
affecting cell cycles or not I I have no
idea
can yeah can we let's say these proteins
yeah that hijack the utin to let's say
treat cancer or something because it
will not let cycl to degrade and the
cell will remain in the same stage yeah
that's a good idea I always saw when I
working on this we call weapons this are
really unique tools you can you dissect
the host cells and um but somehow those
enzymes are quite toxic to the host if
you overexpress them the host is not
happy the cell going to die really
indeed for example this is really robust
you ere expr too much in the cells and
just use up all bin and just just hijack
everything and similarly this like is
also too you toxify bination system
ination yeah it could be if you use a
small month you can develop this as a
tool you can disect use it to manipul in
different ways As You
Wish okay fascinating talk um I'm
intrigued by the fact that the Sid C and
S A are basically only found in leg
janelas what do you think their
evolutionary origin is yeah usually
people believe believe uh those gen so
the bacteria acquired from the original
Asian host so we call it like a gene
trans direct horizontal Gene transfer
but now through Evolution this you know
evolved in bacteria and now the sequence
all the other features maybe evolve some
new ones and but totally different from
you host now it's totally different now
you cannot see any sequence and even
structure wise you don't see them
anymore yeah but how nature created
those and whether or not again this is
still posibly me whether not maybe other
spe has this pass or not we still have
no idea and I know several lab try to
invest this and nobody reported of far
whether or not other species has those
uh pathway or not maybe plan has it I
hope yeah
okay yeah plan passing may we also have
it this has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at Corel n.edu