This is a production of Cornell
University. So also thank you for giving
me this opportunity to uh present our
work on
watermelon.
Okay. So here's uh the outline of my
talk today. First I will provide a
little bit of background for watermelon
although most of people already know you
know and then I uh talk about the
generation of high quality reference
genomes of watermelon and then we uh I I
will talk about the genomeary sequence
of davos rep representative watermelon
accessions and I uh then we talk about
the go and mapping of important
watermelon trace using the resource we
generated and then at the end of my talk
I will spend like a couple minutes to
introduce a new project it's called
cuc so as most of you may already know
that watermelon is a member of cuc cubid
family which includes
uh okay melon cucumber watermelon and
pumpkins several very important
uh fruit
crops and this is a uh what fruit
map and and you can see watermelon is a
very is a worldwide fruit c. You can see
watermelon everywhere in the
world and watermelon is also a
economical crop
and it it
uh so in 200 this is the data I got from
uh F
2012 what the whole vegetable is 57
million hectare was was grown about 6%
is for watermelon
And in China even more you got
7%. That China is the leading producer
of watermelon. And you can see the
production in the world is about
105 105 million tons annually and China
produce about six
67% of the watermelon in the world and
also the consumption per capita
consumption is about 3.5 times in China
than the average of the
world. So watermelon is also um the the
most popular fruit worldwide ba based on
the production and you can see
watermelon ranked number one on the
production. So tomato is not kind of
here. Tomato is if you count tomato as a
fruit then tomato is a number one.
Tomato is about 160
million but most people treat tomato as
vegetables not fruit.
So you can see the several popular
fruits watermelon, banana, apple,
oranges, grapes. You know watermelon the
production is the rank number
one. So watermelon is also a very
nutritional crop and this is a nutrition
fact and
also the watermelon contains very high
levels of lacine than any other fresh
fruit or vegetable. It it has uh
contains like 15 to 20 microgram per two
cup serving. That's very
high. And the watermelon also contains
this citrine. So the name of citrine was
derived from the Latin name of
watermelon. So watermelon the Latin name
of watermelon is the crolos lanatas. So
that citruline was derived from the
crolos.
So this is a very important amino acid
that maintains cardiovascular function
and also there's a report say that this
amino acid have some biagara like
effects but it's certainly good to your
uh to to your heart to your
health. So watermelon is also emerged as
a model system for uh for nonclimactaric
fruit quality development. It it uh when
people study like single
accumulation, fruit wening and rapid
fruit
expansion, watermelon become a very good
system and also the cucub species like
watermelon, melon and cucumber fl is
they also as a model system for flower
sex
determinations. So this they have a
three different flower types. So male
flower, female flower and a bisexual
flower. And based on com combination of
these different flower types, the plant
one plant could have different flowers.
So you have different flower types plant
like this monocious that's only have
male and female flowers in one plant and
mono is a male and bisexual flowers. So
this these are two major uh flower types
in watermelon. But in cucumber you have
all kind of the seven different flower
types. But watermelon now has uh the civ
watermelon have very narrow genetic
diversity. Although their phenotype
diversity is is very large but their
genetic diversity is very very narrow.
That's causing the bottleneck for
breeding. And also the watermelon has a
complicated quantity of traits. I think
this same as other crops like fruit,
fruit size, sugar content, shape, fruit
shape, the flavor and maturity, shelf
life, uniformity, growth ve
etc.
And also uh watermelon is sensitive to
to quite a lot of diseases like f this
is the most important disease in
watermelon is a fizarium build and also
it's a
uh there's a lot of pest in watermelon
like a and also root
not neop
neatode so not because of this problems,
the narrow genetic diversity, all kinds
of different complicated traits and we
need modern tools such as the genomic
tools. That's what we the the talk the
the focus of the talk today that need to
be developed for watermelon to
facilitate its breeding and
research. So next I will talk about the
reference sequence we generate for
watermelon. So so far we have generated
three reference genome in uh like last
seven or eight
years. The first one we generate. So in
2008 we are we we formed a international
watermelon genome
initiative and we uh the the the goal of
this uh project the watermelon genome
project the one of the goal is gen
generate a high quality draft genome of
watermelon cardiva 9713 is this cardio.
So this is a east asotype. It has early
maturity and high fruit
quality. And we also have these uh
additional go uh go um the objectives.
One is the resequencing of uh of the
watermelon accessions that I'm going to
talk today also and also we generate a
lot of transchrome data involved in uh
different interest biological process
but this I will not talk this today.
So watermelon is uh the genome size is
about 425 million base pairs and it's
highly homozygous and is can be easily
inbred. So so I even in 2008 it's not
not that difficult to do genome
assembly. So we uh we we did a genom
assembly using the whole genome shutter
gun approach purely enomina sequence and
at that time the main sequence is like
40 50 base pairs or 75 base pair now
it's like 250 but we still managed to to
assemble a very high quality genome. So
the uh the M50 size is 2.3 million base
pairs that's pretty high compared to all
other assembled genome at that
time. And we also assembled about 80%
more than 80% of the genome. So the
genome size is 425, we assembled
353. So as we we we did at that time we
did analyze the unasssembled reads. We
found most of them are repeated
sequence. So that's that's what I what
we
expected and we did a genome annotation.
We identified about 23,000 genes. It's
uh it's less less than most of the crops
that the tomato has 35 million. Even
abdops had 27 35,000. Even abdopedis has
27,000
genes. So the reason we have much less
gene this could be one reason. So the
first thing we analyze this genome we
found there's no whole genome
duplication event occurred in in in c in
watermelon and also in cucumber we
didn't find any uh recent whole genome
duplication but we uh in arbopsis they
have two recent whole genome
duplications and in tomato and potato we
have a recent whole genome triplication
event and all uricots have a ancient
triplication And you can see this
ancient triplication also exist in in
watermelon and and and cucumber. That's
expected you know. So without this whole
genome duplication then that's why we
got much less gene numbers in in
cucumber. And recently we sequenced the
uh the pumpkin genome. This is also in
the cucet family. We found a whole
genome duplication and the the gene
number in pumpkin is is like 32,000. is
much higher than than
cucumber. We did some comparative
genomic analysis. So our finding is that
the transition from the 21 chromosome
utic. So the udicart has an ancient
ancestor which has 21
chromosomes. So uh that that involved a
large number of fishes and fusions. So
in order to reach the modern 11
chromosome structure of watermelon and
you can see this uh mosaics of different
ancest blocks. So during the whole
genome evolution this shows how the uh
the genome from the ancestor come to the
modern watermelon and also we identified
large synonyy we found a lot of synonyy
between the cucubid species the melon
and the
watermelon. We also checked the uh this
citrine metallic uh metabolic pathway
and the interesting thing is that so we
compared to
arabopsis and this is the pathway the
only thing we found that there's a
expansion in this two families in
abdopsis there's only one gene gene
members but in uh in citrine in
watermelon we have two members for this
two gene families and then we are
Because data we we we checked the uh the
expression pattern and we found the
three genes are downregulated during
fruit development that's that's
corresponds to the high elevated
settling content during fruit
development because this uh this this
two gene families are involved in
degradation of the settling. So this is
a settling that is degradation although
this form this circle and feedback loop
but I mean we believe that citling
accumulation in the maturing fruit in uh
is likely due to decreased activity. So
this decreased activity of citrine
degradation okay with uh the uh rapid
advance of sequencing technology. So we
recently sequenced another genome. So
the the one the NASA M3 is a East Asia
ecotype. So now this one was American
eype. So you can you can clearly see the
big difference of this two uh two uh two
ecotypes. So the fruit shape is a is
different. This one is round and this
one is oblong. And then the uh the fruit
size this one is much larger. This one
is about 25 to 35 pounds. And this one
is about 10 to 15
pounds. And there are also uh I mean
other uh phenotypic phenotypic
difference. And the reason we s this one
because of the a group in Charleston. So
this this one was a was developed in
Charleston, South Carolina. And they are
using this as a system to develop all
kinds of studies. So we uh we we we also
using the whole genome shot gun using
the illuminina the most recent
illuminina technology we didn't use any
pack bio and you can see the difference
I mean after the the technology
evolvement you know this was done in
2009 something 2020 2010 this was done
in 2014 and you can see the M50 size
from 2.3 million to 7.5 million increase
and also the uh the genome we assembled
So when when risk getting longer then a
lot of repeative sequence now can be
assembled. So we assembled about more
than 90% of the genome. So this I mean
this genome probably the the highest
quality we have been we have assembled
so far in my
lab we got about about the similar
number of genes and then we identified
the single nucleotide variations between
these two between East Asia and American
and American nucleotide. And we found
that they are the genome of these two
species are highly similar. This is only
the snip rate is only about like six
snips out of 10,000 base pairs. That's
that's very very
low. And we also identified as uh
structure variations larger insertions
deletions inions or duplications.
And we
identified mainly deletions. We
identified
2771 deletions in Charison gray. This
American
eucalype and and only uh you can see
when we talk about the wild reference
genome next you can see the big
difference. So now we only have
200 233 kilobase deletions in the genome
and also 500 kilob 600 kilobase in this
genome and interestingly we found that
this deletions are enriched in in this
uh uh fruit QTL fluid weight QTR region.
So we have this orange lines are fruit
weight QTR we have five fluid weight
QTLs. So the uh chromosome 6 to 11 I
didn't show here because they don't
contain any fluid weight CTL as far as
as
reported. So uh you can see the uh 36 of
this delions are in this five regions.
It's highly enriched and that's
understandable because you can see this
fruit two fruit are this fruit size
fruit weight are highly
different. Okay. Next we uh I will talk
about a wild watermelon. This the
reference genome. This is more
interesting than the American
eotype. And we actually we initiated
this wild watermelon before the that
chalice gray American type. And and
uh and you can see the highly diff the
the the the phenotypical difference of
this two uh accession. The wild species
there's no sugar content. You don't want
to eat it because also bitter you know
and it had white flesh and hard texture
is very hard and it has late maturity.
It also mature but it's very late but
the good thing of this one is the
resistance to the uh filement rail to
the fun
012 and nas3 is sensitive to this
one. So we did a genome assembly the the
uh the uh assembly the quality is about
the same as 9713. So we we emphasize
about 2.1 million base pairs and we
assembled about 80% of the genome. And
then we uh we did a comparative genomic
analysis and use a molecular clock to
date the speciation events between the
wild and cultivate watermelon. And we
found out that these two species was uh
the speciation event was occurred about
1.3 million years
ago. So tomato and potato the speciation
event occurred about six million years
ago. So this is much I mean because it's
the same species it's much closer than
tomato and and
potato and we identified genomic
variations and you can see now we have
3.9 snip identified compared to
200,000 that's like 5% of the snips
identified in between nasal mastery and
charison gray so that mean this two this
genome and the the wild wild species and
the uh the cultivated watermelon their
genome are highly different. There's a
lot of difference and you can see this
50 almost 16,000 genes were affect by
this
variations. That's about 80% of the
genes in the genome. 70% maybe 70% of
the genome. And we also identified 680
kilo uh,000 small
indail and which leading to frame shift
in 247 genes.
So we also identified the large
structure variations the present and
absent variations and we identified in
NASA Y3 we identified 6.7 million base
pairs compared to like 200 or 600
kilobase it's is much much more and we
uh the gene affected by this is 270 and
also we identified 5 7 million uh
present variations in uh in this this w
wild watermelon it contains 223
genes as I mentioned before. So this uh
uh wild accession they have
resistance to uh found one found risk 02
and 01 and
two and we compare this genome and we
found that the the uh the R gen MS
resistant genes. We only found that two
two genes that are totally unique that
that only exist in this PI and one gene
would exist in in this
NAS13. So that means this gene are
totally absent in one or another. But
when we check this uh this present and
absent variations because some genes
they uh they are not totally gone. the
the the the violation maybe just uh just
cause a frame shift maybe truncate a
part of intron. So we found several MBSR
genes that in this list and also disease
resistant genes disease related genes
like receptor like protein can also find
some
u some genes are related to abotic
stress stress like heat shock
proteins. So this may also explains the
difference between these two uh the
phenotypical difference of these two uh
watermelon accessions. So wine is highly
resistant to disease and also can grow
in very high conditions like desert you
know a high
temperature I think this uh this stuff
may relate to the flavor I'm not sure
you
know we also identified the uh the
inversions we identified 66 inversions
and interestingly we identified one into
chromosome rearrangement events And you
can see this is in cartuate watermelon.
This is a wild watermelon. So in
cartivate
watermelon this watermelon chromosome 11
in wild this part was was uh become
rejected into chromosome 2 in in
cultivate
species. The uh we we we we did several
checks to make sure it's not assembly
error. We using read the pair and rates
or met pair rates to to confirm this is
it is a real interchromosome rearment
but the uh the implication of this re
rearrangement in watermelon qualities of
phenotype that's we don't know we don't
know yet remains
unknown okay so we generate the
watermelon reference genome which
provide a great resource now with this
this resource available now we can do uh
genome
resequencing. So we did genome
resequencing was a wide range of
watermelon accessions. So watermelon was
was
thought to originate from
Africa. So was originated from Africa
then distribute to the world but whether
is is originated from southern Africa or
western Africa. So now it's still a
debate. There's no clear evidence to
support that. Most people thought it's a
it's originate from southern Africa. But
recently people argue that they maybe
get from western uh Africa. The still is
still not resolved
yet. So this is uh the wild watermelon.
But in in about 4,000 years ago, we are
the seeds as well as the paintings of
watermelon. This p this painting of
watermelon was found in in Egyptian
tombs that's built more than 4,000 years
ago. And and you can clearly see that
this watermelon I'm not sure this
picture
shows. So the shape the first shape is
different from from the wild type. So so
wild type or wild type watermelon is
round is round shape. And that means
that 4,000 this one is a little bit
long, right? I'm I'm not sure whether
it's that clear. So that means in 4,000
years ago, people is already start to
dumpate watermelon and use watermelon as
a as a as a I mean as a fruit, you
know, this called a a far fruit in
Egyptian.
So this is a watermelon in the 17th
century. So you never see watermelon now
this kind of watermelon in nowadays. So
I mean in 17th century the watermelon is
like this. Maybe you think oh people
living in that area it's is very tough
you know eat this kind of
[Laughter]
watermelon. So then this this is a
modern day sweet dessert watermelon.
This this kind like the
evolution uh history of watermelon based
on the uh on the uh available evidence.
But the problem is that the scen the
scenario of watermelon evolution still
remain largely unclear. The first one is
a what is the ancestor of of
watermelon and we know this white
watermelon there's all kind of different
white watermelon but which one is the
ancestor the ancient ancestor of the of
watermelon and the second one is what is
the direct progenitor of cart watermelon
and also what's a domatification
process so uh to to answer this question
I'm I'm sure it will hard to clearly
answer those questions but we are trying
to using this genomic sequence data to
answer part of these questions and the
watermelon has four
species. So this red one is it's a uh
citulus nanatas that's the watermelon
species is also include three sub
species. So this one is cultivated
watermelon. One is American cultiv
watermelon also divided into uh American
eotype and east Asia eotype. And then we
have this semi-wired
watermelon. And then we have cetroidis.
That's it's called wild wild watermelon.
And then we have a
se I call horses watermelon. the uh
salana satellas uh rai and then this
choleens and also this one. So this is
this this this wild species and this one
is now the uh neonos. It's hard for me
to pronounce this one. is originally
called the Jumpspark cucumber but they
they classified as a stolas and you can
see this is a fruit of that
one and uh also the taxonomy in
watermelon is also a huge debate. So
this is people classify this as a as a
four five different species but now
people thought it's probably seven
species. So they they they class this
one as different
species not sub species. So it's still a
debate you know. So we did a uh we
select 174 representative accessions
from a jump plant collection of 2,000
accessions and we we did genome
sequencing. We generate a total of 910
gigabyte data gigabase data and the
average risk coverage depths for each
genome is about 15x. That's pretty
high. So we identified 24 million
snips a lot because of those wild wild
species. But you can see we only
identified about one million snips from
from this cultivate species within those
groups. And we identified 5 million in
semi-w another close to 60 million from
ctoides and 7 million from
choleys. And we use this snip to derive
the uh the genetic diversity using the
pi uh parameter. And we found the uh the
uh the civ species the uh genetic
diversity is less than one
one to
negative3 and the uh the choleensis the
genetic diversity of chessens is pretty
high. It's
6.48. When you compare this to uh to
other crops and you can see the genetic
diversity of watermelon is is extremely
low even lower than cucumber. You know
cucumber is uh the uh the cular one is
about 1.85
85 East Asia is lower is is greater than
one you know and the rice indica 5.7
Japan
3.7 and soybeans the civ one is close to
two so this confirms the previous study
that the cultivated watermelon had very
very very narrow genetic diversity that
cause huge problem for breeding a
bottleneck for breeding
We we then use this snip to build this
filogenic tree. And the uh the first
thing we found is that this
one we use cucumber as a root as all the
group. And we found this one was not
clustered to watermelon. It's clustered
to to cucumber. You know, you can see
this these two cluster together.
And as expected we found a lot of all
the uh cardiv species they clut together
then this
semi-w then this
ctoidis and this uh this wild species
they cluster
together and then we have thought about
does this uh this one is is a real
watermelon or is a melon or is a
cucumber. So we did some analysis. The
first one we did is bas this the
fogellic tree clearly shows it's not
watermelon right then we did we map the
risk to all kind of different genomes we
have we have cucumber genome we have
watermelon genome we have melon genome
we also have two pumpkin genomes we
align the the the rect to them we found
the it matches most to
melon and also we did fish and we found
the the chromosome number of this one is
24. It's 12 chromosome pairs. That's
same as melon. The cucumber had seven
chromosome pairs. Watermelon had 11 and
melon has 12.
So we conclude that this one is not a
watermelon species. It should be a melon
species. So then we did not use this one
in the in the downstream analysis.
So we did a a population structure
analysis and the the uh the conclusion
from this population structure analysis
is that the
uh this semi wild
uh
watermelon should be the direct
progenitor of the civular
watermelon and the uh and originally
people thought this choleensis should be
the ancest
uh the ancient ancestor of watermelon
but this this population structure
another did not support that because you
can see we didn't see any this orange
block the orange alo we didn't see in
the cultivate species we didn't see any
orange block from this uh from the u
from this choleic
senses and we uh
we haveized that these two species you
can see this have green, blue, orange
and and
and this was scion
whatever. So that's have this uh all
colors from the cultivate species. So we
uh we hypothesize that this two could be
the ancient ancestor of watermelon. But
this conclusion is not that uh
conclusive you know because we didn't we
didn't sample a lot a lot of
species but we can uh we can rule out
this choices as a
ancestor and also we uh we found that
this one this uh ctoidis or lanatas the
subspecies they could be a separate
species instead of a sub subspecies
based on this population structure
analysis it it's you can say it's highly
different from the other
species. So we then uh identified the
selective swap swap we using the p ratio
between the uh the semiwired watermelon
and the cable watermelon. So we
identified the
uh the the select swept across the whole
chromosomes and one thing that very
interesting is that we identified this
uh this this uh uh select swap. You can
see this the huge genetic diversity
uh decrease reduction in in this region
and we found this region corresponds to
a fruit weight CT. So fruit weight is a
major trait that was selected during
human
domatification. This then we we found
this one and also we found a a lot of
other interesting stuff that but I will
not talk about here due to the time
conference. So watermelon we we we are
it's a major problem as I mentioned
before a major problem for watermelon is
a disease and we check the watermelon
genome we identified 46 MBSR genes
that's represent the least number of
MBSR genome genes in any any genomes of
crops you can see
uh cubid species normally has very few
but watermelon even has less cucumber
and what and the melon and other like
tomato you got several hundred but in
water in the watermelon you only have 46
that's cause
uh problems for
watermelon. So then we think about
because the wild species they are highly
resistant to watermelon to dis all kind
of different diseases and we hypothesize
that maybe some genes was lost during
the
domestification. So we did some
analysis. This is this analysis was not
done on the uh on the 134 accessions was
on 20 accessions we did at the fourth
time but the results should be similar.
So we denote we align the reads to the
uh reference
genome and those that are aligned we do
a denovo assembly. We we divide those
unaligned to two different groups. The
group one is from the cutwood
watermelon and then the group two
includes semi- wild and wild watermelon.
And you can see the group one we didn't
find this is this is the gene was
missing in the tomato in the watermelon
genome but we didn't find any diseased
genes then from the uh the wire species
denovo assembly of those unmapped reads
to the wire species and we found is
highly enriched with the disease
resistant
genes and we are we then map this risk
to confirm this this is not a uh
sequencing or assembly the arrow
whatever or in the in the genome we map
the uh the cart
reads we we map the reads from this
cartas to this genes and none of them
was was found. So that means this this
this
this genes are are real missing during
domestication
process. Yeah. So the conclusion is that
a large portion of disease resistant
genes have been lost during watermelon
uh domestication. So this domestication
process which have focused on desirable
fruit trade and yield. So it's not
focused on disease resistance until
recently. Okay. Next I will talk about
using this this data resequence data we
generate and other resource we generate.
I uh show you several examples on how uh
we identify QTLs using GWAS approach and
also QTL mapping approach.
So we did on the uh the uh GW was
analysis on form one resistance. We
identified QTLs on chromosome one and
the chromosome 3 and also found two
resistance. We identified QDR major KDR
in chromosome
11 and sugar content we identified a
major on chromosome
2 and this one I will talk a little bit
more later you know is a bitterness is a
a major trait during uh
domestication and I don't think probably
no one would like to eat a bit
watermelon so this is why uh was mapped
to the chromosome one later we clone
this
gene. So that's using the natural
natural accessions the 134 natural
accessions to do gbas analysis that
proves that it can identify some
interesting QTRs. So so we have a a
recominant inbred line population real
population. So this real population was
derived by cross from this 973 the east
Asia ecotype and also this wild
watermelon. So we have whole genome
sequence genova genome sequence for both
and we we we generated this real
population and we did a shallow genome
resequence for this 96 reals and we
generated like 247 gig data and the
average genome coverage was about 5.2
and 2x for for this real
lines. We checked the uh the uh the re
combination pattern and also and also
the uh the the origin of the uh of the
genome from which parent right so this
uh this uh blue means that this this
region is from
uh nam 3. So red means this region is
from that PI from that wild watermelon
and gray mean green means hoacles that
confirm that this this uh population is
high quality. You didn't
find any green or I at least I couldn't
find any green from this figure that
hoyagos because this is a highly
embedded real population confirm this
the quality of this this
population and we you we use this uh uh
this population to identify additional
cods or kind use kind of like a
complimentary approach.
for critical mapping and you can see uh
this for F1 is confirmed. This is the
peak of the
F1 and F one also mapped to the same
region at using G was but this one did
not map this uh this uh this this locos.
But for fun two we identified this major
QTR also identified in this population
but we identified another QTR on
chromosome I believe it's chromosome
9 and for content it's confirmed
confirmed the g data is also on
chromosson 2 we uh we identified this uh
this QTL then we did further analysis we
we we mapping them to very nar arrow
region between this this two this two uh
beam
markers. So in this within this uh this
region we found a large cluster of uh of
transmembrane sugar
transporters and we uh when we compare
to uh do some comparative analysis with
melon
melon sugar criteria also contains this
this transm sugar transport. So we did
some functional analysis and turns out
that one of them indeed can transport
sugars. Okay, this is the fine map QL
mapping of bitterness trait. So we clone
this gene and first this is uh the GW
was
analysis. So it's a uh first map to the
to the chromosome one. Then we use this
uh uh real population and narrow down to
this region and then we use uh 1647 F2
population and narrow down to this two
markers. So this two markers and it's
highly it's a co- segregated with this
indoor marker. We didn't find any re
combination events for this marker and
we narrowed down to
uh I think it's about I forgot the the
region the region contains five genes
and one of them uh we found is 200 base
pair of mitochondria sequence inserted
at first axon in nonben non non betito
accessions.
So, so this 200 base pair of
mitochondria sequence insertion in the
nonpent accessions are highly consistent
with within this 96 real population and
also in the natural population. So in
the natural population we check the they
be or they no be and for non beetle
accessions they all contain this 200
base pair mitochondria secret insertions
for n for beta watermelon they do not
contain this one.
So I think they are this 200 base pair
insertion disrupt the function of this
gene then it will not generate that
little chemical you
know okay here's a uh uh I before I go
to that that new project introduced to
that new project I would like to uh
provide a summary on what I talked so
far so firstly is a high quality
reference genome have been generated for
an east Asia genotype or ecotype I'm
sorry and American ecoype and a wild
croid accession. So compatible genomic
analysis provide no insights into water
watermelon genome
evolution and the resequence of the uh
the genomes of 134 divers watermelon
accessions generate a large
comprehensive watermelon genomic
varation map. This provide another very
useful
resource and based on this uh uh genetic
variation map we uh we find that civ
cultivated watermelon had very narrow
genetic diversity that's causing the
bottleneck for uh for watermelon
breeding and also we found that a large
portion of disease resistant genes have
been lost during watermelon
domestication and based on the sequence
analysis We found that this one
previously classified as a watermelon
species should belong to
welon and the sub species the
ctoidis and could be a separate species.
It should not be classified as a sub
species and g analysis identified from a
number of
agonomically important traits. So
including the uh the found resistance,
sugar contents, fruit size and the bet
gene was further cloned through QTL fine
mapping. So we are in the process of
doing functional confirmation of this
business
gene. So last I will spend like two or
three minutes talk about this uh uh kick
cap project. So this is a newly funded
project by USDA is for through the
specialty crop
program. So the title of this project is
leveraging applied genomics to increase
disease resistance in cuca
crops. This is a beginning of a new
project to develop additional genomic
resources for the cucida community.
uh Rebecca Gumat from Michigan State is
the PI of the project and we have 21
copiis and from 11 institutions. So I'm
the uh the leader of the genomic and the
bionformatic team and
Michael Mazuric is for from plant
breeding department is the lead he's
leading the squash team and also
Christian also involved in this project.
So we have uh this project have three
objectives the big
objectives. The first one is a develop
genomics and a bionformatics breeding
tool kits for accelerate crop
improvement across the cubit
cubitization and the second is perform
genomic asset breeding to integrates
disease resistance in cubit cardio.
So the third one is perform economic
impact analysis of cost of production
and disease control and provide readily
accessible information to facil
facilitate disease
control. So I'm highlighting several
points. So because the these three uh
big objectives have a lot of small
objectives I I I I can't go to too much
detail. So in the uh in the
bionformatics team there are two main
objectives. The first one is uh perform
GBS analysis of PI that means jump plot
collections of the four species. We uh
we probably uh do GBS for about 1500
collections for each species. That's
that's about 6,000 species. Then we we
uh from those species based on the TBS
uh information we identify a core
collection of
384 accession for each of the four
species that can be used for the
community uh used as a comm community
resource for gass analysis. So in total
we we probably do uh
10,000 uh do do genotyping for 10,000
accessions. We uh we provide access to
cucub genomic tools and a database while
this international uh uh cucub genomic
initiative website. This website was
developed by my group about like seven
or eight years ago was also maintained.
So this database was developed in my
group during the past like seven or
eight years. I didn't get any funding
for this database but now finally we got
some funding to do this. So we we we we
plan to make a huge improvement of this
database. We did get some small money
from the company but that's not compared
to this big
one. So here is a list of of diseases
that they focused in this project.
So this uh the uh ferasm revealed that's
a major focus for watermelon and dy
mildo is for cucumber and also we have
others the gummy
stem and also the
viruses. Okay so with that I would like
to thank everyone involved in this
project. This is a a huge consortium and
I I couldn't provide all the list in
this slide but I would like to uh
emphasize several key people in this
project. Why is Hono Sen from my group
he did mostly the assembly and and the
genomic analysis and also Shiau he he
was a wing student in my lab and now in
this national
nec so he also did uh the genom
analysis and the uh the QTL mapping and
major uh vet lab work was done in
Yongu's lab in this institute field and
all other people contribute to this and
the
funding support the work in my lab for
this project was from national science
foundation USDA and city communist. So I
hope you have fun with watermelon.
[Applause]
This has been a production of Cornell
University on the web at cornell.edu.