this is a production of Cornell
University um so today my talk uh first
I want and another thing I want to thank
Brian for his kind introduction it has
always been a great pleasure for me to
work in this lab since I was honrad and
uh I believe that will convey to you
through my presentation okay so today
we're going to talk about uh motility
regulation in this pathogenic system as
moning G pass Our tomato disease
resultant and the first thing I want to
touch on is to show you a little bit
about this bacteria so here you have a
picture of our road shap stus cell this
is a regosa cell unfortunately not a
sery but this is the highest uh uh
resolution I can find uh on the internet
so you can see that uh we have a rod
shaped uh cell and with polar flagala
which we we will touch on in a minute
but our species suumo Seri is a plant
pathogenic bacteria that has a wide Host
range because there's over 60 total
Passover uh the model strand we're
interested in uh is dc3000 which is a
tomato pathogen but can also affect uh
arabidopsis as well as tomato uh this
strain has been developed as a model
strand largely thanks to people in this
department on this very campus because
uh people like Alan comr and Greg Martin
we know oh we know a lot and a lot about
their types series equation system and
infectors so but today I'm going to talk
about not the uh verance part of it but
the mtil part of it and I got into this
because when I joined the lab back in
2017 uh swingle lab has already been
working on motility for a while and this
is the result at the time I joined the
lab where you have uh s disease
resultant use this motility to invade uh
to evade plan immunity especially the
part of uh PTI which is where the plant
are detecting
feling so without going too much into
this uh the detail about this model
which uh concerns a chapter of my S that
I won't be present here today but will
probably come up in my B exam uh I just
want to say that at the time we already
know a little bit about uh motility in
has this ecological function so what
motility are we talking about there are
total five different types of motility
that are present in
bacteria uh and we're mostly concerned
about swimming motility in this strand
so uh several features of swimming
motility I'd like to point out is one it
requires the bacteria to be inside of a
certain liquid or semi liquid
environment two it needs this file
it needs fum as the main organ if you
would say or as a main structure it
relies on to facilitate the movement and
three it is consuming energy the uh the
fum rotation relies on proton Moto Force
to power itself to generate the torque
and pull the bacteria
forward now motility in bacteria in
general has been topic of study for past
half century or more and the most
well-known model of motility regulation
in all of bacteria is
chemotaxis this is a kind of a algorithm
or building the bacteria if you say that
follows a very simple logic it always
want to improve the chemical uh
environment for the bacteria and here
I'm showing you that if you put a
bacteria a hypothetical scenario where
you have from cold color to warm color
the concentration of say a neutrient or
some kind of chemical bacteria really
likes and you have our a polar Flite uh
fulum bacteria such as ponas going uh
moving or swimming inside this
environment so what you would observe in
any case would be kind of run and Tumble
model which describes the movement and
the sudden break and then the
disassociation of all
of all the po polar flum and then
reorientation at a random angle and it's
also described as a bias random walk
because uh the randomness of the break
but also it's biased towards in such a
way that when it's going above or it
when it's climbing the the gradient of
the nutrient or the chemical it actually
likes it has a lower probability of stop
and reorient so the biased r more well
ended up help the bacteria move uh to a
higher concentration of the of the
chemical that it actually
likes
so ponus is a well annotated strand is
one of the F uh this is resultant is one
of the first fully sequenced bacteria uh
plant pathogenic bacterium thanks to
that we can fully transfer the knowledge
we know on eoli and all other IIA uh
about this chemotaxis regulation into
this strin now this is a very
complicated system and I won't go into
much detail about it but all I want to
show here is that we know what these
genes are in our genome and we can find
them by any kind of like screening uh we
have so let's touch a little bit on what
motility can do in general the most
basic function of motility in any
bacteria is try to get to different
different location where there are
nutrients present and on the it's kind
of like the two sides of the same coin
that you can also kind of get away from
your clone mates so as a group of the
same identical strands you are evading
competition with your king and that way
your group in general or overall will
have a higher efficiency at uptaking
nutrients to into your organism and help
with reproduction and so on or other uh
important functions so as I elud to a
little bit earlier our group has been
working on the bacteria using its
motility to evade plant immunity so one
other motility what other functions can
motility achieve in a plant pathogenic
bacteria well in our example the plant
uh thisas result and getting to plant
apple plast and the challeng is face in
there is that the PTI is detecting it uh
the PTI is detecting using feling and so
on so that adaptation as our lab has
previously found uh is that it can use
LG to downregulate motility as well as
fla synthesis there you can apply the
same logic to other locations where the
plant pathogenic bacteria can land on
such as Leaf surface before they enter
the aplast uh Steve Lind group uh in UC
Berkeley has previously found that some
of the challenges plant paic bacteria
can face on top of leaf surface includes
it is has it has very unevenly
distributed nutrient and as we all know
as plant uh if you're ever taken a 3010
or 4010 you know that there's also very
limited entrance into APO Plus for any
bacteria pathogen of uh plant so that
could potentially be mitigated by kot
taxes there has been literatures showing
that
bacteria can use some kind of organic
acid as a signal they're tracking to
find those natural openings and wounds
well but there are also other known uh
challenges that are present on the plant
surface such as the extra environmental
hazard from the sound the UV lights and
also civil lindos group has also shown
that there's very high osmotic stress on
top of that uh and another thing that
haven't been discussed a lot in the
literature is on top of a PL surface you
can have the competition with the
epified microbiome and we don't yet know
a whole lot about what the bacteria is
doing to deal with or to cope with those
challenges but as a small spoiler I
think we have found some evidence in our
screening and uh later I will show you
the data that they might have uh some
mechanism already in place for
that uh in addition to that I'd like to
show you also introduce to you the idea
that the disase resultant is a social
bacteria in that it it engages in social
behavior such as cell cell communication
here I'm showing you that it does hover
our a typical Corum sensing system uh
this is how the bacteria is most
famously known to interact with its own
species as well as some other species
and they can co-ordinate expression of
genes and so on and this is result also
engaging production of public goods such
as surfacant and such th four so here
you are show seeing the typical or the
most uh famous yellow pigment p in in
our
stren so with all that I like to present
a question I uh I like to discuss today
uh that is what eological functions can
this isant achieve with this motility
control because now we already kind of
know it can do a little bit of you know
dealing with the host uh maybe help with
this virulence and such
and with that I'd like to present the
first two chapters of my
thesis the first project I want to get
into is a TNC based screen of noble
swimming mtil gen in this this is a
collaborative project between our lab
and the philal lab uh mainly with uh Dr
Tyler Helman who joined us a couple
years back as uh a post do so at the
time we already know that we want to
find novel motility Regulators in this
3,000 because because the LG we have
done a couple um screenings with the LG
project and with various success and
Tyler at the time joined us with a very
powerful tool that is
TNC so what exactly is TN well TS in its
essentiality is asking the same
questions over and over again across the
genome that is if a strand has a point
mutation in this is introduced by
transposon insertion in a given Locus in
genome does that strength grow Better or
Worse under any type of environmental
selection you impose or not
impose so you can imagine that we have
two strands here each represented here
uh those black dashes represent their
relative abundance or how many copies
there are in a population the first
strand we have here has a copy uh has an
insertion on the tip of G A and the
second strand we're talking about here
has a insertion that at end of the g b
so what you can do here is you can pull
this Library population pull them and
let them go through some kind of
selection and after they grow you can
sample the posterior or the after
selection population and then count the
relative abundance of the copies of each
of those strands and with that you can
see that g a in this uh hypothetical
scenario it's abundance decreased after
the selection whereas g b remain more or
less the same and with that we can say
oh G A the loss of function in G A is
not is preventing the growth of that
strand under our selector uh under our
selection
criteria so with that we can scale it up
and make it a full
screen instead of just one strand
purging you can have multiple
now and so for each one of those strands
you can calculate the relative abundance
of the the before and after our
selection in the in the final in the the
respective populations and with all of
those strength inness or the strength
relative abundance you can calculate the
gene average thinness so that will be a
ratio that is either below one equal to
one or above one and this helps us to
establish a link between a gross genome
type to a Gene's function to uh a Gene's
contribution to a selected function and
this selection is totally arbitrary we
can manipulate it as we
want um and ttler come with us uh come
to us with this method as well as a
library that has been generated by Dr uh
Jennifer Lis in UC Berkeley which has uh
been mapped but hasn't unfortunately
been published
uh and another note here is that uh in
the data I will present you in the
following slides those ratios will be
converted by log scale so everything
that's below one will now be negative
and everything above one will be
positive well so now we have this
powerful tool the next thing to figure
out is how we do we link that to
motility because we're essentially
interested in motility contributing
genes well the at the time when I join
the lab
this method of using soft hour swimming
media to quantify the swimming phenotype
is already long established in the lab
and also it's a standard uh method in
the field so what you do here is you
just inoculate your bacteria strand in
the middle of a 3% aror plate in this
case I'm showing you a minimal medium
that is Mob spaced uh and you let it
grow for this is resultant in this
particular media con uh recipe it really
takes 48 hours for you to get to the
size of decent measurement and if we're
dealing with some kind of mutant that
does not actually uh move or somehow
have impaired motility it the colony
simply does not expand from the
inoculation point so the logic of this
essay is that the low motil low motility
strength cannot move far from the
ination
point so how do we incorporate that and
the TNC method to make a
screen
well the most easy thing to do is just
like BR force and fuse them together so
well that's what we started doing um so
we take the library culture and we make
an inoculum from that which is easy and
we take the time zero sample as you do
in all TNC experiments and you and we
just inoculate and let the swimming
asset go with a library so this is a not
a single strand but a pool of bacteria
strands that each has a single mutation
somewhere in the genome and we let them
grow we sample everything that's in the
red circle which is a whole colony and
then we use that as our samples to
repeat this process or we just uh and in
addition to that we also keep a sample
for DNA extraction and
barsic so in that you can see that the
selection we're imposing here is not
much it's just the growth in the media
recipe we provide them and as well as
the swimming
Aur so the the expected hits we are
looking for here is that we're looking
for nutrient restrictions because this
is a minimal medium and also metabolism
genes that help them going through those
nutrient um but we're also thinking
because this is a
this is a neutron limiting environment
so motility will help in this case and
we're not sure how many of those we will
find so let's just roll with this and
set up a
baseline but in the end what we found is
we actually hit a quite a lot of
motility genes so here I'm showing you
uh the four tiers of th motility
regulation that is present in origin
sudon orosa and I'm transplanting that
here uh in this is resultant genome so
here you can see some of them are in
white those are the ones that are
missing homologues in our strand uh the
ones in Gray are the ones we didn't find
in our mutant Library uh at all and then
the red ones are the ones that we found
across the seven replicates we did with
uh seven total passages we did if at any
any point of time they have a
significant penalty for loss of function
so that means those strands with if the
bacteria has a lot of function in any of
those genes they're not growing or we're
not P getting them from the final
samples uh black means the the ones uh
black means exactly opposite of that
meaning that they are always uh being
recovered so we found total 34 out of 47
uh of this and that is pretty nice but
also we're still facing the problem that
we need to distinguish them from the
nutrient restriction genes and
Metabolism
genes so to counter that uh after long
time of trying to figure out what to do
uh I came up with this scheme which
turns out to be I I think it's intuitive
at least is that if we add another layer
of selection what if now I select
against motility if the bacteria if the
environment itself is selecting for
motility and I then add an arbitrary
selection against motility doesn't that
mean only the motility genes will
respond to this selection they are still
growing in the same Neutron condition
and all so they should though if those
genes are having high M uh finish
phenotypes they should be present in
both groups but if there is a difference
between those two selection schemes
those should be the response I detect
from just the motility contributing CHS
so we want with this uh model and the
first thing we expect is well now we're
selecting against motility so the
motility should decrease on population
level and voila they did uh which is
pretty neat and when we then look into
how the finish for genes are behaving
across these
passages we found a very clear
split uh that when we're selecting for
everything the population kind of
evolved this way and when we're
selecting just for the uh non motal
population in the middle of the plate
the population evolved in a very
different
trajectory so what do we find so so this
is a good start we think we're hitting
something so we look into the highest uh
finish values or finish phenotypes we
have in all the all of these lists of
genes and we found three groups of them
that are behaving very differently the
first group represented by the
chemotaxis genes uh QB and kyy these are
known chemot taxis uh motility
contributors they have a fness that is
lower when the whole con is passage when
the plate itself is selecting for modil
but when we then added the extra layer
of selection they reverse back their
finish to be positive meaning now losing
those genes are not as bad for the
strengths once select for low motility
the second group represented by FL motor
genes mode a and mode B uh do the exact
opposite their response is flipped and
that is still a mystery to us why they
would do this uh and then the third
group of genes which I think most of
this audience will be interesting is why
we hit HP three equation CH uh they are
active and they are having a positive in
scores in either cases meaning that
they're on in this uh minimal medium
situation but mob's minimal medium is
not the Euro hard minimal medium pH so
we're very curious why they're actually
on here U and we tested them they didn't
BR do anything to motility
unfortunately uh and those three groups
when we plot out every Gene and their
respones across all our passages you can
see a very clear split of this
Rears so because we have so much so many
more questions about the second and the
third group of genes we ended up
focusing on the chemotax genes because
we know what their phenotypes should
look like once we go into individual
mutational study of this
genes and the three members uh other
members of this group are pspd 46 which
is a cyc GMP enzyme so this uh kind of
like links it to multil in its nature
just by what we know about cyen p and we
find that well indeed you have a
phenotype where you knock it out and
it's slightly uh it impairs motility and
when you complement it back the motility
come back a little bit not fully but
partially also this is a overex
expression instead of its natural
promoters uh T 42 is another interesting
one because this is anti-ma factor for
oxidative stress that has been shown uh
uh by the previous member of philal lab
and it has not really been link to
motility or confirmed to link to
motility in the past and we found it has
a very clean impaired motility by now
Cod and overe expression at completely
restor the mtil phenotype here so that's
telling us that there are linkage
between stress response and motility
control the Ecology of it we don't know
yet and then the outb of Mo the
hypothetical protein pspto
429 absolutely stunning result in that
knock out knocking it out does not
really do that much it slightly impairs
motility but when we overexpress it it
abolishes
motility so very odd and we don't know
anything about it that's where we get
SRA acted into go for in on
40229 um so this is a hypothal protein
as many of them are their small proteins
that it has total amino acid
273 it has a only annotation on the
protein is hdod domain from 23 to 210
which does not tell you really anything
hdod domain is such a general term that
incorporates all kinds of functions it
doesn't really contain much information
and I'm showing you a kind of a model
here so we tried a whole bunch of
methods trying to figure out what this
protein is doing the one that ended up
working for us is error P PCR so this is
we generate another Library well that's
a lot of Library generation within one
talk there's one more um so we generate
a library of sequence each with few
single point mutations by aror Point PCR
so this is you're trying to use a
different polymerase and so on trying to
get error sequence happening during PCR
and then we fuse that we put all of them
into our expression constructs and ask
them to perform uh on swimming media so
what happens there is because we know
the while type 429 overe exer phenotype
is complete abolishment of motility is
very easy to screen for them and we
ended up getting 40 different plasmids
that are uh having fail to suppress mtil
phenotypes um so here I'm showing all
the sequence we got amino acid sequence
we got that are still fallen and uh I'd
like to divert your concentration into
the conservation plot here in yellow
these are where we found among those
Fallen sequences that are having
mutations from the wild type which is on
top uh and also we use this tool called
scan it which can predict protein
protein interaction by just inputting
amino acid sequence that is recently
developed and that gives us a prediction
on each uh amino acid residual How
likely they are involved in protein
protein interaction and we indeed find
the highest uh predicted interacting
side is kind of like aligning with a hot
spot here so we went in and we did the
mutation we replace those two arginines
that are being flagged out with
allings and we found that the phenotype
is
gone so great now we know there is an
important residu for this suppression
phenotype uh the ecolog of it again no
idea so what have tell you so far for
just one of those uh for the first
project is that one TN is again very
powerful as Lori told you a couple weeks
ago and as long as you can select a
function this is a tool that can get you
most of the Gen you're interested in or
give you great candidates uh second
swimming motility in this can be
co-regulated by stress response uh with
no previously known connections to
motility uh 4229 has a dominant
suppression FAL on motility it's
swimming but as additional note it's
also swarming I didn't show the
phenotype here uh and yeah because we
know nothing about the ecological
significance of this there's a lot more
study to do uh if we want to follow up
on them so I hope this has picked some
of your interest in motility because the
next story is going to be a little bit
more wild than
this um I'm showing I don't know how
much it's showing here but I'm showing
you a very weirdly shaped disas Colony
here and this is something we found
almost
coincidentally or by accident uh back in
the days and this is a socially induced
disas res swimming motility we call
beted
expansion so back when I joined the lab
uh Brian and Kar was interested in the
phenotype when you put two colonies of
the same species bacteria onto swim
media they somehow form this Gap and
they don't they behave slightly
different than they were if they are
growing along so I was uh I had the job
to replicate this phenotype uh a bunch
of times and in doing that we also
incorporate the interspecies
interactions as sort of like a a second
control for these
phenotypes so in doing that what I
realized is sudas is doing something
weird when sudas is paed again deia on
third day or uh paired with eoli or
zenonas on fifth day you start to see
the colonies are doing something uh on
this edges that are closer to the
interaction partner and I was very
interested by this I don't know what
they're doing but I want to study it so
I try to standardize it the problem is
this colonies are not really
standardized this one is on day three
this one day five day five
so I need a way to bring them to a more
comparable level so my solution I
because the strands were using uh our
model strands and our strands with more
genetic uh resource wisdom I was able to
get non motal mutants of them and
standardize this phenotype to such so
you can see that when you have a unated
control of disas result and is more
regular uh is radial and a uh symmetric
whereas when you have a EOL bait here it
start to behave non symmetric uh the
same with DK but when you put another
disis result and as it's interacting
partner here it's back to being
radium so great now we have a
standardized phenotype I can start to
quantify
this the first thing we quantify is how
much grow they are having on each side
or how much the bacteria Colony
expanding on each Direction regarding
the position of the bait so here you can
see the blue uh lines here represents
the proximal because it's Crossing well
to the bait uh and the red uh is the
disto because it's away from the bait
from the both stars and the inoculation
point and the quantification of that uh
is laying up here you can see that with
eoli or dekia as a bait the overall
Colony expansion is up but within the
two sides of the colony the proximal
especially is induced by the presence of
a
bait and we can we later uh we recently
come up with this actually is to trace
the colony edges and then just overlay
them to show that there is a significant
difference in how the colony morphology
is happening so here you can see that
even with uh control plas made so
they're growing slightly slower than the
previously shown uh you still have the
extra growth or expansion on the side as
is close to the bait proximal to the
bait so the next question I had for this
was uh is this cimot taxes because it
looks very much like Chim tax to me for
two reasons one is directional kot taxis
is always directional and two we
observed uh in many of our replicates
that if you're the the closer location
of a back single bacteria is located or
of a colony this this resultant colony
to aate you seem to get stronger effect
so those are chemotaxis like features of
what we're seeing here however we our
collection of chemotaxis mutants are
usually nonmodal which means you just
don't get motility and you can't really
use them to test whether they are behind
this phenotype so the next thing we
could do was to test for
inducibility so the idea of that test is
if you have a chemotaxis like Behavior
where it's tracking some kind of
accumulable s chemical signals or
depletion of that you can just let the
depletion or accumulation happen for
longer and then that should provoke even
stronger
response and we kind of find that uh
this is a Pyon I'm showing with Aria
amalo
e273 as a bait and you can see that this
bait here has been in alculated 20 4
hours before the disase resultant colony
is inoculated on the right you have a
bait that's the same species of aronia
that's inoculated at the same uh time
Point as your disas resultant and you
can see a very clear Behavior difference
this one has stronger diff uh
Behavior we can also replicate that uh
with the tracing but with ecoi it still
provokes a very different back uh Colony
morphology but in this case is more
lateral expansion so it's more on the
sides of the
colony so with that our conclusion here
is that it is something that's
accumulating it's either accumulating of
a signal or depletion of a signal but
it's accumulable in its nature the next
thing we did here is we're interested in
what is the driving force for this
Behavior to manifest and at the time we
have two hypothesis we it can be either
gross difference so maybe this part is
growing more or it is a major uh
motility difference and to test that
what I ended up doing is I ended up
cutting the plate in half so that
separates the plate whole plate into two
sides one is proximal to the bait the
other is distal to the
bait and I'm curious where whether those
two parts of the colony are actually
having similar amount of viable
cells so we did the
test and indeed when a colony is baited
the proximal side is having more viable
cells than the digal side whereas when
it's just a normal Colony growing on own
that didn't happen but very very uh to
our like biggest surprise here is that
we couldn't detect the immediate finish
benefit of doing the behavior because
the total viable El in the colony is not
significantly
different so that push us more laning
towards this is a motility phenotype
rather than a gross
phenotype so we recently uh with the
help of the new fancy microscope we got
we were able to look at that more
closely uh under that and here I'm
showing you on the top uh so in this
panel the bait is is towards the left on
the top I'm showing you the sampling uh
the field of view that's fixed
coordinate on the proximal edge of the
population and on the bottom is on the
distal and you can see that on the
proximal you have uh so the this is 3,
here is Tagg with gfp and you can see on
the proximal Edge you have faster growth
the intensity changes over the 90
minutes course a lot whereas on the
bottom there's not
much uh but also you can see the
movement of the cells so I it might be a
little bit hard to see on this
resolution but uh the first Y Line is
where I marked the initial Edge uh at
the beginning of 48 Hours post
inoculation is and the the what this
line here is where I could our larger
our higher resolution find the edge of
this this Colony uh the same is for the
bottom so the short of the story is over
90 minutes of observation the proximal
Edge moved about 600 microns whereas the
bottom Edge uh the the distal Edge moved
only like less than 200 Micron so we're
seeing that there is a movement
difference
here well since we're seeing that much
difference in behavior of those two
edges we're now interesting if we can
find any genetic genetic mark for them
so the approach we took here is we want
to sample those Edge populations and see
if we can find uh a transcriptomic
difference and indeed we do so here I'm
showing you exactly where we sampled on
each plate we used the most distal Edge
or the most proximal Edge to aate within
our disant colony and with wrong our
withle
and at the end of day what we found is
the proximal edges that are most close
to eoli bait and the proximal Edge
that's most close to a dek bait are
behaving very very differently than all
the other edges we were able to sample
and those edges kind of mix together
which is more clear on this PCA plot so
you have the deia in blue and Eola in
this red uh eclipse
so the biggest uh so we went into the
list we think we found something and we
want to is a list of differentially
regulated gen the biggest uh F change we
found was with this hypothetical Gene
another hypothetical Gene pspto
5639 does not have any information but
in the very close neighborhood we also
find this more aging and we were able to
confirm both of them are indeed uh
induced in that popul in in the proximal
population towards a bait
uh by qrtpcr
so what does that do more a it is
annotated and we know from it annotation
that it incles mum co-actor biosynthesis
protein a it's also a gtps for what we
know uh Moco is a highly conserved uh
function across bacteria species and
also across kingdoms so even humans and
uh plants have Olin co-actors they're
involved in Redux enzymes and also uh
those are involved in global softare
nitrogen and carbon Cycles Mo a again uh
additionally Mo a was the only heat
among all the RNC data we have uh within
this moal function within all the genes
that are linked to mum co-actor
function so well but we're genetics what
can we do we knock it out
and find out that it somehow mitigates
or eliminates the
phenotype but when you put it back you
have the extra growth as you can see the
tiny like w type control here when you
add it back by OV expression that extra
growth come
back so great Mo a is our
guy but is it the gtps part or is it the
moal part
because GTP interact with GTP that also
can potentially interact with cycl digp
so we're really curious which uh
approach did it take to actually
influence motility and in this case our
Behavior so we look into what's in the
moo
bensis and uh this is a moo bensis genes
in coli and we picked another essential
Gene for this file synthesis function we
picked MOA which is the last in the step
of moo assembly where it in insert the
mum actually to the co-actor
complex and we did the genetic thing
again by knocking it
out and again we were able to see this
phenotype or this Behavior disappeared
when we knock it out and come back when
we overexpress
it so great now we know moo is our guy
instead of just Mo a so what I have told
you so far is that uh in this chapter is
that swiming motility is socially
inducible and the behavior Rec call beta
expansion is tracking some kind of
accumulable uh signals be it's the
actual accumulation or depletion we also
know that beted expansion results more
from motility rather than growth uh from
our extraction or viable cell counting
assay and last but not the least moo
contributes to to the development and it
seems to be essential to the whole
behavior and now we enter the wild
speculation
word is it just me or does this look
like a charge to you
too like this looks very aggressive to
me right so we don't yet know that much
about its ecology we have speculations
here and one of our speculations is that
this is a competition behavior and it's
trying to get closer for either
territorial rench or getting into a
closer position to initi to initiate one
of the uh cell cell interaction
mechanism such as type six secretion or
actual cell killing we have no
information of those genes being uppr
regulated in our RC data at all not type
six not any like toxin production or
anything like that but we cannot rule
out ones they together they might do it
um but again this is just fascinating
and I've been looking at this and think
of this for last six years and we still
haven't cracked it
yet um so as a as a summary I hope uh
those materials have pick your interest
in motility in our very uh closely
studied disease resultant bacteria hope
you that help you appreciate that
motility regulations can respond to
social interactions as well well as
environmental stress and there's a lot
more ecology to be studied in this
system uh with that I like to thank uh
the past and coverent Steve uh swingle
lab members our collaborators Dr Jan
leis Dr T Helman Po in the audience uh
and uh the Cornell T-Rex and BRC that
helps us with a lot of the sequencing
stuff we do i' like to also thank my
committee members uh and everyone that I
interact in the office daily as well as
uh the amazing postdoc and uh graduate
student body uh I'd like to make one
more comment I have a bunch of friends
who told me I'm the like happiest
graduate student they ever
seen um and I think that's largely
because I'm inan this amazing community
and I work in amazing lab um and with
that I like to have my birds take
question from me but I will speak for
them so any questions for eigor Josh so
in your the second part of the talk
bacterial baiting and such the ones that
it's swarming towards or charging as you
put it at the end can it eat those
bacteria and or if you mix them together
or Co inoculate at the same time or put
them really close to each other does the
pseudomonas kill the like eoli or
whatever else is there so we have done
some m is oh okay so the question is if
we just co- inoculate the two bacteria
together are there evidence of uh
killing happening uh we haven't been
able to observe any like killing with
like stance and stuff uh yet we were
able to see suppression but if we co
inoculate in liquid culture but that
could also just be neutrient competition
uh instead of active killing we don't
have a lot of evidence on or we we have
very few evidence on that actual toxin
production or anything is involved in
these interactions so our main
hypothesis right now is that it's a it's
a competition Behavior but it's on the
level of exploitive competition where
it's just trying to grab more nutrient
for
yourself
loric really great talk um I had a
question about uh your TNC data um so
you pulled out these like type three
secretion signals do you think um um
since this is like I guess a social
interaction like do you think there's a
possibility of uh like another way that
you could look for things that might be
signals that are going between cells
presumably those would not come out of a
TNC because they'd be like shared among
the population but like can you is there
some other way you could look for like
what those type three secretion signals
are like what they're signaling or what
they're sensing or whatever yeah so the
question is is there alter alternative
message to screen for or look for like a
signal that is being transferred in
between the bait and the and the Dison
Colony our lab has done something before
trying to go like you know Mass back and
stuff like that uh we didn't really get
anywhere with that um I remember one of
the so that happened when I was do
honrad I think and uh the another GR
undergrad at the time Mel who was
working on this and I remember the
comment he made was there's so much
processing in so so what he was trying
to do was trying to extract the gel in
between the colonies and trying to
figure out if we can find something in
there u i remember the comment back then
was though they were super processed
like there are so many layers of
processing that he was pretty negative
about like potentially finding anything
and I don't think we ended up finding
anything I was gonna say like do the the
secretion genes you found do they do is
there is there anything known about what
they're transporting like that help get
at that at all the secretion genes I
found are there any information about
what they could be so for the social uh
motility so MOA a is not not a secret so
malum co-actor in general are not well I
think all of them are not secreted
they're
cytoplasmic so we don't that actually
didn't point us to any directions that
leads to like a potential secreted
signal into the into the space I guess I
was talking about the the hits from your
TNC your your type three secretion hits
oh okay so that actually does not
involve in does not relate to the
motility so social motility yeah Adam
question typ you got in that hit you
said you were surprised by those hits
because those genes aren't even
expressed under those conditions did you
confirm that they're not
expressed uh we were okay so Adam's
question is were did we confirm the type
three secretion genes were uh active in
the uh mob's minimal media
condition we did not going to that rout
so when we found that uh the type
secretion type three secretion genes are
there what we did is we pulled out all
the mutants we have on types three and
did motility assd with them and we found
that they weren't really affecting
motility so the only other explanation
is they were on and they were taking a
toll on the metabolistic or on the
energy for the bacteria so that their
growth might be negatively affected by
having them there that's what that's our
hypothesis for why we might have those
hits Zoom
chat a lot of congratulations thank you
all um but no
question no further questions let's
than this has been a production of
Cornell University on the web at Cor
l.edu