so in this video lecture looking at the
13 major characteristics of
handwriting i stress major
characteristics you can get down to the
details as we see pictured here
but we're going to get kind of at the
broad and look at some examples
of the major characteristics in
handwriting also great to look at your
own handwriting
well the statement for comparison is
going to be jack and jill went up the
hill so we're going to keep this
consistent
through the samples we're going to look
at through these 13 different
kind of methods of comparison so these
kind of characteristics that we're going
to be looking at they're all listed here
i'm going to go through them
so hopefully you can stick along stick
around and pause the video it's
encouraged you can kind of
look and compare to see what you're
looking at for these
13 major characteristics we'll start
with the first one look at
line quality well the letters are the
letters erratic are they shaky or do
they flow
you can see an example of smooth shaky
or nervous or juvenile
and or or deliberate here so
these are just different line qualities
to be looking at
the degree of smoothness shakiness or
kind of deliberate writing
that the person may have done you also
have word and letter
spacing so what's the spacing of the
letters now
uh this example right near me we see
this kind of generated on a computer
form
but is the spacing between the letters
uh between the capital letters and the
smaller letters is there a consistent
pattern that we see that
space between capital letters space
between word formations what is that
spacing
again these are characteristics we're
looking at in someone's handwriting
sample
we also have letter comparison as well
as
size consistency how does the ratio of
height and width compare
are they consistent are they consistent
or are they inconsistent
how's the height of the overall writing
it's the height of the tall to the short
letters is there evidence of diminishing
strokes it kind of gets smaller as you
go through or as it increases you go
from left to right here all things again
to be
comparison and looking for consistencies
looking at someone's pen lifts is the
writing continuous or does the writer
lift the writing implement between
words not only between words but
sometimes between the different
letters you want to consider how often
are they picking that pen
up and moving it to the next letter or
word as we can see here
uh we can see this kind of joining
that's occurring here
between the letters of the same word but
there is a space
again between words some people will
break that kind of between the capital
letter and a lowercase letter there's
definitely a space there
there's a pen lift there as we would
call it then connecting strokes or
letters so our the capital layers
lowercase letters connected or
continuous or not as i mentioned before
we can see some of that
um also pay attention to how the first
letter starts and also how the last
letter ends is there a flare
is there a direct line at the end they
had a flourish it's called is your
abrupt
ending is there kind of this kind of
stroke kind of begin
to flourish to start the word um start
the letter i should say
so you're looking at kind of where are
their connections where are their
strokes in their letters beginning and
ending strokes leading to the
page placement so when we're looking at
where do the letters begin in relation
to the space
provided on a piece of paper now if
there's no lines that can
increase the variability that you may
see but where does the letter begin on
the page are they starting at the same
point
are they starting in the middle is
starting where are they starting how far
are they spacing it from the edge of the
paper that they're writing on
letter formation cursive and or printed
so are there any consistencies within
this
are the letters printed are they written
in cursive is there a combination of the
two
so often it can be seen how are the
letters oriented to these slants are the
angles are they
upright all again factors to be
considering
shading and also the pen pressure so we
can see this
large variability here as far as
is the pressure equal or unequal when
applied to the upward and downward
strokes
do you notice a pattern are there
consistencies are they putting more
pressure initially than
lighting up as they're going through
writing it's because is it the other way
around
again these are attention details that
will allow someone who's analyzing
handwriting
to be able to pick out some of these and
make comparisons or find similarities
that other people may not be able to
find or see
also the slant we talked about is there
a slant to the writing
in general you can use a protractor
music determine the degree if you want
to get to that level of
specificity but does it favor the left
or the right or is it variable
again consistencies within the writing
are important
baseline habits so how does the text
relate to the lines in the paper
it's written eyes above or below the
line are there consistent patterns are
they
very key about staying on the line and
having for example the p
drop below are they having some that
travel below they're having
some that drift above all these baseline
habits
are often consistent that you may see
flourishes or embellishes that i hinted
to before
are there additional curls or loops
added to the letters how fancy is the
writing
are there certain letters that this
handwriting has consistent
flourishes or embellishments on and
other letters that do not have that
again a pattern you might be able to
pick out and notice
placement of the crosses on the t's and
dots on the eyes
it's simple as it states here how are
the t's crossed are they in the
high or the middle or in the low portion
of the t
how are the dots of the eyes place are
they left right are they centered
um all things to be kind of considered
here we could see some extreme examples
here are they
kind of are the dots of the eyes a
little circle are they a true dot
where's that dot placed the dotting of
the eye
can be quite interesting when the dot is
precise it indicates order attention and
concentration by the author
an i without a da or a dot incorrectly
drawn indicates a lack of attention by
that
person or a kind of negligence by the
author were they in a rush
could that play into it as well in the
crossing of the ts
some of the characteristics there when
investigating the t how the two main
areas the stem and the t-bar
several characteristics compare the
shape of the stem angle of the stem
what's going on with where it's being
crossed where's that t
placed is it on a slant or not again
things to consider this t-bar
characteristics at least the
uh the height of that where is it placed
on that
what's the what's the progress of the
t-bar is it kind of
favoring a left or right side what are
the dimensions
of the tivo are the directions of the t
bar so as simple as
you know writing the word it i t two
l two letters can really tell a lot
about someone's handwriting potentially
lastly we have the margin formatting so
how much empty space
is left where does the writer leave the
empty space on the page
is it consistent is it jagged is there
an angle to it
these are things again to be looking at
as part of
all of the factors that go into
handwriting
analysis so as you can see it can be
quite varied but if you kind of break
these apart and
pick a handwriting kind of go through
all 13 you should be able to find
some of these unique characteristics and
if you look at your own handwriting
you might find things that you didn't
think you were doing all along