welcome to this tobacco university video
we're going to tackle looking at the
farm bill and the confusion regarding
thc
and how it is defined within the 2018
farm bill so first off what does the
farm bill actually state
well the farm bill has a definition here
the term hemp
that means the plant can visit l and any
part of that plant including the seeds
thereof and all derivatives
extracts cannabinoids isomers acids
salts and salts of isomers whether
growing or not
with a delta 9 tetracannabidiol thc
concentration of not more than 0.3
percent on a dry weight basis
this is how the 2018 farm bill defines
hemp so this makes it seem like only
delta 9 thc
is of concern until you get to another
section
particularly section 297b 2a
i is red which causes the confusion
there's this main source of confusion
here
so what does that kind of refer to what
is that looking at well it specifically
states that a
procedure for testing using post
decarboxylation or other similar
reliable methods
delta nine tetracan ivanol thc again
concentration levels of hemp
produced in the state or territory of
the indian tribe
so what are the typical accepted testing
methods well there's
two there's the post decarboxylation and
then there's high performance liquid
chromatography
hplc so as decarboxylation turned
marijuana
into marijuana and this is looking at
that thca
heating it and then creating that kind
of delta nine
thc here so that he is removing that
carboxyl group
that's essentially that a form of the
thc to get the
delta nine thc so this is important to
kind of make this distinction of this
kind of
variant that does occur so we can take a
look at this
definition here of post decarboxylation
this is a process
which the acid cannabidized
cannabinoids sorry which such as thca
are heated to an active form
this then converts them to a neutral
cannabid
cannabinoids like thc so this is that
conversion of that thc a
to that delta nine thc to
decarboxylate hemp it needs to be heated
to around 220 degrees fahrenheit
for around 30 to 45 minutes of exposure
although that time
does vary as you can kind of see here a
little bit
so this is that decarboxylation step
this is that
cannabinoids converting that thca to
that delta 9
thc so we're looking at that high
performance liquid chromatograph hplc
formerly referred to as high pressure
i'll look at chromatography again
looking is a technique in analytical
chemistry used to separate identify
and quantify each component in a mixture
it's very good at being very precise
about that
it relies on pumps to pass pasteurized
liquid and solvent-containing sample
mixture
through a column filled with a solid
absorbent material
each component in sample interacts
slightly differently with the absorbent
material
causing different flow rates of the
different components and leading to the
separation of those compounds
as they flow through the column what
that ends up creating is
like little peaks and you can think of
these peaks being like kind of a
fingerprint
signature of what that compound contains
broken down into very specific kind of
areas there i mean where there's a peak
you can trace that down and have an idea
what
that compound actually is and what's
present there if you run two different
liquids
they'll give you two different peaks two
different signatures there
so why does the testing method affect
how the law is interpreted
well both testing methods allow for the
amount of delta 9 thc to be detected
however hplc unlike the decarboxylation
step does not need to convert
the thc a to the delta 9 thc
and instead of isolates of the delta 9
thc so you're getting this slightly
different results here
which is what's leading to part of the
confusion so when we interpret the
actual
farm bill as the law recommends post
decarboxylation
but also states that hemp is defined as
under 0.3
delta 9 thc so there's that kind of
controversy there and
because this has led to the individual
states to determine what the law means
and is somewhat contradictory so
it's being defined as under that delta 9
thc
but is that the total thc is there some
interpretation going on in the state
basis
depending on what step or what kind of
process they're using as far as
what thc are they exactly calculating so
there
could sadly continue to be confusion so
the usda has not developed a standard
test for determining the delta 9 thc and
as we saw here
the decarboxylation and hplc do yield
slightly different results there
so until the test that has been
developed there will continue to be
confusion between states and the federal
law
unless further clarification from the
federal government is given
so i know this can be a little bit
confusing but hopefully this provide
with some
detail or some of the science behind the
reason for the confusion
and the potential different
interpretation
of the 2018 farm bill defining hemp