when it comes to outdoor growing
oftentimes questions get asked about
how far should i space my plants what's
my ideal planting date
well here is going to be a trial looking
at hemp cannabis
uh to answer some of those questions and
we presented here on tobacco university
[Music]
so let's look at the 2018 hemp cannabis
plant spacing
in planting date field trial by uvm
now if you're looking to get some more
information on where this information is
pulled from
here's a link to the article and this
study by uvm
answers a lot of questions growers may
have at least provides you with some
research data comparisons again uvm is a
university of vermont
extension they're the original source of
this information
so first off well where are we talking
geographically did this
research where was this research
conducted and we could see here way up
in kind of northern vermont here almost
where kind of new york
vermont and canada all kind of come a
little intersection there
so keep in mind probably a little bit
far north compared to
some other growers but just gives you an
idea again where this was
where this occurred as far as the
different plant spacings
there was a one foot by one foot three
foot by three foot five foot by five
foot with the plant spacings
and here we can see the different
populations of plants per acre
with each of those different spacings
with outdoor research good to have an
idea of the location the previous crop
the planting date fertilization harvest
date
and here that information is provided
also with outdoor locations one of the
great variable
factors is the weather and here while
and it'd be a little different for your
regions it's important to know
that for outdoor locations the weather
is important to know because it can vary
from year to year
and vastly impact the data collected in
here while you may not be growing in
this exact location you can get an idea
what their departure from normal was for
average temperature
precipitation as well as growing degree
days of the months of june july august
september and
october then we're looking at our plant
spacing on
plant weight and also plant height well
the plants in the five foot by five foot
spacing had significantly greater plant
weight
compared to other spacings the average
weight was 9.11 pounds you can see that
right here
vastly different than the two other
spacings that were also studied
the plant heights relatively similar
across all plant spacings
looking at height again measured here in
centimeters
now plants facing impact on flower yield
because that's what we're kind of
looking at
is kind of the yield and particularly
the flower yield
well the five foot by five foot spacing
resulted in the greatest amount of dry
matter flower yield in pounds per plant
this could be correlated with the
highest pounds per plant weight
however the one foot by one foot spacing
resulted in the greatest amount of dry
flower yield
in pounds per acre so again important to
make this distinction between pounds per
plant
and pounds per acre if you're going to
be growing on a very large scale and
you're concerned about pulling the most
pounds per acre
that can slide you to one spacing if
you're limited on the number of plants
you want to have the highest
pound per plant well that might shift to
a different spacing
if you're curious with some more the
detail the data looked like the data
table is provided down here
on this slide and you're welcome to
pause the video
now the planting date impact on plant
weight
and height as might be expected the
plant weight in pounds per plant
decreased as the planting dates became
later in the year
and we can clearly see that with the
planting date of june 14th june 21st and
june 27th
and the plant weight in pounds overall
decreasing from there as you eat with
each
proceeding later planting date from the
one studied
now planting dates impact on flower
yield because again it always comes back
to kind of that yield in the end
it was surprising when averaged across
all plant spacings
there was no significant differences
observed between planting dates
for flower yield however there were
differences noted when plant spacing and
planting date interactions
were investigated so that's just an
important kind of note there that where
where were there differences and where
they're not differences
again see the data here really at the
lsd level of 0.1
no significant difference shown here
now we're looking at our planting
spacing
myself here plant spacing impact and
yield and also
plant weight well the june 14 2018
planting the five by five foot spacing
plants
showed the best yields and highest
amounts of unmarketable buds
on a per plant basis for the june 21st
planting the one foot by one foot
spacing had the best yield and least
amount of unmarkable buds
per acre basis and here we have the five
by
five foot spacing again for the 27th
planting having the best yield and
greatest amount of unmarketable buds
per plant so again looking the data here
we can see the different spacings
different planting dates here's the 14th
the 21st and the 27th
i've tried to provide a little bit of a
summary here focusing on them see the
plant weight
dry matter or flower unmarketable dry
flower
dry amount of flower yield in a
marketable dry flower yield as well so
it's important to take into
consideration
that unmarkable dry flour as well as far
as what might be considered to be a loss
or need to go really to
extraction or be a lesser quality
overall
so the conclusions is that surprisingly
the 5 by 5 foot treatment generally had
the greatest amount of unmarketable buds
per acre on a per plant basis however
this could be explained because the
flower buds were deemed unmarketable
primarily due to soil contamination that
was simply because the plants were so
big
there could be some drooping effects to
occur so it's important
yes it produces produce those
unmarketable buds
but this was a reason why they were
considered to be unmarketable
now as always weather has an impact and
climate variability may
affect the yield benefit for example
comparing the 27th of june planting
compared to that 27th of june planting
the june 17 planting yielded 165 pounds
of dry matter bud
uh per acre more and the june 21st
planting yield did about 488 pounds of
dry matter per bud
per acre more even though it was planted
seven days after the june 14 planting
it yielded more this could be because
june was a relatively cold month for
this
2018 year compared to historical
averages
which may have stunted the june 14th
planting
so again this just kind of shows you the
variability and sometimes the luck of
the draw
when you're looking at outdoor planting
lastly just my
end kind of grower suggestions of we
looked at all this information
you know what can i kind of like pull
from this information what could i use
for this information
well in regards to plant spacing if your
area is
limited size greater plant spacing of 5
foot by 5 foot is advised
to grow larger plants growers are
suggested
to apply more individual care to each
plant to reduce the unmarketable dry
flower yield
however if you're in a growing situation
that your area is not space limited
then a drastic reduced plant spacing to
all the way down to
one foot by one foot will increase the
dry matter flower yield in pounds per
acre
with reduced need for individual plant
care
so again everyone wants to know what the
ideal plant spacing is we can come down
to what the grower's conditions are
as far as planting date goes assuming
favorable weather
mid-june should be the target planting
date to allow for timing with the
longest photo periods of the year
to hopefully retail in the best yields
at the end
so again these are just some grower
suggestions here but kind of that
interesting note
if you're looking at the pounds per acre
or pounds per plant how that will affect
your spacing and that really comes down
to your method or style
of growing so hopefully this was helpful
to digest some of this complex data
to give you some actual suggestions that
you can apply to your field growing
situation