okay in this tobacco university video
we're looking at the 2019 cbd cultivar
trial data summary from cornell hemp
research facility
so there's a lot of great information in
this i'm going to try to provide a brief
overview you're welcome to pause the
video to take a look at some
of the information presented as well as
look in the description for the source
cited uh where you can potentially find
this information for your uh to look at
it even further in more detail
so let's get started first off the
cultivar details
this is a list of all the cultivars
there's 30 cultivars used in this study
that can be seen in this list in
addition the information provided is the
propagation material used which included
dioecious seeds as you can see here
feminized seeds
there's a couple listed and whether it
came from
a clone we can see the clones here now
many people are always looking at you
know we're the source of this
information
and this is the source where these
cultivars
and propagation material was acquired in
addition
if it was grown from seed we're looking
at the percent
germination from those from those seeds
we can see those
listed here something having very high
percentage of germinations some having
very
low percentage the nas are not
applicable of course applied to the
clones because they have no
germination and then we see the percent
female which is very important
now if they're dioecious we would expect
them to be 50 most of them are hovering
around that range
if they're feminized we're looking of
course ideally at a hundred percent
but that doesn't always occur here we
see a feminist seat of 95 percent
that's that means five percent of those
could be male and it's important always
to take a look
and here's the list of the 30 cultivars
again
now that we have the observed cbd to thc
ratio so while the ratios were
consistently between
20 to 1 and 30 to 1 remember it is not
about the ratio but the percentage of
thc that defines a plant as hemp or
marijuana
as noted in this trial most high cbd
cultivars
will not be compliant with the 0.3 total
tc
threshold so it's just important
remember just because it's a very high
cbd producer
it doesn't matter the ratio matters the
amount of thc
produced percentage of tg produced to be
classified as temporary marijuana from a
federal level
the sampling technique so what was
utilized here the cornell researchers
sampled all 30 cultivars
each week after terminal flowering to
track cannabinoid accumulation
they also sample dried and stripped
biomass from all 30 cultivars
because of the consistent cbdtg ratio
cultivars that exceed 7.9 percent
cbd will also exceed the 0.3 percent
total thc because it's a fixed ratio of
cbd to thc
so again just keep that caveat in mind
now we're looking at total cbd and this
is kind of a very interesting
graph here the total cbd and total thc
accumulating curves for all 30 cultivars
are kind of indicated by the colors here
most cultivars accumulate high levels of
cannabinoids by week two or three
the top 10 10 centimeters of shoot tips
were sampled and cannabis were
quantified using an hplc high pressure
liquid chromatography
and then overall we can see a general
trend here of from weeks from terminal
flowering we see that increase
this dotted line represents the total
potential thc
and that represents the 0.3 level of
federal limit
now most most people think that the cbd
and thc naturally correlate with each
other and we see that true in a lot of
the cases
but i want to draw your attention to
these two curves right here
where we see the total potential cbd
peaking early
and then actually dipping as weeks after
terminal flower going on and as those
cbd percentages dip we're seeing an
exponential
increase here in thc so this is where
also it may come
to be important based on what cultivars
you might be
growing or what strains you might be
growing as far as when you harvest again
this is all above that 0.3 level
but in certain cultivars this might be
below that 0.3 level and then
increase later in the season so timing
of harvest
can also potentially play a role
depending on what cultivar you might be
growing again in these examples
this would be all above that 0.3 level
but just something to consider that it
doesn't always correlate
with cbd and thc
now flowering time is strongly
correlated with exceeding the 0.3 total
thc
threshold so what is this showing well
this is a timelapse growing the season
milestones for the 30 hemp cultivars
yet again some cultivars mostly favoring
those early flowering ones
i had two distinct flowering groups
early represented with the
capital e and we can see here's the
early flowering group
cultivars are ordered from the earliest
flowering at the very top here
to the latest flowering down here at the
bottom no offense
late sioux is one of the latest
flowering varieties
the vertical black line here indicates
uh the transplant date of
june 5th day lengths are listed along
the top of the plot at 30 day intervals
here
and what we're noticing is in particular
of importance
sample exceeding is greater than 0.3
percent total thc
and here we see what those that had the
earlier flowering groups
they were much more likely to exceed at
0.3 level at an early
part of the growing season those that
were later to flower
we see a typically a trend here where it
becomes later that they would exceed
potentially that 0.3
thc level there so again just some good
information here to kind of look at
and see the difference that cultivar
selection can make
now in addition to looking at
cannabinoids and
terpenes we also want to consider
disease resistance
so powdery mildew susceptibility there
were significant differences in powdery
mildew
susceptibility by the cultivars the
mccarthy's
site a had more powdery mildew than the
bluegrass lane
site b so overall this site just had
more powdery mildew than the other
data were logged transformed for the
blue s lane farm trial
letters indicate statistically
significant differences between
cultivars based on the post hoc tukey's
hsd
test that's with statistics while we can
look at all the data here what is
definitely an interesting note is that
no powdery mildew was observed on first
light 58. so that is kind of very
interesting it's indicated by the letter
a
here so we can see that all the
different letters again no significant
difference so
there's a lot of cultures that share
that but because
first light only has the a alone and no
other letters
it's kind of a genetic kind of stand out
there where if you have an area with
high powder
mildew you know chance of getting it if
you want a cultivar it's very low
in kind of acquiring that we can see
that these uh
cultivars that have the letter a would
be once initially look at
but definitely early indications that
first light at both
sites basically was observed to have
basically no powdery mildew so again
important consideration there
something to look more into now we have
biomass
and again this would be a great time to
kind of like pause the video here so you
can kind of take a look at the biomass
on the measurements provided this is per
plant averages for biomass measurements
looking at the wet biomass stripped
biomass dry
percent dry and percent strips there and
kind of the differences between the two
so again this gets into a little bit
more of the details of kind of the
amount of biomass
that would be produced you can see here
late sioux again it was one of the later
ones to kind of flower
does produce a very high in comparison
uh
biomass there then we have the
cannabinoid analysis this is where most
growers kind of focus on now cannabinoid
analysis for chemotype 3 which is the
high cbd individuals
note that 7 cultivars also had other
chemotypes 1
and two that consistently exceed that
0.3 percent total thc
threshold the biomass shoot ratio
is the quotient of the average stripped
biomass measurement to the average
last shoot tip measurement i just want
to point out that while a lot of growers
will look at the total cbd percentages
in this column and take a look and see
what they you know can glean from this
but we also want to be mindful of the
ones highlighted in red
are over that 0.3 percent
thc level there and because it's a fixed
ratio typically if we exceed that
0.79 cbd that automatically will mean
we're going to be above that total
thc percentage above the federal limit
but in addition to just the main two
we're looking at cbc
cbg levels so there's a lot of
information here another great data
table to take
a look at pause to kind of do a little
comparison if you've been tracking one
of the cultivars throughout here
and then lastly the cultivar just the
general summaries provided here
for chemotype we typically want to avoid
type 1 and type 3.
we want to look at the flowering date
the cbd yield per plant so we can see
that
here the cbd yield in kilograms and
where
and they do flower now keep in mind
there's a lot of different cultivars
i'm here a lot of different
considerations to take place but
hopefully this provides at least some
initial
information based on actual research to
help guide your decision
making process