welcome to debaco university's 50 000
subscriber thank you video where we're
cultivating students to grow beyond
their teachers
[Music]
so again a special thanks to all 50 000
subscribers to this channel so far
now what does your subscription mean
well it's been
really truly great to see the worldwide
reach of the channel and the main
indicator of overall interest is the
number of subscribers so for those that
have subscribed this simple click of the
button is very much appreciated as part
of this channel the number of people
that value quality education here
provided on tobacco university is highly
encouraging it's been great to read all
of the comments to see where you're
watching the videos from
now again welcome to debacle university
this might be your first video a little
intro video here but it is an
educational based channel and we have
the following main focuses as far as
content areas and playlists go so if
you're here because of one of those
playlists you might want to explore some
of the others or maybe you've got
recommended some of those videos so a
lot of videos here a lot of knowledge a
lot of education hopefully that you find
enjoyable
so why should you encourage others uh to
subscribe well many watch videos to help
solve a problem so you are welcome to
share the content on other platforms
simply encourage others to subscribe to
the channel it's a great way to kind of
help spread the word about the channel
the goal is to continue to this again
spread this knowledge seeing the number
of subscriber account grow is been has
been encouraging it's also quick easy
and free which you really can't say much
about other things i just included kind
of the watch time for subscribers and
this many are not subscribed so
hopefully those that aren't watching
some of these videos can simply just
click that button and help that
subscriber count increase even more
just as a last bit here thank you to all
the debacles out there for all of those
who have and will subscribe thank you