okay here I'm going to go over the five
s workplace organization methodology see
the five parts listed out here and then
explain them each in a little bit more
detail they keep in mind this
methodology of five s refers to five
Japanese terms used to describe the
steps of the five s system for visual
management on the following slides a
tunnel for the American term will be
stated and I will put their Japanese
term in parentheses I will only be
referring to the American term here it
is basically what this is in general
this methodology is having an organized
clean efficient workspace so the first
one is sort and want to sort through
your materials keeping only the
essential items that needed to complete
the task you want to ask yourself what
do you actually need go through
everything and if you do not need it get
rid of it think of it it's like making a
survival kit you know keeping only the
essentials laying everything out do I
need all these different lenses ask
yourself exactly what do you need to
have then they're set in order and
that's organized in and ensure that each
item has a day designated in logical
place maybe you want to keep some items
you typically use more at eye level
though so you use a little bit less that
are light on the top there's a little
heavier here at the bottom location of
the items should be easy to find in
access and also labeling everything
makes it really easy to identify you can
see also here at the bin system locating
all the glue the highlighters the
sharpies the rulers all very nice neat
everything is set in order then there's
shine proactive efforts to keep the area
clean and orderly to ensure
purpose-driven work clean and maintain
the organized workspace that can be also
including an area for cleaning materials
it also be just having everything laid
out very well and efficiently this
convolve routine tasks are just sweeping
the floor removing dead leaves and
performing maintenance on equipment this
is really what causes the operation to
shine the key part to make this work
efficiently is that it's proactive
you're doing this ahead of any potential
issues then standardize when a create a
set of stairs for both organization and
a process you can develop your own
parameters that fit within
other previously described terms they
suggested though that schedules are a
good way to approach this having a
timetable having it by the days of the
week having it by the time of the day
that can be a great way to standardize
things much as we see here with the
pallets for shipping it's a standardized
way to ship large products forklifts are
used and becomes very easy to transfer
that from one place to another they have
sustain and that's sustaining new
practice practices and reflect on your
actual practices to ensure you're
following this 5s methodology the system
doesn't work unless it's continuing a
regular repeated basis over time want to
sustain this method you just want to do
it once and unchanged want to implement
this and in a way that can sustain
itself so that you're continuing with
this efficient workplace environment for
the long term to not only make your
current employees I'll work very
efficiently but anyone that make them in
but might be new can easily pick up the
tasks and fit right in with everyone
else