so you're going to look at some of the
abiotic issues that impact plants
awesome listed here are like extremes in
temperatures it is it cold or heat other
stresses can be droughts Landy heavy
metals and a couple others and I'm going
to discuss here and these are a bad
issues impacting plants these aren't to
be confused with biotic or living issues
so all a Vatican non living many of
these come down a grower error but being
able to classify plant issues in this
category can help it develop in the plan
of Correction and ultimately prevention
going forward these are important things
if you can classify them this can help
you going forward in avoid making
mistakes in the future
also there are nutrient deficiencies so
under fertilizing plans can cause
unwanted stress to the plans which can
stunt their overall growth individual
nutrients have characteristic looks that
can aid in identification of what
nutrient the plant is deficient in so
it's because the leaves are yellowing
that the leaves are certain color it
depends where they might be located but
they can help with the identification of
that nutrient so your grower will know
what to properly feed the plants as far
as food goes to avoid that deficiency in
the future in the opposite of that
there's also nutrient texas cities often
growers will think more is better and
this is not the case the goal is to hit
the optimum range of what the plant
needs watch the exact fertilizers blend
or ratios that you're using because it's
possible for a nutrient to be over added
if a grower only focuses on one nutrient
of interest for example fertilizing for
nitrogen and over adding phosphorus
sweet example here you're using this
fertilizer for nitrogen work focus on
the nitrogen number moritz nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium if we're
fertilizing for nitrogen we could be
over adding the phosphorous so be
mindful of that don't biscuit lock-ins
the walnut ring you're concerned about
look at the blend in the entire amount
of fertilizer in all the nutrients that
it contains hit your plant will be
exposed to you want to have kind of all
your ducks in a row and keep everything
nice and consistent when we're getting
one way out of whack also sun sunburn or
light burn so sunburn often happens when
plants are moved from an indoor to an
outdoor operation are also light burn
this can result when light types are
changed or it can also occur
plant is allowed to grow too close to
the lights I can cause a burning to the
plants really damage the leaves and
apparently stunts most apical meristems
is growing tips of the plant herbicide
or sprayed image in general if
outdoorsman spraying an herbicide to
control weeds and the area be mindful of
the potential for drift small droplet
size and wind will increase the odds of
this you can kind of see that occurring
here while the these particular person
spraying just to here we can see the
drift or the carryover the one is
definitely blowing into this direction
because you don't see a lot of sprayer
is going this way for indoor operations
often growers will mix products too
strong or mix them that are incompatible
or they can even make the applications
during full light intensity of the
canopy which can also cause damage that
could easily be avoided and its damage
is a physical damage this is why it's
classified as a biotic ozone our air
pollution is not typically a major
problem but one it should be taken into
consideration if there's an area of
damage that either it's sudden
widespread with other abiotic category
descriptions not fitting with grower is
seeing typically kind of get this white
or this bleached look to the lot of the
leaves this communicating the potential
of air pollution air contaminant or
ozone damage it's going to occur in
indoor or more commonly in outdoor
operations in general if you are using
an ozone kind of method of odor control
be mindful it's not functioning properly
there's a function if there's something
that's not going right that could
potentially cause some ozone damage to
the plants