here I'm going to provide a brief
overview of the plant hormone abscisic
acid after wondering what this is
pictured here this is an open and a
closed stomata and it's involved in this
process so abscisic acid typically
abbreviated ABA it's kind of incorrectly
named that it's not related to obsession
with its SLOS plant growth so what you
see a abscisic acid please don't confuse
it with a position because it is not
involved in that it's important in
drought stress and other stresses
particularly important for causes these
stomata to close so we see our target
guard cells here if we add a BA or
abscisic acid it can cause cells to
become flaccid through the guard cells
here mr. monitor close so when plants
want to help decrease sir what a loss
abscisic acid can be a hormone that can
be activated to help close this dimana
of those plants in addition sisig acid
prevents seeds from germinating while
they're still on the plant plant doesn't
want to have it to germinate before fall
so the ground can kind of grow and
prosper there so abscisic acid is
involved in that it's also involved in
suppressing seeds from germinating even
when off the plant for example apple
seeds have a very high amount of acetic
acid takes them years naturally to be
able to germinate it's because of their
high optic acid content the Pacific acid
also changes gene expression patterns
and it's considered in return homeland
because it can block the effects of
auxins so keep in mind we have a lot of
these hormones that are interacting with
one another stick acid in one of those
its inhibitory Homan actually suppress
or block the effects of auxins in the
plan