so this video lecture series is going to
talk about something you may have
experience with and that's acne bit over
I do is some of the science and give you
some of that background on what causes
this skin irritation that's very common
so first off I want to provide you with
some resources for some more information
I've pulled some of my information
directly from here and going to kind of
cover it briefly and you're welcome to
check out the scientists for more
information that provided with the links
to their PowerPoint slides first off
remember that acne is one of the most
common skin diseases with about 17
million Americans affected according to
the data and newest research close to
100% of people between the ages of 12
and 17 have acne in genetics do play a
role but they're not the sole or
potentially only cause of this
so people were surveyed about 503 here
and nearly 50% of respondents to the
question what do you think causes acne
said clements of skin many people
believe if they keep clean skin they
won't get acne and sadly this is not the
cases and does not hold true and when I
talk about why that is so what does
cause that was a true cause laugh is
caused by the plugging of alcohols which
is mostly due to excessive sebum
production by sebaceous glands steam
made by the influence of androgens which
are male sex hormones testosterone being
an example I have the oil well here we
have the excessive oil production that
skin characterization a plugin of these
follicles speed up the formation of acne
normal skin bacteria produces irritating
seven-second causing inflammation that's
also external influences such as
friction and also medications can also
be causes of acne caused that to be
worse in some individuals the kind of
quick summary of what acne actually is
it's the plugin of the follicle to begin
with
there's also excessive sebum production
in the presence in activity of the
bacterium pro piane bacterium acnes is
the actual bacterium named ultimately
this will lead to inflammation and that
causes the
redness 2bc looking at diet stress and
acne wasn't controversial link between
diet and acne you know does it cause it
as it influence it although many
patients believe that their acne is
influenced by certain foods Western diet
may be associated with acne there's kind
of that glycemic index
I can potentially be linked to acne but
it's not necessarily as much of our
presence as we may think skim milk may
have some of these in cryogenic hormones
and it could be associated with acne in
teenage girls in particular stress
acting among the university students was
associated with exam stress so there is
a chance that some instances there can
be these factors that may influence it
but it's not I say the main cause of
acne our androgens in acne the male
hormones remember these some of these
male hormones while entitled male
hormones example testosterone are found
in both males and females the reason why
they're called male hormones is they're
found in higher concentrations in males
and these can cause the oil glands of
the skin to produce more sebum which is
more oil and I think that excessive
sebum production can lead to that
increased evidence of acne now there's
two main forms here that can occur to
make conditions that can result in acne
one can be a high hormone level this
increased amount of hormone can lead to
overproduction of sebum - see here hi
hormone level excessive oil production
there's also another condition could be
high receptor level the ischemic cells
overly sensitive to the signal resulting
in high production of sebum so there's a
lot of receptors even there's kind of a
lower amounts of the hormone present
there'll be a lot of binding sites and
that can lead to a lot of oil being
produced resulting in greater incidence
of acne now cause of excessive sebum
production and increase of our inter Jin
here hormonal secretions become higher
during puberty which causes these
sebaceous glands to become larger and
simply produce more sebum remember it's
that ki sebum production that is causing
the main cause of that acne that does
occur in both males and females women I
can have them
Oh cycle being prior being pregnant
starting our ending can take
contraceptive pills which can cause
hormonal changes we can influence them
even further so as I said medication can
cause that certain hormone level changes
can also influence the semen production
which then will result in acne heredity
and against that drugs can also
potentially influence this look at the
variations of acne a very light
condition here little characters by our
whiteheads blackheads example very hard
to see moderate which is inflammatory
increases and becomes more serious and
of course the severe case see here can
also result in scarring in the most
severe cases look at some facts and
causes about acne most people think if
they eat chocolate and greasy foods for
example the nice droplet bar or the
french fries will that cause it got me
to occur well there's no scientific
proof there's a correlation between that
well dirty skin cause acne
well actives caused by acceptors
production of sebum from the skin that
necessary dirt can stress caused
increase after you getting it ready for
an exam or
big tests there is potentially some
relationship there however recent
studies do show these corticosteroids
which are increased during times of
stress may stimulate sebum production
and hence worsen acne so it may not be a
director always a direct cause but these
corticosteroids if they increase that
sebum production that is what then will
result in acne facts about treatment of
acne why do I get asked me
despite washing my face several times a
day well too much washing can actually
irritate the skin further and worsen
your acne so James Lee watching her face
daily with a mild cleanser or soap and
patting it dry can help reduce acne but
excessive washing is actually a bad
thing so we believe this let acne run
its course would be fine well if you
have those severe cases it could cause
scarring
should I squeeze the acne should I kind
of kind of get rid of it that way
well squeezing can actually cause that
in fact i'ma try to go deeper into your
skin and if acne cannot be cured in a
month then should I try other drugs or
treatments well
these are very slow acting which is
again that what people want to hear but
you typically have to wait over a month
to see if there's actual effects because
you try something next week or the week
after didn't work it may take longer for
that to actually activate me see results
lastly the purpose of these acne
treatments to decrease the sebum
production that's the key part here
where we reduce the bacterium reduce
securitisation and eliminate
inflammation dermatologists would be the
best they can combine two or more
treatments to create an effective
therapy to prevent new lesions from
forming so one of the one plus one
equals kind of three here well in
certain cases you can try to separate
treatments you could get a very positive
effect more than just each one
individually so this kind of just
relates to the purpose of acne
treatments each individual is unique and
dermatologists can have more tools at
their disposal have seen more cases and
as a result can suggest the best mode of
treatment for you in your individual
case where if they prescribe something
too may have to wait over a month for it
to work which may not be what you want
to hear but hopefully the goal is that
long term the reduction in serum
production to ultimately reduce your
acne