okay here we are look at active forms of
hydroponic systems the basics of those
often timely require a pump or in some
way to move water that might be
considered unnatural yeah now this is a
a bad thing that's something that we
need to do to make that water move where
we want it to so it's efficiently
delivered to our plants now there's many
more options with active hydroponic
systems compared to those passive
systems whose passive systems rely on
capillary action in a wick here we have
an increased amount of options to move
these nutrient solutions due to the
diverse amount of water pumps that are
available that will be scaled in size to
fit particular operations to maximize
efficiency there are recirculation pumps
in these are systems in place that will
reduce nutrient solution and reduce loss
so it's kind of that recirculation that
kind of recycling of that water however
if the system is not clean and it
includes all parts of the system disease
can spread very fast so for example if
this one container became infected or
recirculating that water amongst all
these containers they could all transmit
that disease and all become infected
because the entire area here of
production to have a plant disease then
there are one-way systems and these
often lead to increased cost use the
waste generated we're kind of pumping
the water one way and that's it it's
going to also cause an area soil or
water contamination keep in mind this is
a lot of times with overhead systems
many hydroponic systems will reuse some
form of recirculation and this is why
cleanliness is so important