so here we look at the adaptive or
sometimes called the acquired immune
system there's a very precise sequence
of steps that goes on and the key part
here is we need to have the immune
system remembering and recognizing and
acting in a very specific manner through
this process or branch of the immune
system if you remember the innate immune
system is the other one that you're born
with and can be thought of as the other
branch of human system so looking
specifically at the acquired immune
system we may have seen this image
before relating to a hormone binding and
having a response that occurs but a very
similar process that goes with the
acquired immune system or getting the
adaptive immune system the first part
would need to have a very specific
recognition of the foreign substances
then occurs to the proteins on the cell
surface this acts to immobilized
neutralize or destroy them then we want
to amplify the inflamed inflammatory
response and active a complement so
what's happening is once we have that
binding occurring we want to destroy
that specific foreign invader but we
want to activate a bunch of other
cellular responses to help increase the
body's response to this foreign invader
and this helps the entire body maintain
high health because once one becomes
infected the body's immune system is
alerted and then this can be spread
throughout so the acquired immune system
technically has three main components to
it the first one is an antigen specific
so here's our antigens
these antigens are a molecule that
provokes a specific immune response
which specific to an antibody so the
antigen is the specific molecule that is
initiating this immune response now in
acquired immune systems is a systemic
process which means it's not restricted
by any region in the body and this is an
example plant we talked about systemic
insecticides or systemic products that
can go through the plant same concept
applies to the human body not restricted
by any work and travel within the body
in the third component to the acquired
or adaptive immune system is
fact that has memory they become
educated cells that remained after the
invader is gone every members and is
able to recognize certain pathogens the
coordinate system the it's two separate
overlapping arms one or B cells and
they're called the humoral immunity for
body fluid and they're thought of i
intact invaders outside the cells I
think T cells which is called sailor
immunity
they attack infected cells so again two
different components both performing
under the same immune system but have
different in separate overlapping arms
there it is most complex and slows to
respond are acquired immune system
because it has to activate cells for
each new invader or antigen on first
exposure takes about ten days to reach
peak levels so this is a more of a
long-term effect it's not an immediate
there is a little bit of a delay in this
recognition process antigens is a macro
molecule that reacts with the component
of the immune system so here's an
example of an antigen the figure above
here shows the entire structure of an
antigen and the different structures
here projecting from the different
shapes and then they're over exaggerated
in this image represent potential
epitopes so a given antigen may contain
several motifs which are recognized by
immune cells in each motif has an
epitope so again a little over
exaggeration with different colors and
shapes but the key part as we learned
with proteins this shape is very
important for recognition and we're
seeing that also the that theme name
continued with the immune system so the
antigen binding say is different in T
and B cells so a t-cell receptor spans
the membrane and projects variable
binding regions into the actors belly
the cellular space binds the process
antigens via MHC major histone complex
here now our b-cells look very different
on just a quick comparisons from as a
branched appearance and this one has a
single appearance where b-cell receptors
are embedded in the membranes of the
b-cells and bind to their variety of
antigens through their variable regions
the signal transduction region transfers
the signal into the cell so you can see
this one goes completely through it has
an intercellular domain this one does
not this one does have the branched
variable regions and soon has a single
variable region they both have antigen
binding sites here and here but the T
cells only have one the B cells have to
think of B's having two bumps and he's
having one lime to help you remember
those these cells are catching the
Gators in body fluids so what they do is
they originate in the bone marrow so B
cells to help you remember the name you
can think of be standing for where they
mature is in bone marrow remember bone
marrow is producing our red white blood
cells and also our platelets interacting
with that lymphatic system so there's B
cells originating they mature in that
bone marrow so getting D cells you think
of bone marrow they circulate in the
blood in the lymph and the response for
catching invaders in the body so here's
our B cell we see through binding
receptors here with our helper T cells
go over in another lecture we're now
seeing we're producing memory b-cells
for the longer term and then plasma
cells here with antibodies strewn about
b-cells are important for recognition so
they want to see identification and this
is why the MHC is part of the receptor
used for that so peripherally plasma
cells produce antibodies you see here
and our memory cells provide quick
response on re-exposure so while
initially might be in a slow process
Patri exposure is where that quicker
response is occurring in the memory
cells so they're holding on for the long
term
lastly our t-cells are destroying a
decklid cells and they are present in
mature in the thalamus here so a way to
help you remember that the original
marrow but they mature in the thalamus
so T cells thalamus T and T event they
develop the ability to identify foreign
agents by antigens presented on the cell
surface so we see our antigen presenting
complex here we
our recognition site you have our
t-cells being involved in destroying
infected cells which are very important
to the proper functioning of the immune
system