okay here we're gonna look at
adaptations and reproductive strategies
here so starting with a life history of
adaptations in general well life history
is a complete lifecycle of an animal you
were looking at the salmon life
histories are diverse with many
different organisms having different
adaptations to their environments chosen
salmon here is they choose to run up to
freshwater streams of - they were born I
can see that they end up spawning in
extremely shallow water concerns is a
fish that spends most of its life out in
the open ocean I just run up to these
extremely shallow gravelly kind of beds
to spawn that's an example of a life
history adaptation to get away from some
predators here it gives its fry or its
small babies here a chance at survival
before entering and spending most of
their lives in the ocean now life
history adaptations there's two main key
ones that we want to focus on there's
something collared are selected and the
next one's going to be K selected so
it's been a moment here on our selected
adaptations these are selected
adaptations or populations that favor
exponential growth model they have a
very high rate of increase and they're
followed by a rapid rate of decrease so
it's kind of like the boom-bust model
here of adaptations where they have a
rapid rate of increase they have a rapid
rate of decrease our selective
reproductive strategies are more
opportunistic they have a short
maturation period and also a short
lifespan example here B the mosquito
there's many small offspring and usually
one early reproductive cycle they have
no parental care and a very high death
rate so you can see that here with
ladybugs mosquitoes would be examples
since the rabbits can improve it
multiplied they're very rapid rate in
the hail massive decrease in populations
in days to more evident here with our
mosquitoes and insects here where we
have a very short life span no parental
care and sadly a very high death rate
now in contrast to that either they are
selected so in contrast to are selected
there's something called
K selected adaptations these are
populations that experience competitive
logistic curve
of growth in the favor of reproduction
near the carrying capacity it's our
general adaptations case selected
individuals have a long maturation in
lifespan the example would be elephants
here are bears and whales they have few
but large offspring usually several late
reproductive cycles did extensive
parental care and as a result of that a
very low death rate so keep in mind idea
to compare case selected adaptations to
the unconscious that they are selected
ones and what animals may fall in this
and why that's a tenth ages for them and
kind of so that what animals may fall on
ok selected and why it's advantageous
for those individuals looking in general
here at parental care strategies most
natural populations exhibit a
combination of the arcade adaptations or
get to extreme examples here so base my
level kind of more are selected and more
K selected we're look at the kind of the
species of barnacles and wasters for
example they can produce about 500
million fertilized eggs per year name
this energy into producing this many
offspring as possible but as a result
they provide no parental care and as
results have very small portions of that
15 million year actually survive species
such as gorillas they only give birth
approximately once every five years
however they miss a significant amount
of time and energy into ensuring the
survival of their offspring so in this
case the gorillas and chimpanzees they
choose to have less offspring but put
more energy into care boys and barnacles
put no energy into care and they just
put all the energy into odds of
producing as many individuals as
possible you can see here the Frog and
the rabbits are kind of more in the
middle here chimpanzees and gorillas we
have one extreme and oysters and
barnacles being the other when it comes
to parental care strategies and both of
these are able to succeed in the global
environment but you could see that their
strategies are very different