here we're going to look at some of the
specifics in regards to adding carbon
dioxide to a hydroponic grow set up
specifically carbon dioxide should not
be added to the water this can adjust
the pH we can affect nutrient
availability to the plants roots need to
respire so they need to actually consume
oxygen and they'll actually give off
carbon taxing themselves so we're
talking about carbon dioxide enrichment
for hydroponics it is not directly
relating to the aquatic or the water
nutrient based environment should be
added to the growing environment as this
can be beneficial not to the water again
with a great control over conditions of
the grower this is a possible to further
maximize plant productivity in addition
to the introduction of carbon dioxide
enrichment I want to make sure that our
nutrients are all lined out where they
need to be we're maintaining a good pH
temperature and EC a parts per million
why make sure also our lighting is
maximized we're getting a good part
level to the plants our timers and
everything is functioning properly both
for our hydroponic pumps and also our
lighting and also I put a picture here
for ventilation so if we're venting the
area we want to make sure we have a
properly matched sized fan for our grow
operation if we oversize the family
could be pulling out the carbon dioxide
that we're going to be carefully and
precisely adding to our operation so is
it worth it well in one word you yes if
you're maximizing other conditions so
keep in mind that if you're just going
to add co2 to get bigger yields that may
not be the case you've got to make sure
your lighting is maximized gotta make
sure nutrients are all dialed in
everything else is going well this is
one way to help increase or lift the
potential maximum yield tank system can
be used if you are using a generator
that produces Heat so keep that in mind
a lot of times with hydroponics there's
enough other pumps running that may also
generate heat Jenners will also produce
other gases as a byproducts this is
again can also increase the moisture
which may be something you do not want
to increase any more in a hydroponic
setup so at the end keep in mind that
come and I said is worth it don't add it
to the water and make sure you're
maximizing all your other conditions and
your venting system is not overly size
so you're not pulling out the vital
carbon dioxide
use a controller and at a timer and if
you should be able to
see some benefit with adding carbon
dioxide allowing your plans to more
efficiently produce sugars