okay here we investigate adenosine
triphosphate or ATP I'm going to see
these three letters used quite a bit so
I figured I should help describe what
this molecule actually is provide you
with a basic picture here and against it
didn't seem triphosphate so you can see
the adenine and then three phosphate
groups but let's look at this a little
more detailed because it is important
for cellular energy so first off
adenosine triphosphate it's a
multi-purpose chemical energy storage
molecule it's considered powers cell to
your work and it's considered the energy
currency of the cell looking at here a
little bit closer
we have adenine molecule a ribose sugar
which you might remember from RNA both
of these carbons are attached to oxygen
and then three phosphate groups reason
why it's at three phosphate groups
talking about ATP adenosine triphosphate
what this shows here is the triphosphate
with all three of those phosphates if
we're talking about adenosine
diphosphate the day there'd only be two
phosphates and mono phosphate there'd
only be one phosphate molecule so again
there's the image from the title slide
and how do all these molecules differ
well a MP and then Essene mono phosphate
has one phosphate group and as a result
the energy from bonds is a very small
amount and the energy stored is minimal
this is kind of the least energetic of
the molecules we then go up to density
diphosphate where there's two we have
more energy and a greater amount of
energy stored in those chemical bonds
and last we have adenosine triphosphate
which has substantial amounts energy and
that's the greatest amount stored in its
chemical bonds this is why we typically
refer to ATP being the energy currency
in the south is the most energy but
realize that ADP and AMD also do exist
so talk about this you know bond energy
well the energy is stored in chemical
bonds of molecules the chemical bonds
over energy stored and when the bond
breaks their energy is released this is
why ATP with our three phosphates has
the greatest amount of energy because as
these high energy bonds only can
these phosphate molecules together you
ever see adenosine diphosphate here so
we need to think about this for is a lot
of electrical charges will the bonding
the phosphate groups to adenine require
considerable amount of energy because
the energy required to kind of compress
a spring together this is the attachment
of phosphate groups and each phosphate
group being another spring that's been
compressed when you break those bonds
getting the spring here kind of letting
go
this is energies released when that bond
is broken so again ATP if you have three
these buttons together we have that much
more potential for energy so the third
phosphate we get adding to ADP would be
ATP same in with am P if we had one
phosphate missing diphosphate and
another phosphate group using
triphosphate the phosphorus is eager to
get away the bond is broken great amount
of energy becomes released energy
available when ATP loses a phosphate so
as we're releasing energy were breaking
that bond running from ATP to ADP or ADP
to AMD the nanp missing mono phosphate
portion the molecules stays the same
adding a third phosphate group or
phosphorylation adds energy think of it
is used the people were compressing that
spring removing the phosphate group
which is released through hydrolysis
it's like freeing and uncoiling that
spring releasing that energy lastly
here's the ATP cycle because I want you
to realize that it doesn't exist
all the time as a TP the phosphate
available cell has an unlimited supply
of energy so as we're looking at
phosphate groups as we're able to break
them down here to form ADP and then
attaching a phosphate group ATP again
we're creating and breaking those high
energy bonds which is going to be used
by this cell
to perform all sorts of necessary tasks
so this energy between a DPM a DP is
contained in the phosphate high-energy
phosphate ester bond when that's broken
energy is released and when we're
attaching that phosphate group we're
creating that potential offer
energy when that is broken