here in this tobacco university video
we're going to go over some mathematical
equations
so you know how to adjust your organic
matter and not just kind of eyeballing
it where you could
add way too much or if you're looking at
purchasing it you might not purchase
enough
all right let's get into adjusting
organic matter in soil
now as i said this will be a math kind
of a base kind of approach
so you're suggested to maybe let me go
through it once
pause it for yourself and then go back
over the information there to apply your
own information to it
so first off when we're adjusting
organic matter and soil we want to know
the present
organic matter percentage in the soil
the organic matter percentage in the
organic amendment we'll be adding in
this case i'm going to use peat moss as
an example as well as compost
and the percentage organic matter
desired in the mix of the two
the volume ratio of the two that must be
combined will be determined as
follows so you have to always start with
that soil test
and having an organic matter percentage
calculated on that soil test
so that is going to provide you with the
letter a here this would be the kind of
equation we're going to go over a is the
current
soil organic matter percentage in your
soil that's based on your soil test
b represents the organic percentage of
the organic amendment
now as i said you can assume you'll be
100 for peat moss
or compost are typically around 25 to 35
c would be the target soil organic
matter percentage after amendment has
been added
we're gonna use about five percent uh
for our target
this will calculate x which is the
fraction by weight of dry soil in the
final
mix and one minus x is the fraction by
weight of dry organic amendment needed
in the mix
we'll also take this one step further
and go from weight to actually a volume
which is what most people
usually purchase things in or tend to
think in so let's look at converting
weights to volumes
well the basic equation is going to be
to convert weights which is x and 1
minus x
to volumes since you know how one will
work with the material
a conversion must be made using the dry
bulk densities of the material to be
mixed
so ps located right here is the dry bulk
density of the soil
and for soil it's usually 1.0 to 1.2
grams per cubic centimeter
and that can also be usually found on
most soil reports
po represented right here is the dry
bulk density of the organic amendment
the dry bulk density for peat moss is
0.15 grams per cc
our compost is typically 0.5 to 0.7
grams per cc
again if you're using a different dry
bulk density for
your organic amendment try to research
and find out what the bulk density is of
that
amendment s and t here s is the volume
of parts of soil material
teas the volume parts of organic
amendments so when you divide
s by t you obtain the volume of parts
per soil per one volume of organic
amendment
so while this is a lot of information
here this is that background
let's go through an example and hope it
makes a little bit more sense here
so here's that example now keep in mind
right below me here
i provide you with what i've shown
before what a b c
x and 1 minus x stand for now i've given
us an example here to work with
this since if we sent our soil out we
get our organic matter percentage at 3.4
percent
we're going to be adding peat moss at a
which is considered to be 100 percent
and our target organic matter percentage
would be 5
so the question becomes how much peat
moss do i need to add
to my soil which is 3.4 percent to get
to that
target value of 5.0 percent or soil
organic matter
so let's go through that well we take
100 minus 5 which is the
b minus a which is the organic matter
percentage of the amendment in this case
pmos
minus the target organic matter
percentage we divide that by 100 minus
3.4
or in this case it'd be b minus c minus
a
100 which is the peat moss which is the
organic amended we'll be adding
minus the soil organic matter the a here
when we take this and
subtract those and divide it by that we
get 9.834
and x minus one is to get the fraction
by weight of the dry peat moss needed in
the mix
which is uh 0.0166
however we want to convert these weights
to volumes because that's typically how
we think
so this is all converted here to get to
the weights we're now going to take this
next step in the next slide to go to
volumes
so here we see the same numbers carried
over
and here's our x there's our x minus 1.
the ps is at 1.1 grams per cc
that would be the bulk density of the
soil and then po is the dry bulk density
of the organic amendment because this is
peat moss
we're using 0.15 grams per cc and we see
here we apply it to the equation right
here
we get our s we get our t we divide our
s by a t
and we get 8.076 so what does that
number
equate to our mean well that means so
you would add about eight parts of soil
per one part of peat moss which
translated would be eight cubic yards of
soil
to every one cubic yard of peat moss to
get to that
target level of 5.0 percent organic
matter
from that original start of 3.4 percent
so hopefully this kind of gives you some
information here to kind of go
through your own and to go back for just
one moment
with all this information here you can
easily find what a b and c
are you could take your soil test
reports apply
that information to this example here
and hopefully develop a calculation so
you'll know exactly
how much how many cubic yards to
purchase to ensure you're getting the
target
soil organic matter that you want
without overbuying or under buying
and this is a lot better than eyeballing
it so take a little time to go over this
it'll be worth it in the end