so here we look at aeration of water
this may come across as really easy see
here we're just kind of pedal system
where we're kind of mixing and splashing
the water around adding oxygen and air
to that water to help keep it well
oxygenated but there's some citizens who
I'm going to describe it to you may not
be familiar with
so first awful large scale if we pumping
water into the air and letting gravity
cause it to fall back creating a passive
method of aeration it could be a really
strong pump I mean really high cost it
to fall back or can we just kind of
these smaller pumps here again adding
pumping it up and learning what kind of
fallback through gravity kind of in this
kind of passive form of iteration which
can be very effective and it's used a
lot for display purposes and fountains
to keep the water aerated in areas that
may be in public display such as parks
at the forum of aeration for growers
commonly used by injecting air into the
water this difficulties is an airstone
we're taking an air stone at the bottom
of the tank
using an air pump to pump water pump the
air down through a tube and then letting
the the air bubbles kind of come through
the water and mixing it that way this
uses oxygen that's naturally in the
environment and this depends on
increasing the water surface contact
with the atmosphere that's kind of how
you're helping aerate the water the
bubbles here are kind of for the most
part passing right through reaching the
surface and tests during that surface
and it's that surface contact at surface
stirring that's occurring that is
allowed an aeration process to occur
something you may not be familiar with
or may have heard of but that related to
this aspect is a use of electrolysis so
electrolysis of water is a decomposition
of water into oxygen hydrogen gas due to
the passage of electrical current what
happens to be of our water and we're
separating out into its hydrogen and
oxygen components by this process
electrolysis this creates very small
nano scale so really really small
bubbles that form how this looks here
and there's a comparison between an
airstone versus taking an active air
pump pumping air through here and a lot
of the bubbles pass through the water
causing a bubble effect here and then we
have the electrolysis it almost looks
like
like a small fog occurring underneath
the water on o2 grows marketed towards
growers in this twin star is also
marketed towards cream enthusiasts they
both kind of operate on the same
electrolysis form versus the air stone
the Oh to grow company they're a
division of oxygen research group and
their technology platform holds four
unique patents with their electrolysis
technique they claim 50% or more
dissolved oxygen and a standard bubbler
other slogans kind of interesting that
says get out of the Stone Age in the
sense that they feel their system is
creating these small nano bubbles
actively oxygen water much more
effectively than a typical air stone
does require a little bit of the setup
there's a cost involved with this
there's electricity required so these
are all things to consider as growers
include to youtube links down here
remember the in the description there's
a link to all these slides and click on
these links and see some of the company
info there I just wanted to provide you
with something when you're looking
actively aerating water prime may not
have thought of electrolysis and it
might be something worth consideration
because of the increased surface area
here of the producing of the native
bubbles if you're really looking at
maximizing the aeration and oxygen
you're adding to your water