if you're interested in learning about
aeroponics
this debaco university video will help
you understand aeroponics in more detail
all right let's look at aeroponics for
cannabis production
well starting off with the basics of
aeroponics
and aeroponics basics are the plants are
grown while suspended in
air with water and nutrients splashed or
misted onto their roots
this system uses minimal water and
nutrients if done correctly
with no reduction in plant performance
now while there are commercial systems
this kind of shows kind of a dyi kind of
version here of
what a grower kind of constructed to
create this aeroponic system
just to show you how simple it can be
there's
now we're looking at the general system
again there's many different types
all with the same premise aeroponics
involves a reservoir with a nutrient
solution
and a raised planter bed the roots are
suspended in the air
as we can see in this image up here and
typically do not make direct contact
with the nutrient solution in the
reservoir
but have the solution delivered via a
mist or supplied via
a pump there we kind of see the little
spray jets evident right here
typically plants are started in rockwell
or other medium and then placed into the
aeroponic system
so the roots have some substrate that
they initially start in the system can
be used for clones
and initially gets roots started for
cuttings as well
now the advantages to this system as you
can kind of see here the
pictures of the roots kind of speak for
themselves and
how you can get how do you get roots
that look like this well
the advantage is the grower has full
control over the nutrients delivered
directly to the roots of the plant
side to that is the grower has full
control of the nutrients so the grower
is needs to be on their game so to speak
with making sure they're delivering the
right amount of nutrients in the right
concentrations where more
is not necessarily better also this
system allows for aeration of the root
system
the water use is very efficient and
there's no need for growing medium
potentially maybe a little rockwell at
the beginning eliminating this cost
and also the disposal issue with a lot
of growers often forget about
however no system is perfect so the
disadvantages are due to the high level
of control a grower has
this needs to be attentive so
they may not be the best option for new
growers so this system
can perform great yields can perform
great routes but as i said the grower
needs to be aware of what's going on
so new growers just getting started may
struggle careful monitoring of
is essential which allows for nutrient
concentrations as well as ph values
typical nutrient solutions are changed
every seven to ten days
and the system should be cleaned between
growth cycles if not more often
the plant life depends on the life of
the pump
so growers need to be monitoring the
pump and ensure
that they also have backups and
electricity supplied to this type of
system
it can also be some upfront cost that
may be prohibitive
to some growers who are looking to
implement potentially this system
the equipment just to kind of show a
little image of kind of general
equipment is a container with a lid
the lid will have some form of plant
support
inside of the container water pump with
misting heads in this region here
a water monitor and of course a nutrient
solution
to ensure the plants are being properly
fed
now the targets for using this type of
system
would be to have a continuous water
monitor
so you need to have that continually
monitoring that water and the levels of
that water
to start with you're looking at a ppm
usually around 700
temperature of the water around 65
degrees fahrenheit
the ph around 5.5 to 6.5 with the target
or
ideal ph being 5.8 again these just
provide you with some general initial
targets and you can tweak them from here
as you see fit for your cannabis growing
operation