okay here we are Explorer aeroponics
which is a form of hydroponics well it
can take on many forms
I think utilizing the easy clone cloning
system is a great example of aeroponics
because this is a true form and it is
used for the cloning process but this
same form can be used to grow plants for
longer term than just cloning now
aeroponic system offers the highest
performance possible think of the EZ
clean setup where we have a water
reservoir here we have a water pump corn
with spray bar creating this Jets of
water that come out and fall down back
in the reservoir and kind of recirculate
through as a result there's no growing
media used at all the plants are simply
supported by this phone here and in the
cloning operation there's no roots
initially and the roots will be allowed
to form here through the constant
spraying of water and also allows some
form of aeration of that area as well
you can see there's some recent clones
on the left and some older clones on the
right sometimes because this is a
cloning operation with no roots they
will start to yellow a little bit but
oftentimes once they start to develop
roots they will start to green back up
again now fruit sources been in a dark
road chamber that's down in here inside
this easy clone Energon nutrient
solution constantly being sprayed to
create a continual spray of that
nutrient solution on those newly
developing roots air is also present to
allow their roots to breathe this is why
this can become a very efficient system
here the downfall is that the risk
growth can limit its ability to spray to
come into contact with the growing roots
what does that mean well but as those
roots become denser and clump together
when it's initially just kind of one or
two there's a lot of area however as
those become denser and start to grow
one can have reduce the spray contact of
the other roots another downfall is if
the pump fails the entire system can be
lost so you are dependent on that water
pump they're always good to keep it in
an area where it can constantly hear it
or always check on it multiple times
during the day if possible so if it was
to go out you could catch that
immediately and not risk losing all of
your plants growing under this aeroponic
system now it's
official system for cloning as we see
here the clones also have a water
monitor here keeping in assessing the
conditions in addition to a ceramic
metal halide light now this is great for
cloning but often full-season birth is
not recommended especially for large
scale production facilities also the
system is dependent on electricity a
hundred percent of the time so that also
needs to be taken into consideration so
that we're not having any sort of pump
failures leading to the entire loss of
the crop