despite these mice looking very
differently they are actually
genetically the same in this debacco
University video the Audy Mouse model to
study early nutritional effects on
epigenetic Gene regulation will be
discussed on how the uh nutrition of the
mother can potentially impact the future
[Music]
Offspring all right let's get into this
ay Mouse model now there's a great
YouTube video to kind of go over um and
help explain some of this I'm going to
try to break this down uh so we can
relate this mouse model potentially to
something that was also seen in humans
so first off since we're going to talk
about epigenetic should probably
describe what this actually is and Epi
uh genetic literally means in addition
to changes in genetic sequence so this
is not looking at just gen sequence
we're looking at additional
modifications to that the term has to
involve to evolve to include the process
that alters gene activity without
changing the actual DNA sequence and
leads to modifications that can be
transmitted to daughter cells there will
like this there likely will continue to
be debate over exactly what the term
means and what it covers but this gives
you a good understanding many types of
epigenetic processes have been
identified we're going to look
specifically at methylation um here and
describe a little bit more about that
it's basically methyl groups added to
DNA sequences um and the epigenetic
process are natural and essential to
many organisms functions but if they
occur improperly there can be major
adverse Health as well as behavioral uh
impacts and effects perhaps the best
known epigenetic process in part U for
methylation uh has been methylation
because it's in addition to removing the
methyl group it's pretty easy to
identify um and it really um provides
this initial investigation while other
things can apply we're going to look
specifically at methylation it was first
con uh confirmed to occurr in human
cancer in 1983 making of utmost um
importance there for illnesses and
health
conditions so looking at this kind of uh
example here well it stems from the
second world war in the winter of 1944
to
1945 there was a German blockade that
caused famine in the in Western
provinces of the Netherlands a legacy
longitudinal study five decades later or
after this had occurred showed that
people born to mothers who were in the
first 3 months of pregnancy during the
famine had significantly higher
instances of obesity diabetes
cardiovascular disease and cancer in
their adult lives this led to the
development of the hypothesis called
fetal susceptibility traditional
genetics really couldn't explain what
was going on here um however in 2003 a
study conducted uh by two scientists uh
Robert Waterland and Randy jle uh with
mice May provide some supporting um data
um to this and I included a citation to
their study and describe a little bit
more of kind of what they found and how
it relates so this fetal susceptibility
hypothesis um it's traditional genetics
really couldn't explain kind of what was
going on here and the concept is that
some of these um you know effects seen
in The Offspring could be connected to
potentially um other factors from the um
prenatal stage uh and kind of the mother
maternal diet
and that famine during that critical
development time period of the fetus may
have caused some developmental
modifications that then led to the
predisposition to obesity and
cardiovascular diseases later in life
that's what they looked at with this
model so it's brings us to the Audi mice
here um Audi simply means um you know
large yellow Audi mice it demonstrated
the fetal susceptibility and opened up a
new way to look at genetics genetic
mutations were thought to be the cause
of diseases and in some cases they can
be and while this may be the case it's
not the only case that may occur so
we're looking at our mice here from the
title side image and another one right
here both of these mice are genetically
identical they're the same but the
phenotypes are very different so we're
looking how the genotype impacts the
phenotype and vice versa here what's
going on here how can they have the same
genes but have very different looks or
morphological features so I kind of Rel
to the kitchen analogy we got the genome
is like the recipe The genome contains
the blueprint for making maintaining the
organism that's kind of the set standard
set of instructions then the epig genome
is the chef uh when in where and how to
make it work the epome provides the
regulation of those Gene Expressions so
the chef comes in and they're going to
make decisions meaning if they're
looking at you know making a breakfast
they're probably more likely going to
choose the um recipes for pancakes and
muffins and eggs if they looking at
dinner they might choose something more
in the you know steak rice and and salad
there so it's kind of U izing The genome
which is the recipe the epome is a chef
that's directing where and when it's
being utilized so we're looking at the
importance of Gene regulation
methylation comes into play and that's
the um ch3 can block or turn off or
silence different genes we see that
molecule right here see the methyl
groups attached right here each cell
contains all of your DNA a few
exceptions for example red blood cells
but look very different so if you think
of your skin cells versus your liver
cells very different um looks very
different functions but contain the same
genes uh this is simply due to the
expression of or what genes are being
expressed in those cells for example
your eye cells contain the gentics to
produce hydrochloric acid however it's a
good thing this Gene is not expressed in
your eyes but that Gene is activated
where it's needed in your
stomach so this brings nature versus
nurture um into you know uh comparison
as well or debate early in development
signals are given to differentiate cells
and these signals are carried on as the
organism grows in and develops the
genetic signals can be influenced byal
environmental factors stress and diet
and this leads to environmental
epigenetics at critical stages of
development the environmental factors
can have a greater influence on the
final gene expression of the individual
shortly after fertilization is a
critical time point is this is when
cells first are developing famine in
those mothers while early in pregnancy
impacted development of their fetus and
again we're looking at fertilization the
form of the zygote the two cell the four
cell the eight cell age very very early
on on how if something occurs during
this stage it could really impact uh
what genes are being
expressed now this agui Gene going back
to this all mammals have the agui gene
that controls the distribution of dark
pigment and go back to our genetically
identical mice here some brown and the
are brown and they stay normal weight
their entire life some are the tan
yellow color and they are obese and have
high instances of diabetes and cancer
the differences are due to changes in
that Gene expression the change is real
transposon which is a viral segment of
DNA that moves or jumps to different
positions in the genome and that can
alter gene expression so that transpose
on we can see here taking that sequence
and just cutting it out and moving it
over here well it's been physically
moved in space and that what's that's
what can cause this change in gene
expression we also have the presence of
methyl groups you know when we have uh
methyl groups being added or removed
that can also affect the um expression
or the suppression of that particular um
Gene so here we see the Audi type here
um in our you know nonmethylated groups
and we see that being expressed and we
see that yellow obese and tumor causing
when we see methyl groups blocking the
promoter region blocking that Gene we'll
see that normal normal weight and that
brown
coloration now those tan yellow mice um
the transposon physically located right
next to the agui gene we can see again
that same example right here uh an over
production resulting in the tan yellow
coloration and also block the feeding
control Center in the brain so kind of
two things were occurring this results
them in being obese and this is also
inheritable T have a greater percentage
of similar offspring that would become
obese early and unfortunately get sick
so we see in the neurom methylation that
blocking that goody Gene normal weight
TN coloration and that nonmethyl group
that Gene would then be expressed
leading to that yellow coloration and
that unfortunately developing higher
instances of diabetes and overweight
so can the phenotype be changed
environmentally well the tanelle mothers
were split into two groups in the part
of the experiment um and they had an
experimental group and a control group
the experimental group of mouse or fed
uh Mouse Chow rich in methyl groups
there um which contain folic acid
chlorine vitamin B12 and these provide
methyl groups which are involved in gene
regulation the control group was fed
just regular Mouse gel so with these
originally umy m
when they're fed this diet we can see a
change here a percentage change the
experimental group mothers have more
normal or brown mouse Offspring compared
to the control group indicating those
Audi mothers that were fed those High
methyl groups those methyl groups were
put uh on the genes to block that Audi
Gene and they resulted in more normal
mice that occur so it's just showing how
the environment can affect the gene
expression imp fact of that Mother's
diet again just to reiterate it here the
incorporation of those methyl groups uh
the feed essentially silence or turned
off the transpose on this results in a
return to the normal umy Gene with mice
being Brown and of normal weight the
unmethylated early uh in development
results in the activation of the Audi
Gene through the animals entire cells
and that's continuous throughout the
life in the animal always being yellow
so once expressed early on continues
this is the first study connect a
mother's diet to impact on the
expression of the offspring's genetic
code it was kind of a breakthrough and
is still talked about even to this day
now this leads to the epigenetics which
is the mechanism by which the
environment can affect the expression of
genes which can alter disease
susceptibility obesity may be impacted
by nourishment of the mother received
before the baby was even born so what
environmental factors change the
epigenome what are the genes that are
being altered these are all questions
that we have however now we do have the
tools and know what we're looking for so
several studies of the umbilical cord of
newborn babies found that lower
methylate levels in the
cdkn2a gene that regulates fat cells was
associated with greater fat tissue in
the child at 4 years old and increasing
their obesity risk later in life so
again this is showing another connection
between the prenatal stage and diet and
impact the mother has on the developing
fetus to how that Offspring uh has later
um traits The Offspring has later in
life so what's the research you know
results what are the impacts of these
well it has changed how we view the
adult disease secep ability for some
cases and has entered the term
epigenetics into vocabulary this has
impacted research in nutrition drug
Discovery infectious diseases as well as
genetics genome alterations are
difficult though crisper is helping with
this but epig genome alterations may be
easier once identified and small changes
in nutrition can alter disease
setability not through alterations of
the genome but by altering the epig
genome it might be more susceptible or
might be more easier to be received by
the public to help their potential
future offs
spring so the environmental impacts on
the genomes environmental impacts can
reprogram genetic inheritance for better
or worse so we're expanding this model
out from just the genes and the
environment making you to the genes uh
the environment and also the epigenetics
playing into this kind of Trifecta to
make you you and to see kind of what you
may be more likely to be predisposed of
not saying family histry doesn't play a
role but family history is a part of it
as well as the environment and
nutritions um exercise and lifestyle
that you have as well as the epigenetics
as well as a new consideration um as
this
Trifecta however lastly just the counter
point here uh during reproduction demain
cells tend to go through two full cycles
of demethylation that process strips of
all methyl groups and thus epigenetic
information from germ and embryotic cell
so germ are basically sex cells to date
there's no evidence that epigenetic
Transformations can survive two rounds
of biochemical cleansing and what that
refers to is kind of the image here if
the original
um if the grandmother who smokes is
altering potentially their own epome
could also affect the baby that they
have and if the baby's developing those
germ cells at the same time and it
impacts those cells now only do we have
the original grandmother's Offspring
affected you can see more obese here but
potentially their offspring could be
affected however looking at this process
we're not looking at kind of this
multi-generation jump but definitely a
correlation here of mother to initial
Offspring there so again just something
to keep in mind and something for
expecting mothers to keep in mind during
that critical stage of development to
definitely uh be mindful of nutrition
because it could have potential impacts
on your unborn child