you may have seen these odd-looking
plastic pots here with all the holes in
them
these are called air pots and in this
debaco university video
i'm going to cover air pots for cannabis
[Music]
production
let's learn more about air pots and
related to cannabis production
so first off if you may have seen these
so what are the benefits of using
air pots well the goal is a healthy root
system and a root development while
maximizing aeration
and that's where they get their name
from they're called air pots because
they're increasing aeration
to the growing substrate the shape of
the sidewall minimizes root circling and
encourages the formation of fibrous root
structure
this fibrous root structure is really
where a lot of the absorption
occurs in the plant roots for the for
the actual plant growth
a fibrous root structure allows for more
efficient nutrient and water
absorption so one of the advantages of
using a pot of this
style now the type of plastic pot here
so
they are made out of typically a plastic
material at least is what we see here in
the images
and usually it's a recycled plastic
material so that's an
advantage there we're looking at the
applicability and environmentalness
of the container they're made to last up
to 10 years
even in outdoor environments so it's not
something you buy once and just use ones
some you can use for multiple growth
cycles
and potentially multiple years as well
the air prunes the roots so the air pot
where does that get its name from well
we have this aeration but why would we
want to have air in that
sidewall well as root grows towards the
air holes
this will prune the roots once the root
is terminated
this induces root branching so this
increase in root branching is what
causes
an increase in the total surface area
and really helps that plant
be able to scavenge for nutrients as
well as water
this increase in root branching this
increase in surface area all benefits to
the plant
when we're dealing with a limited kind
of container area
with the root mass increase through the
branching this allows for a greater net
to capture nutrients in water you just
have a much finer area to go out and
allow that plant to be readily absorbing
water and nutrients
now they have a wide usage so this
concept works beyond just cannabis and
has been shown effective in vegetables
landscape and nursery plants as well
currently seem to be more popular in
europe where which is
likely due to to the developing company
is based
in the united kingdom this is probably a
wire contributing factor
to why these pots tend to be a little
bit more popular
in the european market but they're being
used united states and really all over
the world because of the benefits
mentioned here
so even though they may look a little
strange on first inspection
you can see some of the benefits and why
growers are using them for a variety of
plants