okay here okay a very brief overview of
allergies now keep in mind this is a
highly variable based on the individual
some people may be allergic to here or
dander so may be allergic to nuts of
some kind tree nuts or peanuts so may be
allergic to pollen and there's a whole
host of other things but we kind of all
have that same Ivy's end result where we
have that have itchy eyes running nose
in this general kind of not feeling well
so when clipping becomes harassment so
what are allergies well allergies in the
general sense are when the body mounts a
major defense against a harmless
substance that's what the whole point
about allergies is about so we have that
itchy eyes runny nose swelling and this
major defense despite the substance
that's reacting to being completely
harmless hay fever
and houston testaments are examples
during the allergic reaction process
mast cells initiate the inflammatory
response they release histamine
capillaries swell and mucus production
will increase an example of this too
would be asthma and asthma histamines
cousin nearing of air passages in the
lungs this can be very serious we cut
off the air passages or there's too much
swelling we can eliminate the body's
ability to breathe and essentially get
air in or out of the lungs nestlé's and
dalton allergies will mast cells are a
main component of the allergic response
ecology such as pollen are related to
the antibody known as IgE I have a
separate video and over antibodies like
other antibodies IgE antibody is very
specific and it's very important for all
of our antibodies here one acts against
oak pollen the other acts against ranked
ragweed so we have that very high degree
of specificity that does occur the first
time in allergy prone person runs across
and allergens such as ragweed here he or
she makes large amounts of ragweed IgE
antibodies these IgE molecules attach
themselves to the mast cells the second
time the person has a brush was Bradley
the IgE prime mast cells release green
rose
powerful chemical known as histamine and
cytokines and leads into the environment
and as a result that chemical mediators
cause the characteristic symptoms of an
allergy here is a prime example or the
sequence of steps that your body goes
through mounting an allergic reaction to
initially a piece of ragweed pollen that
really is benign and does not have any
serious health threats so that's kind of
the whole point of the allergies here
your bodies and mounting this high-end
immune response for a basically a
harmless substance