this video is on the alternation of
generations and plants commonly this
topic can trip students up so again
every reminds you to this link below in
the description is for the slides and
you're welcome to pause this video and
watch multiple times until you fully
understand the concept the opening image
here is a very simplified version and I
have several others throughout the
presentation if you part we want to look
at the gametophyte phase in the
sporophyte phase so sporophyte and
gametophyte might we think me to fight
think producing gametes and the
sporophyte is producing spores that will
help you just with the initial potential
for confusion so what's the basics of
this process well the situation is quite
different from that in animals where in
animals the fundamental process is that
a diploid remember to an individual
directly produces haploid or n gametes
by meiosis we see that pictured here so
if a multicellular organism two men
directly producing unicellular gametes
at one end and those fuse together to
form again the multicellular 2n organism
however now in plants this alternation
of generations in the life cycle this
thus between a diploid again to end
generation of sporophytes and a haploid
and generation of gametophyte so how
does this differ we still have our
multicellular sporophyte here but we
have a multicellular gametophyte here
unlike the unicellular in animals how do
we get there well there's a two N's four
and then there are one and gametes that
are forming this cycle so this
alternation of generations we see
there's a couple more steps involved in
plants versus animals so it's important
to keep track of this let's go through
some examples so this shows you more
familiar with in humans here sperm and
egg coming together through
fertilization to form the embryo that's
producing the individual that's then
producing the adult and pastas is
repeating however here meiosis is
producing male and female spores but
there's a male gametophyte and there's a
female gametophyte
these can be multicellular haploid cells
then through the process of
fertilization that produces the embryo
that's producing the end
that prisons the adult so there's an
extra little step involved compared to
that of animals or in this example
humans here's that same image from the
beginning in early pants plants meiosis
was delayed in the cells of the zygote
divided to produce a multicellular
diploid structure this resulted in an
alternation of generations in which a
diploid generation alternates with a
haploid one so a diploid generation is
called a sporophyte they're going to be
producing the spores and the haploid
generation is called the camino fight
that's me - sneaky means let me see that
pictured here here's our gametophyte s--
producing our gametes which are fusing
together to form our zygote which is
going through the process of mitosis to
form the sporophyte sporophyte goes
through meiosis to produce its spores
the spores entity become a multicellular
communicate that in turn produce gametes
and so on and so forth this upper region
here is all haploid this will all return
all diploid so let's put this into a
little bit of a picture here so the
diploid generation is called the
sporophyte remember the 2n it's located
up here then this is a moss how Pledge n
is the gametophyte and that is the
example here so we see the gametophyte
being haploid and it would be example
down here and the sporophyte here would
be the diploid now these can look very
different ferns to a very stark example
here alternation of generations in ferns
each can look very different the
sporophytes what we might be familiar
with with the fronds and leaves but the
gametophyte actually looks like this and
again that's the result of the union of
spores fusing together to form mitosis
and this
gametophyte is going to produce the male
female gametes that will fertilize to
provide the developing sporophyte which
will grow into what to know it as our
firms unique to ferns
those form the yellowish brownish mass
at the edge or underside of the front
we've ever seen the fern may have
noticed these structures the shape and
arrangement and location of these what's
called sori are often valuable to use in
identifying a fern so they're very
unique to do
it's burn species in the Sawyer that
sport producing structure if you ever
seen a furnace call these little dots
under it those are the Sorai
so again this is a great image here I'm
gonna repeat and go through some of the
steps so here a diploid zygote two
single-cell haploid gametes each
containing an unpaired chromosomes fused
to form a single-celled diploid zygote
through the process of fertilization
this is I go now contains n pairs of
chromosomes which is 2n chromosomes in
total
notice the line yes is everything it's
going to be in the 2n this is our first
phase of 5 moving along here getting to
our sporophyte this single-celled
diploid zygote germinates dividing by
the normal process of mitosis which
maintains the number of chromosomes at
two ends obviously the two men here this
results in a multicellular diploid
organism this is called the sporophyte
because at maturity produces spores and
working our way clockwise around here in
the sporangia
when it reaches maturity the sporophyte
produces one more sporangia which are
the organs that produce the diploid
sperm mother cells or sports sites these
divided by a special process called
meiosis that reduces the number of
chromosomes by half remember crossing
this line here the initial results in
four single-celled haploid spores each
containing n pairs of chromosomes and
you see here four cells as for spores
here each being cowboyed so we started
with 2n now we're going to each one of
these being and and four of them you
moving along with myself by the way
single-celled haploid sport terminates
dividing by the normal process of
mitosis which maintains the number of
chromosomes at n so we're maintaining in
this box this even though mitosis is
occurring and these cells are dividing
they're still haploid so there's still
haploid cells here everything on this
side of the line is haploid remember the
result is a multicellular haploid
organism called a gametophyte
and that's the key part here it's
multicellular haploid organism
it's even a fight signe the fight
because it produces the gametes so kind
of an easy way to remember that
progressing here they'll last up when it
reaches maturity the commuter fight
produces one or more community tangia
which are the organs that produce
haploid gametes at least one kind of gme
poses some mechanism for reaching the
other gammy
in order to use with it so is it the
example here of the sperm in the egg i
highlight it in the box here when these
come together that's the process of
fertilization that's going to take an N
in an end form a 2n which is a diploid
zygote and the process will repeat
itself so I know initially this can be a
little confusing you may want to review
this I've found an excellent study guide
resource here provided the links here so
again it's in the description you can
click on the slides and directly click
on these links to be able to give you
some information here I think will be
helpful in describing this process and I
tried to go through it in an organized
fashion as I said you may have to
rewatch this or pause it at certain
times but hopefully this is helpful in
explaining what is a pretty complex
topic