so even though analog monitoring systems
may be considered kind of an old way of
doing things
in this tobacco university video i'm
going to cover why they may still be
utilized and why growers may choose to
use them over digital systems
[Music]
all right let's get into analog
monitoring systems for indoor cannabis
production
so starting with the advantages of an
analog monitoring system is
first one being it's the simplified
mechanics they're reliable and less
prone to failure
and they also tend to be less expensive
compared to digital
monitoring systems all these are great
attraction points to many growers
the analog systems are simple they are
just
kind of a little bit of that kind of
fail-safe end of things
definitely allowing that kind of
repeatability because it can translate
to simple purchase setup and go
operations there's no need to calibrate
standardized in some cases
they just kind of are right there and
kind of in your face
with many other complications in a grow
facility
having this simplicity is a critical
piece of environmental monitoring
can be welcomed to many growers
especially if you're looking at just
quick reading at what's the temperature
what's the humidity having an analog
system
can be advantageous in that regards also
the analog
is simple the reliability analog
monitoring systems do their simplicity
are often less prone to failure
digital sensors can fail unexpectedly
where analog signage will work with
basic mechanics
so the likelihood of unexpected failure
is less than a digital operation
give the comparison of these two
different phone types the digital phone
and more
analog phone how many times in the last
10 years
have people gone through and had to
change out their digital phones
when these old style rotary analog
phones can last for 10
20 30 potentially up to 50 years and
still be
operational so also in addition
we have to consider price points with
many expenses of a growing operation
saving some money and a monitoring
system can be important
in analog systems if set up properly
will not perform
any less than the competing digital
system while there may be some
features missing compared to a digital
system analog monitors can still provide
growers
important information so this is why
they can still be utilized in some grow
facilities very effectively
well where analog monitors are and are
not recommended so if you're going with
an analog system
typically i really wouldn't recommend it
if you're looking at ph or carbon
dioxide enrichment or looking at light
levels
they're more advantageous for just the
temperature humidity just to give you an
idea of where those
typical environmental factors are around
lastly i want you to remember with
digital and as well as analog
is that the sensor is only as good as
the placement so watch the other video
here to make sure you're placing your
sensor in the right location
so regardless of what system you're
using you're getting an accurate and
reliable reading