here we're looking at the analysis of
paper
and some of the properties of paper
specifically how it can help us with
forensic science
so first off there's types of paper and
there's many types of papers so you
might be thinking of the paper you're
taking notes on
but there's inkjet paper there's blind
paper there's wax paper there's filter
paper
there's many different types so this
just shows you some of the variability
or the extreme variability
but even within for example inkjet paper
there is some variability
so the paper additives so paper have
things added to them
the seasons makes the surface of the
paper less porous to ink and this allows
handwriting and print to look sharp
and clear this can be something for
looking at a note we might notice
something like this
there's fillers added that add color
surface texture and durability
and there's coatings these coatings help
improve the look and surface properties
of the paper
coatings make the paper more suitable
for copiers printers or even normal
handwriting
the kind of the image that we see here
we can see those layers may not be
consistent
throughout some could be of various
thicknesses this can also play an
important role in identifying the paper
so i've been talking about paper well
what is it in general well pretty much
it's made of wooden cotton
and at least those are the most common
ingredients that make up today's paper
now the amount or the type can be a
little bit variable but those are the
general components
there's also common additives to paper
and these are chemicals that are affect
the color the occupancy the strength and
durability and brightness
and they are part of the paper producing
process things to consider
with paper looking at typically the
thickness is the first thing that you
may
notice uh thickness is measured
sometimes
in gsm or grams per square meter or a
caliper or referring to the thickness
in thousands of an inch and you'd use
calipers to measure that
you can see here greeting cards being
very thick and heavy in tissue paper
being on the other end of the spectrum
here being
a lot thinner in this form a lot lighter
in grams per square meter
the texture of the paper this plays a
big role when it's printing how it looks
when complete completed
it can be coated in uncoated textures
the coated
allows inks to kind of dry on the
surface where uncoated
those absorbed fibers get into the paper
into the
fibers that we can see here in a little
bit more of a detailed view
often this means the inks will appear
more vibrant and intense and coated
stocks
so this is just something to consider
when you're looking at the paper or if
you're looking at handwriting or
ink used on that paper then we also have
the brightness so the brightness you
could think of this as like the wattage
of a
light bulb brightness is the volume of
light reflected off the sheet of paper
it's a 0 to 100 scale it's a measurement
of reflectance of the blue which is
shorter wavelengths of the visual
spectrum at 450 nanometers what does
that translate to well
here's a paper of 100 brightness here's
one of 90.
you could see the 90 is a duller in
appearance than the 100.
there's also finishes that might be put
onto paper
so these are other things to consider we
have the
uncoated the matte the glossy and the uv
gloss paper's
finish this is referring to like the
sheen or how shiny
the paper is when it plays a role in the
readability and the look of what's
printed on
the page the difference between uncoated
matte and gloss is primarily the amount
of coating that is applied to the paper
we could see here these different types
shot under the same light you can see
clearly it being reflected the greatest
intensity with the uv gloss
and pretty much non-existent on the
uncoated and barely visible at all on
the mat
this just shows the kind of example of
the coating on how
that can impact the shininess to that
paper
we also have shades of white so the
paper what was it
on white paper well there is a bunch of
different types of white paper if you've
been to a paint store you know
uh the plethora of amount of options you
have under simply the color white
there's variations that include comment
like soft off white there's silk white
soft asparagus here um antique white
cause you have a
large variability here they're also
often considered part of the natural
color scheme
and are very common um types used for
paper
you also want to consider the occupancy
of the paper that you're that you're
looking at
a high occupancy and low occupancy high
economy is going to block a lot
and low occupancy you're going to be
able to see through it it's referring to
the degree of obstruction
of light that's expressed as a
percentage so for example something has
occupancy means that 98 of the light
cannot
pass through the paper low occupancy
means the paper will have
more show through so this is like can be
like a simple little light test look it
up under the of the light
and see how easy it is to see through
high occupancy is going to be like
business or card stock that's going to
be really thick
in dense paper and low occupancy as you
would hope it would have
would be like tracing paper something
very thin so you can see through it
last thing you want to consider in
certain papers is the potential for a
watermark which which is a unique image
and paper that appears at various
shades of lightness and darkest darkness
when viewed
with transmitted light watermarks be
used on potion stamps currency
and other documents is very common to
find them a lot of times money is used
to kind of
help prevent counterfeiting but there
are some companies that do put a
watermark
within their paper sometimes in the
corner sometimes in the entire
background
it can be difficult to see but if it
is present you look under the right
light you'll be able to find it
and all these factors can help you
identify
paper and match it up to something that
might be found on a crime scene versus a
stock paper source