here we're going to look at the analysis
of inks
particularly in pens and while you may
think they're all the same
there's actually some unique
characteristics and identifiable
characteristics
that can be applied to forensic science
so first off just a general ink
comparisons if you've got this kind of
container here with a bunch of pens well
inks in question documents may be
examined and compared
with other inks of the same document or
with ink in other documents
even with ink that's in seized pens so
this is important to consider
collecting if you're collecting evidence
to be collecting pens from the area
of the crime scene because the goal is
to determine where the similarities and
differences
potentially may exist so when we're
talking about comparing
inks if an old document has newer ink or
alter
alterations to that ink it could be
determined if you look at kind of the
straight copy here everything looks the
same but there are certain techniques
that we can do to determine what might
be a different ink what might be a new
ink
and it can allow us to see some changes
that may have been made
in a questioned document so just in
general
what is ink inks are a complex mixture
of colors and additives
in a simple diagram describing the
selective reflectance of a pigment
so we have kind of we'll say say white
light with all wavelengths hitting our
ink surface it's only it's absorbing
these different colors
and reflecting in this case the blue
color so we'll interpret that as
blue ink now we look at a little more
technical kind of terms
to identify ink components scientists
can use
infrared or mass spec or chromatography
in both the glass gas or liquid phase
this can help determine a signature to
that
ink what particular components and
ingredients are being used
to specifically identify that one
particular ink
well why would we have this high degree
of specificity well there's actually an
international
inc library where a lot of inks from
different manufacturers
are stored it's maintained by the us
secret service and the international
revenue service
includes more than five hundred ing
steaming back to the 1920s
every year pen and ink manufacturers are
asked to submit a new ink
if they have new formulations so this is
a
giant library of inks that can allow
pinpointing of if a pen was used to try
to identify
what time period that pen came from
and how that might be able to impact the
materials found at the crime scene
these are chemically tested and added to
the reference for collection
and this is what develops this library
which allows for this
great database to be used for comparison
when we're trying to identify certain
inks