so here i'm going to go through some of
the anatomical and molecular records
related to evolution
think of it as some of the macroscopic
and some of the microscopic
records related to evolution first off
we have the
presence of vestigial organs the
structures that are no longer in use
such as the human appendix
and wisdom teeth apes have much larger
appendix that's involved with the
digestive process
we have these structures and we can
easily live without them
this is evidence that they may have been
used at one time and now for born
without them
we have no negative effects molecular
records will evolutionary distance is
one for example
new alleles arise by mutations that come
from
predominance through favorable selection
so in this case we have this kind of
population before
after selection we have the favor of the
red circles instead of the yellow
this could relate to the resistance
level of something going on in the
environment
we also have the example here for
whatever reason the dark gray is favored
over the white coloration
so we have this change over time
now we look at specifically these
molecular records
and this kind of divergence that is
occurring we can look at kind of
degrees of divergence or how dissimilar
two species may be
evolutionary changes involve the
continual accumulation of genetic
changes
distance related organisms accumulate in
greater number of evolutionary
differences and closely related ones
this divergence is seen among
vertebrates in the 146 amino acid
hemoglobin
beta chain so what does that kind of
mean we're looking at hemoglobin which
humans
monkeys dogs birds frogs and even sea
lampreys have
seeing the amount of amino acids that
are different between this hemoglobin
polypeptide
compared to the human so in this case
the monkey has eight
difference the dog is 32 the bird is 45
the frog
67 different amino acids and then the
lamprey 125.
this indicates that while all of these
organisms have hemoglobin
lamprey is by far the most dissimilar
because of its high degree of variance
and the
frog and the bird are more distantly
related to humans than the dog or the
monkey
and we're looking at our molecular clock
and the difference between these
the same pattern of divergence is seen
with dna sequences
such as that of the cytochrome c gene so
what does this kind of refer to and mean
well here we have millions of years in
nucleotide
substitutions well changes appear to
accumulate at a consistent rate
this phenomenon is referred to as the
molecular clock
this means these mutations are occurring
at a relatively consistent rate
different proteins evolve at different
rates so the more complex we have
the least amount of differences compared
to the greater amount of differences we
have here so here we have again the
human the pig the duck snake
uh fish and moss species in yeast we
have this large divergence here
so looking at the molecular clock the
degree of uh nucleotide substitutions
that are occurring
over this period of time we're seeing
some sort
of consistency to that pattern over a
long period of time
indicating this molecular clock we've
also something called homology
so the eyes of these organisms are not
homologous that's the first kind of key
point
but the genes controlling the eyes are
homologous
so let's kind of look at this in more
detail when we are comparing the genetic
similarity to
to protein similarity of an eye control
gene
across species that's what we're looking
at in specifics here
the mouse is the comparison standard so
for example
the genetic similarity and the protein
similarity so protein scenario
to the mouse between the eye of the
mouse the shark the squid in the flat
room is all a hundred percent
however what's different is the genetic
similarity to the mouse
so this gets into genotype and phenotype
so genetic similarity to the mouse the
charcoal is eighty-five percent the
squid seven
a little over seventy eight percent
flatworm 71.6
so we're seeing that there is some
genetic variability
even though this protein is consistent
throughout
so this indicates remember there's
multiple uh
multiple ways you can make the same
protein get to the same amino acid with
different genetic code different rna
essentially
within this molecular record looking at
500 million years ago an ancestor
involved switch
for eye development so probably simple
type of eye
one pigment cell one photoreceptor this
gene was passed on to its descendants
these descents involved
more complex eyes well if we have this
kind of light and dark sun single that's
one way
but if there's more complexities being
developed
this is a way that that gene can be
modified to development of
kind of the complexity to the eyes for
example that we have
we can sense a lot more than just light
and dark we have lenses
um colors there's a lot of complexity
just within the eye
this again shows that kind of basic
there's nerve fibers and photoreceptors
while getting to development of a retina
getting built with cornea development
lens
being able to kind of sense objects at
different distances
being with night vision depending on
what animal you're looking at
a lot of complexities here
looking at dinosaurs as well we could
see this high degree of complexity
that is occurring in divergence between
them all we have
definitely a change that occurred where
a lot of them went extinct
so why did that happen you know what
they clearly did not
best fit that environment but this just
shows you that progression over time
now molecular evidence we have dna dna
hybridization it's called where dna is
separated with sufficient heat to create
single strands
these uh then closely related sequences
will join together or what we call
hybridized they'll stick together more
strongly since there are more
complementary bases
so you can't take the dna we kind of
separate it out we see what it may stick
to
the closer the sequences are related the
higher the melting
temperature the tm will be required to
separate those
this is just a kind of a way to tell
this hybridization how similar the
genetics may be because if they're more
similar they're going to be bound
tighter
and take more heat to get them to
separate out
now whale evolution something else to
kind of look at the evolution of whales
beginning with their
ancestor their descendants of
terrestrial animals
return to the sea this is another
example of
evolution doesn't mean getting more
complex necessarily
whales distant relatives may have been
land-based with walking
and they may have slowly reduced those
limbs to become more flipper-like
and to become more fin-like to be able
to best fit the aquatic environment
versus the terrestrial one
there's a lot of evolutionary critics
the
seven principles of objectives that they
have here it's not sadly demonstrated
there's no fossil intermediates
there's intelligent design evolution
violates the second law of
thermodynamics
proteins are too improbable to form
all these objections are really without
a great scientific
merit when you start looking at them to
be kind of supported
a lot of people bring up religion
related to um evolution this is just
looking
at um pope john paul the second november
19th 1996 some
an address that he made regarding
evolution because the catholic church
and evolution tend to be thought to be
very much conflict
so he stated that today almost half a
century after the publication of the
euclidean
new knowledge has been led to the
recognition of more than a hypothesis
in a theory of evolution it's indeed
remarkable that the theory has been
progressively accepted by researchers
following a series of discoveries in
various fields of knowledge
he goes on to say the convergence
neither saw nor fabricated of the
results
of work was conducted independently and
is itself a significant argument in
favor of the theory
so keep in mind this is a theory uh but
in science theory is a very well
established well-supported
um idea or concept versus a theory that
we may be familiar with more
in common everyday world