okay have a little bit of a unique video
lecture here for you on angular
movements since we're talking about
movements it's kind of hard to show that
and static images so I have included
quite a few gifs here in this video
lecture love to hear your comments below
after watching it which we may have
liked or didn't like about this unique
lecture series so starting with just
some of the background we have our
angular movements what is that
well angular movements are produced by
changing the angle between bones of a
joint when we're bending occurring
that's when the angle between bones
decreases here's some of the categories
we're going to be looking at extenders
flexor abductors adductors so on and so
forth and here's the description
hopefully you find the gifs a little bit
more interesting and memorable to be
able to make connections between these
categories so flux on and extension so
this an occur in both the lower leg here
you can also occur in the head region so
if you look our individual here we have
the green extending and then flux out
and they're going back flex on the
extending on the green looking at the
blue leg you'll notice that when it's
going forward here we have the extension
and then the flux on the bend
here's a flux and here's the extension
looking at the green line there's that
flux on there that moving back flex on
and extension now in the head region the
same thing can occur extensions moving
backwards and a flux times going forward
so we see initially the initial values
of flux on the followed by the extension
going back hopefully that so it makes it
a little bit more helpful to remember
these two moving on we have rotation now
there's two different types of rotation
we have a lateral and a medial rotation
so joe joel mchale here who knows
initially that rotations a lateral
rotation followed by a medial rotation
there so the rotation of the head that
lateral followed by the medial there
returning to that midline so those are
two different types of rotation and then
video
abduction and adduction here so it's
important remember when we're going away
you think of opposing that would be a
deduction here you see our femur and
articulation of our ball and socket
joint our abduction is when it goes away
from the midline and then adduction here
as once as it's returning towards the
midline so abduction followed by
adduction turning that midline abduction
and then add duction return that anymore
elevation and depression looking here
particularly at the mandible so when the
mouths are open here on the simpsons
that's the depressed mandible or all
kind of hanging mouth open and and then
maggie helps homer there l the elevation
of his manual bringing it back up so
depression is down and elevation is
working its way back off there moving on
protrusion and retrieving so we see the
fish here initially we see that
protrusion as that jaw extends out and
be choosen as that mandible comes back
in here the woman at the lower points is
pushing her chin in in the recruiting
position of her mandible pronation and
supination
we see that here where we're rotating
our radius over the ulna via the
pronation you see that here with Justin
Timberlake and Jimmy Fallon you see that
rotation that is occurring here when
they're both in the parallel position
that would be the supination and when
it's rotated over that'd be called
pronation step remember supination that
parallel is considered the standard
orientation there also another video on
the forearm pronation and supination
there hopefully you found this lecture a
little bit unique interesting and
memorable