welcome to debaco university here we're
going to be looking at
animal hair descriptive characteristics
and some of the distinguishing factors
that we look at when we're looking at
hair particularly at the microscopic
level so starting with why is animal
hair in general important
well if evidence shows animal hair
present it can generate questions
such as if the victim does not own a dog
it could
interfere with suspect owns a dog or has
come in contact with a dog
also dna can be removed from animal's
mouth if bitten and blood samples can be
moved from the animal's fur
feet or etc so when we're looking at why
is handle air
important even in forensics
investigation
identifying animal hair can be very
important
there's different types of animal hair
so keep in mind when we're looking at
comparison different hair types on
animals
we are often looking at guard hairs
which are thicker
longer straight and form the outer
protective coat of an animal
the fur or wool hairs are thinner often
soft
kinked and not straight and found close
to the skin forming an insulating inner
coat to the animal
and we have tactile hairs which provide
sensory functions and typically found
the head of animals
such as the whiskers let me just kind of
see this quick comparison here
of here's here's the dog here's the
guard here and here's the under fur here
you can just see from the same dog
this stark difference in those animal
hair types just on quick
visual inspection both at 400
times magnification now the cuticle
scale pattern is another area we want to
be looking at
we have the intricate scales that are
random overlapping patterns
much like roof tiles and are often
flattened so here's that example here
of the intricate kind of scale pattern
that we see
then we have the spinous which are
scales that have spiny long and pointed
appearance that overlap and you can
definitely see that here in the
mink here then we have the coronal which
are crown like scale pattern which is
very
fine hairs it looks like a stack of
paper cups common in small rodents
bats and is very rare in humans
so this is an example here of bat hair
and we can see clearly
on how it's very distinctive on a visual
basis
compared to the mink hair here or just
kind of the unidentified animal here
with the intricate scale pattern
this is an important method of being
able to identify
for at least classifying the hair in a
particular species
moving on to the cortex color was a wide
range of natural colors and shadings
that do occur and we see a couple of
them here
we have guard hairs of a black bear a
brown bear and a polar bear
and just click on that cortex color
that's the region right here we can see
the
differences as well here and those
colors in shadings
then we have the medulla description
categories so how we kind of going
through
and describing the different medulla
regions well let's remember the medulla
is the innermost layer of the hair and
serves
as kind of the mirror of the hair that
center portion it's composed of air
filled components that are typically
harder to see in human hair compared to
other animals
looking here at the coyote the harbor
seal and the raccoon
we can definitely see some major
differences
in how we classify the different medulla
patterns that we notice now those
patterns
specifically we're looking at they could
be absent
they could be fragmented they could be
intermittent or they could be continuous
and there's just one example of looking
kind of a far away
microscopic view of the fischer cat on
how we definitely see a unique
medulla pattern here there's different
structures
so here's just that quick kind of uh
comparison of morris
morris a cereal multi-serial
cellular or a lattice so this amorphous
kind of
shape here let me get into the lattice
the multi-cereal the unicereal
very distinctive patterns and we're
going to see some examples of those here
so first off starting with the amorphous
shape
it appears as a solid line but lacks a
clear pattern or
structure and this is what we're
noticing here
and looking at a jersey cow's hair
sample at 400 uh
i'm sorry at 40 microns here this is an
example of this
amorphous shape and if you're not with
the jersey cow that's what one
looks like there the uni on this serial
has one ladder row of components running
down the hair longitudinally
and here's kind of what the general
image looks like and the example of that
would be
guinea pig here so we can see that ud
surreal pattern here to the medulla
and there's a happy little guinea pig
there looking at the camera
then we have the multi cereal here and
this is looking at an example of
rabbit hair would fall under this
category this has multiple
ladder rows components running down the
hair again in that longitudinal
direction
and we can see that evident here keeping
it the same magnification
of 4 40 microns here with
rabbit here then we have the um
cellular where we're looking at a wide
band of randomly shaped
cell-like structures and the silver fox
would be an example here
of this medulla pattern and looking at
each one of these bars removing 10
micro meters here then this
lattice structure so this can occupy
nearly the entire width of the hair with
small circular shaped components
if you look really closely here at this
deer hair sample we definitely see that
and again there's filled us there's
partially filled this would be
considered
filled of this white-tailed deer in the
image here
now we have something also called the
medulla index this describes
the thickness of the medulla layer in
humans the value of the medullary index
is usually about 1 3 or less and that of
animal hair is typically
one half or greater and how we get that
is looking at the diameter of the
medulla
compared to to the diameter of the
actual
hair so how do we go about that
calculation
again using a microscope that would
ideally have
some way of measuring that the index
this medullary index is calculated by
dividing the modular width
by the width of the entire cortex here
we'd write those two numbers down
we divide those two and we multiply by
100 here and here's the diameter here's
the total width there
and we would simply divide those two to
get this medullary index
this can be important for identification
for classifying
and keep in mind this still always falls
under that area of class evidence not
individual
evidence but still important to document
and
when we're looking at developing an
understanding and comparison
of different animal hairs as we saw in
the images in this presentation