so when we think of threats to canvas
plants we may think of merely the
microscopic and very small threats we
can't forget about the larger animal
threats to cannabis production so in law
threats may be of greater concern for
outdoor operations well but mice can be
a problem indoor grows as well as the
outdoor grows now while a bunch of
animals here pictured odds are starfish
enjoy fish probably not high on the
threats to cannabis but others
definitely are for example threats from
above we want to watch out for birds
they can attack particularly newly
planted seedlings outdoors in particular
crows can be very destructive in that
regards turkeys can also be a problem if
you have a recently tilled field with
all this exposed soil they like to go to
recently prepared field and dust
themselves or they can walk across
plastic you're using that for weed
control do damage there so be mindful
and keep an eye out for turkeys larger
animals such as deer and bears well
bears are an issue sorry is that much
you can really do because there are
large powerful organisms that can easy
tear down fences and do whole host of
damage onto your plants but also
yourself deer though make things called
deer fence and they can potentially do
some feeding damage but also a physical
plant damage deer fence is the best
method of control but be careful to
ensure that the bottom is well secured
typically think of deer jumping over
fence but they also like to try and
crawl under the fence so make sure at
the bottom is secured very well as well
as the top the fence should be about
eight to 12 feet tall you can cheat as I
said by having the fence shorter but
using poles that are the full kind of 12
10 feet so tall there because deer will
run up to the fence and they'll look up
and he'll look for the tops of the poles
and that can be one way you can try to
cheat use a shorter fence because feds
can be expensive and try to get the same
effect of preventing deer from entering
your gross base fish from below the
Gophers and woodchucks living pucks a
tawny shell here on Groundhog Day
these are animals that burrow they be a
challenge because they dig holes and
tunnels I can go under fences and they
can also be very destructive in a very
short period of time I can sometimes
bury
to try to eliminate them from going over
should say under and burning the tunnels
but they can be again very destructive
in those regards threats that are small
so mice involves are examples of very
small animals that can cause a large
damage to it operation for mice watch
for plants as much as the seeds you're
storing and also going to be planting
sometimes you go through and plant a
bunch of seeds and mice can come through
and burrow and dig up and just kind of
play in the soil and cause all sorts of
germination is challenges their cat can
be very effective method for control to
kind of keep mice away kind of having a
set up in let me have her traps is
another way but just be mindful
especially starting in the spring or in
the fall when you have a heat source
they easily can find that and be very
destructive also keep your seeds stored
in sealed containers that might so go in
nests those other either threats from
grazers squirrels and chipmunks
squirrels can be curious and cause
random and frustrating damage at times
they also be very difficult to control
electric fence can help with squirrels
small havahart traps with chipmunks with
peanut butter SB is a way to help
control them they're very fast moving
and again can burrow and dig and top
plants which is again not welcomed in in
a growth area
lastly rabbits rabbits may be numerous
around plants but often do little or no
damage out so you have a threat with a
question mark here these odds are while
they may be around then odds of them
doing really severe damage are quite low
so again don't think you have to
eliminate everything in this case this
could be an animal you can potentially
tolerate due to the threat of it causing
damage is very low