welcome to another video here on debaco
university
in this video we're going to be looking
at animal versus human hairs
and different regions when you want to
look at and inspect them
and how a animal hair would compare to
that of a human hair
so you could hopefully distinguish
between the two so first off
human or animal there are some general
characteristics of each type of hair
that can help
initially classify it as whether you're
looking at a human hair or an animal
hair because if you find something at
the crime scene
even though there may have been humans
involved you want to be able to rule out
or classify it as just human or animal
in the general category
so first off animal versus human hair
looking at the general size
for length the human scalp errors tend
to be longer than most
animal hairs we're looking at the
diameter human hairs are usually in the
range
of 0.05 to 0.15
millimeters animal hairs can be narrower
or coarser
so just that quick little comparison
there i can help you initially start to
classify it
a lot of this comes with just seeing a
lot of samples as well
now analysis human hair looking at the
pigmentation in particular
well for human hairs gently consistent
pigment throughout the hair shaft
with slight increase in density towards
the cuticle for animal hairs the color
is more essentially distributed
throughout the more dense
towards the medulla region we're looking
at the color banding
for human hairs or when untreated it can
usually lack banding
while animal hairs will have a banded
appearance to them
for hair treatments human hair can be
treated and animal hair
rarely exhibits dyeing bleaching or
other cosmetic
treatments so again keep that in mind
when you're looking at
investigating here the pigmentation
portion
now looking at the medulla region so
we're looking at kind of the microscopic
view
of comparison comparing these hair types
for human hairs they only have
an amorphous medullar structure animal
hairs can have a complex regular
geometric
cellular medulla for the medullary index
which is the ratio of the diameter of
the medulla to the diameter of the
actual
hair the human hair is almost always
less than one-third
and anal hair is usually greater than
one-third a lot of times often greater
than
one-half and we kind of see some
examples here identifying them
we have the buffalo the camel on the cow
the horse the donkey
the sheep the goat the dog and the cat
here and this little sidebar here is 62
and a half
micrometers for comparison now kind of
the anatomy of the human hair versus the
animal hair provided with a lot of kind
of
comparison points so if you're looking
at the shaft region animal hairs
tend to have different shapes than
humans such as that
spatula shape found in rodent hairs
really get the root of the hair
well human hair will have a bulb or
ribbon shaped root
while animal hairs can have different
shaped roots typically kind of brush
like in their appearance
at the tip of the hair particularly
human hair of the scalp
is usually cut or frayed at the tip
while animal hair is usually
that has that natural kind of taper to
it so when we're looking at the scale
region
of human hair only exhibits a regular
angular
kind of scale patterns while animal hair
will have a variety of types
and can have more than one type in
within the same hair
lastly looking at the cross section in
my hairs to have some more unusual
shapes
for example um kind of like a dog bone
um like shape which is
evident of rabbit hair as just one
example or
a cigar shaped and that is evident that
of a seal
so those are just some obvious kind of
cross-section shapes that can help you
potentially identify or classify
what animal it came from so keep in mind
there's a lot of comparisons that can be
made between human and animal hairs
and while humans may be animals we're
looking at the different types of
species of
animals and hopefully this provides you
with kind of some quick little regions
to look at
and how to identify whether it's human
or if it's animal hair