okay here we're gonna look at some of
the details in the animal phyla we can
see everything from sponges to Nigerians
to whales to see stars to worms all fit
into this very large and diverse phyla
that we might be most familiar with so
first off looking at the general
features of animals and I can kind of
fit myself in the mix here kind of put
myself right there because I do qualify
as do all humans here so animals aren't
heterotrophs meaning they do not make
their own food need to consume it plants
and autotrophs are the ones that would
make their own food animals do not
multi-cell there so they have a
mitochondria but lack a cell wall as a
result animal cells can be quite
flexible they can move from place to
place they're deployed they have diverse
forms and habitats as we can just see
from the image here we produce mostly by
sexual reproduction have a common
pattern of development and have unique
tissues so general features all the
animals in vertebrates account for 99%
of all species in the animal kingdom
most occur actually in the c3 phyla
dominate animal life on earth arthropod
a and mollusk and chordates so while we
may think of kind of you know our most
favorite animals or what we think is the
most kind of common arthropod is by far
the greatest and invertebrates account
for 99% of all species so just be
mindful of that of how well one percent
of vertebrates
there's chordates are very very small
total amount of species so looking at
the family tree animals consists of 35
very different phyla textiles
traditionally have compared anatomical
features the end result though is
biologies so we're looking at the domain
kingdom phylum class order family genus
and species you're looking at the phyla
level so we're looking here kind of at
this bar here and working to be more
specific
so all animals in this case are in the
kingdom Animalia and are all in the
domain Eukarya and we're looking at
separating out that phyla
more specific so within this animal
family tree here the traditional animal
ecology is being revised molecular
systemics systematics you should say are
used uses unique gene sequences to
detect relatedness and construct cell
genetic trees we're getting away from
the phenotypic features and getting more
into the genotypic features as a result
has recruited new divisions and new ways
to divide different things to really see
what is connected looking at the
genetics of those now the current look
here we can kind of see are having
tissues are notitia so this would be our
common ancestor way down here no tissues
going off to the left tissues going off
to the right so everything here
including or having tissues sponges or
peripheral and not including tissues
within there we can have a radial
symmetry or bilateral symmetry we're
looking at a whole bunch of different
other ways to divide things there's
animals malt
they have protostome development or due
to sperm development different ways
again to kind of separate things and
classify them well lastly they cladogram
with key branch points this gives you
another idea of a way to break things
apart looking at having vertebra having
jaws or lungs or four limbs and legs or
a mitotic egg how would they how would
things be separated and what would be
considered to be more complex so well
this is a very diverse a phylum that we
might be familiar with this hopefully
makes it a little bit easier to at least
associate some of the physical features
when we're looking at developing branch
points within that phyla