welcome to tobacco university here we're
going to be investigating
animal hair comparisons and while we can
see some obvious differences here
at the macroscopic level we're going to
be looking more at the
microscopic comparisons of different
animal hairs
from different animals as well as with
on the same animal
so first off animal hairs in general uh
do not pines
possess enough individual microscopic
characteristics to exclude
other similar animals and can be
associated with a unique
individual so we're just kind of looking
at just generally classifying them
if the question here exhibits the same
microscopic characteristics as a known
hairs
it's concluded that the hair is
consistent originating
from that particular animal and we could
see here we're maybe comparing different
pelts
of different animal hairs so when we're
looking at the images and i'm going to
include
hopefully quite a few of them so you can
be able to kind of get that nice little
comparison between them we want to be
thinking about the diameter
of the medulla the scales and the
general patterns of those hairs
so again what's the what's the diameter
uh what's the medulla what's the
repeating kind of shape the perimeter
what's the width and the length again
measured in microns here
if provided a scale and here we're
seeing just kind of that example of how
we might want to break down
one of these microscopic images going
forward
so just a general comparison you know
just looking at kind of the obvious
classification we can see some
very stark differences here looking at
scale casts looking at that kind of
cuticle region
of how some are kind of like all
interlocked with one another
how have these definite kind of like uh
scales of a fish interlocked
together uh the river otter here having
a little bit more of that irregular
pattern
um so again just having no background
just kind of looking at these four
images we can clearly
see some differences continuing on
to looking at comparing fibers within
one family these are all classified
under the rodent family and still we can
see that there are some
differences here as well again maybe not
as historically different as the last
image
but definitely when matching an unknown
sample up to some knowns
we could definitely see where we could
at least eliminate some potential
options
so just taking one example here looking
at the
links uh for example here when we're
looking at kind of
the diameter and the medulla as i said
here we have the little bar here
uh representing 20 micro meters here
here we're seeing um this would be the
diameter of 40 microns and a medulla of
35. keep in mind that the guard cell
from lynx number one is what's shown
here
on the cells medulla are long flattened
shape that span the width of the medulla
some of the cells are slightly cupped
with many bubble-like features
between the cells this is continuous
repeating s-shaped running between the
cells throughout the medulla
now the images down here all the images
on the slide are all from the links
keep in mind we have the guard scale
cast here
so we're taking a casting of the actual
kind of cuticle region
we have the guard here pictured here we
have the
under fur and then we have a different
area here
of the under furnace and we can see that
there are
some differences so keep in mind that
we're here
we're looking at a general comparison
between the two
um so it's important to keep that in
mind when we're trying to make some sort
of
matches or classifications of hair that
might be found
continuing on here for the red fox and
we kind of see that similar image look
at the diameter look at the medulla here
a crossroad fox guard here in polarized
light so how we look at it can also
impact the image that we may see here
we're seeing the cells who do appear as
wide flat and shaped with no
regular boundaries in some places the
cells appearing angular
and this is the guard cell at 400 times
magnification
and here's the guard scale with the
scale cast so again that's we're kind of
taking that cuticle
region and getting a cast kind of an
impression if you will
of that cuticle region this is the
midsection of the guard here
keep in mind where you're taking that
the lower section the mid
or the outer i'm going to be kind of
more towards the tip region
that can impact potentially what you're
going to see in an image so important to
document that when you're taking
pictures
then we have the here we have the short
tailed weasel
and we're seeing the guard um here where
the medulla shows a transition where
fibers
widen there's a deep wavy s-curve here
to the medulla
the location where the medulla
transition has a wider section
of hair we do see that differentiation
occurring here
in this guard cell keep in mind this is
at 200 magnification this is the
short-tailed weasel the under fur
region where we're also noticing some
very different medulla
present here so again just that source
of comparison
looking at a woodchuck so here's one
kind of nibbling on some plant material
there
looking at the under fur we're seeing a
compilation of kind of
hairs here and we do see kind of quite
the difference
here we have unicereal lateral medulla
we have a more complicated medulla and
here we actually have no medulla due to
the intense
pigmentation now present so again
keeping in mind where you're sampling
that hair
or where that hair is being identified
might require you
to look at different regions of the
individual but will help you potentially
identify where that hair sample may have
come from look at the scales near the
base here
look at the wide shape between the scale
margins
this fairly smooth scale margins here
all of these with a trained eye can
allow you to kind of
get into some more of the details of
comparison we also have
typically the diameter of the hair to
the medulla can help us
define that medullary index
likewise we also have the beaver here so
again a brown here that's great
but we can see some differences between
the beaver and the woodchuck so while
initially they look like brown hair
and even very similar organisms on a
quick look
looking at the hairs we do see some
differences and it's important to be
looking at those details
so you're able to kind of classify what
was that here from a beaver
or hear from a woodchuck in the example
provided here
then we have the arctic ground squirrel
and
again that kind of diameter to medulla
is a very common
characteristic here that we're used for
comparison also looking at the scale
cast again for that source of comparison
and classification now keep in mind
this is only a small sample but if this
is something that interest you want to
look at it into some more detail
the alaska fur id project at alaska
for id.wordpress.com is where a lot of
these information was
gathered is a great resource has a lot
of
different animal cares for comparison
and of interest of you
i highly recommend you go about checking
this resource out