and this debaco University video I'm
going to go through an in-depth as well
as a field look at anthocyanins so I'm
going to give you an anthocyanin
overview I'll also look at genetic
regulation in field observations of
cannabis hopefully you enjoy
[Music]
so first off to give you a little bit of
the progression of information you're
going to find in this video I'm going to
go over basically what are anthocyanins
and provide you a basic background also
the regulation of anthocyanin and
biosisynthesis which gets into some new
insight into Gene regulation at the
molecular scale and then we'll go out in
the field for early season and
mid-season plant response to
environmental stresses that cause it to
increase anthocyanin production to be a
macroscopic view of how most Growers
will see or recognize anthocyanins I'll
provide you with a outfield look at some
recently transplanted cannabis plants
and Care will provide you with a late
vegetative growth anthocyanin look so
first of us let's start with the basics
and these Basics always here on debacle
University try to be science based so
here is an article I can take a look at
if you want to learn more about
anthocyanins and there'll be another one
referred to as well in this video so
first off again what are those
anthocyanins kind of what they look like
on a chemical structure but anthocyanins
are colored water soluble pigments which
are a class of flavonoids impart
pigmentation of the plant parts and play
an important roles and plant
environmental interactions these
components and compounds can also have
medical benefits as well you see a
couple of them kind of listed here and
again these are found more than just in
cannabis plants blueberries as well as
other fruits and vegetables can express
these as well
so again there's just also more than one
anthocyanin blueberries contained five
out of the six uh they're just missing
one there each has a different
coloration however the color is
influenced by the pH light temperature
and also the structure in general though
anthocyanins are red in acidic
conditions and blue when the pH is
increased it's going to give you an idea
of the general pH you can see all the
very similar structure but again some of
them are pH dependent can actually be
used as an indicator
so that color changing complexities here
color changes in response to pH
variation of the anthocyanins
this can be used as a pH indicator and
actually extract it from red cabbage to
actually take red cabbage and put it in
a blender and I take some of that water
out and then you add different PHS it'll
actually change color right before your
eyes and you can based on what color you
see can indicate what PH put it in
acidic solution it'll turn more the
pinkish reddish used if you put it more
in a slightly basic it could be more of
the purple if you put it in a more
extreme basic it could be more of a
yellow coloration so fun experiment if
you wanted to try it gets get some red
cabbage in a blender and some degrees of
acids and bases you can literally see
the color change as an indicator
uh with answer signings they also have
something called copigmentation so
copigmentation helps to stabilize the
color of the leaves flowers and fruits
of the plant this increased color
intensity can be due to the
co-pigmentation of anthocyanins and the
flavonoids here's a little bit more of
the detail here of copigmentation
there's metal ions that by the B ring of
the anthocyanins in this case aluminum
binding changes the anthocyanins from a
red to blue color so there is some
degree of complexity that can be
associated with this here we see a low
anthocyanin and the high of the sign of
production this is typically how Growers
are going to recognize it by simply the
degree of purple that they may see
expressed in their plants
now high temperature can also influence
the plant so anthocytes are less stable
at higher solution temperatures in the
plant
previous study the one who showed you
reports a heat treatment at a maximum of
35 degrees Celsius reduces the total
anthocyanin content in the common grape
to less than half the amount and control
berries that were kept at 25 degrees
Celsius so again we're talking about
stability of things anthocyanins kind of
if you increase the temperature too much
you can have that reduction on there in
total concentration
now heating it designs in the extract
solution so if we're looking at these
heat treatment of an anthocyanin and a
rich extract solution may not cause a
degradation of anthocyanin pigment so
it's important here that we're looking
at now the extract of the solution here
this is because the extract commonly
contains phenolic compounds that are
enzymatically degraded by phenyl oxidase
so in this example mild heat of the
extract to up to 50 degrees Celsius has
been shown to inactivate the enzymatic
reaction without the denaturing of the
enzyme the anthocyanin can be preserved
despite the increase in temperature this
is because if the endocytes are being
broken down by an enzyme if that enzyme
has the wrong shape and it can't perform
its function therefore it's denatured
well because the enzyme can no longer
break down the anthocyanin they can be
exposed to greater temperatures so
that's kind of like an interesting fact
there when we're talking about the
extract compared to the actual in the
plant content
now when we're looking at extracting
anthocyanins this can get quite
complicated um here but organic solvents
typically methanol and ethanol are
considered as generally safe extraction
medium isolation of antiscience using
water-based extraction though is Lex
toxic procedure and when it's being
implemented a little bit more frequently
this subcritical water-based extraction
uses acidified water with hydrochloric
acid to a pH of about 2.3 that is
subject to high temperatures we say high
temperatures will get between 110 and
160 degrees Celsius under a constant
pressure of 40 bars this is a highly
effective technique for extracting
anthocyanins from fruit and you can see
it does require some equipment but
really offers the
greatest extraction percentage of this
particular compound
now separation of xanthocyanins while
anthocyanins are extracted from Plants
as a crude mixture for that reason
separation or isolation of specific
types of anthocyanin is needed for a
specific purpose separation and
identification of anti-science can be
done via various chromatic methods here
so just kind of an example here hplc
high pressure liquid chromatography
liquid chromatography Mass Spec NMR
nuclear magnetic resonance there's a lot
of different methods and that kind of
will depend what might be looking at
separating or what degree of specificity
you might need whether it's a
qualitative or a quantitative method as
well
now getting in more into the
biosynthesis so if you want to learn a
little bit more about the hygiene
regulation here this is a relatively new
published article that just came out uh
really gets into some of the details
maybe not for the you know the grower
more morphological macroscopic view but
really this is kind of a breakthrough
that's going to help us out with the bio
Gene regulation of anthocyanin
production
so transcription factors the molecular
basis of anthocyanin biosynthesis and
Cannabis sativa remains elusive however
for this reason research still provides
information regarding the regulatory
genes of anthocyanin biosynthesis this
will be useful for biotechnological
improvement so even though this is just
kind of like a little bit of a glimpse a
little bit of an Insight this could
potentially be the research that
perpetuates this going forward
so why do we want to look at a
transcription Factor transcription
factors and what are transcription
factors they're basically proteins
involved in the process of converting or
transcribing DNA into RNA so we have
genetic codes in our genes and then
those DNA goes to RNA and that RNA is a
messenger RNA that will then get made
into a protein so transcription factors
include a wide number of proteins
excluding RNA polymerase that initiate
and regulate the transcription of genes
there's a really simple way to think
about it you think about is it's an on
off switch the description factor
determines whether that Gene is made or
that protein is produced or whether that
is turned off there and again it occurs
at the molecular level but it's a simple
on off transcription Factor yes make
that protein or no do not make that
protein
so why look at transcription factors uh
well they're important for Gene
regulation and also cell signaling one
distinct feature of transcription
factors is that they have DNA binding
domains that give them the ability to
bind to specific sequences of DNA called
enhancer or promoter sequences again
that promoter reach would be the area
that can be the light switch turned on
or turned off
as a result this all the direct impact
on the expression or the suppression of
this particular Gene so we see here if
there's an enhancer it's going to allow
this to kind of go through and progress
and allow that protein to be made or if
there's a silencer or a suppressor
that's going to prevent that or stop
that act as a wall of barrier turn that
off now our bodies that want to make
everything all the time so this this is
important to have this regulation but
here we're looking at it specifically
for this anthocyanin a biosynthesis
process
So within that there is the um myb
family for of transcription factors the
my B transcription factors abbreviate
TFS if I use that um preceding or
preceding this as one of the largest
Gene families in Plants it gets its name
from the myoblast
um came from the first identification of
these which was in avian oncogenes
interesting background there 203
identified nyp family transcription
factors have been found in eukaryotes
now they do play important roles in
biological processes well beyond what
we're going to look at here including
plant growth plant cell morphology
pattern building physiological activity
primary and secondary metabolite
reactors responses to environmental
stresses you could see involved in a lot
this family of transcription factors
plays a vital role in regulating
anthocyanin biosynthesis as well in fact
R2 R3 myb genes have been identified in
the Cannabis sativa genome alone here
we're looking at an example here
arabidopsis but we're looking now at
this article really making it more
specific to the canvas sativa plant
so what are these R2 R3 and YB genes why
are they you know why are we looking at
them and this is other previous
researchers did confirm that the
esmybf1 as a flavonoid specific
regulator which participate in the
biosynthesis regulation of the flavonoid
derived bioactive components now this is
looking at kind of that genetics which I
know can be look a little confusing if
you're not used to looking at charts
like this but just think of this as a
genetic sequences you're looking at the
genes or the coating the recipes to make
certain proteins
so these transcription factors are
widely involved in the secondary
metabolites of organic acids in
medicinal plants it's been found that
these R2 R3 myb transcription factors of
the fourth subfamily are involved in
metabolism of the female paranoid as in
negative regulator in various medicinal
plants what does this mean in short
we're looking at we're in that Gene
regulation we can choose to upregulate
or down regulate certain genes and now
we've kind of identified that marker
according to this published study
so into science Regulators are
identified based on the phonology as
well as the expression profiling of
genes in two areas here of the canvas
sativa differing in the content of
anthocyanin pigmentation in the sugar
leaves to punitive regulations of
anthocyanin biosynthesis named as a
csmyb33 and csmyb78 were identified so
again we're identifying specific regions
within the cannabis plant based on This
research so that can really be utilized
now to start to Target or look for
certain sequences we can definitely see
that image B has more of that purple
anthocyanin regular upregulation than
does a plant a here
so they looked at similar plant so they
were looking at the transit
overexpression of these in leaves of a
close relative of tobacco and as
comparison it was founded there was a
stronger in terms of activation of the
anthocyanin biosynthesis so we're
looking at the certain genes looking at
a you know a cross comparison here
developing that analog there for
comparison we're definitely seeing this
in derivatives of cultivated tobacco
seeing that increased expression I think
just on the pictures alone you can see
that higher degree of purple coloration
that enhanced anthocyanin pigmentation
the leaves as well as the sepals the
transatic lines there so we're able to
modify those genes and we are seeing
that proof of concept with that
increased purple coloration
so this is a start so it's great
information but there is still limited
knowledge about the structural and
functional attributes of the R2 R3 mybs
in canvas sativa we can see that they
are found in other plants as well we're
trying to understand specifically in the
cannabis plant so I know there's a lot
of background information there so how
does this actually help a grower after
this in-depth investigation about
anthocyanins and hopefully you've tuned
in this long most Growers recognize this
as a purple coloration to their plants
often this is a result of an
environmental stress I'm going to show
you two examples of this plant response
I'm going to be out in the field early
season showing you plant shock showing
increased anthocyanin pigmentation in
the main stem of recently transplanted
seedlings and here is going to show us
increased anthocyanin production on Leaf
petioles indicated right here due to a
sudden increase in light exposure due to
the removal of a nearby plant's shading
so hopefully you've enjoyed this kind of
like background look detailed new
genetic look and now let's go out in the
field where you can also see this
comparison of different plants with
different anthocyanin levels of
production
now many Growers may think this is a
phosphorus deficiency when they first
look at it because they're seeing the
purple coloration of the stem and also
the leaves here but this just may be a
simple transplant shock plants about two
weeks in the ground here and you can see
that knowing the soil test has a
adequate amount of phosphorus so a lot
of times it gets misdiagnosed as a
phosphorus deficiency when in actuality
this might be simply a stress the reason
why I continue to say that if you look
at some of the newer growth towards the
top here you're noticing that's green
and yes there is some still stress kind
of towards the edge but it's a way the
plant can produce what's called
anthocyanins those anthocyanins shade it
from the sun because it is out here in
the middle of the field so this might be
just a perfect example of a little plant
stress that is not a nutrient deficiency
at all
So today we're outside investigating
this purpling on one of our cannabis
plant stalks the reason that this had
occurred in the first place is that
right where the camera was there used to
be a much taller cannabis plant growing
providing constant shade to this side of
the plant but suddenly because of bunny
damage it got taken down so in result
this plant received much more light on
this side than it was typically used to
resulting in this purpling pigment it's
like a sunburn but for a plant you could
tell it's a sunburn
because it doesn't occur on the other
side it's just where the light hits the
stem that it has this purple
pigmentation the anthocyanin come out
and create this purple pigment
and that's what causes sometimes
purpling within the stems of your
cannabis plant