so here we're going to look at
antibodies or immunoglobulins both are
interchangeable terms we see the image
here on the title slide with a constant
region in a variable region the variable
regions here is referring to the ends
here no sizzle cutaways shape is very
important these proteins need to bind to
antigens and this is why there's a
variable region up here is because of
different shapes these can take time so
looking specifically at the definition
of an amino globulin these are class of
proteins of the immune system that are
also known as antibodies says as I said
a kind of interchangeable terms but what
is an empty body
well antibodies are attached to foreign
substances to allow the immune system to
destroy them it's important to make note
here that the antibodies are not the
ones doing the destruction they're
merely attaching to the surfaces to kind
of signal the immune system to come
destroy this foreign substance they're
specific to each type of horse for in
some sense so this variable region these
specific shapes match a very specific
foreign substance so as a result we have
many different types of antibodies now
we can classify them into these five
main groups IgA IgG IgM IgE and IgD in
the IG sitting for abbreviation of for
the immunoglobulin each or levels of
each type of these antibodies can give
your doctor and indication about the
cause of a medical problem
so as we'll see in some of the certain
tests will do for certain antibodies to
determine if your body's been exposed to
certain antigens now within our
classifications we have monomers dimer
is referring to two and Penta MERS he
referring to five different ones
only IgM sarpent immers iga s are
diverse in IgG IgE and IgG or both
monomer antibodies so starting with the
IgA here the fountain airs the body such
as the nose breathing passages and
digestive tract it's important that
these antibodies are located in these
regions because they protect body
surfaces that are exposed to the outside
foreign substances this is our specialty
about 10 to 15 percent of antibodies
present in the body or iga s and a small
number of people actually
produce IgE antibodies it's a rarity so
do you need them to live no but by
having them you're able to better
protect your surfaces that are in direct
exposure to the outside environment with
IG G's so keep in mind the second my
first G I should say is lowercase in the
second G is uppercase they're found in
all body fluids
they're a monomer they're the most
common IMT body found in the body about
75 to 80 percent it's important for
fighting bacterial and viral infections
and only type of antibody that can cross
the placenta and pregnant women this
helps protect her baby or fetus they're
also utilized here as we see this Zika
virus antibody test IgG and IgM antibody
test so if we're looking for someone
that may be exposed to the Zika virus
might be carrying it some way we can
test for the antibodies to see if
they're present and this is why the
antibody test you see here in here in
ihe G and IgM indication referring to
the antibodies classification that this
test is in tune if it's indicated with
its presence
IgM are found in the blood and lymph
fluid are the first type of antibody
made in response to an infection and
they cause other immune system cells to
destroy foreign substances IgM and
devisor about 5% percent of all the
antibodies in the body and they're the
only ones that fall into the pentamer
class we see our antibody level we have
initial dose of a legitimacy IgM primary
response increases above IgG and then
goes away
our second dose of antigen the IgM does
come back but our IgG you can see very
different so IgM is the the first type
of antibody made in response to an
infection that initial or primary
response they are made during the
secondary dose of the antigen but you
could see that in relation to IgG their
secondary immune response is minimal
IgE if you suffer from allergies this is
one that you can blame here they're
found in the lungs skin and mucous
membranes they caused by to react
against foreign substance such as pollen
fungal spores in animal dander they're
involved in allergic reactions the
levels of IgE are often high in people
with allergies and there's certain
limits as far as what would be
considered a low level moderate high and
very high levels here and we can
classify them as such so if you are more
sensitive to certain pollens or
allergens you can probably vein i GE for
your reactions IgD isn't IG is an
interesting one these are antibodies
found in small amounts in the tissues
that lie in the belly and chest
however exactly how they work is
actually not 100% clear so they do exist
we now observe presence they do have
some very basic idea of their
understanding but exactly how they work
specifically is actually not clear just
goes to show scientists are continuing
to do research on things that we may
know exists but we need to understand
better how they perform and work a way
to mount device to kind of remember
these it's called gamed so you don't
forget any G AME D and this is referring
to the different antibodies there this
is also a great summary slide to kind of
give you that review of what my G G does
IgM IgD and so on and so forth lastly
the five immunoglobin classes here we
see the names we see the properties and
associated with the structure here on
the right hand side just another way to
help your review and help you understand
the difference between the different
types of the musical elements present in
your body