yeah I'm going to discuss a very
destructive plant insect called a
schvitz now while it may be small in
size with a lack in size they definitely
make can make a poor in numbers in
disruption so first off identifying what
you have is important so for an
indication of aphids well they are very
small you can see here looking at a
canvas plant how small they look in
comparison the cone was like a little
white dust covering the plants what
allows them to kind of mass multiply is
a little scary sometimes here is that
they can be born pregnant so we can have
an ancient kind of within an aphid
giving rise to Moray fits really causing
their numbers to increase dramatically
not to say they can't lay eggs but this
is one way that they can mass multiply
they are piercing insects so their
mouthparts are for piercing looking
specifically at getting into the phloem
which transports the sugars in the plant
there are six a third species in
particular that are specifically attack
cannabis plants while there's many other
species six in particular have been
identified to attack cannabis in
particular now we're to look most adults
do not have wings so you want to look at
the underside of the leaves
typically shy away from areas of bright
light some species prefer older lower
leaves and others prefer younger upper
leaves so where you find in the plant
may help identify and identify what
particular type of Av did you have
however regardless of what type they all
follow the same basic pattern they all
have very similar ways that they can
destroy the plant early damage can be a
challenge to detect in part because that
they are so small honey deal will be
excreted from the aphids and this is one
indicating factor when you are looking
at identifying them now how to prevent a
fence or they can it's important to do
this because it can vector diseases
particularly viruses polio viruses to be
exact
more moist conditions with minimal air
movement will increase the damage
occurred by aphids you want to inspect
incoming plants for them and avoid high
nitrogen fertilization as this can
promote lush growth that is favorable
for aphids if it's kind of like this
kind of bloated look to leaves and it
can easily cause through and in fact
that and they do in fact it's
particularly they transmit viruses you
can get this kind of weird mottled look
to the leaves you can also get this
weird kind of crinkly look to
some of the leaves and other leaves will
look fine this is very indicative of a
viral infection typically vectored by a
fits and what a vector is is just an
intermediate that can transport certain
diseases to other ultimate hosts here
know how to control them
to common control methods are lady
beetles and green lace wings lady
beetles can be refrigerated and released
when it's advantageous just the grower
within reason and releasing them to
evening or early morning near a few
colonies while the vents are closed is a
way to get the maximum effectiveness
from that you may need VP applications
not easily purchased in released so it
makes it great for grower control
another one it can be used for aphids
are green lace wings and they can sprint
larvae over an area because they're
cannibalistic so if you do buy them as
larvae you want to spread them out
because they will eat each other you
wanna look for clean new growth the sign
that Athens has been killed the sense
that you've reduced that population and
the plants not able to produce new
growth again however keep in mind if you
are using these in a greenhouse and it
does get warm above 95 degrees they
typically will leave the greenhouse area
in secret of cooler temperatures so
again these are two methods of
biological control for aphids put a
little link down here if you want to
learn a little bit more about Athens and
how to control them and prevent them
from damaging your crop