okay here we're going to look at the
area of convergence and determining the
point
of origin which is very important we're
kind of analyzing
cast off blood splatter or blood spider
in general as far as where it may
converge
where that point of origin may exist so
looking at the point of convergence
examples
when we're looking at angle
determination and determining where
those kind of blood splatters may have
occurred it's very important
to try to draw lines and try to
determine where that convergence
point actually may be we see here on the
kind of cartoon representations as well
as a larger kind of real world image
here
where if you look at all these
individual little drops we see
definitely a
point of convergence located right here
in the red
circle now here's a five mil blood
squirted from a syringe at a height of
one
meter so the point here is trying to
give you an idea of
what those droplets may look like when
you kind of zoom in and look at them in
a closed space
and how important is able how important
it is to be able to determine the
direction
and also potentially the angle of impact
now that point of origin as you
mentioned being able to calculate that
angle of impact remember still length
and width are two important measurements
you need to take
because it's the width divided by the
length and you take the arc side of that
to get the angle
reason why this is important is when
you're trying to determine that origin
point
knowing the angle of those different
blood drops can help kind of trace back
and determine the height above the point
of convergence
so here we have the distance from the
point of convergence and we have the
height
being able to use this angle of impact
with a string method able to kind of
help determine that origin point which
can be very critical
when trying to reconstruct a crime scene
tracing origin of the blood spots well
we have the point and conversion method
which generates a 2d image but then we
also can take it a step further to point
of origin method that adds a
third dimension to it the application in
the field of course is to use it in
a string and a protractor at the scene
in our user computer and laboratory
to determine that point of origin which
will help tell the story
of what occurred at the particular crime
scene