okay so you can't want to go over
artificial lighting setup basics it's
really easy for growers to go out and
buy a bunch of lights and then worry
about setting them up so what if you
think about your grow room or your gross
space and look at it realistically and
then buy lights that match that
particular setup so first off planning
your lighting system well all lights
generate some form of heat so you should
have an idea about how you're going to
manage this basics should be taking the
consideration our distance your plants
this is you're going to put those lights
from your plants also distance from the
ceiling method of cooling and capacity
of this circuit so you kind of have
these competing ideas if you want to
light the area but you have this heat to
contend with it kind of becomes this
little chess match of how you're gonna
organize things and you want to make
sure it's organized ahead of time so
you're not fooling around with all these
potentially very expensive lights with a
in a system that will not work so
distance from plants and distance from
the ceiling so depending on the stage of
growth and type of light well the
recommend distance will change for
example if using fluorescent lights or
looking about three to six inch distance
between the plants and the lights
high-pressure sodium Zoar your other
high intensity lights looking at two
feet or greater also want to consider
the distance from the ceiling as this
has to do with the day to cool the
fixture and seeing this grove facility
here there's a good distance to the
ceiling allowing plenty of air
circulation and ability to cool the area
very easily the method of cooling the to
choose lights these lights can generate
heat should also consider a method of
cooling it could be potentially passive
but usually assisted in some way I'll
serve the same purpose but will depend
on the basics of the growing space so
fan assisted is probably the most common
I can see here's a can filter it's able
to really circulate the air well and
also purify and clean the air while it's
also circulating it also one because
think about the system capacity it's
very easy and call it just to add lights
I'll be sure your system can support the
power requirements needed take the total
circuit and support connect up to 80% of
what can be supported by the stated
value of that circuit even if everything
on that circuits not ring at the same
time consider it the worst case
area.also hopefully using a breaker box
kind of assisting here and that kind of
the old knob-and-tube infusers here
upgrade to kind of a modern day on
electrical box here help reduce the
chance of fire and Ally to spread things
out much more effectively the wire gauge
- the higher the number the smaller the
wire diameters we see here 30 gauge 29
gauge 28 gauge as we get to 10 gauge
much larger 4 gauge 2 gauge 1 gauge this
is little counterintuitive that larger
numbers that smaller wire gauge for
teens often considered as standard
however if you're doing a long run with
high power consumption 12 gauge or a
lower wire will be recommending to
reduce the chance of fire importance of
a grounding plug so we're looking at the
example between this plug in this plug
the entire electrical system should have
a grounding plug if your outlets can
only accept a two prong electrical
device you are highly recommend to
upgrade your system here to include a
grounding plug and these kind of would
be the updated system into the older
system here and both running at the same
voltage but the grounding plug is much
advised because of that ground that is
present to help again make your system
as safe as possible lastly you want to
make sure you're properly seating the
bulb so take care to ensure the system
is often unplugged and take extra steps
for good electrical connection both with
the ballasts and also at the bulb
connection a lot of times you can see
here that they'll fit in which want to
make sure they're seated properly I also
want to clean the bulb in the reflector
before turning it on make sure
everything checks out before adding
power and turning this on so you have
the safest and most efficient way to
light your plants