in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over artificial lighting
options for cannabis production and give
you some of the pros
and cons of some of the common
artificial lighting sources that you
might be considering
[Music]
so if you ever wonder why there's so
many artificial lighting options well
there's some advantages and
disadvantages of each
which will be discussed here so first
off the goal of all grow lights
is to help plants grow that's the whole
idea or concept behind all the
artificial lights
there are different than typical room
lights because grow lights are based on
the spectrum
that is required by plants so just
because we see a nice
light that looks nice we want to make
sure it's
specifically designed for plants so it's
producing the spectrum and the
wavelengths that the plants need to
utilize
so provided with a good reference
article here looking at some artificial
lighting systems
all sources provided right here if you
want to look at it for yourself
in greater detail now looking at a
variety of grow light options
there are wide range of bulb types that
can be used as grow lights
however the general categories include
fluorescent lights which are typically
t5 lights
high intensity discharge lamps or hid
lights which include high pressure
sodiums and ceramic metal halides
and then light emitting diodes which are
your led lights
which would be getting very popular
recently so again this is just a nice
little comparison
looking at the spectrum the cost power
draw efficiency and applications
i'm going to go through here and provide
you with some advantages and
disadvantages of each
however before i get to the specifics of
the different types we want to look at
letting
technology continues to change so while
technology continues to kind of change
over time
the degree of light efficacy
advancements varies by the light
type led lights show the greatest
promise for continued future
improvements
we see a lot of leveling off in our many
of our other
lights such as the incandescents the
fluorescence the metal halides but we
see the led light group being definitely
one that is kind of
going against the general trend of
leveling off and this is kind of
exponential rise and here's where it's
estimated to kind of go to
going forward so that's just something
to take into consideration
now the distance between lights in the
plants so here we see just a little
example here of some
led lights and we kind of see a
measuring device here to kind of get an
idea how far that light
is away from the plants the distance
between the lights and the plants should
be based on the intensity of the light
this should be measured using a par p
pfd or pfd
meter there the lower light output the
closer the plants should be
and the higher the light output ideally
the further the plant should be
simply to avoid the chance of leaf burn
or damage
to maximize yields growers should keep
all plant factors such as water
concentration of carbon dioxide optimum
levels because cannabis can tolerate
high levels of light which can help
increase yields assuming all other
factors are not limiting
including but not limited to nutrients
so let's look at the first one here
looking at our fluorescent lights well
the advantages of fluorescence is that
can be close
placed really close to the plants
they're also not very expensive and the
bulbs have a very long life of about
twenty thousand hours
however the disadvantages are that they
have a low light intensity
they use multiple bulbs per unit and the
disposal of those bulbs can be a
challenge because of some of the toxic
metals
that they contain going on to cmh or
ceramic metal halide lights
the advantages of those are that they're
easy replacements for a for professional
light setup
one bulb design with more spectrum
options compared to the fluorescence
and they also have a long bulb life why
they're not used
is that they're not great for the
flowering phase they produce a fair
amount of heat
and also the disposal disposal of their
bulb as well but it tends to be smaller
and tends to be less of them compared to
a fluorescent option
high pressure sodium lights can be used
for the entire growth season even though
it's not ideal for the vegetative stage
it still can be used prices have become
very attractive meaning they've been
reduced quite a bit
and it's considered to be the industry
standard so there's many reliable
options with the high pressure swim or
hbs lights
reason why some growers elect not to use
them is that their bulbs have a
relatively short life of only about 5000
hours
they do produce a fair amount of heat
and they have a limited
spectrum there so there's some
disadvantaged high pressure sodium
lights
lastly going onto led lights the light
emitting diodes they are full spectrum
light
and they can increase compounds that
define high quality cannabis
they also have a very long life of
typically 50 000 hours or greater
depending on the manufacturer
however the disadvantage of led lights
is the initial cost
there's a lot of variability currently
on the market and the total coverage
area per
light so when investing in any light you
want to make sure to do your research
look at everything extensively and make
the best
option that's a fit for your particular
growing situation