this is gonna be a very brief overview
of the artificial lighting options and I
see a bunch of them here in this veg
room and dis identifying which ones that
they are and what their main purpose is
so the types of lighting options are the
best uses here provided so there's nope
in the picture here of fluorescence but
T fives are high energy if efficient and
they're typically used for clones or
seedlings for hid the high-intensity
output lights metal halide lights are
typically used for veg the veg phase
even though they're not pictured here
CMH is our ceramic metal halides our
propagation into veg this is one example
here should be a CMH light high pressure
sodium is used for flowering and anna
has that kind of yellowish tint to it
lepo light emitting plasma is veg or
used as flowers and supplementation also
produces a very white almost slightly
bluish light here and then LEDs can be
our light-emitting diodes and this can
be for the full grow cycle this one's
not necessarily a full spectrum is kind
of purple and pink light on there some
that will produce a very clean white
light and those used for a full spectrum
so just this gives you that quick little
comparison of how these different lights
look some of the different colors that
they can produce and how you can easily
identify them one potentially by their
structure or two by the color at least
that we perceive that light to produce