you may associate ascorbic acid with
vitamin C being and oranges and other
citrus crafts and you are correct but
here were a look at its impact as a
plant hormone and what effects that can
happen plants more than just the citrus
such as the oranges and lemons so this
vitamin C is abundant component of
plants its proposed functions in post
synthesis as an enzyme cofactor this
also includes a synthesis of ethylene
gibberellins and anthocyanins and also
in the control of cell growth so it can
have more than just the post synthetic
process it can also control and regulate
potentially cell growth in plants L
absorb acids is just referring as lv 4
into the type of shape that it has we're
looking at L and D forms L is more
biologically active this is the form of
vitamin C so it's essential for plants
as it is to animals is this something
that crosses both plants and animals
vitamin C here regulates cell division
do you can see here growth and it's
involved in signal transduction it's the
passing of signals within a plant or
within a cell in general in contrast to
the single pathway responsible for
absorbing acid both synthesis in animals
in contrast to that plants use multiple
pathways to synthesize this particular
plant hormone this perhaps reflects the
importance of this molecule on plant
health because as multiple pathways okay
something was to happen to one plant
almost need a way to kind of produce
this particular plant hormone at
absorbing acid as a result they have
multiple pathways to be to accomplish
that so our C acids not only important
antioxidant also appears to link to
flowering time developmental senescence
which is the degradation of plants
leaves here for example they senesce
they die off like the leaves in a New
England fall program cell death which is
apoptosis in response to pathogens
through complex signal transduction
Network so what I try to show a little
bit here is this complex network is just
an example of how you can have one input
finding a whole cascade of events to
occur ultimate leading to gene
regulation there's just some of the
examples
sorbic acid can do lastly therefore it's
assumed that absolute acid affects
phytochrome mediated signaling just
process during the transition from the
vegetative to the reproductive phase in
the final stage of development and
ultimately senescence so when you're
flipping your plants going from our
flowering going from a vegetative to
that flowering stage during that flower
development absorbing acid could be
occurring in higher amounts and
influencing that so again I'm just an
example how a plant hormone well may be
needed in small amounts in the plant can
have large effects on that whole plant
physiology and ultimately potentially
even the anatomy