okay so here we're look at some of the
details behind aseptic technique and
what this basically is is keeping things
clean and to the point of being sterile
in conditions that require this to
prevent contamination so instead of
techniques our precautionary measures
taken to prevent contamination of pure
cultures and sterile laboratory
equipment treat all organisms as
potential pathogens even if that may not
be the case was this technique involved
it's kind of this isolation of things
that's occurring preventing
contamination allowing only the natural
bacteria in that area or that pathogen
you might be working with preventing
from getting from escaping and limiting
cross-transfer of unwanted
microorganisms the general goal the
proper procedure will note the chance of
that cross-contamination is he kind of
here touching a dirty surface and going
somewhere else
well the kinds of this simple
accomplishing it can be a challenge as
all portions of the process must be
adhered to you can't be sterile for a
little portion and then go on and then
not be sterling be sterile again because
you'll ruin the entire protocol there
could also be important for example with
food items to prevent contamination when
processing food and during the cooking
process I want to start sterile so in
the lab this may involve producing
previously sterilized products that come
in sealed containers here might be
firmer at the dentist office for example
or we left to sterilize what you're
going to use so there's techniques UV
light is one example there can be
sterling fluids it can be used so you
want to start sterile with whatever
tools you're using whether you purchase
them sterile or you sterilize them
yourself one have a clean working area
so keeping the area clean before during
and after an experiment are key concepts
to keep in mind this will help eliminate
the chance for contamination
this goes to equipment to IP using for
multiple experiments probes that might
be used for different areas you want to
make sure everything starts clean you
keep it clean during the experiment and
you also clean it afterwards wash hands
and use gloves so just because you're
using gloves doesn't mean you don't have
to wash your hands hands should be
washed before then you put the gloves
remember to wash your hands after as
well even though these ideally will be
creating a barrier between whenever
you're working with it's good practice
to wash before but the gloves not and
work with them and then wash after in
case anything was to breach the gloves
here have materials on hand so read over
the protocol ahead of time and be sure
all necessary items are in hand are in
places that are easy access this may
involve you're taking chemicals putting
on a tray as make keeping things in
close quarters to the equipment you'll
be using read that protocol fully over
and have everything you need on hand
keep it in close easy access this will
prevent you from having to travel long
distances but will this help increase
the odds of our chance of contamination
occurring you want to work efficiently
so the longer it takes you to make
transitions to greater chance for
contamination here we see we're in a
sterile hood everything is closed
everything is efficient plates are here
all the tubes are here we got a flame
everything is very close quarters easy
to find easy to get to and through
proper lab technique you should be able
to work through this efficiently now if
you're working with petri dishes
so keep the dishes closed and when you
need to access the media tilt the lid
just enough to gain access you wanted to
say remove the lid and go through heroes
this image would show you want to just
lift it enough just so you can get in
there transfer what you need to and then
close it back again don't lift that lid
completely off even though it may look
like good for this picture it's not a
true story all technique even if you're
in a hood this can still cause a chance
for contamination to occur you want to
limit that as much as possible hear us
you're working close to a flame we're
just lifting it as much as needed for
the duration at speeds that transfer
close it stack it and move on this is
all good ways to keep everything sterile
and clean which is important when you're
looking for high level of detail in your
experiments