so you want to grow your cannabis plants
that normal atmospheric levels of carbon
dioxide
that doesn't require any additional
enrichment plants have been doing just
fine
on this level of carbon dioxide for many
many many years all outdoor plants
are subject to atmospheric levels
however there's a couple things you
should keep in mind
[Music]
so let's look at growing plants
atmospheric carbon dioxide levels
related to cannabis production
can we talk about atmospheric conditions
they have been on the rise here we can
see some
circulation but overall we do see a kind
of in this example
kind of an increase here a linear
progression running around that kind of
around that 400 ish parts per million
would be considered
atmospheric levels now as i said i'm
going to use at
400 parts per million to be that normal
atmospheric levels
keep in mind that cannabis has been
grown atmospheric levels carbon accident
for thousands of years
all outdoor plants that's what they're
subject to this can produce quality
yields assuming no other factors are
limiting and as i said atmospheric
conditions
are on the rise and they are varying
year to year
so if we are growing in atmospheric
conditions something you want to keep in
mind
is air circulation so by simply
circulating air around the canvas plant
a grower can deliver 400 parts million
of carbon dioxide
fans and air circulation are important
components of any growing environment
so this supplementation of carbon oxide
comes as a bonus
you don't want to have the arb stagnant
because plants can consume
the carbon dioxide and actually reduce
those levels
so by circulating air particularly
bringing outside air in
is a great way to ensure they're
constantly getting that normal
about 400 parts per million atmospheric
levels
they're growing plants at these
atmospheric levels and there's no need
for any additional equipment
or monitoring devices this makes a very
easy grow and this could be an indoor
grow
this could also be an outdoor grow
probably a little easier in the outdoor
grow but
even indoor grow keep that air moving
keep bringing air out from the outside
in
to ensure your growing environment is at
least at atmospheric levels because it
extends plant canopies can cause that to
drop below
now there are some challenges with
atmospheric conditions
if air ventilation is not sufficient
while plants are consuming
large quantities of carbon dioxide this
can cause those carbon dioxide levels to
drop below
atmospheric conditions which is around
400 parts per million
if levels drop below 250 parts per
million or
lower this will actually result in plant
stunting with no monitor it can be
difficult to know if this happens
so just constantly keep air moving
around now we see the kind of the
example here with
a lettuce crop many crops like lettuce
can benefit from supplementation of
carbon dioxide
plant on the left received less than 400
parts per million
then the plant below here received 500
parts which again is above atmospheric
levels but we can see this difference
here at least visually
now for indoor conditions keep in mind
with
indoor indoors lighting needs to be
supplemented as well
if only using atmospheric conditions
lower light intensities can potentially
be
used because even under 400 parts plant
of carbon dioxide
plants will be correctly limited if
given higher which is considered above
my
900 micro moles of light levels
so just keep that in mind that if you're
seeing different lights for sale and
high intensity light
it may recommend with carbon dioxide
because plants at atmospheric levels
can not really use much above 900
micromoles
so these atmospheric levels
normal atmospheric levels can produce
good yields as growers have been working
with this for many years
however this should be considered the
standard or control
production levels because if you add
carbon dioxide you have the potential
to increase your yields from here