so you may have heard that they're going
to get in the autopsy results from
a victim or a body well what does this
exactly mean
well here at tobacco university with
this video of autopsy basics we're going
to go over
some of the background regarding
autopsies
so first off when an autopsy in general
it's a basically it's an internal
medical examination of a body
used to determine the cause and
circumstances of the death that's the
entire goal
of performing or conducting an autopsy
now keep in mind that there are two
different
terms that sometimes use interchangeably
and they really shouldn't be
one is a medical examiner and one is a
coroner a medical examiner is a
government official
which is always a physician and often a
forensic pathologist
and charged with the investigating
sudden and unexpected death
deaths or deaths from injuries the
coroner is an elected official with
death investigation duties that signs
the death
certificate so keep in mind these are
distinctly different people
they once a government official wants an
elected official and they have
very distinctive and different
backgrounds so these terms should not
be used interchangeably now death is
defined as
we're trying to determine here the end
of life is to
put it simply it's characterized by
stopping of blood circulation
and brain activity when the heart stops
beating oxygen is deprived from the body
and the cells will begin to die at that
point
once enough cells die life cannot be
restarted
so we're looking at this is how our
defining death here
the goal of autopsies so the whole point
of
providing them is to try to determine
the manner of death which is the means
by which the person
perished the cause of death which is the
reason why they died
the mechanism of death which is the
specific body failure that may have
occurred
and the time of death is referring to
when the person actually
died now the manner of death there's
different categories that can be placed
in
there could be natural as if this is
caused or determined to be caused by
disease
cancer physical injury stroke or heart
attack and occurred
only or solely by those then there's
accidental if it occurs without apparent
intent
there's suicide if caused by the
deceased
person or individual homicide is defined
as if someone other than deceased
caused it and then we have suicide and
homicide examples such as shooting
burning poisoning hang drowning or
suffocation these are all kind of manner
of death
categories the autopsy could classify
death as when we have causes of death
which there are
many uh and this is the simple reason
why they died we just see annually
number of deaths caused in the world in
2016 right above me
with uh cardiovascular disease and
cancers being at the very top of the
list here
and we can kind of see everything else
again projected all those numbers in
millions of deaths annually
looking at the world population for the
year 2016.
because you have a little zoomed in
version here the top 10
global causes of death for 2016 again
expressed in
millions of people then we get the
mechanism of
death so what the mechanism of death
would hear
is we're trying to describe the specific
change in the body that brought about
the cessation of
life what was the kind of the method at
which that occurred
if someone has been shot they may have
died from loss of blood for example
someone dies of a heart attack they may
die from pulmonary arrest
and if someone is strangled they may die
from affixiation so this is looking at
the
mechanism of death and here's a sample
kind of death certificate
just provided here just you can kind of
get an idea of what's included there
and lastly we have the time of death so
a lot of times forensic investigators
are trying to estimate or determine what
time this was
and this is simply when the person
actually died and this can help
determine who to
include or to exclude based on alibis or
location at a certain day or time
that's why it's such a crucial part of
the investigation process
to try to determine and pinpoint that
time of death even has to be estimated
with its great degree of accuracy given
the information
that can be gathered and collected