okay I'm going to go over autoimmune
diseases here I'm going to give you a
brief definition as well as point out
some diseases that you may have heard of
but did not know that they were an
autoimmune disease so first off the
definition of an autoimmune disease what
happens during this is cytotoxic T cells
and B cells lose their ability to
distinguish self cells from non-self
cells as a result from this the body
actually starts attacking its own
tissues so as a reminder in a normal
immune response we had antigens that
invade our body build up antibodies to
form against them when the antibodies
remove the invading antigens as a result
the advisors remain and protect
ourselves for the long term that's a
normal case however in an autoimmune
disease our immune system forms
antibodies to self antigens the
antibodies attack self antigens and as a
result the body has a high degree of
inflammation and tissue damage that
occurs it's basically the body attacking
itself instead of being directed with a
high degree of specificity to foreign
antigens that are invading the body now
a couple examples of autoimmune diseases
that you may have heard before but may
not kick in autoimmune diseases have a
couple listed here multiple sclerosis
type 1 diabetes rheumatoid arthritis or
just some examples there's over 100
autoimmune diseases and I want you to
realize that they infect many different
components of the body they're not just
isolated to one region or one type of
tissue for example autism multiple
sclerosis is involved with the brain
leukemia involved with the blood we have
our celiac and Crohn's disease at the GI
tract fibromyalgia with the lungs so you
rheumatoid arthritis with the bones
there's many here and these are all
examples of autoimmune diseases with the
same basic principle where the body is
unable to distinguish self from non-self
and as a result sadly and self attacking
its own tissues causing inflammation
damage and as a result many different
types of diseases