okay and this be able to give a brief
overview regarding autumn leaf color
changes and how we go from a deep green
leaf to slowly over time getting to a
light green getting to a yellow getting
to an orange or red to a deep red and
ultimately Brownlee what's going on in
the leaves through this process will the
start on what plants do this and in that
all plants go through this color change
deciduous trees are the ones that go
through this there's ones that drop
leaves in the fall time when this is
does this occur again since the fall
time or autumn how does this happen
there's a precise sequence of steps that
plants go through and have a very
distinctive pattern that they follow why
is this advantageous to the plant while
the plant
kind of like wastes all the energy you
put into developing the leaf
well it's using the most efficient time
of the year and maximizing that then
realize in the winter there's just not a
lot going on it's very cold out and it
drops its leaves it's more efficient
than just to chase it we go dormant
during that time however this is only
possible through a very precise sequence
of steps so the plant is and wasting
energy
so in general how the trees know that
it's fall time it seems like every tree
in an inner region knows its quote it's
full time and there's a couple key
factors one is the shortening days and
this is reduced sunlight intensity
temperature is also decreasing so
there's certain indicators that these
plants can sense that kind of it's fall
time winter's coming let me get ready
and prepare myself to be able to go
dormant so I can survive through the
harsh winter and come back better and
stronger in the springtime so again it
has to do with the position of the
northerners some southern hemisphere in
relation to the Sun and this is how we
get our seasons because of the tilt of
the earth and how it rotates and then
revolves around the Sun and because of
this this is how plants know in our
region that's how we can develop these
maps of peak foliage times to be able to
determine when would be the best time to
go see some of the better colors in
different parts of the United States so
where did the colors come from what
color tune is indicate changes in
concentrations of certain pigments so we
see here kind of no change to tree
being there and the coloration
differences that's going on here as long
as you're not colorblind typically from
late August or early November is when
we're seeing this transition occur and
this particular color palette here is
for sugar maple trees different trees
may have different color patterns that
go through the sugar maples in
particular are known for producing some
very brilliant colors so what's going on
here
well leaves are green do the high
percentage of chlorophyll but as this
gets depleted other pigments become more
dominant leaves don't actually change
color that's kind of a wrong misnomer
that we typically say well it's actually
happens the colors are always there it
is happened to be hidden under the
dominant chlorophyll so as we reduce our
chlorophyll the next most dominant
pigment is this carotene it's a yellow
color so as you break down the
chlorophyll now together carotene let me
break down that and we have our into
silent and as we break that down and
from our oranges to our Reds we're
changing the pH of the leaves changing
I'm sorry the pH of the potential soil
or have a changing weather conditions
and this is what can cause a variability
in the color that may be seen in a
region from year to year Louis there's
gonna be a good color or bad color year
weather does play a little bit of a
factor in this to be able to get the
full color range that may occur now
what's actually happening on the leaf or
the atomic level here we're noticing
that chlorophyll is of course the most
dominant and then we're breaking the
chlorophyll down the carotenoids here
may be maintained and as an orange or
yellow color Rubisco and other proteins
are recycled so it's important to
realize this transition of colors is
occurring because the plant is trying to
conserve as much energy it's breaking
down the chlorophyll first then it's
breaking down the next stage here and we
see that evident here bring down the
chlorophyll then a carotene
then our anthocyanin and it's try to
conserve and store some this energy to
be able to be ready for next spring if
it just simply dropped its leaves and
wasted all this energy that it put in
what may not have enough energy reserves
to be able to produce these leaves in
the following spring
ultimately ends in cell death and that's
the brown color that we typically see
and shortly after that the leaves will
drop if you have noticed when the leaves
drop there's not much to them because
the plant has tried to conserve or take
back as much usable products that it did
produce and store them in the trunk this
then will be used as initial source of
energy to go to push through the next
leaves in the fall and spring some
people take advantage of some of these
stored sugars in the tree trunk through
the process of maple syrup where they
need freezing temperatures at night and
above freezing temperatures during the
day to really get the SAP flowing and
they're able to kind of harvest some of
the sugars that the plant has reserved
in its trunk
hopefully it gives you some appreciation
for the color changes that we see you
see a little bit of that background of
actually what's going on from the plant
standpoint