okay here we're gonna look at the plant
hormone called oxen this is what it
looks like on the chemical structure I
call it the ball and stick model here
but we're learn about how it influences
and impacts plants so starting first
oxen can move through the plant from the
site of initial production move to the
process of active transport now it can
diffuse this is a hormone that can
diffuse through plant cells but only
diffuses at a rate of about a centimeter
per hour
however when oxen is transported through
active transport it's much faster about
10 times as fast I mean they can move 10
centimeters per hour and this is
advantageous to the plant we see that
here we see our oxen moving down here
through the process of active transport
you know moving those proteins embedded
in the cell wall through the cell
membrane here and it's using ATP so it
is an energy investment for the plant
but this is advantageous because it's
able to get that oxen throughout its
system much faster it's kind of the
tortoise in the hare example here
diffusion would be the tortoise and
active transport would be the hare in
this case
so what's oxygen do well it's got a
couple functions as some secondary
actions one is root initiation another
is vascular tissue differentiation 3 is
tropic response force apical dominance
and 5 is a development of excellent buds
flowers and fruits and I'm going to talk
about these a little bit more detail
this is again the hormone here oxen that
we're gonna be talking about so starting
with promoting rooting well as we see
here here's example of some cuttings
taken with no oxen applied and it's see
the root development on them is quite
poor when oxen is applied that we see a
much more advantageous formation we see
here also comparison of different parts
per million of a particular oxen at 0 we
see hardly any root formation and as we
increase our oxen levels we see an
increase in the rooting percentage in
total now a da is a type of oxen and
we're seeing here the same kind of
increase in rooting from initially no
oxen added however what's interesting
here
is that 2 grams per liter we see more
roots then at 16 grams per liter so
other kind of shows here is our routing
increases to a certain point and then
plateaus it can even if we increase
oxygen concentrations too much you can
actually cut a slight decrease in our
routing that we see here so more is not
better and auxins but definitely some is
better than none as far as increasing
our routing there's many products that
are used to promote this lateral buds of
roots I should say to form and we notice
here hormone in is a very common form in
1 2 &amp; 3 we've heard of different
concentrations clone ex is another form
of an IBA here that you can apply to
plants to increase the routing now with
both of these auctions in general might
be a little unstable it's good to keep
those products stored in the fridge cool
temperatures to make the auxin last as
long as possible so there should be as
effective now i'll simpliciter Olinda
freshen of vascular tissue well there's
a wound site oxen will be involved here
to differentiate tissue to repair a
vascular system we kind of see here a
little bit loose highlighted on the
vascular system in the Mara's almond or
phloem and oxygen plays a role in cells
differentiating into those particular
vascular tissues this one here so we
notice that auxins of all the tropic
responses and tropism refers to growth
in response to a stimulus there's light
and sense of sunlight water where the
water's might be located we just want to
maybe go towards that in gravity this is
how roots know to go down and shoots
know to come up so we see here is our
light response here well it's important
here on the light response we see in
this case these two plants bending
towards the light
now all this does occur this occurs
because of auxin so we see here in the
first image here the light is right
above the plant and these are awesome
concentration it's pretty even however
now is that light source is a little bit
more to the side here notice our plant
kind of starting to bend over towards
the light and what's happening in order
for the plan
to bend like that the cells on one side
need to basically get bigger so oxen
concentrations increase causing these
cells to get larger and these elongation
of cells cause the plant to bend because
we have basically the same Erie on each
side well one side gets longer we're
noticing that that side it's gonna get
longer it's gonna start to push over and
bend towards the light you can think of
this if you're running around a track
right the lot on the outer circle is a
longer distance and on the inner circle
so here with these elongation of cells
this is a little bit longer that's going
to cause the plant to bend towards the
light and that's what you see here so
while we see the plant meting towards
the light that's actually because of the
hormone auxin promotes apical dominance
apical dominance is in today inventory
influence on the apical bud upon lateral
buds so what does this mean well first
our apical bud is at the top lateral
buds are on the side so a plant that has
strong apical dominance would be example
here it's a strong triangle kind of
shape strong kind of sense of that
central bud there
weak apical dominance is this kind of
weeping tree where we don't see a point
we don't see a point don't see kind of
the middle part doesn't have that nice
symmetrical shape here very weak apical
dominance this is also involved in point
setting of plants if you look very
carefully at points edea that's a large
bush like form that looks more like this
you'll notice in the center there's
pinch points these apical dominance sees
leading shoots have been pinched and
that is causing this lateral blood
formation to occur we see that here also
so this inhibitory influence on the
apical bud upon lateral buds well when
we have a normally growing plant here
that actively growing the bud tip has a
lot of oxygen in it that shoe tip is a
source of option that inhibits lateral
Bloods from forming so here's our
developing buds and they're kind of kept
in that kind of slow development dormant
like state however when we pinched the
top of that we're removing the oxen and
now with the reduced amount of oxen
there's no more suppression to
lateral buds and we see these Laurel
Bloods being growing at a much greater
rate than they are here evident here we
see our Tillery buds if we pinch that
top portion off these will be encouraged
to grow out
however we pinched the top off we notice
the lateral buds grow but when we pinch
the top off if we add oxen supplemental
oxen we notice that those lateral buds
never develop this is a way to prove
that oxen is the ones suppressing
lateral blood formation so this is
important if a plant actually breaks the
tip off because of wind or animals come
along and eat it that's going to remove
the oxen and that's gonna cause these
lateral buds to sprout however under
normal conditions the plant doesn't want
to compete with all these leaves so it's
just going to maintain that central
chute aquanauts fruit development so as
seeds mature they release oxygen to the
surrounding parts which develop into
fruit that covers the seeds so here a
normal fruit and we see little seeds
here now if we take out those seeds we
notice that the strawberry hair doesn't
grow nearly as good now if we take the
little seeds off and we spray it with
auxins but if we get someone a return to
normal not quite a hundred percent
because it's interacting with other
hormones but we see a much closer
resemblance of the normal fruit then if
we just take the seeds off limiting the
oxen from development this year
evidence of roll box information of
fruit and structures and similar
functions again here's our normal
strawberry
here's if we take all the seeds away and
this trial run is very interesting this
happens if we take up the end of those
seeds off there's a central kind of
equator point we noticed the fruit below
that point does not develop normally
with the fruit above that does so
without sea formation fruits do not
develop developin seeds are a source of
auxin so this just gives a little bit of
an example showing you normal conditions
and how the influence or dependence on
fruit development that oxen plays lastly
oxen or synthetic auxins are actually a
weed killer so while oxen is a plant
woman can help plants develop synthetic
auxins have a way of potentially
eliminating plants from growing so as
May synthetic auxins are used as
selectively weed killers or herbicides
this one called - for days used to
destroy broadleaf weeds does not affect
mature monocots causes plants to grow
itself to death basically grow so fast
they can't support itself an actual kill
itself more readily absorbed in
broadleaf plants so on certain weed
killers you may see them advertised as
kills weeds but not the grass because
it's got two four D it's a type of
synthetic oxen and it's a selective
broadleaf weed control selected in the
sense that's going to target mainly
dicots where monocots will not be as
affected by this especially if they're
mature hopefully that was helpful to
help explain a little bit of the hormone
oxen and how it can influence plant
growth