welcome to this tobacco university video
here i'm going to go over
tips and tricks to help you avoid
potential issues with aeroponic cannabis
[Music]
cloning
all right if you've tried an aeroponic
liner or didn't have great success
i may fall into one of these issues if
you are looking at starting with
aeroponic cloning
hopefully this will help you avoid
potential issues early on
so starting with some of the common
issues well for us is ph imbalance
many times growers they have something
that's too acidic or too basic
not realize it so this is why it's
always important to have a good monitor
system
also want to make sure your temperature
is in the acceptable range if it's not
that's going to cause potential your
roots to burn if it's too hot or
not really form at any great rate if
it's too cold
also nutrient levels tend to be more on
the excessive side with what i see some
growers
everyone has their own kind of gauge or
idea i would first start with any
solutions you're adding to definitely
follow the manufacturer's
recommendations or
even go less do not go more so what's
the problem solving how can
you avoid these issues well i use the
blue labs guardian
monitor here it provides live readings
of the parts per million
it could be ec or tds whatever you
choose the temperature could be in
fahrenheit or celsius
as well as the ph so this is a great
way to look at three main factors
environmental factors for cloning
to help ensure all of them are within
your preset acceptable target ranges
now i'm sure must have on hand and again
there's
many things growers should have on hand
but these are some of the very basics
the most basic would be a ph up and a ph
down
solution to ensure you're able to keep
that ph within your target range
also standard lotus blend of nutrients
can be an a great addition
again you don't need a ton of different
nutrients this clonex clone solution
really can work
sometimes even just plain water does
everything set up ahead of time
ph wise temperature wise uh that can
also be
effective but adding a little nutrients
can help increase your odds of success
now there are some advanced options so
depending on what level
you want to get into while there's no
substitute for basically checking your
plants there are some additional options
that can help reduce the time from when
something goes wrong
to when you know about it you could send
in certain alarms or alerts get text
messages get
automatic emails sent out to people and
not only would you be aware of it
there's even options where you can get
automatic dosing where if the computer
realizes the ph is coming up too high
can add particular solutions to help
bring that ph back down
to your acceptable range to avoid large
swings
in potential environmental conditions
that would reduce your routing success
as i said there's monitors with alerts
and there's many different ones you can
alert
you want to conditions outside the
program acceptable range that you have
set can also be sent immediately to use
your where
live as it happens so you can be right
there and hopefully offer
a correction point with the minimal
duration of time
this can also allow you to correct the
issue with minimal time stress on the
plants
and again the whole goal here is to
maximize your rooting
now there's also as i mentioned there's
automatic dosing solutions here where
for high end operations the ranges can
be set and monitor can be connected to
an automatic dose
injector where it can kind of work
automatically
where the environmental condition
becomes out of the acceptable range the
computer can automatically correct it
with little or no input
from the grower once the conditions are
set up by the grower
this is a hands-free approach and is
ideal for large-scale
operations now we're looking here at
some callus formation so the formation
of
callus can be an indication that
something is not quite right
an initial small callus may be followed
quickly by the root formation so don't
think immediately when you see callous
something's going wrong
but if you're getting an increase in the
size of the calc without roots
that can be an indication with large
catalyst grower needs to check the
environmental conditions the plants are
in
to hopefully ensure that the ph
nutrients
and temperature are all in the correct
ranges
and that provided you with just an
indication of the ranges that i use
lastly you want to be thinking about the
length that you have for you the stem
for rooting some growers cut them a
little too short try to get away with
too small of a cutting
so in this additional video i'm going to
walk you through a comparison
of different stem lengths to give you
the idea of what the proper stem length
should be
to ensure you have the best success with
your clones
so if we look at our cannabis clones
here we'll notice that this one
has a very turgid leaf very upright very
how it should how it should look
nice kind of turgid leaf right there
this one looks a little more flaccid a
little more
kind of wilty kind of look to it so
what's the possible reason for the
difference between these two
well if you look closely they were both
harvested at the same time
they're both in the same area so it
makes a little perplexing some growers
find
how can one can look so good and another
one can kind of look kind of
on that more wilty like look so let's
investigate this a little bit further if
we kind of zoom out
here just a little bit and we look at
the turgid leaf start
with this one first look at that clone a
little water spraying
so if we look at this clone we can
notice the
amount of area that was left below
so if i kind of work this one out put
that there
go look at the area that was left below
we can see that there is definitely a
significant portion of rooting area on
there for this clone
look at the wilty one if we compare that
one
right next to it we can clearly see that
there is a difference between those two
so if we kind of go up and look a little
bit here
[Music]
so here we're looking at the difference
between these two the rooting area
on the more turjan one here
definitely much larger area here located
right below
compared to the one that is definitely
more flaccid and more wilty
we can clearly see that this one has a
much less area to root in and that's
what's causing the kind of
flaccid like look to the leaves here
compared to the one that's definitely
more turjan we can see it as leaves
able to support themselves horizontally
so we clearly see this plant has an
adequate area down here
for rooting this is why these leaves are
a lot more
turgid able to support itself still
hasn't rooted yet
but definitely looks much better overall
[Music]
in comparison when we look at this plant
we can see how much more flaccid it is
leaves much more droopy and that's
simply because the rooting area here is
much more
limiting so there's not much area to
absorb water
to maintain the hydration in this plant
now may root end up just fine
right now looking a little bit more
droopy than the one we saw
previously a lot more flaccid to this
one simply because of the limited
rooting area here an ability to absorb
water
you