so this is going to be a brief overview
of the axial and appendicular skeleton
of the human body the axial skeleton or
bones of the skull vertebral column and
rib cage we see here highlighted in blue
we're going to spend more time in other
videos learning about these in more
detail but for right now just know this
is part of the axial skeleton in
contrast the appendicular skeleton are
both of the upper and lower limbs
shoulder and hip highlighted in the pink
red color here and also these looping on
over in more detail right now just
important identify these two different
subcategories of the human skeleton
looking a little more specifically at
the axial skeleton what that's composed
of they said the skulls many bones and
composed skull the vertebral column
we're gonna learn about the different
regions they're in the thoracic ribcage
and how these different ribs differ the
access gelatin supports and protects
organs in body cavities in touches the
muscles of the head the neck and the
trunk it's important for respiration and
attachment of muscles as part of the
appendicular skeleton speaking of the
appendicular skeleton these are some of
the bones here you should be come
familiar with and be able to identify
these the clavicle the scapula the
humerus the radius the ulna the hip bone
the carpals the metacarpals the
phalanges the femur the patella the
tibia the fibula tarsals metatarsals and
phalanges are just the basic overview of
the appendicular skeleton and all these
bones minimum you should be able to
identify again this is just that quick
overview of axial appendicular skeleton
with other videos to provide with more
details on the different regions within
these skills