here we're gonna look at the balance and
hearing sensory receptors starting with
hearing but not from a human standpoint
but from a fish's standpoint fish have a
lateral line this is how they this is
their sense of hearing they're able to
sense objects that reflect pressure
waves in low-frequency vibrations this
red line shows where they might be
located in this shark we see this
distinctive line here on this fish now
on this fish the striped bass you might
be initially think there's multiple
lateral lines but there's technically
only one if you look very closely at
this line here the darker line is
actually the lateral line so special
only has one lateral line despite many
stripes this is a striped bass caught in
the Connecticut River after launching
from the Rocky Hill boat ramp now
continuing on in fish under other skin
they have these canals that have sensory
structures containing hair cells
directing into a gelatinous cube kula
these vibrations produce movements and
hair cells bend in depolarize
associated with sensory neurons so we
see here the events that it's moving
back and forth and you see that's all
kind of attached all these different
nerve fibers this is how the fish is
able to sense these pressure vibrations
through the movement of this cupola and
a little bit more intensive an image
here you see how it's kind of organizing
all these different sensing outer hair
cells and it's this movement back and
forth of these low pressure waves that's
being interpreted by the fish and that's
their sense of hearing without having a
distinctive ear like we do now in humans
sensation of gravity in motion so maybe
one reliance is located here we're
talking about hearing in ears well it's
very important because your sense of
balance is related to your inner ear so
those receptors in the ear that informed
the brain where the body is in three
dimensions gravity is detected by the
shifting boat oullette sensory cells and
these are located in a gelatin like
matrix and they're composed of your
inner ear so the force of gravity is
what's causing them to move tilt your
head forward gravity is pushing them all
down and that's
your sense of where you are in
three-dimensional space so your ability
to walk as a youngster it's actually
dependent on development of your inner
ear so you're able to sense three
dimensions so that helps you be able to
maintain your balance and this is the
reason why the motion so balanced the
psycho motion if you tilt your head
forward the force of gravity moves well
motion is detected by the deflection of
these hair cells by fluid in a direction
opposite of that motion so that
acceleration standpoint they're going to
go the opposite way these hair cells are
found in the cupula inner tent like
assemblies in three semicircular canals
so a very similar structure to the fish
also using sensory receptors in hairs
here we're just using it now to detect
motion and this is kind of related here
of acceleration at rest or deceleration
eyes all sense of motion based on the
movement of these hair cells in
three-dimensional space near bodies
perception of those now properties of
sound / sound is simply a pressure
disturbance altering areas of high and
low pressure originating from a
vibrating object here we see a tuning
fork composed of areas of refraction and
compression represented by a sine wave
here in a wave length which is the
distance between two consecutive waves
either two consecutive peaks here would
be two consecutive troughs any frequency
is a number of waves that pass point per
unit of time in the amplitude here is a
distance between the origin and the
crest or it could be the origin and the
trough that would be the amplitude the
speed is simply wavelength times
frequency now frequency is the number of
waves that pass forgivin
point at a given time and pitch is the
perception of different frequencies we
hear basically from 22 if you're lucky
20,000 Hertz it's determined by
different frequencies kind different
parts of the membrane to vibrate
different sensory neurons are fired and
this is how you're able to determine
different pitches now amplitude is the
intensity of the sound measured in
Phoebe's that
fools and loudness is subjective
interpretation of these sound intensity
relates to how often neurons fire so for
sound waves wave corresponds to pitch
amplitude of the wave corresponds to the
volume the sound wave shown with the
dashed line is softer in volume than the
salvation with this solid line so here
we're looking at our volume in
comparison so you notice it's basically
the same same pitch same kind of
different amplitude same wavelength that
I should say our different amplitudes
here but our wavelengths remain the same
and we see here the kind of small
talking call yet bird we see the very
angry large large bird here indicating
that difference in our amplitude even
though our wavelengths are actually
remaining the same consuming ayman sound
is heard air vibration is detected it is
a tickling in your eardrum your eardrum
is a membrane that's pushed in and out
by waves of pressure and there's three
small bones ossicles are the bones of a
located on the other side of the eardrum
and increase with the vibration force
amplified vibration is transferred to
the fluid within the inner ear and the
inner ear chamber is shaped tightly
coiled snail shell called the cochlea we
see that here in purple
well investigate a little bit further so
we're transferring the sound pressure
waves or eardrum ultimate to the bones
located here now in the caca there hair
cells that rest on the membrane running
up and down the chamber and they're
converted by other membranes see that
here this is a cockpit here in the
region that's coiled like as a snail's
shell sound waves entering the cafe
accustomed to sandwich and vibrate bent
hair cells same nerve impulses to the
brain it's kind of like all these like
receptors here and they're basically
movement is how we're able to interpret
those different pressure waves located
in the air this is found through
transduction which are vibrations that
travel up the fluid-filled interior and
talk via different thicknesses of the
membranes vibrate responds in different
frequencies of sound
we kind of see that evident here here
seven thousand Hertz 5,000 4,000 3,000
2,000 Hertz 20,000 located right here
not heard by very many in the same
principle applies here where there are
hair cells and the cross section
calculate here the top right figure note
that there's the addition of the upper
canal and lower canal attack it also has
a middle canal there's our upper lower
and here's our middle canals that were
zooming in here the bottom image is the
site of the sound actual transduction
and it's movement of the stereocilia and
hair cells results in the action
potential that travel along the auditory
nerve that's ultimately it's being sent
to the brain and it's how we are able to
perceive sound