ever get a soil report back and see
basic saturation listed
well here on debaco university we're
going to explain a little bit about what
those numbers mean
all right let's get into base saturation
in a soil test report
and here we see there's some sample
numbers with some ranges given
but let's get into just what is base
saturation
so that's the first question here as
we're looking at base saturation just
what is it
and it's the percentage of the soil's
cation exchange capacity
occupied by calcium magnesium and
potassium
is referred to as base saturation keep
in mind though that ph does have an
impact on these levels
so we say cation exchange capacity
cation
keep in mind soil particles are
typically mostly negatively charged
cations are positively charged ions we
see that here with our calcium
our potassium and our magnesium are all
examples of positive cations so here
we're referring to this
as the ability to exchange those we
could see them
changing as we get uh more towards it
closer to a neutral ph
very acidic ph we see there's not a lot
of calcium there's not a lot of
magnesium
and potassium held on the soil particle
positive negative components
as we get closer to that neutral we're
seeing increase in that number of
cations or positive ions
so we're looking at the levels of our
base saturation right here so
of low and high base saturation but base
saturation is calculated
as a percentage of cec and its kind
exchange capacity
occupied by base cations this figure
shows two soils with the same cec
but the soil on the right has more base
cations in blue
therefore it has a higher base
saturation
so base saturation is closely related to
ph as base saturation increases
so does ph levels so if we look at this
kind of comparison here between
our two soils so here we have the
low base saturation so down over here we
have the low base saturation
and then we have the high base
saturation we notice that the soil
particles so it's negative charges
and we have the same number of cations
essentially bound to that particle but a
low base saturation
we're seeing a low number of calcium
magnesium potassium
here at the high base saturation we can
see an increase in the amount of calcium
potassium and magnesium ions that are
again
being bound here to that soil particle
and those base cations are considered to
be calcium magnesium
potassium and then sodium acid cations
would be hydrogen
aluminum and ammonium here and they
exchangeable with the acidity
lower lower ph or more acidic levels
we'll see more of those
now word of caution with our uh when
looking at
base saturation if you're calculating
nutrient or fertilizer amounts from the
base saturation
typically these if you're utilizing
these numbers typically this will often
lead to an
over application of those nutrients it's
best to use
the specifics of the actual soil test
numbers and other factors
such as ph in organic matter a lot of
times sadly fertilizer companies will
use base saturation for this
to calculate the numbers because usually
it comes out in their favor
by over applying a little more nutrients
and more fertilizers
than you may need if you took into
account the actual numbers
as well as some of the other soil
properties provided on a soil test
regardless it still comes back to taking
a quality representative sample with
your soil test
so that you can have a good numbers
good data to work with so you can make
an informed
and educated decision going forward