welcome to this debaco university video
here i'm going to be going over and
showing you the basic steps to cannabis
cloning
so in a lot of videos i've talked about
some of the
methods you should go about doing when
you're looking at cloning
some of the process you should go
through but here i'm actually going to
show you
[Music]
all right let's get into the video here
where i'm actually going to show you the
basic steps
to cloning your cannabis plants hope you
enjoy
okay here i'm going to go over how to
take a cannabis clone we see
right here in our grow tent a nice
mother or stock plant
so things you need to keep in mind you
have your cloner already running which
it is and we'll see that at the end
stages here
i also have a beaker here of just some
water because we have to transport these
clones
want to try to reduce the chance of
stress on them so we're going to
get them right in that regular water now
some people will use a knife
you can use very sharp pruning shears to
go through and take our clone
so if we look here looking at this this
is the wife variety
or white strain looking at how we're
going to take a clone we want to make
sure we're always cutting at a
particular leaf
node we don't want to just cut randomly
halfway through in between the internode
area
we want to make sure we're cutting at a
node because one that will allow us the
maximum amount of
stem area but it will also allow us if
we take a clone right
here it'll allow us in the future to
take a future clown as well so we're
maximizing the cloning opportunities
that we get
so just looking at this one right here
probably gonna go right here
clip it right off that's gonna be our
wonderful little clone right there
take that we're going to submerge it in
the water here
again to keep it nice and hydrated
while we go to the next step so i'll go
through and take a couple more
the reason why i chose this specific
area here is if you look a little bit
closer
we can see right here where i took the
took the clone
that's going to allow this one to be
taken potentially in the future allow
this one to kind of grow out a little
bit more
so again here we can see the reason why
i took this here is this will allow this
one to grow out
and we can kind of look down this same
branch and maybe take another one
looking at this one being right here
here's another quality clone right there
stick this right in the water
keep that one hydrated and that's just a
quick example here
of now allowing this one potentially to
grow out and maximizing the productivity
we get from one single plant
[Music]
well that just gives you a little bit of
an idea there of the size of the clone
and speaks well to the health of the
mother or stock plant
right here
[Music]
now looking at this branch right here we
can see there is a previous clone taken
and that now has induced a lot of these
side branches to form
so sometimes we want the clones a little
bit bigger in this case
looking at the stretching that they've
gone on and done we can probably take
many of these for clones right now so
i'm just going to go through and be very
precise with my
sharp scissors and take a bunch
of these cuttings that we're going to
clone
just tossing them in a beaker of water i
have prepared already
and again some of these might be on the
smaller side but always good to
experiment and see but that's
you know on the smaller side there
overall but again no complaints there
when we're looking at taking
a clone just want to make sure we're
putting that directly into some water
so it's not getting stressed before we
bring it over to our cloner
that just shows a great example of how
we took one and now we're getting a
couple more and i might leave that one
going forward but again a great way to
maximize your clones
from one plant
[Music]
you