here i'm going to go over some basic
tire information that may involve some
things
that you've seen but maybe not have
appreciated what is actually there
on a tire so starting with the
components of a tire a whole tire
composed of linear sidewall rubber beads
belts and tread rubber
and there's several layers composed of
them so this helps give them their
strength helps give them their shape
and helps allow them to stay flexible so
again there's a lot of different
components a lot of different kind of
layers
but we're basically looking at sidewall
rubber beads and belts
tread rubber being the main components
there but some may even include some
steel belts
to help give them rigidity and strength
now the tread elements if we're looking
at the exterior of the tire there's
grooves which go around the tire
we have slots which are transverse to
the tire
we have a swipe which are these small
little grooves if you look here they're
located right here to be considered the
swipes
and we also have something called a
tread wear indicator
and these are raised bars that indicate
the tread wear
and they're located not many in
all components of the tire but if you
rotate it through and look closely
you will find some tread wear indicators
on
tires on maybe even your car so these
impressions
and tracks we have the tire impressions
that are the tread design and dimensions
of the tire
we have the tread tracks which are
related to the dimensions
of related to the wheels so it's
important to take these into
consideration as well as with some of
the exterior components
when you're trying to identify a
particular tire or make a match
something you may not have realized is
that there's something called a noise
treatment to
tires so tires don't have the exact same
pattern that repeats equally
throughout the entire circumference of
the tire by mixing the design elements
manufacturers can impact the amount of
noise a tire may generate
if tire designs were exactly repeated
around the tire unwanted noise would
occur
kind of create a wall especially going
down the highway alternating small
medium large
lengths create different pitches this
helps reduce the overall noise
you can see that indicated here where we
have these kind of
different kind of elements of different
lengths
inserted around the tire tread to help
reduce the noise instead it's given
one of those things called i mentioned
tread wear indicators
so if you look at this tire may not see
them initially but highlighted them here
little
arrows they are located on the tire and
they're little wear bars
they're basically a rubber bar that's
raised about 1 16 above the base
of the grooves of the tire the dt
requires six tread wear indicators
so because there's quilt only six if you
look at one particular small spot the
tire you may not see it
so you have to rotate the tower or look
at a different portion
as the tread wears down these will
become noticeable and offer an
indication
for replacement we also have when we're
looking at tires we're looking at
something called original
and replacement tires so this can get
into when we're trying to identify or
match a car to a crime scene
original equipment oe tires they're sold
on new cars thousands of cars have the
same
brand in size then we have something
called replacement tires and they're
purchased to replace old worn tires
typically different than the original
equipment tires and there's a whole
bunch of different tires that you can
select from
if you're looking at replacing tires and
then lastly we have retread tires
so sadly probably familiar with seeing
this on the highway where the retreats
will
break off but re-trade tires are
primarily used for commercial or fleet
vehicles in
the united states two types of retread
processes there's a mold cure process
and there's a pre-cured
process some retreat tires have valuable
individual characteristics
which provide information to the
examiner what they basically are just as
the name implies they're a new tread
that has been put on an existing or
older tire
sadly because of this process they could
break down especially with the heat of
being on the highway and end up as
a hazard along the road but be mindful
that these retread tires have new tread
but are on older or potentially original
tires