so when producing cannabis to be
efficient growums may be divided into
different areas some basic rooms would
be a clone room a mother room a
vegetative room a flower room and a dry
a cure room so just some of the basics
gonna go over just an overview of what
each of these rooms may entail
so starting common to all of these rooms
should be cleanliness good air
circulation and monitoring systems wait
is to control different aspects and
environments within the room and ways to
check to make sure everything's working
and functioning properly the check
protocols is a great way to hopefully
notice that something's going awry very
early so it doesn't damage the crop
permanently rooms may not always be
physically separate so some operations
and this is typically the smaller ones
will have a dual purpose rooms this can
reduce the efficiencies and possibly
cause contamination and spread of
disease quicker when you have these dual
functional rooms and that's where
cleanliness is even more important older
plants with the younger plants and as
older plants may be sick or can carry
diseases potential insects and it could
infect the inner plants also lighting in
tendencies may need to be adjusted older
plants may not be getting enough light
while the other plants could be getting
too much light so it's kind of really
that one room kind of fits all and does
everything this is why typically there's
sections put into rooms and partitions
to allow them each to be treated
slightly differently to maximize
production the clone room so this is
also referred to as a propagation room
seeds can be started or clones can be
routed typically this room had higher
humidity than the others overall this
less intense light required you don't
want to burn other tender foliage and
this needs frequent monitoring that
especially if you're looking to clone
operations to make sure pH is kept well
make sure you're getting roots on your
clones here make sure your seedlings are
started because we're kind of starting
those plants at a very critical part of
the entire process and this is often one
that can be a little smaller because the
plants of course are smaller but needs
to have very careful monitoring so here
we're looking at the mother or stock
plant room this is where the mother or
stock plants are kept
so typically fewer but larger plants and
we want to remain in one of these plants
we
in a vegetative state so keep in mind
it's giving them 16 plus hours of
continuous light some growers may even
choose to run 24 hours this is often
where rare and unique genetics may be
kept so monitoring this area is
important security are also as a high
priority unique individuals have the
picture of the albino here it's found
that goal is to clone that plant to
produce many of those desired copies of
that offspring as a result I have this
picture here because growers may want to
choose to prune them a little bit
differently want to increase the
branching to increase the availability
of clones that can be used for
propagation and the vegetative room this
is where plants are focused on growing
leaves a novelty flowers here keeping
that 16 plus hours continuous light is
important after the entire crop
otherwise if you cut that down below
that you run the risk of your entire
room going into flower prematurely some
growers again run even in this area in
24 hours of light but this often leads
to wasted light and diminishing returns
on investment because of the increased
cost associated running those lights
keep the plants well-fed this is very
important stage for development I'm sure
those plants are night stressed at all
I'm able to produce as many leaves as
possible here you can see these kind of
purple hue to these leaves and that's
because there's an LED light with that
purple heavy purple spectrum running in
this area of the vegetative room the
flower room I hear the foot appeared
should be adjusted to 12 hours late in
12 hours of darkness Wallace is coming
for two as the money room setting up
your plants well in the vegetative room
is important for their success during
the stressful flowering stage so I
noticed have kind of that you had a
yellow look to him so because of running
high pressure sodium lights this is
again often referred to as the money
room even though really setting this
plants up in the vegetative room is very
important to allow them to perform well
when they go into the flowering room or
the flowering stage of development
lastly the drying cure this is the last
stage of the process and controlled
inconsistent conditions are very
important you don't want to lose your
harvest this late in the season this
late in the game is you have the mass
amount of investment in your crop
keeping the lights as minimum as
possible and control over community are
very important you don't have mold
increased want to be
or that you're able to dry them
efficiently and effectively so you get
the maximum return on your investment