welcome to this video on the basic body
orientation terms
while this might seem pretty simplistic
it is important to be able to understand
some of these terms and vocabulary
because if you're generating a report or
look reading an autopsy these are the
terms are going to be used
so it's important that you have an
understanding of them so these
anatomical positions
they're used to describe regions of the
body in common terms and vocabulary and
this is how
scientists can communicate easily with
one another
so that everyone has the same mental
image as everyone's on the same
page now we're looking at some of the
key terms you should be
familiar with well one is the superior
in the
inferior so at the example here the
superiors towards the head
and the inferior is towards the feet so
keep in mind when we're looking at
describing something or where something
might be progressing to
we're looking at kind of towards the
head or towards the feet we'd use the
terms
superior or inferior here
we also have terms called dorsal and
ventral
and dorsals towards the back and
ventrals towards the front so i have the
picture of the fish here because a lot
of
times we think of the dorsal fin which
is on the top here it's on the back of
the fish
the ventral side to the underside
relating this to humans
so that dorsal cavity would be kind of
where the backbone vertebrae
are and the ventral cavity is more
towards
the frontier where the chest and stomach
are located
so keep in mind of that dorsal and
ventral no matter what the orientation
of the organism
is getting to proximal and
distal proximal is towards the point of
attachment and distal away
from the point of attachment so when
we're looking kind of the arm the
proximal area
is closer uh towards the shoulder the
distal region is getting out towards
the hand there away from the point of
attachment so again this might be
important in particular of limbs looking
at lacerations and describing them
as far as where they might be located or
they might be traveling
then we have potentially uh discovering
a body might be on the
supine or the prone position supine's
laying on the
back side which we can see evident as
this person is and then prone would be
laying on the
belly side so describing how a potential
victim was found at a crime scene
these terms will often be used if the
victim is lying horizontally
then we have anterior and posterior and
anterior is the front side and posterior
is
the back we can see that evident here as
well
so again keeping in mind some of these
orientation positions
will help aid in a lot of the
description and then
lastly we have something called medial
and then we have
lateral so measles closer to the midline
of the body and laterally away from the
midline
of the body we can see that described or
shown
right here along with some of the other
terms that we covered so again some of
this is just that memorization
but knowing these terms will not only
allow you to produce
a quality report but read one that might
be generated from somebody else