okay Herman take a brief look behind the
numbers of a soil test so we get these
numbers back printed out and report
after we sent our soil those kind of
numbers mean and how does a lot go about
getting some of those so the objective
of a soil test is to estimate the amount
of plant available nutrients now keep in
mind this is different this is not the
total amount of nutrients as a result
soil test labs using the extraction
fluid to simulate the plant's ability to
remove nutrients from the soil so the
goal is we want to get the ones at the
plant can easily access if they're tied
up and locked up we don't assess those
in the soil report would be a different
test if you want the total amount of
potassium in your soil because that
would assess the amount that's locked up
as we would call it we want the ones
that are easy to get by the plant and as
a result extraction floors or what's
used to try to estimate what a plant can
pull out of that particular soil sample
so this extraction employed well there's
different extraction fluids and this can
result in a different estimate estimate
of soil nutrient supply the appropriate
soil test method for a given region are
selected based on cell characteristics
and climate just as for example the
extraction fluids going to try to wring
out the nutrients in that soil now if
we're in a soil here where we're very
sand the environment may be using a
different extraction fluid than one
that's here with higher organic matter
so again they're gonna be based on the
region so typically if you're testing
soil you want to look at what a local
lab is using for extraction fluid
however there can be differences in
extraction foot so there's two main
extraction foods used in New England
most commonly a weak acid modified
morgan extract in the strong male at
three extract only the University of New
Hampshire that uses the male at three
these are both the universal extraction
procedures meaning that they use
different they used to determine the
amount of majority of the nutrients and
many micronutrients at the same time so
even though they are different
extraction fluids and once more
aggressive they both can give you kind
of the same idea of nutrients then
keeping in mind if you're comparing two
modified morgan extract versus a may
look three some nutrients may differ
batches because of the extraction fluid
that is used