while there may be many consumers of
cannabis here at debaco university the
goal
is to make you an informed cannabis
consumer
so here in this video lecture we're
going to go over just that to allow you
to be
an informed consumer here
[Music]
all right let's go through the steps you
need to being an informed cannabis
consumer
so first off if not provided request it
what's that referring to
well if they're not provided the
information you need to reach your
requests and the information that you
need
so you want to ask for results from the
original analytical report
or the original certificate of analysis
so this is when you're looking at
purchasing cannabis it's great to see a
label
that's uh but we want to also be getting
and requesting if it's not provided to
us
that analytical report what's the
integral report kind of tell us well it
is going to tell us potential
thc levels this is the main cannabinoid
associated with cannabis
some growers are looking for the highest
levels possible while others
are concerned about the thc levels in
their plants to maintain
federal compliance to be classified as
hemp so a lot of growers are concerned
with thc
and it's not necessarily just the most
thc possible
then the other cannabinoid of great
interest is usually cbd
and this cannabinoid also is also a
focus with many growers
with many looking for high levels for
medical benefits
and also to maintain classification as
hemp while keeping their thc level below
0.3 percent so what classifies it as
marijuana or hemp would be that tc level
above or below that 0.3 percent however
for the true medical benefits a lot of
growers are looking at reading as high
of a cbd percentage as possible while
still keeping that thc level
below that federal limit then we get
into organic certified
cannabis you know why don't we see a lot
of organic certification with cannabis
well if you're looking for a certified
organic canvas pretty much you're not
going to find it
organic approaches can be used but
certifying a crop as organic requires
federal standards
and these are not written for cannabis
so again again
organic growing practices organic yes
it's possible but not
certified organic at a federal level
so we get to indoor or outdoor
production which one should i be looking
which one is quote unquote better
many consumers consider the indoor grown
cannabis to be of higher
quality than outdoor grown indoor
production typically yields a better
looking flower
and one with higher cannabinoids
compared to outdoor production
so your indoor production with your
controlled environment artificial lights
good air circulation
can really produce high quality product
compared to the
outdoor growing however this is because
of the degree of those environmental
controls an indoor
grower has compared to the outdoor
environment now this does not mean one
is better than the other
the goal is to look at the in the
analytical report provided
and determine the quality of the canvas
flower based on that
not necessarily the indoor or outdoor
growing nature what does the analytical
report say
now keep in mind your outdoor growing
will have more
variability a bit more inconsistencies
may not look quite as perfect as an
indoor growing
as it's a factor of the environment but
really we should be looking at the
the report of the cannabinoids of the
terpenes to really determine the quality
of the flower
not necessarily the environment that it
was produced in
now that this brings us to that proper
testing and that importance of
the proper testing so these analytical
reports are very important for cannabis
dry flour
as well as other products from a
grower's standpoint
it allows the for a certification of
your final product
and if you're a consumer from standpoint
it allows for the knowledge of the
product to be purchased is clean
of potential contaminants with what is
actually in the flower
when i say clean we're referring to the
example of
passing for example the pesticide test
the heavy metal test
things of that nature aflotoxins want to
make sure we're having a
pure product clean product that we're
not going to have any contaminants that
are going to be ingested
in the consumption process now we want
to request
lab results what's part of making you an
informed consumer well if you're not
provided with the information to be
informed
you need to then seek that information
out yourself testing is required by
cannabis dry flour as well as other
products so if not directly provided to
you
you can and you should be requesting for
that information
a product label is a good start as we
can see here this is a great start
but you really want the original
analytical report
now that label is great for comparison
looking at one versus another and kind
of doing comparison that way
the reason why you want that original
analytical report
is it's going to give you some more
information the numbers should be the
same so what's the difference if you're
comparing your numbers here to your
numbers on the label they're going to be
the same
so why go through the trouble of asking
for this analytical report
well you want to have such details as
the report date the date it was
collected the lab id the product
description
and the lab name all these will help
ensure the test results match
the lot for the product you're looking
to purchase
in distant dates or inconsistencies are
red flags that should
result in caution before purchasing or
using that particular
cannabis product you want to see
everything match up that you can
but then you want to see those
additional details and when in doubt you
can always contact the lab
to see if they can confirm the batch
number the date received the test
results the company they were testing
for because that all just gives you
more information to be informed that the
product you're purchasing
is actually supported by this
documentation and you can ensure
a safe product and therefore you'll be
an informed and well knowledgeable
consumer