on this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at beneficial
insects for aphids in cannabis
production and how you can utilize these
beneficial insects instead of
insecticides for controlling an aphid
population
[Music]
all right so let's get into the video
here to help you control your aphids
with beneficial insects here's a link to
the article and the proper citation for
that article if you want to look at more
of the information particularly of their
materials and methods and they studied
more than just aphids in this article
so first off challenges in the
greenhouse production just in general
well greenhouse cannabis cultivation in
insect infestations can cause many
losses across the board synthetic
chemicals and insecticides have been our
go-to option in the past but with the
stringent
scanning of final flower in materials
and legal restrictions as far as
applications of any sort of products
this is all the driving force between
the development of the new
environmentally friendly
and profitable methods for insect
control
for the plants
so the greenhouse studies a little bit
of the background it was conducted at in
the agriculture university of athens the
chemist plants were grown in two
different greenhouses the beneficial
insects were released only in one
greenhouse the treatment as we'll see
and no additional pesticides were used
during cultivation it gives you the
monash's variety that was used as well
as the temperature and humidity
fluctuations for the growing environment
now the beneficial insects the release
date three weeks after the
transplantation beneficial insects were
released to the treated greenhouse in
order to assess the efficiency of the
biological pest management
so the species here that we're going to
focus on is aphids so that was the main
one that was identified this is
generally how they look i'll show you a
little bit more specifics of some
variants just to give you an idea of how
small they are if you haven't seen them
they tend to be found also on the
underside of the leaves at least
initially
so the basics measures here here we can
see a bunch of different insects and all
identified right down there
but basic measurements include visual
estimations of the infestation recording
of the pest species and populations and
comparison of infestations between the
two greenhouses and only the nymphs and
adult stages of the pests were counted
not the egg stage for any of the insects
that they studied
now the pest population determination
how do we determine how was that
determined uh basically the past
populations were taken in the third
fifth and seventh and ninth week of the
growing the number of avid pests was
counted with a hand lens in order to
identify the efficiency of the
beneficial insects average pest
populations were measured in ten plants
four leaves per plant per greenhouse on
average so it's important with any pest
that we're looking at studying and this
is true for aphids as well as others to
have an idea what the life cycle is of
that past now there's a lot of
information here so
you're welcome to pause the video and
take a look at it more yourself
but key parts here are that they're a
piercing sucking insect and aphids can
also
transmit viruses as well they'll be a
vector for viruses
so that's another reason to keep their
numbers under control on top of the
physical damage they can do also the
transmission of viruses now they have a
complex life cycle
it's what's kind of weird about aphids
in particular is that females can give
birth to live already pregnant young
female clones so it's kind of like they
can really mass multiply very very fast
so keep that in mind as well
now identification of aphids well we're
going to kind of generally put them all
in the same general classification here
of aphids i want you just to realize
that there are different species cotton
or melon aphids compared to your green
peach potato
peach potato potiphabacco aphids or your
true potato aphids your foxclavits how
all of these are in the same category
but their head shapes can be used for
identification coloration and some more
details here so if you had avids and
identified them with a magnifying loop
you can probably identify the specific
type that you have in your particular
growing operation
now it's beneficial insects at target
aphids this is what the study looked at
and they looked at the apodius
combination here and they are small
wasps and they parasitize the aphids we
can see here this wasp actually infects
the aphids with
small little eggs
that go on to complete their life cycle
and then basically eventually just take
out the aphid population many species do
occur in the northeast and enter
greenhouses naturally so this is why
broad insecticide killing of everything
is not advised this gives you also the
life cycle here of the afidius as well i
mean there's about a two week life cycle
for them and this is that ready to
infect those aphids there just shows you
a little size and visual comparison
now another uh beneficial insect here
these are green lace wings
chrysophelia
canaria
and they are green lace wings we can see
an adult right here and then we see the
larval stage here so very contrasting
larval to adult stage again some more
information here their eggs kind of of
the green lace wings are kind of like
these white little areas on a thin
little hair
kind of suspended there so you can take
a look and hopefully find some of those
this kind of again shows you their life
cycle as well so both of these are
beneficial insects specifically to
target if you have aphids
uh in the other control so how were they
you know how the application methods
well for the affodias here they were put
in what's called dye boxes which are
like little boxes that basically hang
within the plants
the lacewings the larvae was basically
introduced by sprinkling the content
from the bottle around the area so these
a lot of times this comes in sawdust or
rice hulls so they're very very small so
you're spreading that also keep in mind
you want to keep these well spread
because the green lacewings can
campbellize themselves before going
after any aphid species
now what did the numbers look like
what's the what did the data actually
show and this kind of provides you an
idea of the actual data here so overall
great reduction in aphid numbers with
the beneficial insect treatments final
numbers were not may not be zero in a
population but to have only about four
and a half per plant when treated with
the beneficial insects compared to 300
in control plants it shows a massive
reduction this gives you the specific
kind of information right here their
data table and the graph really speaks
to the treatment here so initially week
three uh populations in both greenhouses
were relatively the same at least not
statistically different we can see the
control which is the one that did not
have any beneficial insects how it
massively went through an exponential
increase it did drop a little for week
nine but when we compare these to the
control treatments the ones that had the
beneficial insects we can see their ever
decreasing numbers here
so a great benefit to utilizing
these beneficial insects
so average number of pests in the
population as i said the study did look
at other insects but focusing
specifically on the aphids right here
and that's what the numbers i quoted
before average number of pest
populations in the treatment greenhouse
and 80 plants and we could see the
great comparison um there and we got
that down only 368 per 80 plants these
are numbers are in per week here there
so a continuous reduction in all pest
populations was observed throughout the
experiment approaching zero value per
plant so kind of maybe not reaching the
zero but definitely getting very close
to zero
now what was not mentioned in this study
uh was actually a lady beetles which a
lot of you may think of when you hear
aphids you might think oh i treat with
you know lady beetles well keep in mind
if you are going to go with lady beetles
they can kind of tear it rapidly if
they're not handled properly you can
have a lot of loss or death loss their
die back on ones that you're purchasing
so keep them refrigerated if they cannot
be used immediately but should be used
immediately use adequate release dates
oftentimes repeated applications about
seven days apart is needed for if you're
utilizing lady beetles lead beetles need
a good supply of aphids so if your
population of aids is really low
consider other options at least lady
beetles at the dusk or early evening
kind of when the sun or lights are kind
of going off there to avoid the heat of
the day upon their initial release
expect lady beetles to fly away in a few
days about 95 percent of ladybills will
fly away in 48 hours with the rest being
gone in four to five days uh and they
are unlikely to lay eggs in your plants
so if aphids do return you will have to
re-induce lady beetles probably why they
weren't a participant in this particular
study
now are beneficial insects worth the
effort to get this question a lot and in
short yes this study indicates that
beneficial insects could control pest
populations up to 100 percent pest
management with natural enemies is
promising very effective safe method for
plant protection as well as applicator
and so this is a little effort there
that timing is important
so keep all that in mind but you can
have great control
lastly what growers need to keep in mind
is really that proper pest
identification is important since this
will determine the exact beneficial
insect to use if you misdiagnose the
insect if you misdiagnose it and apply
the wrong beneficial insects it's going
to be very little effectiveness and this
does require by the grower frequent
scouting
timing and rate of beneficial insects is
also important and depending on what
insect you're trying to target
different areas where you can purchase
those insects will provide those
recommendations hopefully this was
helpful to you to identify and control
aphid populations and this can hopefully
help save your plants an environmentally
friendly way