all right in this debaco university
video we're gonna look at beneficial
insects regarding thrips in your
cannabis production there thrips can be
a common pest that's identified this
gives you an example what they look like
as well as the damage and this video
will give you an idea of the beneficial
insects you can use to help control
these pesky insects
[Music]
all right let's get into the video here
so first off this is based off a
research article so you're welcome to
follow this reference and citation for
more details into the materials and
methods utilized as part of the study
so first off insects can be a challenge
in general for greenhouse production and
and these can cause many losses
economically environmentally
so here
typically the reason why we're talking
about beneficial insects in this video
is synthetic chemicals have been the
go-to option but there's many
restrictions using these forms of
pesticides this is the driving forced
development of new environmentally
friendly and profitable pest methods for
pest control which will be discussed
here
so first off this was a greenhouse study
conducted at the agriculture university
of athens they had plants grown in two
different greenhouses both one with
treatment
which had the beneficial insects and one
that did not uh the cultivar used was
this myosis variety and this gives you
an idea of the greenhouse's
environmental conditions
now the release date for the beneficial
insects was three weeks after
transplantation
beneficial insects were released into
the treatment greenhouse in order to
assess the efficiency of the biological
pest and method of control
so thrips or the study here this kind of
gives you
exactly an image of what to look like on
a leaf
and this is going to be the main one
talked about here of course the study
looked at others but this will be the
main one talked about in this video
so first off basic uh
measures for management
included visual estimation of
infestation and recording of pest
species and populations and the
comparison of infestations between the
two greenhouses only the nymphs and
adults stages of pests were counted not
the egg stage if you had an idea what
other insects they looked at or what
these insects look like in comparison
this nice little visual kind of key
identification here
might be of help to you
now how were these pest populations
determined well it was the measurements
of the pest populations were taken in
the third fifth seventh and ninth week
the number of pests in this case thrips
was counted with a handheld digital
1600x microscope in order to quantify
the efficiency of the beneficial insects
the average pest populations were
measured in 10 plants four leaves per
plant per greenhouse
so with any pests that we're trying to
deal with understanding the life cycle
is important so i welcome you to pause
the video here
to take a better look at exactly what
thrips are what their life cycle is and
how you would go about identifying them
however i want you to keep in mind that
thrips can also transmit viruses
so not only can they do physical damage
to your plants but they can also provide
a vector
for other
negative impacts to your plants in this
case viruses so controlling the thrips
will reduce the physical damage as well
as the chance at virus vectoring their
life cycle they can go through a series
of six stages in only about two and a
half to two to three and a half weeks at
68 to 85 degrees fahrenheit with insects
realize that temperature you should be
monitoring that and recording that
because that can impact the rate of
development of certain insects now for
identification the adults are very small
very slender as well and they can have
different colorations so keep that in
mind the larvae are actually wingless so
they're not going to travel very far
they tend to like very hidden portions
of the plant so again keep that in mind
now the beneficial insects here uh
first one that was discussed is
ambulance swarovski this is a predatory
mite that pierces the prey with their
sucking mouthwarts and sucks out the
contents there and again some more
information about that specific one here
some tips and ideas you're welcome to
take a look at but again there's a
temperature tolerance range uh so again
we don't want to go above or below that
for to allow for the maximum
effectiveness
then the other one uh shown here is um
arius and kind of a cool kind of picture
here its life cycle is completed in
about three weeks it has this very
darkened kind of blackened back would
you speak it's a fast-moving predator
small soft-bodied insects can also feed
on pollen in the absence of prey so you
could potentially sustain this
population within your greenhouse if
you're growing some flowering plants at
some pollen to keep their populations
going and help
them keep going so they can help you
with thrip control
now the exact method of thrip control
how do we apply these insects well they
can be used with slow release satchets
that we kind of see right here each
contained about 250 predatory mites of
the
swarsky one and then of the arias one
here this was applied by spreading
evenly through bottles measured in the
leaves and also using dye boxes which
are basically little boxes that would
hang on your plants
now the numbers over time because this
was a study so i want to provide you
with the actual numbers
right above me here you can see the
table and then here's the graph
on week nine it was low as only about
2.6 thrips per plant with the treated
those plants treated with beneficial
insects compared to over 40 thrips in
control plants that of course were not
treated and we can see the great
contrast here they both start around the
same the control definitely much higher
and significantly higher as well and
then they treated slowly decreasing over
time great sign that these beneficial
insects were helpful
now average number of pest populations
again it was measured in weeks and this
study did was conducted on other
populations so you're welcome to check
that out but this continuous reduction
in all pest populations was observed
through the experiment approaching zero
plant values as well so it's a great
sign that these might be very effective
in use in your growing operation
now again are they worth it beneficial
insects in general well in short yes
study results that the beneficial
insects could control pest populations
up to 100 percent pest management with
natural enemies is promising very
effective safe method for plant
production as well as applicator
protection as well
now if you are thinking about this and
hopefully you are keep in mind that
proper pest identification is important
since this will determine the exact
beneficial insect used and this does
require frequent scouting which you
should be doing timing and rate of
beneficial additions are important and
when you get down to knowing exactly
what insect researching those contacting
the supplier of the beneficial insects
they can all help you develop a plan
that will be effective at controlling
your pest populations while minimizing
any chance of negative overall
environmental impacts