on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over beneficial insects if
you identify spider mites in your
cannabis production plants and how to go
about best controlling them without the
use of insecticides
[Music]
all right let's get into the video here
so you've identified spider mites you
want to control them this hopefully will
provide some help for you
so first off this is all based off of a
research article welcome to look at this
they look at more than just spider mites
so if you have an idea of materials
methods some more details i welcome you
to check out the reference here with the
link provided
so first off insects can be a challenge
in greenhouse production in general and
they can cause many losses often
synthetic chemicals have been used as an
option but with the medical cannabis
kind of cultivation and strict
legalizations and restrictions on the
use of those pesticides in most case for
a good reason this is the driving force
between the development of new
environmentally friendly but yet
profitable methods of pest control
so this greenhouse study was conducted
at university agriculture university of
athens they looked at two different
greenhouses one that had the beneficial
insects and one that basically did not
this is the minuses variety they were
using as well as the
general greenhouse environmental
conditions that those plants and insects
were experiencing
now beneficial insects the general
release date uh three weeks after
transplantation beneficial insects were
released into the treatment greenhouse
in order to assess the efficiency of the
biological control pest management
strategy
so spider mites this study specifically
looked at spider mites that we can see
right here
particularly the two spotted spiromites
is what was studied uh here and that's
the information that'll be presented on
throughout the the article in
presentation here probably abbreviated
as tssm first two spotted spider mites
so basic measurements
you're looking at include visual
estimations of the infestation the
recording of pest species and
populations in the comparison of
infestations between the two greenhouses
only the nymphs and adult stages of the
pests were counted no egg stage and this
just shows you what some of the insects
look like
in comparison spider mites again being
this
a here but you could see some of the
other insects for comparison that were
part of the study
so how were the pest populations
determined well measurements of the
pests were taken in the third fifth
seventh and ninth week and the spider
mites were counted of the handheld
digital 1 1600x microscope in order to
quantify the efficiency of the
beneficial insects average pest
populations were measured in 10 plants
four leaves per plant per greenhouse
so it's important on any insect or
passage you're looking at controlling is
to have an understanding of the life
cycle
i have a basic kind of idea of what
you're looking at the life cycle as well
as key identifying characteristics so i
welcome you to pause the video here if
you want to read this in any more detail
but just kind of some highlights there
two spotted spider mites they're
technically not insects they're related
to spiders because they have eight legs
and they can go through five stages in
about two weeks so they can multiply
very quickly and go through this
progression although spider mites can
have two color phases so keep in mind
that you're not looking for one
particular color um and they all can do
very varying amounts of damage there so
again take a pause read through this if
you want to learn more about uh spider
mites because you want to know the enemy
you're trying to combat
so going on the beneficial insects
specifically to target these uh spider
mites um so here are the beneficial
insects and this is neocilocus uh
californicus uh this is
significantly cooler and warmer
temperatures will slow or inhibit the
production of their development so keep
that in mind higher humidity is
generally necessary with higher
temperatures however the californians
can persist in low humidity environments
with limited food sources which makes it
a great beneficial insect to choose the
slower pace that these predatory mites
feed
five mites per day and their ability to
sustain themselves on pollen it allows
them to survive for longer when you have
lower pest populations the full life
cycle of calif for forking franicus can
last between one to two weeks and is
significantly influenced by temperature
so keep that in mind if you're in a
greenhouse environment what season you
might be considering applying these then
we have another one here this is a
fellow tila
formerly known as a different name so
again maybe do some research as far as
you know looking at both names
that's what it's currently known as this
is a pink brown predatory midge and can
only gets about two millimeters long
it's about one twelfth of an inch the
antennae of the male insect are covered
with long hairs with those of the female
shorter and thicker so good if you're
using a magnifying loop which would be
recommended the female adult lays eggs
inside a spider-mite colonies the larvae
begin to pry on the spider mites
immediately after hatching the young
larvae feed mainly on the spider my eggs
and older larvae feed on all stages of
the mites so you kind of get that
multiple life cycle benefit or control
the larvae eat about 50 spider mites
before pupating and the larvae are
creamy yellowy brown colorations again
between a quarter to two millimeters
long the pupae can be found inside the
white cocoons along the veins of the
leaves if you're doing inspections as
you should be of your particular
cannabis leaves
now for that two-spotted spider-mite
control the predators were applied by
hanging slow release satchets as we can
kind of see right here each of these
contains about 100 predatory
and storage mites of the californians
per cannabis plant
the other ones here they are introduced
by making a hole in the lid located
directly in the middle of the greenhouse
so you have to be mindful as far as
these beneficial insects it's not an
insecticide you don't just mix and apply
here we're looking at different methods
of application to allow the greatest
benefit for those
beneficial insects to go about attacking
in this case your spider mites
now looking at the data from the actual
study here for two spotted spider mites
plants treated with beneficial insects a
dramatic decline in might pipe
populations this gives you the data
table but the graph really shows it here
week three remember both greenhouses the
control which had no spider my
beneficial insects added and the
treatment which would have those added
were initially right around the same
level now looking here at the
progression spreader mites definitely
increased dramatically dipped a little
bit in control but we can see the
treatment group really a great decrease
here by week nine right here
there was less than two spider mites per
plant on average for those plants
treated with the beneficial insects
compared to over 75 in the control
plants so this massive decrease and
significantly different decrease as well
all great that these beneficial insects
are definitely worth the time and effort
they are to apply
average number of pest populations here
we can see those numbers uh in general
kind of how they were able to be reduced
over time
and these are numbers and weeks a
continuous reduction all pest
populations was observed throughout the
experiment approaching zero value per
plant now i did look at other insects i
will have other videos on those
but this just shows you that spider mite
population decrease
now not mentioned in the study here was
a persimilis
now these do a little bit better i will
admit when there is webbing involved
so they can be a little bit more of a
benefit in that factor if your spirits
have developed that protective webbing
they do want to try to break that as
much as you can
the release of these as the first sign
of might infestations is advised once
leaf damage is serious more than four
mites per leaf achieving the control is
more difficult so keep that in mind you
want to try to catch these early
persimmons these are red in color
relative to the pest mites and they feed
on and are best used to combat active
mite populations but this will leave the
area in search of alternate food sources
if pest
populations drop between a lower level
so again keep that in mind that your
pest population is too low or you're
just seeing it this may not be your best
option some of the other ones mentioned
would be advised
now our beneficial insects worth the
effort will ensure yes the study
indicates that beneficial insects could
control pest populations up to 100
percent pest management with natural
enemies is very promising very effective
safe method for plant protection as well
as applicator production
now what growers do need to keep in mind
if you are considering this which
hopefully you are is that proper pest
identification is important since this
will determine the exact beneficial
insect you're going to utilize this
requires frequent scouting timing and
rates of beneficial additions are
important so the remember you're dealing
with a biological system so keeping the
right species the timing and matching
the species with your pest and the
degree of severity of the problem is all
important to achieve a very effective
environmentally sustainable control
method