okay here we're look at binomial
nomenclature and if you break these two
words down by meaning - Gnomeo referring
to name and nomenclature is this system
of naming you begin to make sense of
this what's is going to be all about and
how important this is for biology so
starting with in general names were
based on Latin or ancient Greek words
and scientists everywhere understood
these languages we want to use terms
that are interchangeable that's across
regions languages for naming our
organisms so that no matter where you
are located in the world where you may
be doing research scientists all over to
know exactly what you're referring to so
the first word of the scientific name is
a species name it's the name of the
genus to which the organism belongs to
the Jews name refers to the relatively
small group of organisms to which a
particular type of organism belongs
remember that from our classifications
in our kingdoms
file ohms and Families how this relates
we're looking specifically here at the
naming of the first word referring to
the genus the second word is the name of
the species and this is a specific
identifier species names are usually a
Latin description of some important
characteristics of that particular
organism humans here you see Homo
sapiens homos being the genus and
sapiens is referring to these species
plotting this - another example and
allowing how you'd understand some more
of the rules associated with this when
we use the Latin name for an organism we
always capitalized the genus which is
the first part but not the species
identifier which is the second part we
also print the name in italics or
underline them you use italics if you're
using the computer or if you're writing
them on a test quiz or any handwritten
who would underline them for example
Acer rubrum which is the scientific name
for a red maple tree so again the common
name would look like this if you were
writing it out if you were typing it you
would use the italics Acer is the Latin
name for maple that's again the genus in
rubber 'm is the latin word for red and
it's refer
to the species certain ones can also be
abbreviated as we can see here a period
and Romo referring to our beautiful
youth all at least red maple trees
humans are named Homo sapiens
so homo because of our large brained and
upright posture through that's derived
from any sapiens because our
intelligence and ability to speak if
you're a star Wars fan and qui-gon jinn
quote right here the ability to speak
does that make you necessarily
intelligent but we also said our large
brain and this gives you an example of
our cerebral cortex not with neurons
that we have in billions compared to a
couple other species here so you can see
the elephant monkey and the chimpanzee
we have sixteen point three billion
which is much larger than any of these
other different species how this might
look myself up here now this might look
is there's a lot of information that can
be conveyed in a very short space so
this is just one example of the Colorado
potato beetle which is actually a major
pest insect and it's here kingdom or
phylum our class and our order family
genus or species and all the numbers
correspond here so I see they're able to
determine what Kingdom it's in it's an
animal and then get very specific here's
a binomial name and that's referring to
again you'll notice it's in italics
because it is typed the first word is
capitalized there's a space and our
second word so our name and authority
and when it was potentially named who
named it all of this information can be
kept very quick and easy and it's kind
of like card like format with the
addition of a picture this can be very
helpful for looking at doing research or
trying to identify and talk about this
specific insect so that people all over
the world know exactly what we're
talking about so getting on how to
properly write binomial nomenclature so
here's an example of again humans this
one is incorrect because it's all
written as one solid word the second
example here is wrong
even though it's two separate words we
notice the first word here is not
capitalized the third version is
capitalized and does have a space but
because it's handwritten
is not underlined this last one here
indicates the correct improper way to
write binomial nomenclature first word
capitalized space to the second word the
second word is lowercase and both words
are underlined if we were typing this on
a computer we could italicize them
so looking at our taxonomy and
nomenclature they're closely aligned but
separate and complementing endeavors in
developing the language of biodiversity
nomenclature is a system for giving
names to organism organisms taxonomy is
the branch of biology that identifies
and names organisms so coming together
we get able to develop the type of
specimen so that we're able to
understand exactly what it is and we get
away from the use of common names even
though it might be easier to understand
certain species and different species
may have overlapping in common names so
this nomenclature taxonomy come together
as we were able to as scientists talk
about the same thing regardless of our
geographic location