in this video we're gonna go over
biodiversity looking at the two midges
that I put here you can see here in the
wildflowers area on the off side of the
hay field a great amount of biodiversity
and in the hay field here a minimum
amount here a picture of bunch of
mushrooms indicating the biodiversity
that can occur in a relatively small
area so biodiversity is simply defined
as the variety of life in it in a
habitat you see the same two images here
we use two terms here species richness
and that's referring to the number of
species in an ecosystem this
biologically diverse ecosystems are
generally more stable than simple ones
these diverse areas allow different
species to be able to match the
particular conditions that may occur
will allow us life to continue to
survive its quality is usually measured
what we call this biodiversity how much
how many different species live in this
particular habitat two important factors
in promoting biodiversity one is
ecosystem size this may make sense in
the simple fact that the larger the
ecosystem contains more diverse habitats
and therefore as greater number of
species a reduction in the ecosystem
size will simply reduce the amount of
species that I can support can
ultimately lead to extinction may occur
in extreme cases if the ecosystem
shrinks too small here's an example a
picture of the world here with certain
amount of biomes defined as different
regions we're going to go over biomes in
a certain different section will be a
project related to those latitude is
another important factor when
determining our s'ti the number species
in the tropics is far more than the
Arctic regions simply because it's a
longer growing season plants can survive
longer plants are constantly growing
allowing animals to eat them and the
climate tends to be more stable so these
dark red regions represent greater
biodiversity and these deeper blues to
black regions represent less
biodiversity and you could see in
general towards the equator regions
there tends
more biodiversity than at either Pole
and this is simply because a longer
growing season more stable conditions
here specifically looking at what we
call island biodiversity this is where
we're getting an equilibrium model look
at isolated island look it's a species
written richness on an island it's
dynamic equilibrium between colonization
and rate of extinction see here we have
a bunch of different birds bunch of
different beaks various items that they
eat here's a generalist and said
catching we have him nectar-feeding
surface swimming filter feeders so on
and so forth they also developed certain
niches to be able to survive hey two
important factors looking at Island
biodiversity the first one is island
size so here's our mainland here's our
radiating points outward the larger the
island in this case Island number two
will tend to have more species and
smaller ones and this should seem
logical if it's larger there should be
more out to have weird diversity greater
number of species can survive there
versus the small little island here
again distance from the mainland so in
this case we're going to call Island one
and two are basically the same size for
intents and purposes with the same
resources however the distance from the
mainland can impact this these that are
closer to the mainland will have greater
biodiversity than those further away and
this is simply like you don't want to
travel very far you're gonna jump to the
closest area before making a long
distance trip to this island I think's a
lot of energy to do that I tend to be
kind of a low close area if you're
parking in a parking lot and it picked
the closest spot very near you don't
want to go to these distant areas here
so that's going to tend to be less
biodiverse further away from that
mainland this again shows a little bit
of a craft indicating our number of
species
being far away I'm gonna have less
species then island closer to the manner
in near mainland this distance effect is
what that relates to farther away
less species near to the mainland more
species here looking at large and small
islands and the smaller island some
players less species and the larger
islands has more species putting that a
little bit different color here looking
to our island biodiversity summary same
thing here fewer species on small
distant islands and more species on
large nearby islands and again when we
say nearby islands nearby to the
mainland and this is on the x-axis here
increasing the species richness so these
many species and these are fewer species
and those on large islands close to
millions tune have greater biodiversity
than those smaller islands that are far
away