if you've considered using biodegradable
pots for cannabis production
this debaco university video is for you
[Music]
all right let's go over some
biodegradable pots uh for canvas
production
let you know some of the options you
have all right so first off i want you
to realize that there is some
variability with biodegradable pots
there's many different types of base
materials that fall under this category
there's common brands materials such as
for example cow pots
are made from cow manure jiffy pots are
made from willpower
wood pulp and peat moss straw pots are
made from
as they would imply straw and same with
coconut fiber also made
from coconut fiber no real surprise
there keep in mind some of these also
have binders that are added to them to
help hold them together
and so for example the coconut coir
might not be something you're if you're
used to growing it as a media
you're looking at here as a pot it has a
very kind of
solid like feel to it there's a binder
in there so it can be very
thin but still hold together that's
going to affect some of the properties
of these pots
now starting with the first one here
looking at just at cow pots many
variations to meet different demands
they do break down in one year if used
in field applications they won't
accumulate over a year they do break
down over the course of a growing season
but they're not well suited for full
growing cycle production so what that
means is if you're growing in a
greenhouse or high tunnel
i'm going to grow in a one of these
containers not the best they tend to
break down over time which is a good
thing
if you're planting them directly into
the field they said many variations many
different sizes
which is great for holding seedlings for
a certain duration of time
then there are jiffy pots and this
pretty much is considered to be like the
standard
however the rate of degradation is
longer than one growing season
if being used in outdoor field
applications so you want to keep in mind
that this will result in overall
accumulation of the material if you use
it year after year in the same field
so while yes does it break down yes but
it does take longer than a year
so keep that in mind then there are
straw pots that are made from straw
and they do break down quickly but
they're not well suited for long-term
growing
they can be very flimsy side when it
comes to handling and transport of the
plants
while in these containers and basically
start wrapped together there's a binder
there
roots can penetrate through them pretty
easily but they are not really
have a great integrity uh to them so
they can fall apart fairly easily
then there's those coconut pots here
this last one that we'll talk about here
roots can often pass right through the
fibers as we see here on the lower side
however if used in outdoor locations
these pods really do not break down very
much at the end of the season
so feel as if they can almost be reused
to the lack of degradation
so while they you know are toted as you
know being great and reusable using
material
if you're planting them outdoors you
want to be mindful that at the end of
the season you may be able to find
basically the same pot originally
planted
so keep that in mind so you don't have
these containers becoming
a potential problem particularly in
field applications