if you're considering using
biodegradable mulch to suppress
weeds in your field this is a great
video because we're going to analyze
a research report and provide you some
information and hopefully some useful
information
so you can be able to apply this to your
own growing situation here on debaco
university
[Music]
all right let's get into biodegradable
mulch for weed suppression
study related to cannabis production so
first off this
is the research article so you're
welcome again take a look at it here
look at it for yourself
look at some of the details i'm just
going to provide a summary
so first off what was the study
objective well to study objective was to
evaluate the effectiveness of several
biodegradable mulches
on weed control and yield of processing
tomatoes in different areas of spain
the goal was to find an alternative to
standard black polyethylene mulch in
order to reduce the waste problem that
is generated from that product
this study investigated a field trial at
four locations in spain over three years
it was a randomized complete block
design with at least three replicates
of nine treatments so the tomatoes
being studied since a long-term study
regarding cannabis of this type does not
exist
in this example tomatoes are being used
as a crop of comparison
at the end of the study review based on
the results specific recommendations for
cannabis
production will be provided so again
even though this study was done for
tomatoes
they have their own specialties we're
going to try to relate this to cannabis
now the treatment study there's there
was nine and we could see them all
listed here with one being basically an
untreated control
one being manual weeding conventional
plastic mulch
and then different types of
biodegradable plastic mulch
as well as paper mulch were studied and
you can see the details listed here
you're welcome to pause the video and
again go through these in more detail
if it's of interest to you so we
densities at the four locations again
another great opportunity here to kind
of pause the video and kind of go
through that
we can see the different areas the
different years so this is what's great
about this
is we're seeing multiple years of
comparison the weed densities of main
weed species found in different years
and locations
in the untreated control plots 63 days
after transplanting
so again we're having some time for
those wheats to build up you see the
locations
we see the weed species we see the total
weeds listed
right here another great here
opportunity to pause the video and do a
little comparison
here we're going to move on so the weed
control 63 days post transplanting so
again now we're getting into
some more of the numbers here and that's
again what makes this study great
and allows you maybe if you find
something of interest to really go
through and look at the specifics and
see how that compares
here we're looking at the weed control
63 days after transplanting depending on
the treatment
for different locations and years now
what's just important to note
is that we've got our letters here and
if they all have the same letter so for
example this location
these should be considered not to be
statistically different
when we see different letters that's
where we start to see some of the
differences
in sorts of comparisons so just as a
quick example here
for this year across all these different
trials basically there was no difference
even though look at the numbers ago
they're different well we look at kind
of put it to a statistical test there's
really really
no difference this year no matter what
type
of sweet suppression you used other
locations you can see for the vast
majority very similar
we can see here barley straw vastly
different than any of the other
treatments
so that's how you kind of go about
reading this data table
income benefits in related tomato data
so we're looking at here cost
income in benefits here's our income
here's our benefit
and percent compared to polyethylene or
the standard plastic mulch
so in this example untreated controls
the percentage compared
would be under would be less than using
polyethylene
untreated just leaving it open see here
weeds sure definitely
added some competition and definitely
reduced yields
others we can see the polyethylene was
kind of that source of comparison
100 and we could see everything else was
of course
better than the untreated control but
didn't quite meet the
levels of polyethylene here for
comparison
now we'll get a category comparison so
biodegradable plastics
can be an alternative to polyethylene
due to the overall good weed control
in high in this case tomato yield paper
mulches do not perform as well
overall but are more diff and are more
difficult to apply and avoid
fracturing however these are the only
products that control
nutsage emergence so paper mulches are
the only ones we see here
that would control nutsedge so if you
have nutsedge as a problem in your area
they can puncture right through plastic
mulch so if you have these as a major
kind of contaminant kind of a weed in
the in the field
using the paper mulches can suppress
them from being able to poke their way
up
and through your mulch now we also have
economic considerations that's a very
important consideration
uh biodegradable materials do provide
benefits however in all cases
they were less when compared to
polyethylene traditional plastic
this is why plastic melted still remains
the most commonly used option
despite the disposal issues as well as
some other issues that it has still the
most widely used option
then we get to manual weeding so many
weeding did result in low weed densities
however depending on the area and labor
this may be
cost prohibitive especially depending on
the size of your operation
and lastly we're applying these findings
to our cannabis production
so in season plastic offers many
benefits but growers must consider the
entire growing season with the typically
well-established root system
based systems of cannabis this can make
the removal of plastic melted at the end
of the season
much more challenging in addition to the
disposal issues
if the field you're planting cannabis
and it has nutsedge though
which is sadly becoming a bigger problem
in many agricultural
fields the more i go into more problems
it seems like there are
growers should consider the use of
potential paper mulch because that is
the only mulch
is resistant to the emergence of
nutsedge message can emerge through
plastic mulch punches right through
and only paper munch paper mulch has
shown effectiveness at reducing its
emergence
so this is where knowing your field can
be also be important
to know that hey it's a lot of nutsage
in this field maybe i would consider
the use of a paper mulch over a plastic
mulch
but as you can see plastic still
regarded as the number one use because
of its benefits
but you want to look at this data and
see which one might fit your situation
the best