here we look at the biological species
concept so how do we get a group of
individuals that's a subset of an
original population and why is that
advantageous I'll go over some of the
reasons of why this occurs so the start
speciation is the process of species
forming process it involves progressive
change and localized populations become
increasingly specialized natural
selection acts to keep them at different
enough so we kind of get this splitting
effect that occurs now biological
species concept is defined as species
are groups of actually or potentially
interbreeding natural populations which
are reproductively isolated from one
another other such groups so kind of
getting this separation that occurs and
this can happen in two different forms
so it is a two-part process that causes
this initially to occur one identical
populations must diverge and to
reproductive isolation must evolve to
maintain these differences speciation
occurs quicker in the absence of gene
claw this is much more likely in
geographically isolated populations so
here we have our formation of locusts
hybrids
we have selection against those hybrids
and over time we get a clear and
distinctive green in blue population so
this hybrid this intermediate was just
not fit for the particular environmental
conditions and our speciation occurred
causing a distinctive green in blue
species to develop so there's two types
here in this pictures a great way to
visualize them allopatric speciation
which is the differentiation of
geological geographically isolated
populations into distinctive species we
have a population here put that into a
picture we have a mountain region that's
separated out we see here geographically
isolated we have our darker colored
green and in our layer color green
sympatric speciation is the
differentiation of populations within a
common geographical area in two distinct
species so this is a reproductive
isolation as a
you see in the middle region here
presents our greater number of lighter
green trees than the darker greens on
the outside and this is a reproductive
isolation that's occurring the through
these sympatric speciation so types of
speciation auto polyploidy instantaneous
synthetic speciation may occur through
collie protein which is more than two
sets of chromosomes Auto polyploidy are
all the chromosomes are from one species
this occurs when an individual has more
than two sets of chromosomes which
before and all derived from the original
species would be normal diploid or 2n so
Viktor word apart Otto polyploid itself
many folder chromosomes how does this
occur well so failure in meiosis causes
the chromosomes to fail to separate so
you're getting this kind of foreign or
tetraploid I mean this isn't always a
good thing to happen but in certain
instances plants in particular autoplay
can occur this is a type of speciation
as I go is tetraploid II or basically 4n
instead of the original diploid which
would be two men the other type is all
of polyploidy which is chromosomes
derived from two species via
hybridization this in particular is much
more common in plants and animals and
this occurs when two different species
contribute to the polyploidy hybrid so
inter pacific hybrids hybrids great from
two different species are usually
sterile
however the hybrids are usually very
vigorous so how does this apply well
getting common polyploid ease oats
cotton potatoes tobacco wheat crops
typically fall into this category where
we're looking at producing increased
yields and because they're sterile
sometimes these individuals may produce
reduced or no seeds which is
advantageous for the customer so now
there's the farmer getting larger and
more consistent crops but the offspring
being produced might be more favourable
to the people buying it you're just some
examples of biological speciation