here I'm going to go over some details
about the biology field trip to human
asset beach we were some of the basic
structure of the field trip and also
some questions you should be asking
yourself and looking at answering coming
away from this field trip so the first
part is it is human asset State Park
this is the address we're gonna be
parking in the main parking lot here
walking down this large walkway to the
main pavilion and continuing out from
there in a state park is connect its
largest shoreline park with over two
miles of beach to enjoy it won't be
visiting all of it will be focusing
mainly from here starting working to
sand dunes and working basically over to
this area here in the loop region first
opened the public in July 18th 1920
juice is an army reservation and the
federal government during World War two
so it does have some store reference and
over 1 million people visit every year
so hopefully we can enjoy it and be able
to understand some of the impacts of
this area we're just that volume of
people that visit the area so just some
quick words of caution just to consider
please carry out what you carry in
regardless of what that is related to
food or anything else to chew brain be
respectful of others in the environment
there may be other school groups there
even amongst your own students and other
individuals from the public that may be
there so just keeping a watch out for
everyone in our group and also other
groups lastly just make sure you watch
out for poison ivy tried to point it out
here typically we'll have green leaves
but when it first comes out it may have
this kind of reddish tones here and at
some anthocyanin that's produced in the
least helps protect it from the Sun
helps shade it there a little bit so
again not something want to be touching
as it can cause of severe itching this
an allergic reaction now getting to the
key ideas of the field trip to keep in
mind you want to be considerate of how
the individual species in ecosystem
respond as the oceans become more acidic
sadly a trend that we are noticing here
with some general global data to a why
will rising water temperature impact the
beach and how will that affect and what
will affect how our native invasive
species interacting with one another can
you find any of native or invasives
what's the role at each speech
environment play in the carbon cycle
it's in the general theory looking at
and also what can we do to help mitigate
negative impacts so general organization
I'm going to go through these in a
little bit more detail this gives you
just an idea when we say beach just
think of sand there are some rocky areas
there are some areas that I don't have
trees and there's trails revisiting a
little bit of each of these major
different areas so these are some of the
key questions to ask sand dunes art and
science water testing plants animals in
salt marshes there's going to give you a
quick overview of these stations here so
for the sand dunes the importance of
sand dunes well how does sandins impact
the local environment can you define for
unique niches found within the zones of
the sandy beach area and what's the
connection between the sand dunes and
hurricanes how do they protect the beach
how could they they become damaged how
could that be a threat things again
three key questions to consider when
looking at sand dunes moving on to blend
art and science well how does art and
science fuse together and what made you
select a story or drawing that you
created at this station so does have
some supporting reasons for that water
testing station you could can identify
the type of the tests that were
performed what the word the results
found or what was the data provided to
you it has this provided information in
the area that cannot simply be seen in
an image because I have a picture here
of the water is that human s a beach
what is the data say what is the result
of the testing some key points to
remember remember the pH scale 7 is
neutral under 7 is considered as sick
over 7 is considered basic on our chart
0 to 14 is the scale albro and tile blue
solution may have uses in a lab of
looking at respiration rate is a pH
indicator and carbon activated in water
will result in carbonic acid formation
reducing the pH plants living at the
beach what are some plants that are able
to survive in the beach environment if
you're walking on a trail look for tag
number four next to a large rock and a
bench what are there different colored
algae we can see here a rock with some
greens and brown why are there's
different colors what do they exist and
you say the question a plant at the
beach may have genetics to grow ten feet
tall but at maturity the phenotypes only
three feet tall
what stresses may be on the plants that
does not reach its full genetic
potential so be thinking and considering
that question then we go into the animal
hunt at the water's edge and if you pit
in my classroom you might recognize this
image it is on the wall I want to
consider what animals can you find how's
the tide impact your ability to find
animals and what are tides how does its
implication affect the shells and
skeletons of sea life a good link you
might want to look at here can you fully
classify one in while starting with the
domain the kingdom then go into phylum
class order family genus and species for
just one of the animals that you are
where someone is able to find at the
beach the value of salt marshes why are
salt marsh is important if we do not
have salt marshes what would be the
native impacts in the local ecosystem
from a bird's perspective then I at
least four reasons why salt marshes are
important and here's again images from
him an acid pH again those resounding
questions we want to be thinking about
how old individual species and
ecosystems respond as the oceans become
more acidic
what is ocean acidification why is this
happening what are some ways individual
species might respond to ocean
acidification how will the lowering of
oceans waters pH impact the ability of
ocean to store carbon in deep sea
sediments what can be done to reduce
this change and things we want to be
considering as overarching themes
amongst all stations in addition while
rising water temperature impact the
beach how this impact current species in
place and the potential spread of
invasive species what impacts is warm or
surface temperature have on ocean storms
what can be done to reduce the negative
impacts and again a good link here and
some data provided with you on this
slide also how we how our native
invasive species interacting how isn't
invasive species defined what can be the
long-term impacts of invasive species
what are some examples of native
invasive species found at the beach
again a great link here to the
Connecticut website the role of species
environment play in the carbon cycle so
it can give you a brief overview here of
the carbon cycle the cycling carbon
involves a few different forms of carbon
however what roles chrome dioxide play
in the carbon cycle so look at that
molecule it has that interact with
plants and animals
what role do plants animals play in this
cycle as well as well as human impacts
and results of fossil fuel-burning
unless we wanted to kind of end this on
a positive note what can we do to help
now when we look in the mirror we'd be
proud what are some activities that can
contribute to the simplification of
oceans we want to be mindful of that and
what actions can we do to reduce the
negative impacts on the environment some
good information provided here and very
lastly in no particular order some
quality resources that might help you
address some of these questions and also
provide some great background on the
beach so again this kind of that
overview of the biology field trip to
him an asset beach in the description
there is the link to all the images that
are used as well as the slides if you
wanted to print those out hope you have
a fun time and are able to learn
something and make a connection to the
study of life