welcome to a video lecture on the
biosphere by me mr. Tuvok oh you made
rememory from such films as the
ecological organization because this
video lecture picks up right where that
one left off with the biosphere so this
slide may look familiar if you watched
that previous video lecture but let's
start here with the biosphere all the
biomes together with marine and
freshwater included the Earth has four
major connected systems which we are
going to go over in detail here the
atmosphere the ecosphere the hydrosphere
and lithosphere all coming together to
form the biosphere which is a portion of
Earth that's inhabited by life including
all biotic and abiotic parts so starting
with the hydrosphere of Earth's water
ice and water vapour is all included in
the hydrosphere oceans account for about
ninety six and a half percent of the
water I'll bet in salt water and it's
found in the oceans freshwater is the
remaining three percent and that may be
locked up in glaciers and ice caps or in
groundwater or surface and other
freshwater this surface and other
freshwater is mainly the accessible
component that we have and most of that
is composed of ground ice permafrost or
lakes here the fresh water distribution
and you can notice here it's a very
limiting resource ice is about one point
seven six two percent groundwater is
next most abundant and surface
freshwater you can see the very small
percentage of the total hydrosphere
atmosphere in soil is even a smaller
percentage than that this is why the
world's so concerned with not only the
amount of water we have but really the
amount of fresh water we have access to
this is the vast majority is locked up
in oceans which is saltwater which is
not really usable for both human
consumption and also to grow plants the
oceans in iswhat bodies of water hold
the lowest amount of water well it's the
oceans there are largest bodies of water
on earth however they contain salt water
only you see all the major oceans here
the Arctic top Atlantic
Pacific River Indian Ocean here so we
have all of these areas but they're very
large but however this is all saltwater
not really useable on most forms by a
lot of our terrestrial based life-forms
moving on we have oceans and ice of
icebergs they're large pieces of fresh
water or ice flowing in open waters well
90% of iceberg is below the surface of
the water so it comes back to the
Titanic here and sadly it ran into an
iceberg a very small portion of the
total iceberg is actually exposed above
the water that can be seen the vast
majority of located beneath the water
surface makes them very dangerous for
traveling boats
continue with that ice we also have
glaciers and they're any large mass of
ice it moves slowly over land salad
we're seeing a lot of the glaciers that
are being reduced I could see the
evidence of where the glacier line was
here in 1885 and this picture was taken
in 2003 how much is receded again images
of the same area taken in different ears
you can see the great receding or
something melting of these glaciers the
freshwater locations is surface water so
what's the difference between a water
shouldn't River Basin well both terms
are used to describe land that drains
into a river stream or lake however a
river basin is the term used is we have
an area that drains into a large river
the watershed is the term used to
describe the area that drains into a
smaller river or stream so you can see
evidence here of the Connecticut River
and where the river basin is remember
that's the term that describes traits
into the large river and then the
watershed is a term used to describe it
drains into smaller river or stream this
is kind of be a general overview of the
watershed of the Connecticut River and
the river basins would kind of be closer
to that large or main river there
something called groundwater so what's
groundwater well simply put its water
that's below the ground the water found
in cracks and pores and sand gravel and
rocks below the earth's surface now the
low could be just a shallow area here or
it could be deep below now it takes a
lot of more time for water to penetrate
and get down into the deeper layers but
all this is considered groundwater
whether it takes only a couple days to
get below the surface years centuries
millennia is all considered or falls in
the category of groundwater we have
something called aquifers so it's a rock
layer that stores water and allows water
to flow through it aquifers are kind of
like these large almost underground
Lakes that occur on a lot of you can
take a very long time to recharge for
water to get in there if we do pull some
out but they're typically very large
areas if wetlands in the area where
water table is at near or above the land
surface long enough during the year to
support adapted plant growth so what
land is an area here we see where that
water tables at near or above the
surface it does contain water for an
extended period of time somewhat wounds
can dry up over time but some will hold
water
the key part they are long enough during
the air to support adapted plant growth
Oh
additional hydrosphere vocabulary we
have a tributary which is a stream
feeding a larger stream or lake
tributaries contributing that water and
they can flood during times of heavy
rainfall reservoir is the lake that
stores water for human use in an
artesian well is a well in which water
rises because the pressure was in the
aquifer so we see an example here of the
artesian well if the sechín saturation
levels above we punch a hole here a lot
of pressure kind of the water flowing
down here you can get this kind of free
flow in this natural flow of water
through an artesian well third we have
the atmosphere so again we're looking at
this virus fear in general looking at
the atmosphere the air blanketing earth
solid and liquid surface so we take a
breath in the amount of air around us
here is mostly composed of nitrogen it's
the most abundant gas in the Earth's
the sphere making up about 70% of the
earth the Chur of the immature breeding
here on earth oxygen is the second most
abundant making up 21% and living organs
are used as food sources and oxygens
utilized by urban adjust other organisms
options released in the atmosphere by
yes as a photosynthesize first
atmosphere has a unique composition of
gases when compared to other plants
within the solar system the blue light
is scattered more than other wavelengths
by gases in the atmosphere and that is
in part what gives the blue color to the
sky now keep in mind that there is
carbon dioxide there is neon there's
helium out of hydrogen but we could see
these percentages down here are a lot
smaller on nitrogen by far than appears
by far the vast majority at 78% then
comes oxygen a little argon we see this
kind of thinness sliver here carbon
dioxide is the vast majority of this
small portion at point zero four oh
seven percent or four hundred parts per
million we can see the others are much
smaller but they do exist this
composition the atmospheric looking
specifically at carbon dioxide makes up
approximately 0.03 percent of the
Earth's atmospheric gases and it changes
a little bit depending where you are
it's also sadly changing over time so
carbon dioxide concentrations in the
atmosphere are regulated by the removal
of carbon dioxide from the atmosphere by
plants as they fix the carbon from
carbon dioxide into carbohydrates
exchanges of contacts between the
atmosphere and the oceans there's a
there's also chemical reactions that
occur within the atmosphere
and limestone we're kind of seeing that
concentration of carbon dioxide
increase very dramatically over recent
years in the atmosphere we have water
which is the atmospheres varies
considerably and also Nancy hydraulic
cycle this cycle is the evaporation and
condensation that results almost daily
here we see kind of that water cycle
here we're having evaporation of water
that condensing the water and
precipitation and that kind of water
cycle repeating there in the atmosphere
the atmospheric pressure and this is the
pressure the atmosphere exists on earth
and it decreases with increasing
latitude so if you seal bottle up at a
very high mountain peak when we start
walking down that mountain and we're
probably driving poorly realistically
driving down that mountain you can see
getting crushed here because this volume
of air contains less particles and it
does at sea level the greater the
altitude the same volume contains fewer
molecules of gases that make up the air
this means that the density of air
decreases as you increase in altitude so
it's a very tall but very very tall
mountain there'll be less dense air than
if you're at sea level atmospheric
pressure versus altitudes we can see
here the atmospheric pressure see more
density down here at the very bottom
then at the top of a mountain for
example this is a mountain very high
Denver for example new mile high it's
5,000 tor and 80 feet above sea level
but there's mountains much much higher
than that fourth component on the vast
areas of geosphere and this features
Perce surface kinds of rocks sea floor
and everything below the earth's surface
it's made up of rocks and rocks are made
up of minerals these minerals are
building blocks for the rocks and
elements are the ultimate building
blocks for those minerals we see that
example here forms of carbon we have a
morphus carbon there's kind of this
blackish kind of substance here we have
graphite which is carbon organized into
sheets and then we have diamonds which
is carbon organized in a very particular
structure there the geosphere is made up
of rocks and minerals just eight
elements that count for about 98% of the
Earth's mass elements composed of the
Earth's crust as you can see here oxygen
and silicon panama by weight very large
percentage there's also aluminum iron
calcium sodium potassium magnesium and a
host of others looking at the formation
of the geosphere these are the formation
of elements by the collision of the Sun
it's released as heat and it's change
from kinetic energy to heat energy the
more gravitational attraction towards
plant their Earth's center
also can lead to radioactive decay we
see that here the formation of our
geosphere that's caused by the collision
with the Sun was a very very large scale
keep - is not exactly to scale here last
we have the layers of the earth we have
that inner core which is actually a
solid turned by the outer core which is
liquid and we have the mantle here
ultimately leading to the very edges
here where we have the Earth's crust
here and basically that is the area that
life is we know it exists and we build
from there the interpreter is extremely
hot here it's inner core here being a
solid outer core being that liquid
component of basically melted iron