on this debaco university video we're
going to go over biotic and abiotic
factors to consider providing with some
examples as well as allowing you to do
some exploration on your own
[Music]
all right let's go over some of these
factors to consider here so we're
talking about biotic versus abiotic
remember there's two main categories
here biotic is the living and that
stands for basically life abiotic is
non-living factors so those biotics are
all the living or once living things in
the environment and abe factors are all
the non-living things in the environment
so some quick examples of biotic factors
some pictures here people animals and
plants while the abiotic factors rocks
water air but also consider wind
temperature and light still fall under
the abiotic category
so if we look at this image here always
talking about abiotic or abiotic item in
this image and this would be biotic this
mushroom here
how about the waves of the ocean
hopefully you said abiotic
and then this rock in the foreground
here
rocks these minerals would be going on
the abiotic side
this wonderful dog caught in a mid jump
here would of course be
biotic
a strand of dna
deoxyribonucleic acid it would be
abiotic
looking hopefully not staring directly
at it at least outside directly at the
sun here
this sun would be an example of
abiotic i have a lot of
you know combustion going on there a lot
of fusion going on that would of course
be abiotic
ah the sand
sand of course being mineral based
abiotic
uh looking at this virus particle here
so for those that don't know viruses are
basically dna wrapped in a protein coat
and i put kind of a good question here
because looking at they can multiply
they can cause severe disease
so what category do you classify them as
that's something we'll talk about in
class
about this
initially it might look like a leaf but
this is actually an insect that has
developed over time to look like a leaf
now whether you saw it as a leaf or saw
as an insect you should classify it
still as
biotic
now all organisms are what biotic or
abiotic and simply put they are all
biotic there now we can classify them a
little bit further as producers
consumers or decomposers but all these
still fall into the category of biotic
so imagine you walk outside the school
list as many biotic and abec factors as
you can i suggest you take a quick
second pause the video here jot a couple
of those down in each of those
respective categories
all right hopefully you did that and
going through and what are some of the
things you came up for uh biotic factors
living things you came up with and
hopefully some things maybe on your list
were trees grass birds people maybe
someone walking their dog as far as your
abiotic list goes you know
looking at that column hopefully that
you have created well those would be
kind of the school building light poles
houses cars sidewalks but don't forget
about sunlight temperature wind things
of those nature as well
so what are all the biotic and
items in this kind of unique image there
so i'll come up with kind of look at the
foreground here the background just a
little bit there what are some of the
biotic and abiotic things there i hope
we can make a quick little list there
just some more practice there kind of a
unique image i think
so um next little trial here you're
going to have 15 seconds to generate as
many uh abiotic and biotic factors as
you can for the image you're about to
see no it's not this picture i'm going
to step out so it doesn't look like i'm
staring at you for the 15 seconds uh but
you're going to have 15 seconds to look
at this image so get ready
and get set
all right and that one's time there so
hopefully you came up with a list and
you can uh take a look and uh compare
that uh in a class as well i can always
go back and
review it and hope you adhere to the 15
seconds there and pause the video and
cheat the system a little bit there but
so the question is you know everything
we looked at here do biotic and imac
factors affect each other
and this is kind of a question of you
know can these two kind of independent
categories have an impact on each other
and things you want to consider is if
there wasn't water in an area can
anything really grow and survive
or if you have an extremely cold winter
in those locations will affect animal
populations in the following spring year
so there are interactions that do occur
so your biotic factors living factors
that affect other organisms or shapes
the environment so back factors could be
predation
food availability competition and
disease or about factors those
temperatures light intensity water soil
ph mineral content gases
those non-factors can also affect
organisms
so it just does get very complex
depending on how much you want to get
into it but remember there are many
interactions that occur each impacted by
a variety of biotic and abiotic factors
with consumers producers you've got
primary
secondary and tertiary kind of consumers
all playing in to the great food web and
hopefully this took a very simple
category of just abec and
biotic factors and gave you a little bit
greater appreciation for the
complexities involved with just this
classification system