here when i take a brief overview of the
four main stages of blood dispersion
as it comes in contact with the surface
as it gets dispersed
and kind of the steps it goes through
between when it initially is falling
to that final result we'll see after so
phase one is contact and collapse and
phase two is the displacement so the
contact and collapse
phase it's when the droplet first hits
the target surface as you may suspect
and the droplet begins to collapse from
the bottom upward
this spot collapses the blood at the
collapsing point is forced outwards
creating a rim around the droplet
this is what we can measure for looking
at getting into kind of the measurement
of that
impact angle if it was on an angle for
example
the angle of impact and the target
surface will affect the boundary by
determining the nature of the rim and
the flow it falls onto
also dimension is the that target
surface
the more porous it is versus the more
solid
it may be that's going to really affect
how that's going to potentially go
through this
contact and collapse phase the
displacement phase
the dimples are present in the
may result in the formation of
individual spatter or a spine
that could develop we kind of see that
spines kind of developing here
the target surface influence the
formation of the spines and shape
irregularities so if it's a very smooth
surface you might get really well
defined kind of
displacement phase if it's a very porous
surface it might be harder for it to
kind of
see that level of detail the dispersion
phase
is where the blood is forced into the
boundary the rim and dimples that rise
upward and opposite in the direction
of the original momentum so here
impacted
as coming kind of coming down and it's
dispersing kind of coming
back up a little bit the satellite
splatter will form to the greatest
extent when the impact angle is closer
to 90 degrees
stain striking the target surface at
more acute angle
produce wave cast off spatter where the
where the blossom effect occurs more
in the form of a wave on one side of the
rim that just makes sense if you're on
more of an
angle you're not going to get
necessarily this perfectly
symmetrical dispersion phase
and last one being retractions is the
last phase of development
the result from the effect of the
surface tension trying to pull the fluid
the stain back into a single form we
have those internal forces there trying
to pull it back
together those internal forces present
in the moving
fluid are overcome by the surface
tension and the liquid
reactants forming spines away from the
potential stain
a very acute angle impacts the forces of
inertia overcome the surface tension
and satellite spots will detach from
there
so just kind of gives you that very
brief kind of look at as we have the
kind of the end phase how you'll see it
in the end
but how would that form well this is
that dispersion phase
and this is that displacement ultimately
starting with that contact phase
all this helps you hopefully understand
a little bit more of what's going
on with blood dispersion because of the
properties
internal to the blood