okay I've pictured here a couple of
bloom nutrient formulations these four
are just kind of a random assortment but
you'll notice that they all say the word
bloom on them typically what that means
is a high middle number which stands for
the phosphorus remember it's a nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium however this is
and that may be always the case if you
look at this one Walt does say bloom the
phosphorus is actually the same amount
as the potassium here so keep in mind
just because it says boom don't assume
it's always going to be a higher
phosphorous number I have to look more
specifically this is why you should be
reading all of the nutrient labels there
so flowering fertilizer is well bloom
fertilizers typically contain more
phosphorous to encourage and support
flowering however growers are often
excessively add phosphorus but can lead
to groundwater contamination so the
phosphorus and soils has a very complex
kind of system of components and inputs
and losses some can be runoff but if it
is over-applied this is where we get
into problems where there's usually
leaching this is usually minor because
it should be minor if you're adding the
proper amount however if you're over
adding you can contaminate not only
drinking water but local area freshwater
systems so an example of that by over
adding phosphorus can lead to algal
blooms in both a small scale so we see
here in a large scale this is a
satellite image this we're looking as
far away as the Great Lakes we can see
algal blooms particularly related to
excessive phosphorous added to that
water system now the paths of
phosphorous to farms and growers well
it's a lot of it's mined in Florida this
is you top it pictured here there are
some other areas that ship duty to the
Corn Belt as fertilizer it's applied to
corn and soybean fields on a large scale
the grain Canadian phosphorus can be
shipped to the Corn Belt then to Yukon
and the grain fed then to livestock and
the manure applied close to the barn
areas as a result the phosphorus that
was originally mine in Florida yes went
to the Corn Belt to help grow the corn
fed to the animals and then applied as
manure this means phosphorus from
Florida can accumulate in UConn's soils
the same thing that happened to
small-scale growers where it's mined in
Florida shipped as fertilizer and
applied and applied sadly and excessive
can lead to an accumulation in a
so why is this generally an issue and we
look at the world of phosphorus
fertilizer supplies we see the current
miss reserves a phosphate will be
exhausted around the year 2050 by
current estimates most of the phosphates
from Florida five countries control 87%
of the world phosphate reserves we see
the US only 7.8 percent with Morocco and
China being the vast majority world
reserves are estimated to last about 90
years so as a result Morocco and China
could be what's considered the OPEC of
phosphorus in the future this graph here
shows the US and the imports of rock
phosphate from 1900 to 2015 and you can
see for the vast majority of the early
going from about the mid 90s back we
exported a lot however now we're seeing
an increase in the amount of imports now
take care of today and you'll take care
of tomorrow we must be mindful of this
problem and manages nutrients in a
sustainable way we seem something that
can cause environmental damage and is
essentially running out is not good
stewardship we see the u.s. mine rock
phosphate now while it did increase we
see it dropping here this is not because
of reduction in use if we go back here
well the u.s. mine phosphate is going
down so in back remember we are starting
to import more so what's occurring is
we're mining less and we're importing
more and this is a particular nutrient
that is essential for plants but as they
said if we are over applying it that can
cause groundwater contamination which is
not good and we're now reliant more on
other countries for this vital nutrient
for plants