okay in this video we're going to go
over blood types and hopefully give you
a greater understanding than just the
fact that there's a B and O blood types
so starting with antibodies and blood
transfusions it's very important
identify someone's blood type if we're
looking at transfusing their blood or
even donating blood so blood type into
the system is the major groups of
red blood cell antigens now at least
have here is an example of a person who
are Type A here make in device against
antigen B so if you're a red blood cell
type a you have antibodies in your
plasma they're AMT B because your
antigens are type a as we see indicated
here by the circles if you're type B
blood type B blood type
you make antigens against a because your
antibodies against a because you have
the antigen B now if you're an a B blood
type
you don't make any antibodies against a
or B because you express both of these
antigens on the surface of your red
blood cells in contrast to that if
you're a group O in this case you do
make antibodies against a EMP because
you have no markers on your very blood
cells and therefore you're not
expressing any antigens continuing on
you may have heard of a negative and a
positive or a negative and a positive
and may wonder what the positive and
negative means well this refers to the
Rh factor RH is abbreviation for rhesus
factor because it was first discovered
in rhesus monkeys it's an antigen
occurring on the red blood cells of many
humans about 85% and some other primates
is particularly important as a cause of
evil addict disease of newborns and
incompatibility in blood transfusions so
does it really matter if your a or B
blood type or positive or negative not
in your day to day life but if we're
looking particularly potentially a
blood-borne or blood diseases and blood
transfusions well now this positive and
negative a and B and O types do become
very important so kind of did you know
your blood type you can kind of compare
here to see where you may fall if you're
part of the majority or the minority
here you
the majority no matter what blood type
across what race the positive is always
a greater number than the negative this
is because flipping back to the previous
slide you'll notice about 85% the
population does is positive it is
positive for expressing the Rh factor so
you can kind of pause the video here and
take in comparison here and see where
you may fall moving on from the red
blood cell type frequency we go to the
distribution of those blood types and
again you're welcome to pause the video
here in the slide and take a look at
some of the distributions of either the
a type the B type or the O blood groups
and where they fall where they're
typically found in different regions of
the world and no major advantage to be
any one group versus the other but it's
kind of interesting to see how different
subsets of populations do develop now
some it's important a red blood cell
compatibility table so I'll move myself
up here and we're looking our recipients
and our donors and our own negatives or
positives or any negatives or a positive
so on and so forth the take-home message
from this is that if you're an a B blood
type you're what's called the universal
recipient we're able to basically
receive blood from anyone and we're
looking at the positive Rh positive in
this case as you'll notice the Rh
negative
do have some exceptions to this rule but
in this case a B+ is a universal
recipient they can receive blood from
anyone what blood type is really sought
after for blood drives in particular or
what's owed blood type particularly own
negative because the dear the universal
donor they can give their blood or
donate their blood to anyone of these
types here so we see that's often called
as the universal recipient but if you
see blood the universal donor able to
give blood Hindu bodies and blood
transfusions so looking specifically at
some examples and how these positive
natives can impact someone the arch
factors another group of antigens found
on red blood cells over Thersites Rh
positive people have them means they're
positively their Rh negative people
don't have the Rh factor it's a
particularly salient when an Rh negative
mother gives
first to an Rh positive baby the mother
baby exposed to fetal blood and thus
produced anti RH antibodies so this is a
example here again Rh negative mother
gives birth to an Rh positive baby the
mother can actually develop antibodies
to their own of fetus in subsequent Rh
positive pregnancies so that's second
born this can lead to the eraser of last
futilities confirm this would be
prevented by injecting the mother with
anti RH antibodies so it is possible
this have to be aware of this they might
be wondering well why or how can a
mother who's Rh negative give birth to a
baby is Rh positive and that comes down
to what the blood type the father is you
see this indication here and almost I
guess dominant and heterozygous here you
can see some of the possible outcomes
here if the father is positive and the
mother is negative well that all of the
offspring here will be positive you can
see the different combinations here of
what potential their offspring options
could be they kind of put this situation
here in a little pictorial form we're
look at this image here and what we see
going on here if you have our Rh
positive father an arch negative mother
now the mother here is carrying a fetus
that's Rh positive that's because the
blood type came from the father antigens
will develop in the mother and she'll
develop antibodies in response
there's fetal Rh positives now this is
crucial for this particularly the second
Ward because she'll come in contact with
that blood during delivery
as a result she'll develop antibodies
and what it becomes important is if the
mother becomes pregnant with another
child and that child does happen to be
Rh positive well she will now have
antibodies that can cross the placenta
and damage the fetal red blood cells in
the unborn baby so this is why it's
important to be able to understand blood
types of both mother and father but what
the potential would be for the offspring
and what order that child is in the risk
factor that may occur again we have ways
of preventing this from happening but
it's important to be able to recognize
these situations this could occur so
preventive measures can be taken