so in this image we see various shapes
and numbers
indicating the impact angle and the
difference that can have on the shape
so here i'm going to go over the blood
spatter impact angle
develop a little better understanding
and also how to calculate that in some
examples
so first off the impact angle is
important because the blood stain
pattern study can also support
one determining the truthfulness of
reports given by the observer
target or suspect can help support
a potential explanation or can refute a
potential explanation for
what may have occurred at a crime scene
so the angle of impact examples
here's just some here and we can see
that
the 90 degree kind of being that flat
and we're kind of increasing at 80 70 60
50 all the way to like 10 degrees
so with stains that are impacting areas
between 75 and 90 degrees spines and
satellite stains occur
all around the stain and however the
angle of impact
decreases the spines and satellites tend
to become more prevalent on one side of
the same compared to the other
and what we're seeing here in this ins
is a black and white image but you can
see
this tends to be darker on the lower
side that's the gravitational density at
the lower edge that blood's kind of
forming
and collecting a little bit more at that
bottom area there
as the angle of impact decreases below
40 degrees
the steam becomes much more elliptical
and the nature of outflow of the stain
usually produces a single
satellite stain now calculating impact
angle
let's kind of see the basics of it here
you want to identify the width and
length is important
a calculator should be used to calculate
the arc sine now in a circle the width
and the length
a little more arbitrary but here we
could see definitely the length and the
width
definitely are distinctly different it's
width divided by length
and this is the formula so note the
direction
of travel it's a little hard when it's
at 90 degrees
because there is no direction of travel
but it gets a little bit harder as we
you know
looking at an 80 or 70 degree but we
start getting into these you know 10
20 30 um 40s and 50s degrees you can
definitely see
getting that elliptical shape this shows
that
the direction of travel so it's going to
impact here and it's going to travel
in this direction meaning wherever the
tail is located
that is pointing like an arrow with the
direction of
travel there so just kind of a way to
kind of orient yourself
if you're not looking at a broad speed
image you're just looking at an image
you can tell which way the blood was
traveling
now here are the blood spatter impact
angle calculation steps the process that
you want to go through
and again it's the arc sine width
divided by length but you first want to
measure the length and width
of the splatter to divide the width
of the slider by its length so width
over length
and then determine the arc sine of the
number typically using a calculator with
the arc
sine function what you're doing is
you're calculating again
that angle of impact
so here taking those same steps what
impact angle did this blood droplet hit
and
drop it refer to the one here now
because it's on a screen you might be
able to tell i've measured it for you
the
width being 1.5 centimeters and the
length being three
centimeters how do you go about
calculating this
well it'll be the width divided by the
length
and then you take you get that to be 0.5
and then what you're going to do with
that number then is take the arc sine of
that
and you're going to get to be 30 degrees
so this
impacted at a 30 degree angle now if
you're wondering where the arc sign
is on your calculator sometimes it is
referring to that
second function that you need to utilize
so just be aware or learn your
particular calculator
and use this as an example to make sure
you can get the same number
now a sample data set we're looking at
the distance fall in centimeters versus
volume of different
droppers in millimeters and we could see
the distance fallen 10
25 50 100 centimeters and eyedropper
produces 0.032 milliliters
pipette 0.045 and medicine dropper 0.53
so the amount of the volume does impact
the generally the size of the droplet
but if you're keeping the at least that
fairly consistent you can
use it as a source of comparison but
this is just something to keep in mind
when evaluating a
crime scene where you may not know the
volume initially
of blood that fell here's a data set too
finding the angle of impacts that give
you some short axis and long axis
angle of impact on a sketch of the
supplier so how it may look
to try to give you some idea of what
these numbers might equate to or what
they might look like
in an image so with that information
going through now and can you be able to
go through some practice examples
i gave you one but now i'm giving you a
little bit of a data set so give you
five different
blood splatters i want you to find the
angle of impact following the blood
droplet dimensions to give you the
length the width
i want you to determine the angle of
impact measured in degrees
so this would be a great time to pause
the video because my next slide is going
to provide you with the answers
to allow you to check your work
pause the video now hopefully you're
calculating and hopefully on your little
scratch piece of paper you came up with
answers very similar to these um so
you're able to accurately be able to
calculate
the angle of impact given the length and
width of a blood spatter