here we're gonna look at blood
components now if you've ever had blood
drawn and put into a vial you know it's
this kind of dark red liquid maybe think
too oh it transports oxygen there's
actually different components that we're
going to investigate further so you can
develop a greater understanding to the
components that make up blood
all of those composers four major ones
we're going to focus on one is plasma
that's the liquid portion that contains
two South nutrients hormones and gases
and comprised about 55% of the total
blood the red blood cells or over
Thersites they're the ones responsible
for transporting oxygen and also carbon
dioxide white blood cells or leukocytes
are important for the body's immune
system and platelets help the body form
blood clots this is what it will look
like after I centrifuge you can see
there's definitely distinctive yellow
clears to whitest region and in the dark
red portion now blood is the body's only
fluid tissue it's got a metallic taste
it's kind of sticky it goes from a
scarlet red to a dark red never is blood
a blue color
it's pH is kept in a tight range between
seven point three five and seven point
four five it's temperature is slightly
higher than normal body temperature and
it accounts for approximately 8% of the
body's weight for males it's about five
to six liters of blood for a females
about four to five liters that plasmid I
mentioned that kind of a yellow portion
blood plasma contains over a hundred
solutes including proteins non-protein
nitrogen substances organic nutrients
electrolytes and respiratory gases and
is that yellowish kind of color to it so
it contains everything from sodium
potassium glucose lactic acid clotting
proteins oxygen carbon dioxide a whole
bunch is found in blood plasma formed
elements so our birth recites leukocytes
and platelets make up the formed
elements only white blood cells are
complete cells red blood cells actually
have no nuclei or organelles and
platelets are just cell fragments we see
those here most formed elements survive
in the bloodstream only a few days most
blood cells do not divide but are
renewed by cells in the bone marrow
excuse a little kind of compares
and what they kind of look like here the
erythrocytes are the red blood cells 99%
of the blood cellular component thereby
concave discs because this is them a
very high surface area to volume ratio
and very important for the nutrient as
well as gas exchange that there's so
needed to do they're also in a nucleate
betweens a looser nucleus at maturity
and have essentially no organelles their
fill of hemoglobin which is a protein
that functions for gas transport
responsible for the red color and the as
they move through the circulatory system
here they have a special protein that
helps give them flexibility so they're
able to move through the veins and the
arteries quite well and they can change
shape is necessary but they will always
kind of maintain overall that biconcave
disc to allow high surface area to
volume ratio erythrocytes are red blood
cells lifespan they live about four
months iron from hemoglobins recycled in
liver and spleen and the hormone
erythropoietin is made in the kidneys
and it stimulates the production of red
blood cells in the bone marrow one red
blood cell contains about a billion
molecules of oxygen that's some fun
facts here where blood cells take about
twenty seconds to circulate over the
body one time and they circulate for
about a hundred and twenty days there
are millions of red blood cells in one
drop of blood and two to three million
red blood cells are made each second so
I'm not going to go too much into the
details the lifespan but you could see
red blood cells you might be taking for
granted how many there are and the
necessary function that they produce
they said they have about 100 and 120
day lifespan older overthrow sites
become rigid and fragile and their
hemoglobin begins to degenerate both
making them basically non-functional
during the ever Thersites are engulfed
by macrophages that's when they're dying
and they're kind of engulfed and cleaned
up that way heme and globin are
separated and the iron is salvaged for
reuse so the body's not just going to
gulp them and completely break them
apart throw them away it's gonna use
some of the components it's important
remember that red blood cells do not
grow do that divide and do not make any
new protein
myoglobin is a protein found in muscle
cells as you could see here are darker
red meat contains a greater amount of
myoglobin they provide oxygen to active
muscles it's very similar to something
that might be more formal tema globin
and it binds to oxygen tighter than
human globins we see here here's our
pressure in millimeters of mercury and
we see our my level and shoots up very
quickly so by ohms oxygen tighter than a
McGlothlin
we'll notice here are two different
types of hemoglobin HF is referring to
fetal hemoglobin which is a little more
efficient at binding oxygen and adult
hemoglobin here but all perform the same
basic function looking specifically at
hemoglobin is a complex protein made up
of four protein strands these different
peptide chains iron is used to form the
heme groups that's what's responsible
for the oxygen binding because it's a
protein shaped is very important when
you can see pH will also impact the
ability for hemoglobin to be able to
bind oxygen so here 7.4 and ere 7.2
decrease in pH causes a greater release
of oxygen so at seven point four humans
more efficient at binding oxygen than at
page seven point two platelets as I
mentioned our fragments and they do not
contain a nucleus grains and they
basically function for the clotting
purposes so you see this kind of like
web here that forms the mechanism by
forming temporary plug that helps seal
breaks in blood vessels they also play a
key role in the formation of them I've
written in fibrinogen and they're that
responsible for that kind of webbing and
that's what's helping block the chapter
trap the red blood cells in here
preventing continuous bleeding to from
occurring kind of shows a little
pictorial here damaged blood vessel
injury here's our red blood cells
leaving activate the platelets start to
bind and kind of make a little plug here
and then we see our fibrin strands
carrying that netting really kind of
sealing that area off from the red blood
cells escaping as well as from potential
invaders from the outside of the body
getting in to the body in the blood
stream there's two different types of
anemias there
Organic anemia which is the result of
acute or chronic blood loss and both of
these are insufficient red blood cells
for hemoglobin in the body so you could
have that insufficient by just simply
losing a lot of blood or having an iron
deficiency which is a secondary result
of hemorrhage and anemia inadequate
intake of iron containing foods can also
contribute to this an impaired iron
absorption so here we see our normal
levels we have our storage and our
transport then we have an iron depletion
we have iron deficiencies
if iron deficient anemia as we notice
that transporting functional iron
decreases at a much greater rate you can
see the suggested rates four grams per
liter for females and males close
typically needed a little bit more for
males and this is our progressive of
iron depletion this is a much worse case
than here sickle-cell anemia may have
heard of that before it's where red
blood cells basically lose their
biconcave disk shape and causes sickle
shaped and that's a defective gene
encoding for abnormal hemoglobin it's a
single amino acid substitution so you
can see our normal protein being made
here and here's a single amino acid
substitution resulting in a mutant amino
acid causing in a mutant protein its
shape has changed the defect caused red
blood cells have a sickle shape and low
oxygen absorbing qualities and also this
sickle shape does not allow it to free
flow through the veins and arteries as
well lastly we have the blood groups
and is referring to Group A has eight
antigens Group B is B antigens group a B
as a and B antigens in group O has no
antigens this is used for classifying
blood types this is where people may say
they're a B or a B or auto types this
also could be a positive or B positive
that refers to Rh factors which is
stands for rhesus factors there so that
gives you a general overview of the
blood and the different components that
it contains