okay here we're gonna be looking at
blood vessels of the body the picture
here of some blood and also have
something that may initially seem
unrelated which is the Connecticut River
watershed on any watershed really for
example and what this is is we can make
connections between this and the blood
vessels in our own body and see how
there's some similarities and some
differences that do occur so getting
into classes of blood vessels there's
three main classes first cert arteries
and arterials there carry blood away
from the heart veins or venules carry
blood to the heart and in between our
arteries and our veins of this structure
here called the capillary and this
allows for extremes of nutrients wastes
and gases now typically as we see here
the arteries typically may be drawn in
red because they're carrying oxygenated
blood and veins are typically in blue
cuz they're carrying blood away from the
heart deoxygenated blood now even though
we may draw it like this and have nice
red and blue images our blood no matter
where it is in the body will be a shade
of red so don't think that your blood is
automatically turns blue and it's the
afternoon oh it's always a shade of red
continuing on focusing first on our
arteries these are a thick walled and
lined with smooth muscle remember this
is carrying blood away from the heart so
away from the heart arteries think away
the arterioles branch off from that the
expanders each heartbeat and contract a
flow afterwards which is what's helping
the blood move as blood comes from the
heart and large pulses the RT must be
able to expand as a result are really
made up of three walls you see one of
them here also where that smooth muscle
is located arterioles are small diameter
than our arteries they surround their
surrounding muscle air can be relaxed to
enlarge their diameter all of these
specific kind of details about the
artery help move blood from the heart
now arterioles as I mentioned they can
constrict to direct and control blood
flow they may for example increase blood
supply to the skin to allow more heat to
basically the
dispersed in the environment or
constrict during stress to redirect
blood to the heart and muscles so here's
our arterial example and that's leading
and getting closer to our capillaries
now our veins are venules which are a
small structure again on the other side
of the capillary they're thin walled and
they collect blood low pressure in these
manuals allows the capillary beds to
drain into them so again we have our
blood coming this way going through a
capillary first entering our thin walled
venule from there we're going into our
veins
so veins of thin thinner layers of
muscle and elastic fiber or walls and
their arteries when emptying they will
collapse so important a number of some
differences between our arteries and our
veins here contraction of skeletal
muscle helps move blood up the limbs and
back to the heart and also veins contain
valves which prevent plaque backflow of
blood so we see here our blood going
this way and to prevent the backflow of
that blood you see here that valve in
our veins closing up here so blood
cannot go backwards this helps move
blood get it back to the heart so it can
be recirculated throughout the body
Ahri's compared to advanced here's a
nice little direct comparison here
here's our example of our artery because
our example our vein and they said they
share the same internal features but the
walls of the arteries are much thicker
because of the higher pressure they have
to endure is a micrograph comparison
that shows the relative differences in
thickness it's a little harder to tell
in this image here but in the pictorial
here but their labeling it's very easy
to tell that much thinner appearance of
the vein compared to the artery it does
also exist here we have much thicker
artery than our being whose arteries
have to deal with the higher pressure
now with aliens and returning blood to
the heart preventing black flow these
presents of valves there's low pressure
in veins that's important to make note
of we also have skeletal muscles and you
need directional valves so as we see
here pushing moving the blood this way
the valve opens then you see the valve
closing
here preventing that back flow we also
see that here blood flowing this way and
then that valve closing preventing the
backflow see here muscles relaxing the
valve closes and then the muscle
contracts here now we're able to force
and move that blood through there might
be a little hard to tell on this graph
on this picture here but we could see
the names are located in this
distinctive region here capillaries so
this is in between the venules and the
arterioles these are body tissues that
contain a vast network of capillaries
capillaries themselves have very thin
walls and allow blood to pass it's only
one cell fit on cell thick and allowing
these blood vessels to travel through
here once all the time this allows the
exchange of gases such as carbon dioxide
and oxygen also nutrients and waste
through the process of diffusion so it's
important this does not active transport
but this is diffusion capillaries are so
fine that red blood cells must line up
single file to go through them so this
is what's allowing that maximum surface
area as well they get that kind of net
appearance to them there's our
filtration and again the movement of
carbon dioxide and oxygen nutrients and
waste is simply by the non energy
requiring diffusion process continuing
on the capillary network connects the
arteries and the veins individual
capillaries have high resistance to flow
but the total cross sectional areas of
capillaries is greater than those of the
arteries leading to it
so blood loss most of its pressure and
velocities it passes through this vast
capillary network so we have that high
pressure here coming from the heart
through our hey order through our
arteries but a lot of that's being lost
we have to squeeze those blood cells one
at a time through the capillaries before
returning to veins before going back to
the heart blood vessels there's a nice
comparison between our arteries and our
veins kind of putting everything
together showing that you that
comparison of how thick the areas are
which is how thin other veins are
doesn't mean they're necessarily
different diameters as we see here but
we've noticed also the presence of a
valve here in the veins
so veins think about arteries think away
from the heart lastly here's a couple of
major arteries and veins
get into these a little bit more detail
when we focusing down the heart
specifically to our femoral artery is
near our femur so you could see some of
the names here match that of the bones
of the skeleton that they're near keep
in mind our arteries are typically in
red veins are typically represented in
blue even though our blood no matter
where it's located her body is always a
shade of red