okay here we're gonna look at how your
body goes about regulating blood calcium
levels so let's start with homeostasis
what does your body want to maintain
well normal calcium levels are ten
milligrams per dekaliter it's normal
calcium levels so your body's trying to
keep on a very consistent rate despite a
lot of changes so how does your body
regulate this well first off if we have
an increase in our calcium level say
plus ten milligrams per liter nothing at
higher than that the thyroid is gonna
release calcitonin which is going to
cause calcium reabsorption in the
kidneys to decrease which is going to
limit our osteoclast activity and this
ultimately is going to lead to the
calcium levels and blood to decrease
back down to ten so here we're seeing an
above ten we're seeing these chaining of
events that occur reducing the level so
then get it back around ten now the
opposite occurs we have a decrease in
calcium level the parathyroid glands
release PTH which is a hormone this will
cause osteoclasts to release calcium
from bone calcium is reabsorbed from the
urine by the kidneys and calcium
absorption and small intestine increases
v via vitamin D synthesis these three
events will cause calcium levels in the
blood to increase hopefully bringing
that level back up to the ten milligrams
particularly to that your body needs
this is a general overview we look at
this now in a little bit more detail so
this is kind of putting it all together
it's you're trying to maintain
homeostasis there's way to increase it
we want to if calcium levels increase we
want to lower them if they decrease we
want to raise them to help maintain
homeostasis now look at this a little
bit more detail we have blood calcium
concentration dropping so we kind of
have this kind of situation it's
occurring here is this decrease in
calcium level that's initially occurring
now looking to some more detail the body
study this is a PTH which is that
parathyroid gland hormone and that's
being released into the bloodstream
that's causing an effect on the bone it
inhibits the osteoblasts
to missy osteo class bone is broken
releasing calcium ions into the
bloodstream this same hormone now in
addition to the blood also is affecting
the kidneys it's doing the kidneys to
recover wastes calcium doesn't want to
excrete that it wants to take that back
into the bloodstream this is causing
that movement of these ions to help
raise these levels up clear this initial
drop that your body's able to sense in
addition to the bone and the kidneys the
intestines will also be affected
these PTH hormone will also stimulate
the intestines to absorb calcium from
digesting the food this is important
because your body's doing whatever it
can help bring these levels up now
calcium levels will begin to increase
this may cause calcitonin to be released
high concentrations of calcium stimulate
these cells to release calcitonin castle
tone will put calcium into bone so in
this case we had low levels we did these
three different events we've now
increased our blood calcium levels
almost too high now we need to reabsorb
that and store that calcium in the sense
of calcitonin that then will ultimately
release with to the calcitonin in the
bone which is to make the osteoblasts
inhibit the osteoclasts and calcium is
ultimately removed from the blood and
used to build bone and then that can
cause the calcium levels to drop which
will then cause the sequence of events
to occur so just want to understand that
it's very complex and how the body does
regulate in this case just calcium but
there is always a way to in this case
raise our calcium levels and decrease
our calcium levels to help maintain that
very delicate balance we call
homeostasis