sometimes in a molecular biology lab
you'll hear people that you think
are lost and using a compass to try to
find their direction
this is a blotting compass because a lot
of the blots get their
names from cardinal directions so these
are blots
in molecular biology well starting first
with a
southern blot a southern blot is a
sensitive method for detection of a dna
sequence within a mixture the dna is
first cleaved or cut with restriction
enzymes to produce fragments
that can be separated by gel
electrophoresis after electrophoresis
dna fragments are transferred to a
nitrocellulose membrane by capillary
action
creating a replica of the original gel
the membrane is incubated with
a labeled probe which binds to and
detects fragments of interest
so we have our dna we have our gel run
it through we have this transfer step
we have this blotting step and
ultimately what we're left with is what
looks like
lines in a column specifically this is
looking
at dna and this is why it is the
southern blotting technique
in contrast we have the northern
blotting technique
and this is a method for detection of
specific mrna
in a mixture of rnas looking at
specifically messenger rna
and while it looks very similar to the
southern blot we just saw some lines in
a column
this is looking at something very
different however like southern blotting
this method is highly specific and
sensitive
rna from cells and tissues is extracted
and separated by electrophoresis
as in southern blotting rna is
transferred to a nitrocellulose membrane
and incubated with a labeled probe
that is complementary to the rna this
method can be used to
quantitate the transcription of rna
under different cellular conditions so
this is kind of a way to get the sense
of the amount
and you can see kind of the end result
located here for
northern blotting looking at mrna then
there's also
western blotting which again has a very
similar image if you just look at it
but western blotting is a laboratory
method used to detect specific protein
molecules among a mixture of proteins
this mixture can include all of the
proteins associated with a particular
tissue or cell type
western blots can also be used to
evaluate the size of the protein of
interest
and used to measure the the amount of
protein expression that's occurring
this procedure was named similarity to
its previously invented method known as
the
southern blot and that's why it gets the
term the western plot looking at
specific
protein molecules now these three
molecules you can kind of like
these three blind techniques looking at
three different molecules can kind of be
compared here
you kind of get the idea of the southern
blotting in the first column the middle
column being northern
and the last column here being western
black and you can see how there's some
similarities between them
but also some differences the key part
looking at
different identifying markers are
molecules in this case
dna looking at rna and looking at
proteins
now i'm just going to mention here at
the very end some other blots
because those are the major ones but
there is if you're wondering there is an
eastern blot a far
western blot at southwestern reverse
northern blah and a dot blot
as well so all these looking at very
specific things
all different blocks southern northern
and western are by far the most common
eastern bodies used for detection of
post transit train
transitional modifications of proteins
far western is used
uses antibodies to detect the presence
of protein protein complexes
uh this southwestern blot is based off
the southern blot that's where it kind
of gets part of its name from
used to identify characterizing dna
binding proteins
reverse northern blot that differs from
both northern and southern blot and that
the dna is first immobilized in a
blotting matrix
then specific sequences are detected
with labeled rna probes
so you can see we get into some little
bit uh different protocols as far as the
procedures to carry out
and lastly the dot blot is a special
case
of any of the above blocks where it does
um now
analyte these added directly to the
blotting matrix
it appears as dots as opposed to
separating the sample with
electrophoresis prior to blotting
so that's one is a little bit different
the rest definitely
depend heavily on electrophoresis and
separating things out in a gel
before transferring them to another
membrane so again this is just kind of
that basic overview of all the different
types of blots that may
occur uh and hopefully this makes a
little bit more sense and you're not
completely lost
in the kernel directions of molecular
biology