looking specifically at the immune
system our body needs many defenses
because it's under continual attack
bindings to build like a fortress to
help protect itself but this isn't good
enough now it doesn't need to have a
fortress it also needs ways to mobilize
quickly to be able to defend itself also
if something is able to breach the
borders and get by the initial first
response needs a way to be able to hunt
down and destroy those invaders within
our body so looking specifically at a
wonderful video that I can have a
love/hate relationship with personally
it's a great video and has greatly
animation you're welcome to check this
link out however some of the terms they
used to describe that I feel don't go
into as much science as I would like as
a result I provide some key translations
here for example when they use purple
things that stands for virus and if
you're able to watch the video and be
able to at least immensely translate
their terms into what those actual
correspond with regarding the cell then
you probably have developed a good
understanding of what's going on in a
particular video their key part is our
bodies under constant attacks so we need
a way to help protect and maintain
borders and also address invaders that
occur to avoid the body having its
machinery being used for purposes that
do not benefit it so how would you
approach this problem is kind of a
general kind of idea of the immune
system well step one is to secure the
borders kind of have a good strong and
well maintained skin in our case that
physical barrier in addition to that we
want to mobilize quickly to block a
breach this is an example if you get a
cut in your skin you want to be able to
rush some help out to that area to
prevent infection from spreading to the
body
lastly third line of defense is to hunt
down successful invaders for those
microorganisms that are able to
penetrate and get into our body we need
to have a system in place that's able to
seek them out and destroy them this
general summary a little bit more detail
would be the first sign to secure the
borders to is basically to prevent the
problem from occurring in the first
place sometimes an ounce of prevention
prevention is better than a pound of
correction and that's kind of the point
here skin mucous membranes I'll try to
prevent or at least limit the entry of
microorganisms now keep in mind not
every microorganism is completely
harmful we have many that we depend on
but we're looking here at the specific
ones that want to do the body harm
certain pathogens in addition to
securing the borders we need a way to
mobilize quickly to block a breach
painting microbial proteins phagocytic
cells to localize in an invasion and
potentially control it right then and
there we want to repair the border is
the ultimate solution and this is why
our skin will scab over to kind of help
maintain that physical barrier in
addition inflammations the hallmark and
most important mechanism to help lock
and limit the potential spread of
organisms lastly our third line of
defense to hunt down successful invaders
we want to profile the enemy indiana's
takes a little time
catch immobilize and destroy invaders
within the body fluids this identifying
destroying and removing my cells that
are already infected is a time-consuming
process and is where the immune system
needs to take some time and to be able
to clear out those invaders that have
been able to get into our body and
sometimes that's why we're sick for a
couple days and then ideally get better
while this process is occurring