okay here we're investigating body
joints my joints can be used for a high
degree of flexibility or it can be used
to help in sports kind of make different
moves and there's a lot of stress and
strain put on joints in many sporting
events so joints in general well what
the what are they they're articulations
of bone the functions of joints they
hold bones together and they allow for
mobility and ways joints are classified
both on their function and also how they
are structured so you can see here just
a general joint here where I learn more
about the different types also are
joints in the skull here we may not
consider these as being very mobile
because they're not but these
nonetheless are still joints that occur
in the body the structural
classification of joints we have our
fibrous joints which are generally in
movable they appear in our skull region
cartilaginous joints which are removable
or only slightly movable we might have
those found for example the disks of
cartilage that help support our
vertebrae and synovial joints so zones
that are freely movable no the ones we
may think of initially when we think of
a joint now our fibrous joints are
strong connections between bones bones
are united by fibrous tissue and the
reason is they lack a lot of motion
sutures are one example they're not
moving joints of the skull syndesmosis
are where ligaments connect to bones
allowing for minimal movement judges
between the ulna and the radius and
mopus here is the specialized fibrous
joint that anchors a tooth to its socket
in the jaw so all these are examples of
fibrous joints here these fibrous joints
are really strong connections and allow
for potentially some movement but not a
lot or high degree of movement very
minimal in the amount they can move
cartilaginous joints are examples are
bones connected with Highland cartilage
symphysis here is compressible fibro
cartilages pads connecting to bones
allowing for some movement so of our
minimal movement between bones in this
case we're having a padding that's
occurring that's why there's cartilage
present there and that's why it's
considered a joint but not a lot of
movement between those simcha does this
are immovable cartilaginous joints that
can be found at the end of long bones
this allows bones to grow in length in
the pubic portions of the right and left
hip bones of the pelvis are joined
together by this a fibrocartilage and
this area here remember we want to
identify a male or a female we could we
look typically in this region to be able
to do so our synovial joints I said
probably the ones we may consider most
as joints and the articulating bones are
separated by a joint and cavity
bone surfaces are protected by articular
cartilage and synovial joints are found
in the joint cavity there are six main
different types all present here I like
about this picture is not only does it
show you all the joints it also shows
where you can find those on the body I
want to present these three at a time
so those synovial joints the general
structure of them they have cartilage
they have that synovial cavity they have
the articular capsule the synovial fluid
and reinforcing ligaments these joints
in which articulating bones are
separated by fluid joint cavity so the
reason why we want this joint containing
fluid is it helps create a nice
lubricating barrier surface between the
two bones
we don't have bone on bone contact this
fluid allows for ease of movement
between these two articulating bones so
again looking at some of the joints here
we have pivot joints which provides
rotation at the top of the spine the
atlas in the axis remember the yes-no
the c1 c2 vertebrae they are actually
portions of a pivot joint the hinge
joints move on just one axis in the
joints allow for flexion and extension
major hindrance include the elbow and
also our finger joint these are examples
of hinge joints Saladin's are for
flexion and extension and other
movements but no
rotation in the hand that thun that
saddle joint between the first
metacarpal and the trap attracts easier
let's the thumb cross over the palm
making it opposable so opposable thumb
would be an example there and that's
called a saddle joint plane joints move
against each other in a single plane and
we see that indicated here speaking an
example on the body would be between the
tarsal bones also major gliding joints
include the in vertical joints of the
bones of the wrist in the ankles
remember our ankles share less similares
with our wrists the condyloid joints
allow for circular motion flexed on an
extension
these are restraints between the radius
and the carpal bone so in this specific
region right here we have that example
of that circular motion that occurs the
ball and socket joint is a freely
movable joint that can rotate and any
access example that here would be our
hip joint the top portion of our femur
articulating with our hip bone now talk
about guys talk about cracking your
knuckles so what causes our knuckles to
pop you can go through and watch some of
these videos and help understand a
little bit about what's actually going
on with when we crack our knuckles