okay here we're gonna look at Bohr
atomic structures and how to depict and
draw out what's called a Bohr model of
the atom developed by Niels Bohr well
first off the Bohr model what is that
it's basically a simplified visual
representation of an atomic structure
assumes that electrons represented with
the e minus sign here move in fixed
orbits each of those orbits is
represents an energy level around the
nucleus we see that here here's our
nucleus these are energy level 1 mg
level 2 3 4 5 &amp; 6
now electrons have to exist in one
energy level or the other they cannot be
in between so again the reason why I
have the picture here of the elevator is
you can only go to certain levels you
can't go to like 1/2 level just like
electrons can't be at level two and a
half or two and a quarter
that's B 2 or 3 3 or 4 so 4 or 1 has to
be at very distinctive energy levels now
how would go about drawing the Bohr
model is we have some simple rules to
follow so looking at here we want to
draw the nucleus making sure to write
down the number of neutrons and protons
in the center region here after that
step 2 is going to be to look at drawing
a circle or an orbit around the nucleus
to represent the first energy level as
you see here now energy level 1 can hold
a maximum of 2 electrons
Marisa's located closest to the nucleus
level 2 no maximum 8 3 is 18 4 is 32
we're gonna focus mainly on the simpler
elements here to get an understanding
after you draw that circle around the
nucleus representing the first energy
level both go through and electron
should be drawn in pairs to make them
easy to count and must fill an energy
level before moving to the next so after
you have two electrons filled up in the
first energy level then you can move to
this second after the second you
can move to the third and then so on and
so forth so look at just a couple
examples here of periodic patterns
looking at Group 1 through 14 17 and 18
group 1 see the red is representing the
outermost shell or the valence electrons
in Group 1 each one of these has 1
valence
electron what we do notice is that
lithium here with its three electrons to
fill up the first energy level and then
one more it goes on the second energy
level with na or sodium - in that first
energy level we see one two three four
five six seven eight in the second
energy level in that third energy level
we have one more so that one is the one
valence electron now how do I know
sodium has these eleven electrons
oh if - here plus eight which is nine
ten eleven there's eleven protons so in
a neutral atom is going to be 11
electrons the same thing goes here for
fluorine neon and argon we're filling up
that first in G level progressing to the
second before with no under the third if
we have electron here meaning so take a
look at couple these models develop kind
of an understanding those how it is it's
relatively easy and I want you to go
through and look at some of these
examples and try them for yourself so
hydrogen phosphorous helium neon and
lithium so pause the video now and try
them for yourself my students are
pausing the video I don't know if
they're pausing the video on that mmm
hopefully there and okay so hopefully
you've gone through and you've taken
those steps and now we have a way to
check your answers so hopefully the
answers that you came up with they do
drew out on the Bohr models looks
similar to these if they don't go back
try to let them try to watch and
understand why they don't if not can
always email me or ask me for questions
and clarifications but hopefully this
develops a better idea of understanding
the Bohr model via via