a hermit tempt to simplify the process
of bone growth and remodeling and see
how this interval aids with the process
of our growing skeleton the stream with
bone growth bones are remodeled in
lengthen until grow stops bones change
shaped a little bit depending on the
conditions that they may face and bones
also need to grow in width as we
progress from the embryo to the fetus to
a child ultimately the adult stage we
see at the embryonic stage we have a
high amount of cartilage present within
the bones and over time we see an
increase in the replacing of that
cartilage with more of this ossification
region in this newly forming bone that
is newly forming bone is occurring and
helping the length of the bone and also
the width of the bone to help support
the increased weight cartilage will
still be left even in adults it's a very
ends basically the head regions of the
bones when a bone needs to articulate
with another bone to create a smooth
surface so this ossification process
this is the formation of bone we have
this high amount of cartilage and slowly
being replaced with this spongy bone
here this de-emphasis region remember
that's the long portion of the long bone
and that's what's increasing remember
this contains our marrow we're talking a
very young individual but gain a lot of
red bone marrow and as we age that red
bone marrow will slowly be replaced with
yellow bone marrow as we pose mostly a
fat and adult we're considering at the
age of 25 because nearly all the bones
are completely ossified in humans by the
age of 25 now bone gross-looking
specifically an x-ray here but 12 year
old child showing the growth plates and
these plates these growth plates these
piphus steel plates are the regions that
are actually growing the new cartilage
is continuously formed older Carlos
becomes ossified remember the
ossification process is basically
forming that College into bone Carla is
broken down and bone replaces that
cartilage over time
this is a femur again this is our thigh
bone one of our longest of long long
bones there and the mature long bone see
in comparison to that growing long bone
we see the diathesis reaching its full
length there the other regions are
maintaining very similar shapes may be
increasing in width depending on the age
spread of this individual but the key
part here is that diathesis is
increasing in length now long bone
growth in remodeling will growth in
length the college continually grows
interview placed by bone as shown so we
have cartilage growing right here you're
in here the college is replaced by bone
at this distinctive lie the college
grows in this region here and the
cartilage is replaced by bone in this
more central portion of the of the long
bone here
so this growth occurs in length because
we're replacing this College through the
ossification process with bone causing
that bone to grow in its length so what
is remodeling then well remodeling is
growing shaft is remodeled in relation
to conditions or stresses that this bone
may be under so we have our bone being
reabsorbed in this region bone is added
by the appositional growth here and bone
is being reabsorbed here we're
remodeling we're slightly changing the
shape of the bone now this remodeling is
actually can be regulated under two
different control mechanisms want to be
hormonal which maintains calcium
homeostasis in the blood and another
could be mechanical or gravitational
forces acting on the skeleton we learn
about these a little bit later in this
presentation but keep in mind that our
remodeling is actually under two
different uncontrolled herbs now the
structure of short irregular and flat
bones these are a little different
choosing to compare these initially here
thin plates of compact bone which is
right here and the outside of spongy
bone and the dipole on the inside they
have no deficits or ethicists here they
contain
the bone marrow betaine the bhikkhu i
the trabeculae are kind of these
structures that give this bone is kind
of spongy look our in infants it's found
in the medullary cavity the areas of
along spongy bone are red bone marrow
remember in adults found in the dipole
of flat bones in the head of the femur
and also the humerus as we age that red
bone marrows being replaced with yellow
bone marrow but it's still very
important that as adults we have red
bone marrow to generate this necessary
cells we need for the circulatory system
importance of ionic calcium in the body
costumes necessary for many things
transmission of nerve impulses muscle
contraction blood coagulation secretion
by glands and nerves and cell division
so it's very important that we maintain
a distinct amount of calcium in our body
more than just four bones wall bones
themselves yes do composed about 99
percent of the total calcium in our body
that other 1% also has very important
functions in the body in class we looked
at read this article so calcium intake
calcium bioavailability and bone health
discuss the bioavailability of calcium
the impact that has on the body so just
because you're consuming the right
amount of calcium that calcium is not
bioavailable that can impact the overall
health of the individual I talked about
this kind of regulating calcium levels
where there's two different ways there's
a hormonal mechanism we're raising blood
calcium levels triggers the thyroid to
raise calcitonin calcitonin still is
calcium salt deposits in bone so here
we're adding an increase in calcium
level trying to get back to the normal
we are activating this calcitonin think
of calcitonin is putting calcium in the
stomach's calcium deposits in bone
calcium levels are being brought into
the bone meaning they're being reduced
at the circulatory system level and
we're returning to that normal level so
here we have a normal level we're
increasing it we're releasing calcitonin
put in the calcium in being reabsorbed
into the bones and this is what's
decreasing the calcium levels in the
blood causing it to reach a normal level
we have to keep in mind we have to also
worry about the other side of things if
calcium levels drop
so if we have falling calcium levels
this can signal this glands to release
this Oracle PTH this is released
osteoclast release calcium from the bone
calcium is reabsorbed from the urine and
kidneys this is increased mer calcium
levels and getting them back to the
normal so keep in mind if we even those
have decreasing calcium levels we're
gonna have osteoclasts release calcium
breakdown calcium from the bone to
maintain this very vital 1% in our
circulatory system in addition to the
hormonal conditions we also have
mechanical stresses Wolf's laws of bone
grows or remodels in response to forces
or demands placed upon it long bones are
thickest midway through the shaft where
bending stresses greatest curved bones
are thickest where they're most likely
to buckle it's just some compression and
tension lines remember compression
forces are what we push something
together in tension would be pulling
something apart here common if you've
ever researched stresses on bridges your
bones are going through that same thing
and this mechanical stress can cause
bones to be remodeled in a way where
they're strengthening the weakest part
on them the trabeculae remember form
along the lines of stress is this kind
of webbing material here large bony
projections occur where heavy active
muscles attach so keep in mind on the
ways to move these the muscles it points
to attachment that's also going to be an
area where we're having this increased
responses mechanical stress so the
forces that are applied we want to make
sure our bones are nice strong and
healthy and they can remodel or
strengthen areas potential weakness to
reduce the chance of the buckling
breaking or even fracturing