in this video on debacle university you
will learn
how to use bone analysis to determine
age how we can use simply looking at the
bone to determine the age
of the individual so first off
in the matrix bone cells are surrounded
by a matrix which is a non-living
hardened material
which they produce this matrix is
composed mainly of calcium
and phosphorus compounds along with
proteins that make bone hard
and slightly flexible while still
maintaining a very strong
structure because it is supporting the
entire body
in this case it needs to be hard but it
does have
a slight degree of flexibility to it we
always think of it containing calcium
which it does but we
also contains high amounts of phosphorus
for the body
the liculi are those are microscopic
canals between
the leukemia and the ossified bone
so when we're looking at a microscopic
view of the
bone here we can start to see some of
these structures
we have this kind of cementing line
evident here the osteons
liqueur kind of those little canals we
see here
and then the leukemia are located right
here
and this can be important when we're
looking through a microscope
to be use these to be identified the age
of that individual
when we're looking at these bone cells
keep in mind that we do have bone that's
constantly being
reformed and it's constantly being
broken down no matter
your age the age of the individual will
influence the rate that this occurs
we have the osteocyte which remains a
bone tissue with the osteoblast which
forms the actual matrix that i talked
about
the osteogenic cell which is the stem
cell kind of that early on cell that's
going through and
forming many of the rest in the
osteoclast which is reabsorbing a bone
material and all these are kind of
occurring ideally in a nice
balance for the individual the histology
or looking kind of at the microscopic
view
of compact bone just to kind of give you
that this is looking at 10x
of ground bone here uh what it can look
like and kind of what we're
focusing on the ovarian uh uh the
parish xi'an canal is what we're going
to be looking at here we could see
looking at this
bone here it gets a little confusing but
looking at
his varying system here we can really
focus in on that
and this is the area within a field of
view that we're going to be
looking at so to determine that
approximate age of the individual
looking at the number of osteons present
in bone sample taking measurements of
the
variance canals diameters can also be
useful
we use this information to calculate the
estimated age of the bone sample
ideally at the time of death here and
that can be used on a skeleton
that we may not know the height
individual may know very little about it
this is looking at that very small we
don't need a very small portion of that
bone bone fragment
to heal to determine the age looking at
the image right below me here looking at
an x-ray of the hand of a
16.27 year old male with an automatic
calculation of bone age with
the bone expert it's kind of puts uh
some measurements there puts some kind
of calculations and puts it into an
algorithm and generates an estimated age
based on a simple x-ray
now these osteons that i had mentioned
they're thin and long
cylindrical structures that contain
mineral matrix
and living osteocytes connected to the
liculi which transports blood these are
solid portions of the bone run its
length and
easily viewed with a microscope which is
why they tend to be used
as part of this calculation process so
you can see them kind of
represented in the cartoon image here
but on the other images you can see them
quite clearly
when we're looking at that microscope
what are we looking at we're going to be
counting the osteons
i want to use the bone specimen so it
completely fills a medium power or
100 x field of view count the total
number of aseans present in the entire
medium power field
now keep in mind the median power
objective lens here
would be 10 because we also have to take
into account
the microscope we're using not just the
objective lens here
so how do we go about that we'll keep in
mind we want the objective but we also
want to take into account
the eyepiece as well typically you're
looking at
the ips adding about 10x to that so in
that case where i want median power
looking
at 100x while the objective is 10
because the eyepiece adds another factor
of 10
that would be how we would get to 100x
if we use high power 400x that would be
the 40 times
10 would give you 400. this is going to
determine the number of aseans present
by using the
variance canals present if only half of
a canal is visible then you count it as
a 0.5 or half an osteon rarely move the
sample to 10 new locations and repeat
the process to get your
data i'll then calculate the average
number of osteons viewed under the high
power
to the hundredths place this is again
another way you can go through and do
this is multi and go
and do 10 samples lastly i want to
multiply the average by 16 to generate
the total number of aseans counted under
median power
which is needed for the age calculation
formula
so you can use the high power you just
take more samples and multiply it by a
factor of 16.
how you're going to use this information
and what does it look like
well the center of each osteon is a
hollow tube called that varian
canal there it contains small blood
vessels that's kind of what you're
looking at
that kind of center region there that's
where ideally the blood vessels would be
present
in the individual now the diameter of
that canal
region easiest way to calculate the
diameter is to use the pointer found in
the microscope
so that kind of pointer there and
depends on the microscope you're using
but that pointer sometimes will even
have a measurement you can also place a
fine scale ruler under the microscope to
calibrate the length of that pointer for
the make script that you're particularly
using
note the modification will alter the
scale so make sure your calibration and
magnification are the same
recommend using typically 400x which is
high power is recommended
measure seven random canals not the
entire osteon under high power
using micrometers and note that 0.1
centimeters is one
millimeter and that equals a thousand
micrometers
and then you want to calculate the
average variance uh canal
diameter here that kind of gives you an
idea of that
increased magnification how that's going
to alter your scale
so kind of when we get to the end here
how do we kind of apply that formula
for age calculation procedure well we
take 30
we add it to the total number of us and
count in the entire 100x field of view
times 0.8
and we subtract it by the 0.3 times the
average of
varying canal diameter in micrometers
we take that those numbers and that will
give us the
approximate age of the individual by
plus or minus three years
so if you go back and kind of look at
the information presented here
uh get a a couple of bone slides look
under the microscope
get the calibration used to the
microscope that you're using
and you could kind of go through and do
this activity
to be able to determine the age of the
individual bone that you're looking at
plus or minus three years which is very
good for
getting a general classification of that
age of the individual can definitely
help the investigation
process