okay here I'm gonna go over different
types of bone fractures that either you
may have experienced or no sadly no a
friend has experienced now someone may
say they fractured their bone well
there's a lot of different types of
fractures and if you've know someone
that has a fracture may be able to ask
them more specifically what fracture
that they have or if they describe how
their bone was broken you may be able to
identify exactly what type of fracture
they have after the completion of this
video lecture so starting with bone
fractures in general brown patch here is
simply a breaking a bone now there's
different types of fractures two main
classifications are closed or simple
fractures and these are breaks in the
bone that do not penetrate the skin
another type is called an open or
compound fracture this is where the
broken bone penetrate through the skin
and do not worry I won't show any images
of this one in particular bone fractures
are treated by reduction and in
mobilization and this allows the
realignment of the bone now the period
of time that someone may stay in a cast
could depend on the type of fracture
that they have and also the age of the
individual and impact the duration that
they keep this hard cast on to allow for
that realignment to take place now some
different types of common fractures here
commutated one is where the bone
fragments into three or more pieces this
is commonly in the elderly the elderly
to have more brittle bones and as a
result they tend to split more into more
pieces now what I've tried to do with
each of these to provide a picture to
kind of help you remember what type of
fracture is occurring it with the bones
and hopefully they find them a little
bit helpful another type of fracture is
called a compression fracture bonus
crushed like the strong metal weight of
the hammer here it's common in phones
that are very porous the vertebral
column our vertebrae are very porous and
as a result they are subject to being
crushed a little hard to see on the
x-ray we can see this vertebral column
is a vertebra in this vertical column is
definitely crushed or smaller not quite
as
as the one below it against be very
painful but these porous bones are
subject to compression type fractures
addition to that we also have us a
spiral which is a ragged break when the
bone is excessively twisted common in
sports injury of that have stopped and
pivot and get that twisting action
that's occurring I can cause a fracture
here of the bone shown by the rope here
the esophageal which is the Ephesus
separates from the diathesis along the
esophageal line this occurs where
cartilage cells are dying
you can see an image here again not very
pleasant even on the x-ray as you can
see the reason why it tends to occur
here is this is where the calcification
tends to occur this matrix is occurring
and that growth plate is located in this
region we'd have the picture of the
chainsaw cutting as we have that kind of
that almost a clear and distinctive
separation amongst the bones here at
that plate there so again not a very
pleasant experience that's kind of
what's happening with this type of
fracture other types of fractures we
have a depressed fracture which is
broken bone portion is pressed inward
typical skull fracture it can be very
dangerous especially with pressure on
the brain or potential for bleeding but
this depressed fracture like the Apple
in the VCR is where the broken portion
of the bone is being pushed inward in
this case the other one here is called
greenstick this is an incomplete
fracture or one side of the bone breaks
in the other side bends very common in
children because they'd have more
flexible bones than those of adults rita
cults greenstick is it's refers to kind
of a green twig of a tree tends to have
this kind of break see it's pictured
here this is in the winter tends to be a
little more common in the winter where
we may have a snow load we see here we
have a one side of the bone breaking
inside the wood portion of the trunk
breaking and the other side bending miss
referred to as a green stick and more
common in children than adults who have
completely ossified bones putting those
common fractures together and a nice
kind
table here I can start to add a
comparison and can you if you saw a
picture of one could you identify it
they gave you the word of one could you
be able to draw a sketch or identify
what's going on if someone identifies
that they have for example a green stick
type of fracture so again review these
go back to some of the pictures and
hopefully find that helpful lastly I
want to go orders how the body repairs
it's a bone fracture which is important
so this blood filled swelling is formed
initially hematoma so he needs referring
to blood tome is that blood filled
swelling is initially formed where that
fracture occurred the break is splinted
by fibrocartilage
on both the internal and external sides
to form a callus region then this
cartilage callus is replaced by a bony
callus slowly over time and this is why
we need to have our bones in a cast to
kind of hold everything in place
lastly the bone the bodhi callus is
remodeled to form a permanent patch now
almost the area where that initial break
or fracture occurred is actually a
little bit thicker than it was
originally so the body will actually
rebuild and repair that bone area
because it was an initial point of
weakness the bony callus is actually
going to make it slightly stronger in
that region however keep in mind that
you can break bone twice because if that
seam area is applied with the same
amount of force it was originally well
that initial site the fracture is
strengthened both regions on the other
side are now weaker in relation to that
same callus it formed so keep in mind we
want to try to avoid fractures but if
you do get one or know a friend or
someone that has one hopefully this
lecture helped you more appropriately
identify what is actually going on with
their particular bones and how they were
damaged