here we look at the plant hormone group
breast no steroids this is one general
category that there's may not fall under
this so I'm gonna speak in generalities
here so Bosco steroids are groups of
some 40 different steroids that are
synthesized by plants and our potent
horns affecting many aspects of cramp
plant growth again there's 40 of them
this is just speaking to what this
general category does these hormones act
synergistically or at least additively
with several other hormones such as oxen
and gibberellins for example however
what's unique about these breasts no
steroids is if they're far more
important pulley than other hormones
they act in far lower concentrations
than the others so while all hormones
act in very small amounts
these can AskMe even smaller amounts to
get the same effect in the end that's an
example why of the Hot Sauce here I
think of them being very concentrated
and a little amount of these can go a
long way and having a plant effect so
what do they do though they promote cell
expansion and cell elongation and they
work with oxen to be accomplished that
they also promote vascular
differentiation which is an example here
where we see xylem and phloem is the
smaller areas here these rasmus steroids
are involved with that separation in
specialization of our xylem the large
Rowling's here and the phloem the
smaller ones here this is important for
the vascular system of the plant they're
also for evolved with tall and
elongation and for pollen tube formation
so very important in the plants ability
to potentially have a successful
pollination process in addition they
have the ability to improve the quantity
and quality of horticultural crops
protect plants against many
environmental stresses so advancements
are using these the hope is that these
brass ana steroids these be ours in the
production of horticultural crops become
a more practical and hopeful strategy
for improving crop yields and success
what does that mean well under normal
conditions if we have a stressor that's
going to reduce the plant performance
however potentially with the use of this
particular hormone we could still have
those stressors and increase the
performance of the plant this is why
they've gained popularity due to the
ever increasing amounts of
environmental stresses plants are under
and the ever demands by growers to
maintain consistent plant performance in
yield and these forms could be one way
to help mitigate the negative impacts of
stressors to plants