okay here we're gonna investigate
different breeding patterns for
different animals and how they go about
conceiving to carry on to the next
generation so starting with this
variation in reproduction among
vertebrates species and also in
vertebrates as we see here with our
grasshoppers
so vertebrates are sexual reproduction
variation most marine bony fish whose
external fertilization and this is where
male and female gametes are released
into the water where fertilization can
occur so this is where we have our
female fish here and our male here is
the large hook jaw here they can tell
the difference these salmon will go into
very shallow water and the female will
release eggs in this gravel and the male
will then release the sperm on top of
that most other Brits use with these
grasshoppers do if it's internal
fertilization where the male gametes are
introduced into the female reproductive
tract specifically this is very specific
versus here there's many many eggs
produced in the hopes that some will be
able to come fertilize and some will
make it in the wild
sadly these salmon then will die shortly
after spawning and that's kind of a good
thing because believe it or not these
small fry or these small fish will feed
off the dead sam and so that they can
have initial sources of nutrients in
areas that are typically very low in
nutrients now looking at the mammalian
species and breeding patterns some are
seasonal breeders
oh there's every productive cycles so
reproductive cycles are periods of
release of mature ovum or basically
mature egg most female mammals have
estrus cycles these were females are
sexually receptive to males only around
a certain time of ovulation this is
typically when dogs are in heat this is
when those females are ready basically
for mating other examples we have quail
which are we call long day breeders and
sheep which are short day breeders so
some are very seasonally influenced in
the versus the winter versus the summer
months this is why and certain animals
can be very well predicted when they're
going to give a litter or give rise to
young they have these very
distinctive cycles and the females are
only receptive to the male's at that
time I will also have for apes and
humans females have what we call
menstrual cycles is where females will
bleed or shed inner lining of the uterus
they can calculate which means to have
sex at any time during there's their
cycle and we see the evidence here of
that cycle that does occur and we have
that releasing of the egg and in that
period of ovulation which is very small
who knows there's a lot of hormone
changes that do occur in the sense of
the body temperature is also altering
and this is helping the women is to
conceive to create a favorable
environment for that egg to become
fertilized and mature into a zygote the
last part here cats and rabbits are
unique they're what's called induced
ovulate errs and they a valley after
copulation due to LH secretion and
Ellie's just a hormone here we can see
that surge that's occurred this is what
allows cats and rabbits to kind of
multiply so quickly is that they ovulate
only after they have sex essentially
this allows them to breed at a very
rapid rate on them to populate areas
very quickly