an important part with the production of
cannabis and the end flowers here is
blood trimming taking the raw plant
product trimming it down to produce just
the fine nug or bud here at the very end
you can see here it's a very convenient
way our intensive process and take a lot
of time and this is for the manual
version so this is how many people get
an entry-level position in the cannabis
industry there bud trimmers for them
sheer selection is very important there
are some qualities you should look for
such as the size of the blades that are
used in the weight of the actual
scissors that you're using quality
equipment should be have non-stick
blades should have an ergonomic handle
and be lightweight because typically
this is is this a very labor intensive
and takes a lot of time but apart it
comes down to personal preference some
people may prefer the straight blades as
I should have shown here some a
preferred angle blades again that comes
down to personal preference but nonstick
blades a lightweight and kind of
something that's comfortable in your
hand are all things that you should be
looking for
there's also automated systems that
trommel system very common large
operations may hear the name twister to
name brand that's a one that makes a
very large scale trommel style pruners
and cutters that basically take raw
plant material and cut it down here to
the initial form of buds however just
because this is automated doesn't mean
that there isn't a need for QC or
quality control as a result automated
systems can get expensive and require
specific set of parameters so just the
angle and the feed rate and running of
those takes sometimes a little while to
get dialed in to work properly there is
a need for continual flow of blood so
high value material is required with
these automated systems you may still
need human eyes and hands to provide
some quality control do some last
trimming of things that got missed
typically its removal of crow's feet
which are the small leaves at the base
of the bud that the trommel may miss in
some cases she's one of the extra set of
eyes to go through so you can ensure at
the end you're sending out a quality and
consistent product