here we're going to investigate bulk
transport so the reason I have this
image of a large tanker ship is this is
moving a large quantity of materials and
we're gonna relate this to cells in
biology and how do cells move large
quantities of material in and throughout
their environments so this might sound
familiar a bulk transport involves these
vesicles small particles or groups of
molecules to enter or leave the cell
without actually passing through the
membrane it's containing them to
mechanisms of bulk transport our
endocytosis and exocytosis
so endo is taking something in
exocytosis is something is leaving or
exiting the cell so bulk transport is
the transport large particles and
macromolecules across the plasma
membrane our endocytosis has three
different types our exercisers this has
one major type so endocytosis is
receptor mediated endocytosis and
phagocytosis
so phagocytosis is cell eating in this
case we have the engulfing of objects
this happens in our immune system quite
a bit here we have a neutrophil which is
a white blood cell chasing down and
attacking this bacteria it's not eating
any of the red blood cells these round
kind of round looking cells here because
it's recognizing those itself it's
recognizing this small little bacteria
as an invader and that's why it's
chasing it down and ultimately engulfing
yet there it would engulf it bind to it
and Gulf it and then use what lysosomes
which contain digestive enzymes they'll
break it down to basically soluble
debris that's nothing to harm the cell
pinocytosis is it cell drinking and
ism's drink extracellular fluid it's
binding the substances and it's pinching
off and it's taking in typically ions
with a lot of water so pinocytosis is
kind of pinching here the membranes and
create the vesicle it's collecting
extracellular fluid typically ions along
with water
receptor-mediated endocytosis this is
the most efficient form its receptors on
the actual exterior surface of the cell
membrane that bind to target molecules
specific target molecules their circles
and they carry ligands and receptors
into the cell so here we have a receptor
it's binding only to one's very specific
thing that one very specific thing
doesn't matter what else is around the
cell
that's what's buying tuna too it's
collecting it's essentially what's
accumulating so this receptor media is
important because it's this cells way of
being able to bind to and collect only
one specific substance so just rambling
grabbing things it's able to bind
something very specific the opposite
process of all this it says exocytosis
it's the reverse of endocytosis instead
of taking something in it is removing or
something and this could be waste
something as an excess amount of
something that another cell may need it
could be a signal so exocytosis I don't
want you always to think of wastes even
though that's typically what's
associated with but it could be other
valuable signals to get out into the
extracellular fluid so that cells around
it can be how that signal and that's one
way of communication between cells
the last part here the thyroid hormones
synthesis process it's very complex
however you should be understand the
circled items here and I circled em in
blue here some of these take you back to
some other video lectures such as
organelles with the nucleus and
reticulum are symporters what those are
about endocytosis what is that in
exocytosis so this is kind of a good way
to kind of make sure you're able to kind
of put all the pieces together from the
series of videos that i have created are
you all going to go back and look at
some of those if you're and there were
some of these terms so that you're able
now to start to understand a little bit
more of some of the processes that occur
as you can see here just thyroid
hormones very complex and they
understand all the parts but it should
be at ease
understand some of the aspects that are
going on here to help you speak into
understand the larger process