so here i'm going to go over bullet
analysis because typically this may be
found at the crime scene
and how do you go about analyzing this
and what do you kind of look for in the
bullet
and also i'll cover the cartridge just
for a little bit because there are some
similar markings
so first off the bullet anatomy is
important to understand
first off the bullet remembers the
actual projectile
so it's actually the point that's being
fired the case is the holding container
the powder the charge is the source of
the explosion energy the primer is the
igniter that's
the initiates the whole the process the
wad for shotgun shells is a plastic
separator between the pellets and the
powder
we see that located here note this is
present in shotgun shell blanks and
could potentially be deadly at close
range
so even if you have a shotgun shell
blank meaning it doesn't contain any
bullets
the water that plastic portion does come
out of the barrel with quite some force
if you're in close range that can be
deadly so don't think again that a
shotgun shell blink
is necessarily not deadly that wad can
definitely
um if it impacts someone can definitely
cause death
now the rifling so we're talking about a
bullet we want to be thinking about the
rifling of the barrel that it's
traveling through so in firearms that
rifling is that helical kind of grooves
that are machined in the inter
interior or bore surface of the gun's
barrel
so we see the barrel here we see a cut
away a nice little cut away
located right over here you can see that
rifling that rifling causes the bullet
to spin the projectile around the
longitudinal axis during
shooting to help it stabilize it's kind
of like throwing a spiral on a football
but when it goes through this kind of
travels here at a very high rated speed
it is spinning
there is going to be some markings that
do occur
so looking at gun barrel rifling well
traditionally sharpens
lands in grooves are replaced by less
pronounced hills and valleys so the
barrel bore has a
kind of polygonal or hexagonal or
octagonal cross
section profile we kind of see here
eight conventional groove rifling on the
left
and octagonal piling rifling on the
right so there are some slight
differences
that can occur but these differences if
you know how to
look and identify them can help you
correlate or match
up the potential barrel that was fired
from that bullet traveled through
there's also something called glock
rifling which is
a some weapons glock pistols is just a
name brand
do not make usable striation patterns on
fire bullets because they use that
polygonal rifling instead of the
conventional rifling
so one group of eight consecutive
matching strike in
agreement would be considered a match
matching evidence
for tool marks for this type of rifling
basically you're going to have a little
different
pattern that's going to be developing
because of the type
of bore that this rifling kind of has
so it's going to be a little different
set of rules or build different ways to
be able to match those
bullets up to that particular barrel
now the firing pin and ejection mark so
again i know we're getting a little bit
away from the bullet here
but you find the bullet you find the gun
you could find the casing as well
the valk of that cartridge so the firing
pin
here in little and where a is pointing
to that leaves an impression when it
strikes the primer it's kind of the
hammer point
uh which strikes the casing cakerges in
the rim
and of rim fired cartridges so this
would be again a center-fired
uh casing here um cartridge so this
would be important to kind of identify
if it was rim fired
it'd be off to the side now you might be
looking at b saying well
why is it if it's the center fire
advisor marking here
well b is referring to the ejection mark
they're called when the cartridges are
ejected from the firearm and can be used
to confirm passage
through the firearm if found at the
crime scene
we also have chamber marks so these are
found throughout the outer side
of the casing and are the result of
regulars inside the wall so the firing
chamber
so again these are just some different
patterns that you might see in the
actual casing
so keep in mind the bullet's going to
have marks that's great place to look
but also do not forget about looking at
the actual casing as well for different
marks
they have breech face marks this is
where there's kind of bold face
signature where that end kind of comes
in contact after
when the explosion occurs and when the
firearm is discharged this
kind of rearward movement or recoils
result of the pressure being generated
in the bullet
going up the barrel but this is coming
back and you can see there's also some
distinctive patterns that can be left
this action at the base of the cartridge
will hit the breach of the firearm
leaving a mark that can be categorized
this can again help you match up
the potential firearm that fired on that
bullet or that in this case
this particular casing looking
specifically at the bullet there'll be
striations
i mentioned that rifling in the barrel
there's going to be striations left on
that bullet
this acts as the gun's fingerprint even
the same macon model of firearm will
produce distinct
striations this pattern will typically
hold true even over time
so it's really important that when you
recover the bullet you don't do a lot of
physical damage to it
because these very distinctive
striations are kind of like the
fingerprint
to that gun as i mentioned those lands
and grooves those will lead to the
rifling
so it's important that the lands are the
raised portions between the grooves
inside the barrel after the spiral
grooves cut into
and produce the rifling now exactly how
they're oriented or how they're tilted
can tell you if it's a right twist or a
left twist
of that bullet which again can help you
match up the potential barrel or
firearm to the bullet that it was fired
from
these unique characteristics so the
number of lands in groups usually four
to six but can range from two to twenty
two
just the number can help you again match
them up
the diameter of the lens and grooves is
something you wanna look at the
width of the lens the depth of the lens
and grooves a degree of the twist
the number twist is the number of inches
the board is required to complete
a rifling spiral and you want to be kind
of using a comparison of a known
and a kind of what was found at the
crime scene
you can see here this kind of matching
occurs typically with a
comparison microscope because it is
really done on the detail level
so again you do some unique
characteristics to help you kind of
identify or match up
kind of the fingerprint if you will of
the gun or barrel
to the particular bullet found at the
crime scene