so with all the factors that can impact
kind of a bullet
looking here we're going to look at
calculating the distance of bullet drops
due to
gravity for example here so
we have the acceleration of gravity
which is an important factor to keep in
mind and the acceleration of gravity is
a constant for free-falling objects
and looking specifically here for earth
a free-falling object has an
acceleration rate of 9.8 meters per
second
squared this kind of gives you that
visual representation
it's going to accelerate the distance
here at the same time points that
one second two seconds three four and
five seconds becomes greater because
that object is accelerating
in a free fall due to gravity at the
rate of
9.8 meters per second squared
so how far did the bullet fall due to
gravity
this is assuming the free fall and no
air resistance so just as you can
imagine
someone who jumps out of a plane is
going very quickly and when they open
the parachute or increase their air
resistance
their rate of fall decreases quite a bit
so again this is a free fall assuming no
air resistance to make the calculations
relatively easy in this case the
distance dropped or big d little d
the equation is distance dropped equals
g which is gravity
times time squared divided by 2.
and keep in mind we're going to use the
constant for gravity at 9.8 meters per
second
so in my practice example what is the
distance dropped for an object that is
that free falls for 3.0 seconds
so again here's our time 3.0 seconds
squared times 9.8 meters per second
divided by 2 will give us the answer of
the distance
dropped and you should get 44.1
meters so here's two more example
problems i walked through the first one
first one what's a distance drop for an
object that free falls for 2.5 seconds
and the second example was the distance
dropped for an object that free falls
for 5.0
seconds or double the amount of time so
you can go through and grab a calculator
grab a pen a pencil grab something to
write with
and go through and solve these problems
i'm going to
reveal the answers hopefully you've
paused the video and solve those
problems because
here are the answers an example one be
30.6 meters
for example 222.5 meters
so just an example where even though
we've doubled the time
that doesn't mean we've doubled the
distance remember it's 9.8 meters per
second squared it's that kind of
exponential kind of increase there
acceleration if you will
now how do we how would this apply well
we want to apply these calculations to a
crime scene these can be used to try to
determine
kind of where that shooter may have
occurred where that angle may have
happened how far did it fall where is a
convergent point
so we've got a lot of things to consider
and typically if you string out the
straight direction of travel and the
angle drop you will determine the angle
or degrees the shooter from the target
this is why it's important to go through
and do this calculation
because it can help you try to pinpoint
what may have gone on
at a crime scene