okay here we're gonna be looking at
calcium deficiency in tomatoes
now our tomatoes we always want to look
this nice consistent red color or in
some cases there might be some yellow
varieties
we're seeing that color consistent from
the very
edge or margin all the way through
however in calcium deficiency
you can see even at the immature stage
there'll be this browning
that occurs typically towards the
blossom end
so let's first look at calcium's
importance well first off it's an
immobile nutrient that means it doesn't
really
travel very well through the plant
meaning deficiencies tend to show up in
areas where it needs to travel the
furthest point
being right here if we look at the image
of the tomato
where the blossom end is the all the
nutrients have to come from the stem
down through the early part of the
tomato
the area that is the closest to the main
stock and then that calcium travels down
because it's immobile doesn't travel
very far so in the case of deficiencies
the plant is more likely to show these
deficiency symptoms
more towards the end of the blossoming
because that's the furthest distance
that calcium would have to travel well
to prevent blossom and rot
in the most economical it's very
damaging
to growers you can lose entire crop
despite growing the entire plants
so it's why it's of economic importance
calcium help forms compounds and cell
walls that's what helps kind of
keep their integrity that's why areas
here that have poor calcium will be kind
of soft as well as discolored
calcium also stimulates root and leaf
development and influences the uptake of
other
nutrients so more than just calcium it
also influences other things
it can also be involved with cell
signaling now there's a tomato trial
here it was done in a greenhouse in
the hydroponic setup here to help
maintain consistent conditions
and the hydroponics allowed only very
specific nutrients to be added
compared to if it was a soil based
system you're going to see a control
plant that was held
fed a balanced fertilizer what a normal
plant should look like and then the test
plant and that was fed
all the nutrients except the one being
studied to allow for the isolated
deficiency
symptoms to show up so this is a
perfect example what calcium deficiency
actually looks like in a tomato plant
this is even before and this is a severe
case before we even get to the actual
fruit
notice the browning of the new leaves
you can see this newer growth has that
browning
that is occurring there tends to be more
damage to the upper or newer portions of
the plant so that's
one characteristic of a calcium
deficiency in plants
keep in mind though this plant has no
fruit yield in it so the odds
are not well of having a marketable
fruit or
mature on this plant when you're seeing
it in the plant even before you get
flowers
so again showing an extreme case you
could see it definitely on the fruit in
the other image but here is what it
looks like
in the actual plant the comparison again
here's that same
plant there we had minus that calcium
treatment and we have the control that's
what a plant should look like
this should be upright but it grew so
aggressively because it kind of fell
over we're seeing the consistent green
color
some areas though in the test plant do
have normal that green
leaf color but the most recent growth
that newer growth tends to get that
browning
that occurs so how do we correct this
problem
well calcium should be fed to the plants
repeatedly since it does take time to
build up in the plants
especially if the deficiency does exist
here's two products here one's called
biomine calcium one called cal
magmax biomin start usually an ounce per
gallon that can be applied to the leaves
and
a drench as well it's omri certified
i'll use caution when tank mixing
because it may not get along with
other nutrients they're typically
applied alone
calmagnax follow the same basic dilution
rate it's not armory certified
but it does improve calcium and
magnesium levels in the plant
and as always with most calcium products
use caution when tank mixing so not to
have any potential interactions that be
unwanted
feeding these to a tomato plant
consistently
or on a repeated schedule will help
reduce the chance that you ever see
a calcium deficiency