in this tobacco university video i'm
going to go over calculating the size of
an
indoor cannabis operation and give you
some numbers to kind of look at and
compare maybe to your own operation
if you're looking designing one from
scratch some ideas
to take into consideration
all right let's sharpen those pencils
let's go to calculating the size of an
indoor row operation
so first off when we're calculating size
here
it's important to know how many
full-sized plants you can take care of
just because you can fit them in an area
particularly for a grow room
if you can't take care of them there
will be an overall loss you want to
factor in also have an idea what your
labor may be
however size available and limiting
amount of light coverage are all factors
into potential size of an indoor
operation
and i'll go over some of the specifics
to lighting in particular at the very
end here
so square foot recommendations and i
stress these are just general
recommendations good starting points
depending on the plant morphology of
your chosen cannabis strain this will
impact the overall size of each plant
also your pruning method will also have
a great impact
note that sea of green will have the
most plants per square foot due to the
short veg cycle
however in general for full-sized uh
flowering plants
one plant per five square feet or two
plants per square meter is the typical
kind of general starting point for a
recommendation
now we're looking at plants per 10
square feet or that one square meter
per growth stage so while i quoted two
plants that beats for the flowering room
if you're looking at propagation in that
same 10 square feet of square meter you
can get over potentially over 150 plants
for a vegetative room you want to
decrease from 150 all the way down to
about three
and when you make that final change that
flower room that's where you'd be
utilizing those two plants
per square meter or per 10 square feet
depending what system you're using for
measurement
now these also other limitations to
consider as i said the labor
just because you can fit them all there
can you take care of them all
do you have the time to dedicate to all
those plants are going to need
throughout their entire grow cycle and
then there's the lighting
that i'll mention in the next slide and
also the circuits just because you can
put 10 lights
does your electrical system support or
can it support
10 lights that you're choosing to
utilize in that area
now i said the lights tend to be the
most limiting so i want to give you just
some general
ideas as far as what lighting should be
used for what so as general rules
if you have a thousand watt hps or high
pressure sodium that we can see right
here about a
five by five foot for flowering plant or
a six by
six square foot area for a veg plant
this is where we're measuring out those
areas 600 watt
hps we see the measurements there cmh
ceramic metal halide you can see that
very similar to the high pressure sodium
as far as square footage
the 615 cmh goes down a four by four
feet for veg and only three by three for
flowers so keep that in mind
a 650 watt led uh kind of similar
to that thousand watt uh hps but be
mindful it's because these are just
meant to be general recommendations you
may not be getting the same
potential output as you would with a
thousand watt there unless you have 420
led you can see the
listed out here this is also going to
impact when we talk about electricity
the amount of cooling that you may need
because if you are using kind of the hps
they will generate a little bit more
heat
than say an led light led lights still
generate heat but just not quite as much
so also take that into factor and
consideration
on how you might be moving plants from
potentially one type of light to another
throughout their growth cycle
and how that will impact things so yes
there are a lot of variables but
it's important to understand some of
those before you go out and start
purchasing anything
so you can make educated decisions and
have to rebuy things
and help increase the odds of success of
your growing operation