this video lecture is going to be
looking at calculating the time
of bullet travel so what we think that
they may travel very fast which they do
we'll be able to calculate that time as
well as some of the distance and
velocity with the equation i'm going to
provide you with
so starting with time from the shooter
to the
target well the time equation is t
equals
d over v or
time which is represented by t in
seconds
equals distance d in meters over
velocity
in meters per second keep in mind that
the units must be
matching so in this example a distance
was measured in meters
so the velocity was in meters per second
and that allows us then to be able to
calculate the time
so looking at that same equation that
hasn't that doesn't change here
a simple example a bullet traveled in a
straight line we're assuming
30 meters and the velocity was
27 meters per second so the question is
what's the time that the bullet spent um
traveling that distance at that speed
well how long
did this take when we go through and
kind of calculate this out
the simplified example here how long did
it take will the answer be 1.1 seconds
and how did i get that
i take the distance which would be 30
and divide it by
27 and that would get you 1.1
seconds now continuing this same idea
and the same concept and the
exact same equation that provided you
with uh
right over right over here i give you
three examples
to work on this type of equation so what
is what is the time
of travel if the bullet goes 100 meters
at a rate of 540
meters per second second example is
what's the distance of travel
if the bullet was in the air for 1.5
seconds so i kind of give you a quote
t in this case traveling at 400 meters
per second that's the velocity so in
that case you need to solve for d
here you need to solve for v what is the
velocity
of travel if the bullet that was in the
air for 0.7 seconds and traveled at 25
and traveled 25 meters what was the
velocity so again this is just kind of
working with this equation
so just to pause the video here take a
piece of scrap paper out and solve for
these
i'm going to be revealing the answer so
hopefully you've solved for those or at
least this is a fair warning if you
don't want any of the answers quite yet
so here we have the answers provided and
this is provided up here and kind of a
breakdown of how i set up that equation
located below now those were kind of
basic examples
i've gone through here and i've
developed what i call challenge
examples and what makes them challenging
is not that the equations changed by any
means
you're still solving the same equation
for time distance and velocity
but here you may have to change the
units you use so for example here i give
you feet per second and i give you yards
here i give you miles per hour in
seconds and i'm looking for the velocity
if i'm giving you feet in seconds so
again this might require a little bit of
some unit conversions to keep in mind
there
um so this is what makes these a little
bit like challenge
examples so again pause the video here
solve them because i'm about to reveal
the answers
fair warning on revealing the answers
now and you could again see the answers
provided
as well with the kind of the basic
two-step potential conversions you may
need to do
hopefully you got these answers and able
to understand these kind of
basic ways for calculating time of the
bullet travel