this tobacco university video is going
to look at calcium and magnesium
and its importance in plants and these
are nutrients
typically reported in a soil test report
so you should have some understanding
of how they impact plants
so here we'll look at calcium and
magnesium importance in a soil test
report
now we notice that it's often marketed
here as bone health for
humans but also calcium magnesium are
also important
for our plants health as well so first
off starting with
calcium so for calcium it's a vital
component of the cell manufacturing
process
calcium also improves the root uptake of
other nutrients
plants growing points are particularly
sensitive
to an insufficient calcium supply as
evident by blossom
enrot those black sunken spots are often
discovered at the bottom of tomatoes and
summer squash here
indicate that these plants were not
getting adequate levels of calcium
also lack of moisture can contribute to
this disorder
and soils that are proper are properly
limed
generally contain adequate calcium
levels because this nutrient is a major
constitute of limestone
however if you're dependent on that lime
for your calcium
be aware that some of that calcium while
in high amounts
may not be necessarily always plant
available
it can occur in other crops as well here
we see the grapes now if we're talking
about crops that don't produce an actual
fruit
because this is looking at the actively
growing points
typically you're going to see calcium
issues at kind of the tips
of plants maybe the browning or the
burning of the tips of plants
can be another indication that your
plants might be deficient
in calcium going on to magnesium here
and magnesium is a key element in in the
development of chlorophyll
magnesium breviate mg is a crucial
for seed formation like calcium
magnesium is usually supplied by
limiting materials particularly
dolomic lime because dolomitic limestone
contains about 20
magnesium so not only are you getting a
ph change
making your soil that might be too
acidic more basic
you're also getting magnesium with that
product epsom salts or magnesium sulfate
may be recommended where calcium and
soil ph levels are adequate
but soil magnesium is still low now when
i say
chlorophyll development we can see here
that the yellow
the yellow coloration of the leaves here
it's a tomato
but look would we look very similar in
other crops for
the magnesium deficiency this is kind of
very characteristic
you can see it'd not be every leaf but
we can see it's definitely evident here
the main veins of the leaf are still
green in the in between veins the
intervenal areas is what yellows
and that's a classic symbol of a
magnesium deficiency
particularly if it occurs on the older
or the lower leaves within a plant
that can be an indication that you may
be looking at a plant
that is magnesium deficient