okay this video lecture is going to go
over the Calvin cycle which is also
called the light independent reaction
because it itself does not require light
specifically to run it is a cycle so you
can see that it does have to regenerate
and this is the steps that will go
through and generate a glucose molecule
so let's go over and try to understand a
little bit more about the complexities
that occur they start off in the basics
the Calvin cycle it has requirements of
products from the light dependent
reaction those are ATP and nadph to
transport those high-energy electrons
also carbon dioxide from the atmosphere
is required and if you remember going
back to some of the other videos we used
to did the light dependent reaction now
well can get specifically the calvin
cycle which is again using products from
the light reaction and co2 it will
ultimate generate a sugar or glucose
molecule so the Calvin cycle basics
overview of the Calvin cycle pathway and
you can see this is a cycle that's an
important it's a circle and all of these
are different atoms I highlighted here
with all the different colors we
correspond to black is carbon white is
hydrogen red is oxygen in pink is
phosphorus so you can see kind of what's
going on here and again this is a cycle
we do have to regenerate the step so we
can go through the cycle again Calvin
cycle sometimes called the dark reaction
this is kind of a not the most accurate
term to use because it can occur during
hours of light when the key part is it
doesn't require light for it to be able
to perform it does require products of
the light reaction but it itself does
not require light it needs those
products to be able to complete the
cycle mainly the ATP and nadph are those
products from the light reaction are
coming over and needed for the calvin
cycle here and again ultimately
returning a sugar molecule so let's live
a little more into the details well
where does this occur the calvin cycle
if you're looking at our chloroplast it
occurs in the stroma is too fluid inside
the chloroplast but outside our
thylakoid membranes the calvin cycle is
very efficient it's about
percent efficient versus the light
reaction only this is about 20 percent
of the photon energy a lot of that's
lost to heat other efficiencies this one
is very efficient very controlled
so our overview during the Calvin cycle
energy in electrons harvested in the
light dependent reactions are used to
produce carbohydrates and is it this
example would be glucose molecule so
we're seeing some of the products being
used we're seeing these three
distinctive steps keep in mind were in
the stroma of the chloroplast there are
three stages first one is carbon
fixation and this is where carbon
dioxide from the atmosphere is attached
to an organic molecule called rubp
during this stage the second stage
myself out of the way second stage over
here is the second stage is called
reduction here in our reduction phase
the energy in electrons in ATP and NADPH
are used to produce carbohydrates which
in our case here is glucose molecule the
last stage is to reach generation
remember this is a cycle the energy from
ATP is used to regenerate the first
substrate of the cycle rubp while loving
this cycle to occur again now while it's
important to remember this needs to
regenerate it's also a very key note
that it takes six complete turns of this
calvin cycle to produce one molecule of
glucose which is six carbons because we
only have one carbon coming in from this
carbon dioxide we need essentially this
to repeat six times to produce one
glucose molecule it's a very important
note with the calvin cycle
looking at the three phases remember
this is a cycle very different than the
electron transport chain that we talked
about in the light dependent reaction
these three main stages when it cover in
a little bit more detail so starting
with the first stage carboxylation we're
fixing our carbon so carbon dioxide and
get it here is added to a five carbon
sugar called rubp by the Rubisco enzyme
a very important enzyme for essentially
light taking our carbon dioxide taking
their carbon here and adding it
now during this carboxylation the result
is an unstable six carbon molecule so
our TVP could see here's five carbons
we're adding a carbon dioxide molecule
another carbon creating an unstable six
carbon intermediate here's a purpose
coenzyme this is going to be easily
broken into two more stable three carbon
PGA molecules we see that here so two
more stable three carbon compounds
called PGA are formed so we have our
five carbon with one carbon from co2
binding creating this unstable
intimating the six carbon it breaks
apart into two three carbon PGA
molecules the second stage is reduction
so PGH B is reduced requiring two steps
and products from the light reaction
here's where our ATP and NADPH from the
light reaction are being integrated the
malko called P gal is formed fjell's the
first stable
sugar product you can see it kind of
separating out here this ultimately go
on to produce our glucose molecule c6
h-12 o-6 now during this reduction ATP
and NADPH are used to convert the six
molecules of pga into six molecules of a
chemical called phosphoglycerate di di
dried P gal is what we're in a call to
make it easy this is a reduction
reaction because it involves the gaining
of electrons from NADPH by PGA so just a
refresher here production may recall
that reduction is to gain up an electron
by an atom or molecule so because
electrons are negative when we're
gaining this electrons we're becoming
reduced in the sense we're reducing that
charge so that's what we refer to when I
say reduced here the second part of this
reduction phase is 6 molecules of both
ATP NADPH are used making glucose this
is obviously very energy intensive so a
lot of those products from the light
reaction are used up during this for ATP
the energy is released with the loss of
the terminal phosphate converting to ADP
you see here for NADPH both energy and
hydrogen atoms is lost convert to nad
P+ so these is then going to go back to
the light dependent reaction to then be
made into ATP and then reattached with
the hydrogen ion to make NADPH both of
these molecules return to that light
independent reaction to become
re-energized so they can come back here
and participate in the Calvin cycle and
this is the reduction stage of the
Calvin cycle the third stage is
regeneration remember this is a cycle
some PL molecules in ATP we generate
rubp
we can get back where we started so that
we can add in our carbon dioxide so we
can repeat the process again because
this is a cycle unlike the electron
transport chain produce an end result in
product this regeneration has three main
components note not only one of the PBL
molecules leaves the Calvin cycle and is
sent to the cytoplasm to contribute to
the formation of other compounds needed
by the plant feel a little part of it's
broken off here again we're in the
regeneration phase so we're talking
we're right in this area here in since
it's also going to be requiring ATP and
the whole point of this is to regenerate
our rubp molecule to bind another carbon
dioxide part two of this since Big Al is
exported from the chloroplast has three
carbon atoms it takes three turns in the
calvin cycle to fix enough net carbon to
export one p gal but each turn makes two
Pig Al's us it makes six you gals in
total so because this is a cycle so it
gets a little confusing this has to go
around multiple times to generate some
of these complex end products the last
phase of the regeneration one is export
while the remaining 5 PL Mantle's
remain in the cycle are used to run
maybe generate rubp this enables the
system to prepare for more carbon
dioxide to be fixed and with to
regenerate and remind our incoming next
carbon dioxide molecule
three more molecules of ATP are used in
these regeneration actions so the
regeneration most of the ATP is used
here between stages one and two the
carbon fixation and reduction but
there's also some to reach
regulating the Calvin cycle will
products of the light reaction can help
regulate this the photosynthetic rate if
the light dependent reaction is going
very slowly there's not be as much ATP
and nadph generated that can slow down
the Calvin cycle even though the Calvin
cycle does not require light to function
it does require products of the light
reaction also the amount of carbon
dioxide present can help regulate this
phase also the end here a couple of you
videos if you want to review these are
independent links that you're welcome to
take a look at and hopefully this tries
to make it a little bit easier to
understand this complex process called
the Calvin cycle to generate glucose