so in this debaco University video I'm
going to add some information uh to the
question can tissue culture remove hop
latent viroid from cannabis plants
[Music]
all right something many Growers are
asking can tissue culture remove hot
plate and fibroid from cannabis plants
so let's get into a little bit more of
the complexities of this as we answer
this question
so this does not mean you can stop
testing or screening this is still a
needed component so a very important
part of the process by testing plants
that are infected they can be called out
as even tissue culture does not ensure a
clean plant and that's something a lot
of Growers I think of a misconception on
they think oh it is tissue culture I can
remove that small number of cells and
then I can remove the positivity of that
plant and I can clean that tissue
however culturing from a clean plant and
producing known complaints is a method
that can lead to kind of a clean
facility as you select out those that
are infected testing your skin should
still occur if you have employees or
bring other plant material in plan on
keeping a plant as a mother and you know
and you still should have a clean
facility so keep this in mind that
testing is not removed from the
operation even if you're going with
tissue culture
but looking specific at tissue culture
is this kind of the answer to this uh
fibroid based on hops it is possible to
clean uh tissue and eliminate the
passage of the thyroid to new tissue
serving things perfect I'm just going to
take some plants tissue culture them and
then don't have to worry about this
fibroid however the portion of the plant
the sample is taken and the cultivar
being used for the plant cells all have
an impact on the effectiveness of this
process however when multiple rounds are
done with testing or screening in
between it is possible to rid a line of
this viroid so it is possible but it's
not just not necessarily a one and done
so a lot of people think I'm just going
to tissue culture and I'll be all clean
well even tissue cultured that plant
could still potentially contain the
viroid
now when we're looking at sampling the
meristem or the top portion would be a
preferred region a teacher culture only
is a small number of cells so where
should you take them from well meristem
culture is the very top portion here
it's more advantageous compared to using
material from a node so it's possible to
get a nodal uh tissue culture but you
want to really go for the meristem if
you're worried about hopolate and
thyroid remember that the viral viral
load can vary by the plant and some
people think this is because the plant
grows quicker you know as the plant's
growing up we're kind of outgrowing
where that virus trying to go through
and run through the plant
that could potentially this may be true
to some extent the reality variety is
not very far away so when you're talking
about that Marathon the very very top
portion because that word is also going
to be running through that plant as well
so take that into consideration
common location based on tomatoes so
when it actually it's more likely to be
found above rather than below the
initial point of infection at least
initially it is very common in Roots and
this may be where the initially
concentrates so if you get a point of
infection up here it will probably
accumulate in The Roots first and then
work its way above that point infection
and then over about six weeks the data
seems to show it infects the entire
plant
you know people are looking to potatoes
because a lot of them are vegetatively
propagated often grower in tissue
culture to produce virus flea free plant
stock that will be used for a number of
years and then tissue culture repeat the
process to ensure clean tissue keep in
mind that canvas is slightly different
if I were slightly different but this is
something to consider that other plants
are being used as an initial protocol
and is showing potentially some
effectiveness
now why that meristem region or let's
look a really close version which you
may not have seen of that meristem
region this is the actual growing point
of that plant the very tip of the plant
has the fastest growing cells a lot of
mitosis occurring here so it may be able
to outpace the growth or spread of a
virus or in this case a thyroid this is
not a guarantee but it does help
potentially increase the odds of
generating virid flea plant tissue this
is why it should be taken from the
meristem and not the bud regions the
schools kind of outrun it not always
true but if you're going to sample from
a region that's where I would Target and
then still test those plants because
they still may show positive take
another meristem region another tissue
culture round and hopefully you can get
a clean plant and to create clean plant
stock