here I'm gonna go over a brief cancer
overview to kind of give you a little
bit of the background of what cancer is
so starting with the basic question of
what is cancer it's simply put it's an
abnormal cell growth in neoplasia
there's two different types though
here's a book benign in a malignant the
benign is very slow growth non-invasive
and malignant is rapid growth and be
very invasive the melina is much greater
concern in the benign here's a little
comparison between the two
benign very minimal nuclear variations
diploid low mitotic count cells remain
specialized or organized but they may
put forms of admirable functions the
malignant because of their rapid growth
they have very build nuclear variation
they range in ploidy they can be like a
diploid that you'd be haploid they could
be tetraploid all sorts of crazy things
low to high mitotic count loss of
specialization of functions lots of
organization often loses or function
that is growing out of control in
malignant
I'll come question maybe ask is is
cancer can I get it you know inherit
cancer well the majority of cancers are
not inherited only about five to ten
percent of all cancers are due to the
inherited gene defect a lot of it is
caused by the environment cancer is a
genetic disease but the majority of the
mutations that lead to cancer are
somatic the current are somatic cells
we're not going to pass those down to
our offspring within the five to ten
percent cancers that do occur from genes
include a couple here and then the
environmental factors here and you can
see how I'm tobacco products diet
infections obesity alcohol all
contribute to ninety to ninety-five
percent of all cancers what causes
cancer has mutations that lead to cancer
we have viruses bacteria chemicals UV
light all these can have different types
of cancers associated with them however
they all have something in common here
they are normal cells and we're never
seen our cancer cells are coming that
growing out of control there's kind of
that lost specialization that loss of
organization that's occurring with
cancer it's abnormal
cell growth and again there's a whole
host of potential sources it's not just
UV light it's not just viruses not just
chemicals each one of these may relate
to a specific type of cancer but all
these mutate our DNA immunes looking at
viruses viruses like HPV is one example
ages standardised s rates on this the
cervical cancer here by country per
100,000 inhabitants
and we could see where there's very
small amounts and where there's
increased risk this on the oranges to
red region this gives you an idea where
there's higher occurrence of this
particular virus where the risk might be
higher for those individuals UV light
ultraviolet light is the ionizing
radiation and double and single stranded
DNA breaks we're having this incoming UV
photon and we're breaking apart portions
of this DNA this is how it's being
mutated and changed and there's
different findings that occur what this
is occurring is just simply a mutation
that can lead into just continued cell
growth and his could arrest the chance
for checks and balances for the cell to
go through boom distances chemicals DNA
in turn in tribulations this is where
we're intercalating our DNA this is
where chemicals might be binding towards
DNA when DNA becomes bound to
cancer-causing chemicals ethidium
bromide is one it's very well at binding
with DNA to used in some labs here this
is this gel it's DNA in it that has
atheneum bromide because it glows under
UV light so it's really easy when
running gels to be able to identify it
however because it by the DNA it's
non-discriminatory it's gonna bind it
the DNA in the gel or the DNA in your
cells as a result scientists at work
with this and I've worked at this before
it be very careful about having a
barrier between you in Athenian bromide
you notice gloves here stored in a very
protected in well labeled container
stored in this particular location hood
serve a purpose when he's properly but
can be a mutant McGann can cause cancer
what types of genes get mutated cancer
oncogenes are activated normal function
cells grow and genes are transcribed in
a normal cell this can be converted to a
cancer cell with the activation of these
oncogenes this is basically taking a
normal cell and transforming it causing
it to become a cancer cell and this is
typically evident by just unrestricted
growth that may occur increase rates of
replication and we see that loss of
specialization those tumor suppressor
genes are also could be inactivated
normal function DNA repair cell cycle
growth is normal leading to cell death
well tumor suppressor genes they go
through and they can inhibit proteins in
cell divisions under control however a
mutated portion here the tumor
suppressor gene is no longer active it's
just located here in the red region cell
division is now now under control
it's out of control and it's happening
too quickly and there's no checks and
balances we see the cells are taking on
slightly different shapes and a lot more
of them this is we as a result of tumor
suppressor genes being inactivated
characteristics in general the cancer
cell and this is again speaking in the
general overview kind of standpoint
self-sufficient growth signals activated
growth factors and signaling resistance
to anti-growth signals mean it doesn't
listen to shut down signals these
inactive a checkpoints it's constantly
going through division again again again
well then zap happens I tried to put
showed in the picture here we have a
cell that stress proliferating one cell
just massively reproducing and
ultimately or mutagens we noticed a
cancer cells here look nothing like the
original cells there's a lot more of
them this is the idea a concept of
tumors what are they there are those a
result of those cells that are just
growing out of control so
characteristics of a cancer cell to be
immortality reason cell death or having
our kilometers at the very end of our
chromosomes
here a young cell has them capped off
just nice aging cell will slowly lose
them when they're basically all gone the
cell dies well what the cancer cell ends
up doing is it kind of puts a little cap
on the end by putting that cap on the
end it's constantly has these present
these cells are gonna have it like that
in mortis all their constant going to be
able to go to cell division and again I
look back here this constant growth and
cell division is what's causing the
issues here yeah these are some other
characteristics of cancer cells there's
six total loser three and four also
resistance to cell death and the cell
doesn't die just keeps dividing keeps
dividing there's normally these checks
and balances to reduce that from
occurring the other characteristics we
have increased branching that occur
these signals that can cause this
branching now the reason why this is a
character this characteristic of a
cancer cell is because they're growing
out of control they need a lot more
exchange of nutrients therefore they're
gonna have the blood vessels around them
start to branch out so they can get more
surface area to volume ratio so they can
exchange nutrients and waste a lot more
efficiently mastitis another one loss of
cell to cell interactions we're having
this abnormal just growth that's
occurred again here's one it's got the
mutation we see the progression over
time to an invasive cancer cell tumor
suppressor genes our guardians of the
genome they're involved in maintaining
genome integrity they were possible for
DNA repair mutants and tumor suppressor
genes lead to mutator phenotype mutation
rates increase often the first mutation
in the developing cancer so we have
these genes that basically like brakes
on a car the goal is to slow down cell
growth and prevent the carbon in the
wall well if we modify these and kind of
take these safety and checks and
balances out well what's gonna happen
that's basic it's like a car with no
brakes it's gonna run into the cell wall
and this is just an example of running
into kind of dead cancer getting that
out of control this p53 is a classic
tumor suppressor suppresses genomic
damage it halts the cell cycle if the
DNA is irreparable p53 will initiate
cell death
the prices we call apoptosis that's
programmed cell death and that's a soul
being able to go through a realizing
somebody's not right and basically
killed itself off so it has stability
within the cell apoptosis again it's
programmed cell death this does occur
normally the cells no longer needed they
commit suicide by activating these
intracellular death program this is
different than cancer this is a normal
process so they'll go back again this
apoptosis this is the cell realizing
something's not right given itself off
of the better of the tissue of the
organism this does occur our toes and
our fingers all right there's no webbing
here there were cells when we were
really small that or in here throughout
the process of apoptosis were able now
to get individual fingers good see here
this didn't occur quite as it should
have as the other toes some animals it's
the male duck here
what webbing on their feet is there
nothing that apoptosis of those
particular cells wait for our hands
tubes who want to be either grab things
more efficiently
chromastone instability is another thing
that can cause issues and mutations here
we're noticing a nice separation these
chromosomes will occur here our spindle
fibers inaccurately grab two of them I'm
gonna pull them in a weird format tune
to the top hole and none are gonna come
down here this is gonna cause an
instability within the cell
well cancer therapy is target so
classical cancer therapies target
rapidly dividing cells they're turning
the DNA it could be a craze to kill
target cells in this example here person
would lay down on the table here this is
gonna fire very precise x-rays ideally
these gamma rays are gonna go through
and target that specific cancer cell and
attack it from different angles to help
to stop it from growing other things
that are targeting these rapidly
dividing cells is chemotherapy you serve
the drugs throughout the entire body
again to really example some of them to
really target and pinpoint those rapidly
dividing cells however as many side
effects with chemotherapy if you sadly
known as gone through this everyone's
experiences a little bit differently
here's some very common
symptoms again hair loss weakened immune
system loss of appetite area there's
different grades of those and you can
see again the goal is to try to reduce
the amount of side effects and again
it's gonna depend on the individual in
the severity of their particular side
effects that they're going to have other
therapies person's immune system will
not be at a target tumor cells because
this surface proteins appear to be self
so how did this cancer cell to begin us
and why isn't our body suppressing it
what appears to be self the recognition
markers do not throw up any red flags so
that our normal immune systems that I
took is not going to target those cells
so new therapies are focusing on
activating someone's immune system
against a cancer cell because it been in
our immune system to recognize these
cells something's that going right here
they could potentially attack the cells
and stop it from growing into a large
tumor modern and targeted therapies
attack specific proteins that are
abnormally expressed in the tumor they
can block over the expressed growth
factors generally there are a few side
effects from this it's so targeted
however we cut it so targeted it's very
difficult to develop these technologies
advances are being made which is great
as we learn more about cell to cell
recognition but it takes a lot of
research it's very specific the polio
virus in cancer there's some great
research coming out with this this is
the polio virus it creates very negative
effects to the body crippling effects
potentially deadly infections by a virus
invading that person's brain the spinal
cord causing paralysis causing basically
death and kind of not a good way between
two and ten out of a hundred people who
have paralysis from polio virus
infection and die because the virus
affects muscles that help them breathe
stops the diaphragm essentially so this
is a very nasty virus causes a lot of
death however it is being used to try to
treat cancer so I've provided you three
links here to a 60 minutes TV spot and
how the polio virus is being used to
fight cancer it's a bold treatment and
it's granting breakthrough status what
the goal is to try to take away some of
the virulence of the polio virus
injected
carousel as a way to help the immune
system recognize the cancer cell to be
able to suppress tumors invisibly have
one's own immune system take care and
clean up the tumor some excellent videos
here I'll provide some great ways to be
able to see how something that's very
deadly could potentially be used to save
someone's life so invite you to check
those videos out hopefully this is
helpful to give you a kind of a brief
overview of what cancer is what some
potential causes are for it