hello welcome to another debaco
university video
here we're going to be looking at the
cannabis naming system that's currently
in place
and some of the issues involved with
that system when it comes to naming
you can see here's some dried flower
kind of the name tags here that have
nothing on them
a lot of times even though it may say a
name on it we may
not have a very valid name and we'll
talk about that here
so first off there's the international
code of nomenclature for cultivated
plants this is the icncp
this regulates the naming of plants
whose recent evolution
has been influenced by human selection
so of course this would
apply or pertain to cannabis based on
that definition
however when we're looking at naming
certain types of cannabis a lot of times
we're using the term cultivar
now when we're using the term cultivar
we have to realize that
this is a unit of classification and it
has a very specific definition
it's an assemblage of plants that a has
been selected for a particular character
or combination of characters b is
distinct
uniform and stable in these characters
and
c when propagated by appropriate means
retains
those characteristics which is when
we're looking
here at different types of cannabis or
any plant in general this means it's
basically
it's a unique form it's a
kind of distinct characteristics and it
is
able to be propagated so this is what
defines
a cultivar now when we're looking at the
room
the rules for naming a cultivar i want
to think of it kind of like a sports
event here
so the ic ncp his rules for naming
describing cultivars
involve valid publication typification
and priority
this is available online for
consultation and regarding these
provisions so they are available to kind
of take
in some feedback and to be able to
provide some uh
suggestions as well cauliflower names
meaning that the icncp provisions
are placed in single quotation marks
it's the proper way
to kind of scientifically scientific
name for that given plant species
and there's the genus the specific
epithet and then the cultivar
there listed in those single quotes at
the end
we're not talking just about a simple
common name that's basically no rules
and there may be multiple names for the
same plant and this also applies to
animals
now variety form and strain do not equal
the same
as the word cultivar so article 2.2
uh stipulates that the words variety
form and strain must not be used
for the word cultivar cultivar is its
own distinctive kind of
entity strain is not uniformly
recognized
so that's one thing to keep in mind and
strains are conceptually identical to
cultivars in concept but almost no
strains have
met the official icncp requirements for
cultivar recognition
and all these sources would be located
in the description here of this video
rules are in place for a reason so like
anything they may we may not agree with
all of them but they are in place for a
reason
there's an argument of the bigger
picture justifies using strain and
cultivar as
equivalent so it's kind of like well
where we have these rules let's just
call them the same
thing and that's really not the case
here
the uh so as a research here small in
2015 reported that they showed
insufficient respect for
codes of nomenclature which hold uh
prametic and moral status
by quoting the botanical codes are by a
large adhered to by scientists
commercial interests
and editors because they provide
stability and reliability to names
that otherwise would result in confusion
so i think the cannabis industry right
now is kind of like
using the the code is more what we call
guidelines than actual rules when there
are
official rules in place for the proper
naming
and just keep calm and follow those
rules otherwise it's kind of going to
result in a bunch of confusion
which sadly we have a lot of right now
now the strain
names so strains become kind of numerous
they
leafly quoted in 2015 they listed about
1535 straight names seed finder
in the same year listed 6 510 string
names
most strains are recognized as hybrids
characterized as sativa
dominant or indica dominant keep in mind
though that strain names are swapped and
counterfeited and generally unreliable
so they're kind of like the picture we
have here with kind of the
celtic sugar around it kind of wind can
come through and it can change
and look completely different and that's
sadly what we're having with these
various strain names in cannabis now
what's in a name will any strain
has not been formally described as a
cultivar for example
the so-called sour diesel should
properly be named as
uh cannabis in italics strain
sour diesel the population's name is
without single quotation marks remember
that these names have no
taxonomic validity so just because you
may know it as sour diesel just because
it may be listed on the package of sour
diesel
these really don't have any true
taxonomic scientific
validity to those names now kind of get
into that straining
variability kind of pointing this out
ak-47 won the best
sativa in the 1999 cannabis cup
and then one best indica four years
later so even
in kind of the cannabis cup of high
times there's been
a single strain that won best sativa and
then four years later it went in one
best indica so this kind of helps
prove that the reliability of these
strains is not really that great
last here we're looking at just some
questionable kind of pedigree
the claimed industry of suprathera
diesel hayes from seed finder
as you kind of go through and read
through here what gives it kind of its
questionable pedigree
so when you see the words like murky
pedigree it's either this or it could be
that
that should throw up us kind of some
caution there of like a red flag like
some things
may not quite be right there and we see
the terms like
likely derived from uh another example
there where just because we know we have
this end product
where actually came from is not really
well defined
and a lot of that goes back to the poor
naming system currently in place