okay here we're investigating some of
the pros and cons to cloning cannabis
plants so starting off with cloning
cannabis this is a vegetative
propagation process clones are
genetically identical to their parent or
mother plants also sometimes called the
stock plant this helps ensure
consistency and gender of the offspring
it's like the clone army in Star Wars
we're generating identical copies and
the benefits of cloning the goals
produced many identical copies of a
chosen individual this preserves the
chosen or desirable traits
unlike seeds that produce a high degree
of variability this ensures only female
plants are produced so only we won't be
wasting their times with the males so
that we're only getting the buds and
cannabinoid production that's very high
as a result this is a very efficient
production method then only in the sense
of the end product but also the process
to generate them in Lewis it needs two
sex plants because you're guaranteed
that they'll all be female and as long
as you're starting with a female plant
then they can be planted as soon as the
roots develop there's not a lot of lag
time in that seedling stage the time the
harvest can be reduced when compared
with the initial seedling delay when
starting with seed so you're not only
improving your time efficiency but
you're kind of making this a nice
repeatable process there are the
drawbacks that for all clones have or
lack resistance to disease so it can
it's possible to lose an entire crop due
to the lack of variability for the
example here of bananas the Cavendish
bananas that we're all familiar with
eating are very susceptible to a
Fusarium disease as a result since
they're all clones bananas are actually
clones of one another once the disease
figures one out it's able to kind of
spread in this Domino like effect and
wipe out potentially an entire crop and
see that here with this plants resistant
this plants not well if we were cloning
this plant all of the offspring would
also not be resistant to the particular
disease and as a result we could lose
them he cloning for sex so as this mean
well Suzie Vaughn to clone infer whether
that male or female plant but this does
this involve taking a clone early from a
plant and placing it in that 12 hours of
light and 12 hours of dark period this
will induce flowering very quickly this
will help you determine if it's a male
or female
earlier in development and can allow you
to make an educated decision whether you
going to keep or discard of that plant
the key is to label each plant ax to
take these cuttings from and where the
cuttings are going for accurate for
accuracy however PCR polymerase chain
reaction has made this obsolete for
large-scale growers however this can be
an expensive process some there's a way
to reduce cost or it is simply taking a
small clone from a plant that they grew
from seed flipping it to 12 hours a day
12 hours night to see what types of
flowers it produces and then deciding
whether or not going to keep or discard
that individual