here I'm gonna provide you with a very
brief history on the cannabis plant also
give you some resources where you can
kind of see a little bit more of the
timeline or lineage for this particular
crop so first off cannabis hemp in
particular it was used about 6,000 to
7,000 years ago archaeologists found
hemp fabrics in northern China that date
back to as much as 7,000 years ago an
interesting note though is that evidence
of hemp clothing only dates back about
2,000 years ago so this difference in
time supports the idea that the main use
of the plant may have been their
psychoactive compounds and that
necessary textures or their fibers
either the properties were likely used
either a medical standpoint or in a
ritual and again at the bottom in some
of the slides I have some links for some
further information did ancient people
use canvas well the odds are very strong
that yes they actually did a 2500 year
olds - of 13 old marijuana plants were
on earth in an ancient tomb in northwest
China is he here very clearly distinctly
seen the tomb where scientists found the
cannabis plant stick it's kind of see
the different layers how they different
organize things there's a close-up of
the shroud line drawing of the contents
and ultimately the bottom layer here so
you can see this shows kind of the
shroud and close-up view here so again
very interesting that dates back that
far they're going to give you that
overview NCR Labs has published a
history of cannabis use and they're just
excellent Google Doc link here to one of
their sheets realize this is a publicly
viewable Google based sheet that covers
many major events worldwide from a
Massachusetts based lab in more recent
history details provided that includes
the day of the particular topic that's
presented links of sources articles are
provided for each event so this is an
excellent resource so I invite you to go
take a look at that so you can brush up
and see some of the extensive history of
the cannabis use now I mention the
history would be you know remiss of me
did not mention the Emerald triangle
which is a region in Northern California
it's one of the largest cancer
producing regions in the United States
it's made up of three counties Humboldt
medicinal and Trinity counties appear in
Northern California
cultivation being started in 1960s it
became exponentially larger with the
passage of the California proposition
215 back in 1996 which legalized the use
of cannabis for medicinal purposes in
California what makes this region in
part so prolific was its growing season
matches or supports outdoor growing of
cannabis very well for long season ocean
near the ocean this also helps these
counties become established as major
cannabis producers fast forward as a
farm bill 2018 where Congress pitted a
legalized hemp which is defined as less
than 0.3 percent THC with the December
12th passage of the 2018 farm bill well
as this translate to with a farm bill
removes him from the Controlled
Substances Act and allows farmers to
pursue federal hemp cultivation permits
while individual states can regulate the
industry within their borders as they
see fit was seen as a major victory at
moving this forward and allowing an
expanded grow of this so what some are
saying about the farm bill it's
absolutely world history what Congress
did is going to change the future for
the industry in the world what makes
this so historic is that back in 1937
there was a draft or there was a drafted
bill that was implemented that basically
made hemp cultivation illegal now it's
exciting 2018 and beyond it's exciting
to finally have defined rules governing
the sale of CBD products in the United
States and now with hemp set to be
treated as an agricultural product the
US FDA or State Department's of
Agriculture will provide oversight in
the plants cultivation so this now
allows this essentially to take off even
more than it has already in a lot of
states and the federal government to be
able to regulate it and treat it in a
manner that will allow people to grow it
to allow continued scientific research
on this down this plant