on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over and explain some
explanation to cannabis reuteralis as
you may know as autoflowers
[Music]
all right let's get into cannabis
reuteralis and a little explanation
about them so what's their general
origin well
these are native to areas of asia
central eastern europe as well as russia
rudor alice is believed to be a
descendant of the indica genetics
however originally cannabis reuteralis
was considered a wild breed of cannabis
so reuteralis is based on its northern
region of origin had to adjust to these
harsh climates and conditions and the
shorter growing seasons this is part of
the reasons why it has this
characteristics that it does
it has been brought indoors and
influenced new hybrid varieties and
continues to be integrated because of
its auto flowering ability so the plant
morphology in general uh one to three
feet tall so it tends to be a much
shorter plant thick and sturdy stems and
this is in part because of the harsh
environment you had to endure its shaggy
growth pattern and it automatically
flowers after about 21 to 30 days of
vegetation and that can of course be
dependent on the exact type that you're
growing harvest is ready in 70 to 110
days from seed and the buds tend to be
smaller but well supported by the plant
so again keep this in mind you're really
not going to find clones because they
are flowering based on days old uh
regardless of the photo period and
that's why for some growers these are
considered to be advantageous
so popular cultivate locations uh for
these uh the key that reuteralis
flowering is based on that days old
again and not that photo period so
they're commonly referred to as what's
called autoflowers they're commonly used
in late plantings in outdoor locations
mainly due to the naturally changing
photo periods of the sun their small
size makes them great for indoor or tent
or
growing locations as we see in this
image right here and due to the general
popularity breeders are utilizing these
plants to cross with some more other
high potency options to create the best
of both worlds great potency without the
need of kind of having that photoperiod
dependency
so common realist cultivar is just a
couple mentioned here lightning
autoflower and problematic cbd as well
as many many others as i said they're
being bred into more and more so
hopefully this might this explanation
provided some good information and
something you're probably going to see a
lot more of