as the growing and production of
cannabis continues to gain popularity
we need to have considerations towards
its long-term
sustainability here on this tobacco
university video the goal here
is going to be to cover some of these
major topics regarding cannabis
sustainability for the long run
[Music]
all right let's look at cannabis
sustainability considerations
so first off cannabis cultivation is
kind of emerging
with the start of the increase in
popularity due to
uh produced cannabis plants this is the
time to ensure
that it starts on the proper path or
just in the early
phases let's start on the proper path
and go forward
in a sustainable manner growers need to
be considering the sustainability of
their practices
no matter the size of their operation a
lot of times it's like oh i'm a small
operation i have to worry about it
larger operations need to worry about it
really everyone needs to be considerate
of the sustainability of agricultural in
general
so correcting past problems so uh going
looking back maybe not necessarily this
far back
but seeing problems that have developed
in other industries
the goal should be of that of prevention
over over sustainability
all right so let's get into cannabis
sustainability considerations
so first off cannabis cultivation is
emerging
with the start of the increase in
popularity to produce cannabis plants
this is the time to ensure that it
starts and continues on the proper path
so we're kind of just coming into this
kind of emerging industry if we correct
the problems now and make it more
sustainable now
that can continue and be the path of the
future growers need to be considering
the sustainability of their practices
no matter the size of their operation
many birds think of
a small operation have to worry about it
that's more for larger operations
and that's false everyone needs to be
considering the sustainability of their
practices
no matter how large or small of a
growing operation that they have
so we want to correct past problems so
when we say past problems we
may not be going back as far as kind of
egyptian times but
seeing problems that have developed in
other industries the goal should be
that of prevention and overall
sustainability want to correct problems
before they become a major
problem many see cannabis at its own
category in
kind of many ways it can be but
considering large-scale production
sustainability is important
even if you're only going to be a small
indoor grower you want to be
considerate of all the environmental
impacts this plant may have
and you must think big picture so many
growers come from a small
under 10 plant growing perspective or
that's how they kind of perceive or see
cannabis as being this kind of small
a couple plants go from there however
growers need to consider scalability of
their actions
if you're growing 10 plants would you or
could you implement the same practices
again given a limited budget would that
be possible with 10 000
plants what would be the overall impact
of that
any little waste you scale it up from 10
plants it becomes
a much larger waste problem
so i'm going to use phosphorus here as
just an example because
a lot of growers over fertilize their
plants with phosphorus so
canvas as many other plants do need
phosphorus however many burrows are over
applying it
and i say over applying phosphorus or
over applying it without
even realizing it which is part of the
problem phosphorus toxicity is not as
obvious as nitrogen so many growers are
unknowingly
over applying phosphorus with no at
least
visual negative impacts however
phosphorus is becoming a limiting
resource and is a fresh water
contaminant so you're using these heavy
kind of bloom based fertilizers
to avoid any chance of yelling the
leaves well that could be contributing
to
fresh water algae blooms and
contamination of that water supply
so yelling leaves has a lot more
implications potentially than just
phosphorus deficiency could be disease
could be a whole host of other things
but growers are often way over adding
their phosphorus now because you get
into toxicity levels
because the plants visually don't show a
lot of negative effects growers are very
apt to do it
because they don't even realize they're
doing it at the time
and you don't want to waste a limited
resource a phosphorus is a limited
resource
chemist growers need to be aware of how
much phosphorus their plants need
and how much phosphorus they can their
plants can uptake and
and how that compares to the amount that
they're applying
many are over applying and do not
realize the waste and potential negative
impacts on the environment they could be
having
so it's very important to have that
education there to realize that there is
negative implications of over applying
phosphorus
so why do we need to transform the
phosphorus use in the global food system
so this
even goes beyond just looking at
cannabis but phosphorus is basically
food it's needed for a whole host of
plants
the growing food demand is equal to
growing uh phosphorus demand
there's only a finite amount of
phosphorus this is going to lead to
potential for geopolitical risks
insufficient global food system to
distribute that food
increased fertilizer cost as the
phosphorus that we're getting to in some
of the mines is becoming less pure
and there's really no guidelines there
are no regulations of phosphorus
and give you the idea of this kind of
geopolitical risk five countries control
almost 90 percent of the global
phosphate reserves
eight countries control uh account for
about 65 percent of the
global sulfuric acid production so only
five controlling 90 percent
um that could be a major area of concern
with
china and morocco being the greatest
percentages as far as countries go
we also need to think we're talking
about chemical waste disposal and this
concludes
all products that are required for plant
production some are
disposable and some are short-term used
others may be longer-term use
but in the end they all must be disposed
of in some way
just consider where the products you
purchase end up and just have that
mindset or that consideration
for anything that you're utilizing as
part of your plant production
so lastly here just to focus on one
thing is looking at artificial lighting
we want to be considerate of the
physical components of that artificial
lighting
this is the ballast the bulbs the cords
as well as other lighting equipment
and also the electrical needs all lights
consume power so where is this power
coming from
now if you're looking at growing outdoor
cannabis you might think well i don't
need lighting
but we want to be thinking of
potentially your weed control options
your plastic
consumption and things like that so no
system is completely free of any waste
products
good to have an idea of where that's
going to end up
how you're going to utilize that and how
you're going to grow your plant
in a efficient as well as a sustainable
way