okay I want to go over the pollination
process for cannabis even though this
may not be easy main goal for many
growers we're taking pollen produce my
male plants and pollinating a female
flower to produce seeds will be an
indication of a successful pollination
process so looking at our flower in
plants and that's well the broad
category that we're looking at and it
follows the same process as many other
flowers there must be a grain of pollen
that comes from the male flowers in the
stamen particularly the anther and it
must travel to the female pistol those
are the white structures we see on at
the cannabis plants from here it's gonna
travel down a pollen tube to reach the
ovule which is where the eggs are once
completed the pistol will turn a brown
color and a seed will begin to form so
you can see that kind of formation of a
seed here make an urge that over a years
our eggs and this is that formation of
seed will start to form as this even
mature x' the plant will degrade and
ultimately diet at the completion of a
life cycle
keep in mind cannabis is in annual plant
this process is sexual reproduction with
a combination of those plants
characteristics and the resulting seed
as we can see right here well the 50-50
chance of either being a male or a
female that's why it's important for
growing from seed need to be able to
have a system in place early on to cull
out the male producing plant it see the
same image here where we see the stigma
we have see the pollen tubes the grains
going down and ultimately forming that
seed that will grow into a seedling now
female flowers unpalatable male flowers
and these are examples of unpiloted
female flowers or referred to as
sensimilla this will be the primary
location of cannabinoids and resins will
peak production six to ten weeks or so
after changing the photo period
depending on the cultivar used this is
is the calyx that will develop and swell
a the pollinated plants will result in
poor quality buds which is why it's
important to remove or isolate male
producing plants as early as possible
the goal is to increase cannabinoid
production have the plaintiff or alt
energy into producing the chemicals
instead of going through and producing
wanted seeds in many cases