okay I'm gonna go over some cannabis
slang terminology while there are many
slang terms out there I've chosen just a
couple select few to highlight in this
video lecture series so first off try
the most obvious that most people
couldn't connector really is the number
420 well as the story goes through this
story behind 420 is that in 1971 five
high school students in San Rafael
California calling themselves the Waldos
used the term in connection with a plan
to search for an abandoned cannabis crop
so they're planning on going and
searching for this rumored crop to be in
the area they designated the Louis
Pasteur's statue at the high school
grounds as their meeting place and 4:20
p.m. as their meeting time after several
failed attempts they never did find that
rumored or abandoned cannabis crop the
group evolved 4:20 into a code word that
the teams used to mean the consumption
of cannabis that's kind of the
background of 4/20 this is kind of where
originated out in California it was
actually a group of high school students
we heard the term veg used a lot those
edges well veg is simply abbreviation
for a vegetative growth it's referring
to the stages of the plant development
that produces leaves not flowers this is
associated with a light cycle of 16 to
24 hours of continuous light so 16 to 24
hours when people plant in the veg I'll
keep the vegetative flower is the actual
trimmed bud so it's the actual product
post ribbon as you can see here so we
referred to as the flower it's preferred
to see the actual portion of the plant
and we're saying the flower don't think
of a beautiful nice pretty flower it's
the actual final trimmed product which
in this case typically does not have any
seeds we hear the term phenyl hunting
you know some growers are going phenyl
hunting well this is searching for a
specific characteristic mystery free no
is short for phenotype so it's phenotype
hunting what these growers are doing is
a phenotype is an observable physical
characteristic of an individual which is
the result of the interactions of two
the environment when growing many
individuals from across there will be
some variability so breeders may want to
select the best individual to continue
breeding that line as a result it will
Fino hunt or they'll be looking for
particular characteristics that they
will may then clone and use in future
breeding work at cloning process as I
mentioned cloning is producing
genetically identical individuals so
it's true whether it's cannabis or
anything else producing more of the same
plants can easily be cloned which allows
for many copies of a unique individual
so if you have a whole population of
plants and you have one there that
really stands out and for whatever
reason you want to clone that and
reproduce those traits well that's very
easy to do with cannabis we hear mothers
or mother plants typically sometimes are
called stock plants and they're used for
cloning or breeding purposes the mother
plants are stock plants that are kept in
the vegetative stage development to
allow clones to be taken for propagation
it's allowing those individuals to be
mass multiplied and especially if you
find a unique trait may want to continue
an entire crop of that particular trait
turps
house is short for terpenes are fake
fragrant aromatic compounds produced by
the cannabis plant they provide that
unique taste and interact
synergistically with compounds in the
plant such as cannabinoids drippings are
naturally produced to repel predators
and attract pollinators these compounds
can be infected by the climate the age
and nutrient profile that the plant is
receiving newts is it reassured for
nutrients or fertilizers and this is the
basic food for the plants to grow
newts could be organic fertilizers or
nutrients that can be synthetics just
referring to the general classification
of nutrients or fertilisers nuns are as
a trimmed blood or a nugget that is the
smokeable part of the flower it is of
high quality it can refer to the entire
flower but more commonly applied to
large or small pieces of that particular
flower well there are a lot of slang
terms to indicate high quality cannabis
nugs also spelled with 1g would be
indication of high-quality hoji kind of
some debate on what this may stand for
ocean grown Aboriginal gangster or
organically grown it's kind of a debated
topic ocean grown support is that one
the cush is trade which came from the
Hindu Kush mountains over in Asia was
brought to the west coast of the United
States the terpenes and effects changed
leading to the term OG Kush to indicate
where it was grown in what effects to
expect this is kind of support of OG
referring to ocean grown however was
also support that OG stands for original
gangster support is that originated in
Los Angeles where og stands for original
gangster which is where the Kush was
first became popularized or originated
masa oh gee could sanfur organically
grown which matches the general produce
abbreviation but there's no official
organic standards set for cannabis at
this time since just recently became
friendly legal so it's unlikely this is
the true meaning this whole goal was to
provide to it as a couple the slang
terminology used for cannabis and again
there's much more this hopefully be a
little bit of a background of some terms
that you may have heard