looking at the all-important flower room
in cannabis production this is of course
a zoomed-in of flower here and deal
you'd want an entire room full of these
flowers to produce high amounts of
cannabinoids and terpenoids it it's
often referred to as the money-making
room like little bars of gold for the
plans even though its productivity
depends heavily on the treatment and
care during the time the plants fell
spent in the vegetative room so while
this is you know considered the money
room because you can consider the little
flowers here at little bars of gold but
really it's treating this plants well in
the vegetative room to prepare them for
this firing room is a very critical part
of this process so the lighting for a
flower room high pressure sodium lights
or full-spectrum LEDs are recommended
these high pressure sodium is kind of
give that kind of a yellowish look and
full spectrum LEDs would lose a very
bright and clean white light this should
be the largest room of both your
vegetative rooms and cloning rooms this
should be the largest because plants are
going to be full sized in this area I
want we could transplant on the plants
as they go in so plants we transplant
them to learn two containers which would
be the largest you're going to use since
plants will reach full size in this room
so some people as they go from
vegetative to flowering room may decide
to uh pot their plants however it's
important not to shock your plants
during this time so if you're transplant
at the same time you're moving the
plants you till have two days for
adjustment before changing the photo
period to twelve hours of light and 12
hours of darkness to help reduce plant
stress
be mindful the amount of changes so just
a container the photo period the room
locations could be slightly difference
in environmental conditions it's
indicative of the rooms stressors you
put on your plant at one time what many
growers will do is they'll first I'll
plot the plants and move them to larger
containers then move the plants and wait
a few days before flipping the photo
period to induce flowering this will
allow those plants a little bit of time
to adjust and not create much of a shock
or stress on those plants to help allow
them to maintain very high yields
despite going through a couple changes
here without causing any loss or due
this plants that's grower induced