welcome to another debaco university
video lecture production
here we're going to be investigating
cannabis indica and explaining some of
its unique properties
and kind of what defines it looking just
at the image here we can see that the
leaf structure the morphology is really
how we classify
an indica versus sativa versus some of
the others so
here this indica is a much shorter and
wider leaf compared to other
sativas which germinate longer and
thinner leaf style
now in addition indicas are generally
agreed that originated on the
asian subcontinent possibly in the
afghanistan region
so kind of look in this general region
of the world right here
whether cannabis indica and kansas
sativa are truly separate species is
actually a matter of debate and some
controversy
since its classification is based on
morphology the general plant behavior is
what is being compared here
so we're looking at the indicas having
certain morphologies or certain physical
characteristics now the indica plant
morphology so what is what are those
physical characteristics what does this
play actually look like
well the height is small growing usually
one to six feet in
height and the internet spacing's
typically three inches or less
the leaf morphology tends to be a very
wide appearance as we can clearly see in
this image here and also in this plant
as well
the leaves tend to be a little bit more
of a darker shade of green again
comparing them a little bit more to the
more traditional
sativas for example they tend to have
more side branching than sativas
resulting in a wider bushier plant
morphology overall
as a result this will cause denser
plants overall in their general
structure
popular cultivation locations for our
indicas
here in general they're kind of that
kind of in-between that i call like
goldilocks plant morphology compared to
others
as a result it increases the flexibility
of locations that it can be used
effectively in
great for growers looking at the quick
turnovers between growing cycles but
they don't get quite as hot as tall and
quick take up the area that sativa would
however indicates are still photoperiod
dependent so outdoor plantings be aware
the timing is also important because
they get shorter you want to be mindful
of that you don't want to plant them too
late in this season because they might
get flipped into flower
a little bit sooner and even stunt them
further
just in general there are many indica
cultivars that exist
northern lights is among the most famous
strain of all time and it's also a pure
indica for just a general sense of
comparison we have the bubble kush is
another example all these are going to
have that shorter kind of plant
morphology
and if you look at one of the leaves
it's going to be more of that short and
wider kind of appearance there
just to give you some idea of what
defines morphologically
a cannabis indica plant