on this tobacco University video I'm
going to cover cannabis pherology an
investigation of the past and also the
present now virology is not unique to
cannabis but we're going to dive into
some of the specifics for cannabis and
viruses that infect this particular
plant
[Music]
all right let's get into the Cannabis
virology investigation of the past and
present so first off there's this great
article I'm going to provide you the
link here it's a guide to Canvas
virology and I'm going to take some
excerpts from this and show you and
break it down but if you want the full
review of the full article Lincoln
citation is provided right here for you
so let's start off with just the basics
viral taxonomy Basics you know how we go
about the naming of viruses well virus
names may be recognized and are based on
actually the plant species it was first
detected in now keep in mind that this
does not mean that is the only plant
that the virus can affect a lot of
people think that your tobacco mosaic
virus they think it only affects tobacco
not the case this doesn't even mean it's
the most virulent in that plant it just
simply means that's where it was
discovered first but this does allow for
a relatively Easy System of
identification and classification
now realize that there are DNA viruses
and there also are RNA viruses there's
actually single stranded and
double-stranded DNA and RNA viruses and
there's different morphologies to the
structures as well
now looking at these kind of taxonomy
just in general we're talking about
viruses discovering a virus and naming
it may seem like a standard process but
it is increasing in complexity now the
reason why is the important due to the
exponentially increasing number of new
viruses discovered by Next Generation
sequencing methods this is what's
causing us to kind of relook at some old
virus names or we re-evaluate how we've
classified what viruses might be similar
to one another with these new methods
discovery that when applied to some
previously discovered viruses again may
lead to a change in classification which
of course can add to confusion if you
knew it by one name or one
classification that could go about and
change and this is not only for plant
viruses it's for all these small
molecules and organisms that we're
looking at and discovering as we learn
more about them we're figuring out well
maybe we should classify them in this
category so you just got to keep up with
the latest and keep up with the
literature
now reported virus and virus in cannabis
uh here these are some of the great uh
ways of classifying the family the genus
the virus The genome organization and
who reported it if you want kind of what
these numbers refer to for references
you'll have to go back to the source
article but this is a list of known
concerns for cannabis Growers when it
comes to viruses and viroids it acts as
a very great way of quickly being able
to go through and see if you identify a
virus should you be of concern may not
be so concerned with the genome
organization but the genus the virus you
could see potato virus Alfalfa mosaic
virus grape line pattern tobacco streak
virus and their respective abbreviations
as well we see quite a bit listed here
now but there are distinct Visual
Diagnosis when it comes to a virus they
do have some very unique Leaf structures
and these are a set of visual symptoms
often on the leaves you'll see them with
modeling a mosaic or wrinkling this is
probably an indication that plant has a
viral infection however you do want to
take it to the lab to screen for and
identify the exact type of virus
now why is knowing the virus important
and you're going to say well if there's
nothing really I can do as a grower why
would I bother getting it tested well
justification to go through the hassle
of getting a virus identified is
important to know how it may have gotten
there for example was it insects
vectored was it it can reside in the
soil what kind of are you dealing with
because knowing that residual uh maybe
what and also what the odds of it might
be transmitted in the seeds are all good
information to know as a grower and they
make these little quick little strips
called Amino strips taken to Labs you
can really quickly identify them they
can do screening and sometimes you may
think you have one virus but you may
actually have two viruses infecting the
plant simultaneously
so why is it knowing the virus important
well allows the grower to provide a plan
what you may have how can you better
develop a plan how can develop a plan of
this prevention going forward what are
you going to Target is it going to be
insect vectors is it going to be soil
board is it going to be nematodes
um it's going to be screening plant
material when it comes in this allows a
girl to better provide a plan
now has improved understanding so a
better understanding of viral vectors
and the Genome of the cannabis plant
also has resulted in the identification
of regulatory genes responsible for
valuable medical and agronomic physical
traits the crispr cast 9 can be used to
Target these genes editing just like
other agricultural crops and lead to the
expansion and proliferation of this uh
kind of understanding of the plant and
being able to really Target these
specific sequences
now there are threat levels of concern
so the authors of the article kind of
made this nice little flow chart here
with the virus infection proof
identification do you have lab
conditions real cultivation conditions
and go on from there and as a result
they dealt these levels a b c and d so
keep in mind that while there are many
viruses that can affect canvas they also
propose this kind of level
classification a being the highest then
going to be C and D being the lowest so
while most of the currently available
information is based on other crops
cannabis can still provide this console
provide a good starting point for
cannabis
note the following level descriptions
are direct quotes from the research
paper that I'm going to provide you with
in this graphical representation of the
categorization of virus infection based
on the level of proof and correlation to
symptoms
so let's start with the highest level
what are the ones who should be quote
most concerned about level a of the
classification includes viruses detected
in the field or Greenhouse conditions
toward which in epidemiological survey
is active these viruses can spread
horizontally by vector or by economic
propagation and have been associated
with significant yield losses in sativa
campus adiva as well as other
economically relevant crops now to freak
you out but these are kind of the ones
you want to be most concerned with we
can see a couple here populate and
vibrate which I'll be describing or have
descriptions in other videos beat curly
top virus and lettuce corrosis virus
these are the ones are classified at the
highest Threat Level for Cannabis sativa
going another level lower we've got
classification B we see the list does
get a little bit longer and this does
include viruses which no recent reports
of natural infection in open field or
Greenhouse plants are available but
whose ability to infect Cannabis sativa
and induced symptoms has been proven
through experimental inoculations and
protected environments in the table 2
provided most of these viruses are known
to possess a vector and other
well-studied and characterized crops but
these vectors have yet to be identified
in Cannabis sativa cultivation context
and see keep in mind as I mentioned in
other videos that when the virus name
doesn't necessarily correlate with
cannabis we have a raspberry ring spot
whereas cucumber mosaic virus potato
viruses remember those aware they were
the plant they were first identified in
Threat Level C so we're getting a little
lower here numbers of this level of
viruses detected and symptomatic
cannabis plants from fields or
greenhouses however none of these have
been inferred as virulence determinants
so today is impossible to Define them as
pathogenic or even asymptomatic so again
these are a little bit lower on that
threat level still something if you're
seeing something not looking right you
see one of these it gets screened for
Threat Level letter c
and then lastly the lowest level uh our
Threat Level D virus is detected both in
symptomatic and asymptomatic canvas
sativa characterized to this level no
correlation has been established between
viral infections and symptom development
whereas persistent infection and wide
distribution are the main
characteristics of these viral agents so
according to this criteria Level D
viruses should not be considered a
threat to chemist CTV production so
we're going to get a virus hopefully get
quote one of these if you are going to
get a virus this is the lowest level and
really aren't considered a threat to
cannabis plants
so that kind of grower friendly system
that they came up with is Threat Level
classification makes it easier for
cultivares to know well if they get a
virus and it's identified at what their
level of concern should be and also is
it possible to prevent it from occurring
in the future good information to have
the intention is to provide the key need
to know information to the cultivar
without the complexities of virology
that's that simple classification system
so again if you do have a plate you
think it's infected with a virus get it
screened get identified and then see
what level it matches up with and that
should match your level of concern