here we look at some different ways to
physically help support cannabis plants
and this could be is first very small
plants there are more commonly used on
large plants and here we see an outdoor
grow there's a lot of wind and other
environmental factors so here it becomes
even more advantageous that now there
are these support systems in place but
they're fairly strong and robust so
trellis netting is the first one we see
that kind of going back in that title
slide we see some horizontal and some
vertical Charles netting trellis netting
needs to be layered out ahead of time to
allow plants to grow through it this is
referring to kind of the more horizontal
approach a lot of miss plants to grow up
and through it should be supported well
so plants don't fall over and break
later in the growing cycle when the
upper plant yields increase in weight
this is something that initially because
it's very spaced in a lot of air can
come through it's just fine but as these
plants go through it and become heavy
laden with yield we want to make sure
that it is well established so you're
not jeopardizing your entire crop then
they're stakes easy to apply when and
where they're needed always good to have
a couple extra on hand if you use them
it should be cleaned in some way it's
kind of see at the end of the season
here where we're getting our harvest
seeing how the architecture of those
stakes looked and here's a earlier part
of the grow and we could see them being
tied up here and kind of helped support
those plants keeping the vertical
growing arrangement lastly there's cages
and they're best applied early in the
brine cycle okay now when you put the
plants in the ground soon after that
they can transmit disease if not clean
between uses if constructed of reusable
material such as these wire cages here
these trails ones both the horizontal
and the vertical typically are wrapped
up at the end season and discarded metal
cages are a great option just make sure
you're in some way cleaning them between
your growing seasons