on this debaco university video just
going to go over cannabis information
sharing in a very brief sense and hope
that you do share this channel with
[Music]
others
all right let's get into cannabis
science information sharing so first off
realize that there are limited
uh published studies regarding cannabis
however the advantages it looks like
we're going to be on the increase
and this is mainly been due to the
restriction of the ability for federal
money to be used to spend on research
due to the classification of cannabis
many current studies being published
with
more being released on a continual basis
which will help improve the overall
education
and information set going forward it's
been said here
that more cannabis research will be done
and published in 2021
so the hope is that this rise in
information will give rise to more
detailed information and allow to kind
of the exponential increase
of the information to be spread and
gained and hopefully benefits to people
all over the world
now if you're looking at doing your own
research and don't have an expensive lab
want to see what other scientists are
doing well if you've got a computer and
you're watching this
great research to search for scientific
based articles
is google scholar google's great
starting point but google scholar allows
you to really research some of those
scientific articles which can really
make things
really get into the details and where a
lot of the other information you read
is really originated from
the hope just in general the hope is
that sharing quality information
is very important and hopefully that
will continue this channel tobacco
university's
main goal is to provide just that
scientific based information
and in return hope is that you're able
to share this channel with others to
help bridge the
knowledge gap to spread some information
to put kind of in the comments which you
might want to see in other videos
a new and interesting article you may
have found and hope that we can
build and continue building this
community here
to help education which will help
everyone in the long run