in this debacle University video we'll
look at cannabis breeding and the
transmission of hop latent thyroid
[Music]
okay so if you're looking at creating
new seeds and doing some breeding you
still need to be concerned about hop
latent viroid and particularly how the
cross is being made so in the
description there's a link to some
further research where I got some of
these slides images from but we're going
to dive into that at least provide a
brief overview so this is looking at
infected female plants have a higher
transmission of hopalate and viroid than
when the male plant is infected we could
see that here with experiment one
positive females negative females
positive females with a negative male
negative females with a positive male
fire was present in the seed coat and
inside the seed when the females were
positive thyroid present on the seed go
in inside the seeds when the male was
infected but we see the transmission
rate higher or greater percentage when
the females were infected still
crossover infection even when the male
pollen is basically transferred from one
um to another it can be as high as 43 in
seeds most of the containers found on
the outside of the seed it's important
we're kind of looking at this comparison
here and it shows the basics of the
design this is looking at some of the
results females or positive males were
negative and we could see a higher
fraction with hot plate and thyroid
compared to when the opposite was true
when the females were deemed to be clean
and the males were infected with high
plate and thyroid Stills transmission
but to a lower degree they Quantified
with 31 out of 71 or 43.7 percent varies
from mother to mother and ranges from 23
to 53 so it could be as low as 23 as
high as 53 on average 43. so this is
where testing is really important even
for breeders even if you're like oh it's
just a male plant set in the pollen it
can still transfer over to that next
generation
now there are limitations in the sense
that the hot plate and varied cannot
become part of the Genome of the
particular cultivar it is existing in
some exterior structure it's not
integrated it's part of the chromosomal
structure so that's a good thing that is
going to help us to be able to find a
way to hopefully stop this thyroid off
from spreading
so what can it do what can impact the
epigenetics or the expression of
genetics in the plant and this is
looking at this RNA based but it can go
through verse transcriptases go back to
DNA ultimately looking at coding for
different proteins and leading to gene
expression this is where you get those
different funky weird shaped leaves
those depressed internodal spacings
those yellow colorations to leaves this
is what hopolite enviroid can do
so where's happily United in the actual
um plant well the viral load or the
viroid load I should say is throughout
the entire plant but can be variable at
least initially multiple samples of the
entire plant should be taken when
submitting a sample for screening and
this is important to screen your mail
plants as well as your female plants for
those looking at doing breeding also if
the plant is very young we might want to
sample The Roots but if you're growing a
mother plant or a long time breeding
male plant it will quickly in about six
weeks spread throughout the entire plant
so again the key part with this is
screening testing and repeat testing to
ensure you know your plants are clean
and you're not having any part of the
reading process with that hoplate and
viride even if you're just using the
male plants for their pollen