so here we're going to take a detailed
look at the flowers that cannabis
produces as we know they produce female
flowers or male flowers but being able
to identify those at different stages is
important early on a plant will produce
something called pre-flowers These are
the first way to visually determine if
the plant is male or if the plant is
female you want to look at the leaf node
for these pre-flowers which will
typically be seen after about a month or
so of vegetative growth pre-flowers are
typically found between the fourth and
sixth node as you count up from the base
of a plant it's not advised to induce
flowering until these pre-flowers appear
even though you can have a plant flower
at any time these pre-flowers are kind
of like your indication that the plants
are ready to kind of go into flour the
female pre-flower looks like this and
looking very down at the the node here
kind of see those white kind of
structures sticking out this white
stiglas coming out here's another
example of a female pre-flower with
their stem is a little bit more
developed these white kind of wispy
almost like whiskers
protruding here from the the plant node
here nail pre flowers look a little
different so this is the female this is
the male they don't have more that cup
shape they're going to be the pollen
producing structure and contain the
anthers
here's another example of a male prefler
a little bit more developed we kind of
see again that kind of larger cup shaped
appearance females indicative of that
kind of white stigma if you see here and
here males a little bit larger more bulb
type looking and those will ultimately
produce pollen and the females the
stigma the goal and the end would be to
capture the pollen there
now male flowers as I said they are
producing pollens we see here and this
can be a problem it's the pollen on
canvas is very fine it can travel long
distances in the air you can identify
them since they have a distinct pollen
sacs here here and this is one it's
clearly shedding some pollen these
plants are of little value low
cannabinoid content and should be
discarded to reduce unnecessary labor in
the potential for cross-pollination in
addition the pollen they produce
concrete not only a mess as we see here
on the leaves but could result in
unwanted pollination of neighboring
female flowers
male flowers reach maturity about one to
two weeks ahead of the female flowers so
this is great for identification because
you can usually identify them a little
bit earlier from the plant standpoint
this is advantageous because this way
pollen will be ready in the area when
the females is are receptive to it so
this is why male flowers are a little
bit earlier and this is allowing the
plant to ideally survive in the long
term because it'll always be pollen
available when those females are ready
the meal plan overall male plants
produce less total flour since each
flower can produce high amounts of
pollen even though if you look at this
fully developed male plant you can see
how much flowers are present on it the
reason why they only produce as much is
plants are producing a lot of pollen
grains per single flower so that's
what's allowing us to easily get caught
in the wind easily get caught in
circulation and passed around
the reason why we don't want to grow
plants necessarily to this full size and
Destroy them as early as possible as we
can identify them because if a female
flower gets fertilized the female plant
will transition more to seed formation
and not cannabinoid or CBD production
and that can really reduce the amount of
harvest someone's getting from a
chemical profile standpoint so then
going on to the female flowers their
distinguishing Factor are white fuzzy
stigmas we see here and definitely
evident in this image this structure may
take a little bit more time to develop
as a may be formed after a light green
seed racks at the node so these are kind
of apical buds here very easy to see but
initially if we're looking right at that
leaf node identification these may be a
little slower to develop definitely than
compared to the male flowers should
start looking for them around the fourth
to fifth branch of the internodes as you
work your way up the plant
um there's a way to try to determine the
gender of your plant whether it's female
or whether it's male and the early
determination will be great to allow you
to know early on whether you should be
keeping that plant investing Time and
Labor whether investing fertilizer on
that plant or if you should be
discarding it if it's a male because it
may produce pollen which could
contaminate your entire grow area