the important room in the in the
production of canvas is the vegetative
room so while this may not have the
initial visual appeal of flowers or just
producing leaves here it's a very
critical room and very important one to
be mindful of so the lighting of this
room is important so this room would
favor a metal halide or the new ceramic
metal halides or even full-spectrum LED
lights running at about 18 to 24 hours
minimum would be about 16 I won't really
go in much under that you start running
the risk of cutting the prematurely go
in the flower
these lights help here for the
development necessary leaves and be
slightly smaller than the final flower
room so these plants will be smaller so
they can be a little more packed in but
maintaining that lightning hitting that
continuous hours of light is very
important this is where timers become
your friend and they're very critical to
maintain that 18 to 24 hours as I said
that full spectrum LEDs or ceramic metal
halides are preferred lights for this
particular instance now the vegetative
room can make or break the crop well
this may not have the visual appeal of a
full flower room is a very important
critical room preparing plants for the
soon-to-be stress of flowering is
important so we typically you don't
think of it as the money room the
vegetative room being where the dollars
remain but that preparation step is very
important if the plants aren't prepared
right the flower room will suffer even
though the flower room has a visual
appeal of the flowers it's very
important to having a well-prepared
plant before it goes through the stress
is all flowering and when you're
fertilizing the vegetative room you want
to monitor growth and fertilizers very
likely required at regular intervals
growth formulas which are typically
higher in nitrogen are favored during
the stage of development you want to be
mindful of the amount that you're
fertilizing if you over fertilize
especially with irrigation water and
overhead the nitrogen furnace of
breaking stems and branches this coming
through the pruning or trellising
process I just become more brittle so
this is just a word of caution that you
don't want to have this happen because
they may have to go through a moving PHA
the physical moving phase before they go
to the flowering room lastly here
cleanliness is happiness this is where
the important art of pruning comes into
play where you can see all these
properly trained you want to keep the
floor clean they won't know any dead
leaves either in the pots are on the
floor through queries constant
maintenance
sweeping and pruning and removing of any
dead leaves because if you keep the area
clean you'll reduce the chance of
diseases and ensure a happy crop for
both the plants and also the grower