then we're looking at growing the actual
cannabis and getting to the final end
result that flower or those cannabinoids
can end up in many different end or
final products so I want to go over just
what a couple of those are first off is
the obvious wonder that's the flower net
allows offer actual inspection of the
final product however can have great
variability even if to dispensary is
carrying the same name you have
different effects typically the flower
requires joints to be used which require
rolling and some people enjoy or
pre-rolls
as they take the work out of smoking so
in both these cases the flower is the
actual plant produced product in its raw
form then we get to something called
hash which is a resin which is consumed
by smoking a small apparatus kind of
refining and getting away from the
actual flower or end product of the
actual plant and transforming it into a
different form
then there's edibles which there's no
need to smoke the product so it's
commonly infusing gummies or candies or
other treats there was an area of
concern with edibles since I am the
pictures here is that minors can get a
hold of them since they look like normal
products and others are concerns with
these are people over consuming without
realizing since there's a delayed effect
sometimes 30 Delta up to 60 minutes
after consumption so they could consume
in this case on one piece of cake or one
brownie and then wait 15 minutes and say
well nothing happened let me have
another one and not really if there's a
delayed effect in their effects after
the consumption particularly for THC for
CBD want to be careful and avoid
overdosing that's what I want to be very
careful and treat this as medicine
there's topicals which are lotions and
balms which are typically used for
localized pain for a very specific area
and make for a very easy application
there's concentrates or oils which is a
broad category that includes butts not
women - such as wax shatters butters or
hashes what this allows is the chemical
compounds of the flower to be literally
concentrated and made more consistently
to a
for more specific dosing we have the
vape pens which offer quick and easy
usage the main issue those increased use
of liners using due to the ease of
concealing the very small easy and -
you're getting the hold these at very
young ages and that's causing a major
issue