okay we are going through and thinking
about cloning can this plant there are
certain tools of the trade that you need
to be aware of if you want to use the
right tool for the right job and here's
a couple outlines here that I'm going to
go into a little bit of detail lasso
healthy mother plant sharp knife reading
hormone media sterile solution
sterilization solution high humidity
lights and clean conditions are all
things you want to have in place if
you're going to go through the cloning
process so starting first with a healthy
mother plant so healthy mother plants
are very important if the stock plant is
in poor health that will directly result
in poor clones and can reduce the
percentage that will actually root
remember cutting us to go in a
high-stress environment so we wanted to
ensure that it produces roots that it
needs we need the mother plant of the
stock plant here to be in peak health so
that this dress that the clones or the
tips are going to go through although
able to not only survive that let go
through and actually produce roots and a
healthy subsequent plant
neither sharp knife so provides a clean
cut to allow for efficient water
transport scissors are not advised since
this will crush the vascular system so
it can be a sharp pocketknife doesn't
have to necessarily be a scalpel but
think about if you put flowers in a vase
when a nice clean cut to allow water to
transpire through and easily enter the
inner vascular system of the plant
breeding hormone it could be a gel or
powder that contains oxygen clinics gels
the best I personally is we can see kind
of an evident here these two boot nodes
have gotten treated with clinics and
gels you can see the large roots and
then these have not associated the
presence of roots here and here but not
nearly to the extent of those that were
treated with the hormone so yes hormones
can have a great impact increasing the
ability for a plant to root media often
rockville because there's other options
such as growing media can be just as
effective for cloning adding Heat and
that can help ensure or encourage the
rooting in the root zone environment so
they see some cubes here you see that
Rockville's kind of made out of that
almost spongy like material the only
little heat mat can help increase the
heat to some extent of the root zone
encouraging a quicker rooting process a
sterilization solution the isopropyl
alcohol is one example
and to keep every part of the process
clean and disease free as possible so
cleaning tools such as the knife is
important and to repeat so that the odds
of transferring disease is reduced what
this means is you want these clean
sterile conditions for the entire
process don't clean the knife at the
beginning take a bunch of clothes from
20 different plants and then clean that
knife at the end I'm going to be
repeating the cleaning process the
sterilization process in between maybe
different plants or even if you're
working at a large plant even as you
take multiple cuttings go through that
process again to reduce your chance of
spreading disease high humidity
environment humidity dome or chamber can
be done this reduces the stress on the
recent cutting so you can see how
they're looking here that nice humidity
dome there being second media here
they're under a lot of stress he lack
roots that high humidity will help
prevent or reduce the chance of these
plants burning the lights to use they
should be running 18 to 24 hours if
fluorescents are often preferred by some
did their soft light and low heat
generation CAMHS or Cermak metal halides
can be used disease can cover the same
area as a fluorescent but require only
one bulb and last longer than
fluorescence LEDs can also be
well-suited full-spectrum their low heat
low power consumption which is great but
for this purpose it can be cost
prohibitive as a result most people
using fluorescence circular halide kind
of replacing those and LEDs would be
great but often too expensive to justify
for this process we want clean
conditions this is a very important part
regardless of the entire process that
does the knife in sterilization of that
you want clean conditions overall this
is often underestimated because the high
plant density if one plant gets sick it
can quickly spread to other plants
clean the area before during and after
cloning it's great and you want to make
sure again that the tray is the media
the tags the areas are placed in
infinity domes everything is clean
ideally close to sterile as possible
tools of the trade a quick summary again
a healthy mother plant very important
that sharp clean knife rooting hormone a
gel or powder
media often Rockwell but other options
sterilization solution clean conditions
at high humidity and some form of
lighting run at 18 to 20
four hours hopefully this will help you
work through and know they have the
proper tools in the trade for cloning