okay human focus I'm chemist seed basics
misused a general seed pictured here
where we have the seed coat which is the
outer shell the embryo contains the hypo
coddles or radical and the cotyledons so
let's look specifically at cannabis
seeds
well seeds in general whether it's a
cannabis or a tomato or a pepper seed
all contain living but dormant organism
so this is important to remember that
there in that seed is a living organism
and as it organism dies that will reduce
the germination rate a lot of seeds now
the DNA is also present in these seeds
which will determine the characteristics
of the plant in selecting the proper
seed or really more appropriate term
leading the proper genetics to match the
growing conditions is important items to
consider or whether you're growing
indoors or outdoors looking for THC or
CBD production keep in mind this course
is focusing on hemp plants so a CBD
production would be one area would be
focused on much more than THC content
mature seeds have a dark coloration are
hard and they tend to be declaration
hard outer shell these tend to be the
most mature and have the greatest chance
for germination if you look at this kind
of lot seeds here this kind of
compilation of seeds well no some are
kind of white some are green these
colorations also indicate that these
tend to be softer seeds to the touch
these indicate immature seeds these will
have poor germination rates then the
harder outer shell that's typically
shown with this darker coloration here
the darker colors will have a greater
germination rate than the immature seeds
developed in a comparison between a
mature and immature seeds mature seed
should be full in uniform as we see here
give them a drop and listen for a thud
if you hear a hollow sound like these
seeds would give this is a sign of
immature seeds so you see the comparison
of these two was the dime there for size
orientation see these are very
consistent tend to be darker colorations
and to be more consistent larger size
these will likely have a much better
germination rate than these immature
seeds here see the anatomy we have the
seed codes they mentioned that's that
protective outer covering we have
cotyledons and kinases and dicot these
are the seed leaves and these be the
first ones to appear once the seed
murders the hypo coddled located right
here is the area of the stem
the roots in soil line and also the
cotyledon waves the radical is the
initial root that is produced from the
seed so we talked about emergence that's
the seed actually plant breaking through
the surface germination is typically
marked by this radical protruding
through the seed coat there be like a
little tail that you would notice proper
seed storage will controlling the
environment the seed is stored will help
increase germination percentages over
time key is consistency if there's a
rapid fluctuations and changes this can
decrease seed vitality however even
under ideal conditions germination rates
will decrease with the age of the seed
growing conditions the goal to try to
maintain as humidity under 10%
temperature from 40 degrees Fahrenheit
to zero degrees Fahrenheit and light
minimal light if any exposure let me
keep the seeds typically in the darker
in an area that is not having a lot of
consistent or very bright light exposure
she should be kept in some form of label
packaged in an environment as cool and
dark to be like a refrigerator a freezer
even a sock drawer in some cases
well the seeds will last about 5 years
if stored properly I want to be sure to
keep seeds away from moisture and this
is a concern as a preventative when
you're storing your seeds when I choose
an airtight container and these little
silica gel packets can be advised to be
included till Polson without moisture
out and labeling those pack those seeds
are very important because you could see
these could easily get mixed up so
keeping them labeled keeping them sealed
allows for reduction in the chance of
miss aligning different seeds and
ensuring you're growing what you think
you're growing
lastly canning jars offer an excellent
for seed storage these are airtight they
can hold many seeds in different
containers they fit easily in the
freezer or other locations they also
prevent unwanted interaction so I give
the example the mice here eating seeds
just keep the season like an envelope or
something when it gets cold out mice can
be for ASIS eaters and get into all
sorts of things you can easily choose
through paper or even sometimes plastic
containers mason jars here are sealed
glass airtight will prevent any unwanted
feeding on your seeds