so on this debaco university video i'm
going to just go a brief
overview here of regarding cannabis
[Music]
education so education is important in
any walk of life like here we're going
to look a little bit more at
the importance of cannabis education and
when looking at campus education well
i'd like to say that you're in the right
place
the goal of this channel is to provide a
quality education
on all the topics covered regarding
canvas this can be difficult to come by
to get that kind of
information that is scientifically based
and by connecting to established
scientific information
this can help propel the expanse of
canvas education
forward and here at debaca university
hopefully you've seen some other videos
on that
try to connect a lot to the scientific
research while maybe somewhat limited
to again drive some more conversation
and to hopefully
keep propelling the education forward
now we want to avoid opinions now
opinions can be great initially
but for real basis of information
sometimes opinions as well as anecdotal
information can be
hard to separate from scientific based
information so be sure to trace
a source of the information presented
the goal
is really to base any sort of
conclusions or information you're
looking at
in scientific research this can be
difficult to find
and it can also be difficult to
initially read and that's why part of
the goal of this channel
is to kind of break it down and give you
kind of the adrenal summary if you have
more interest you can go into more
detail
now keep in mind opinions any little
information
opinions are kind of great at the very
first level here
but we want to work our way up to kind
of the more advanced
levels we're looking at research end of
things so it's a good starting point but
keep in mind it is only a starting point
so how could you go about kind of
starting your own scientific
investigation
well google scholar is a very powerful
search engine and tool to use
it's uh it's quickly uh it's quick to be
able to use it's very user friendly can
find
articles and topics that are
scientifically based so it's a good kind
of
area to start just search it type in
whatever you're interested in this
applies to cannabis as well as any other
topic
as well google scholar is a great way to
kind of be able to efficiently
search a lot of scientific articles
quickly
so when you find one scientific article
that you like well as i say one good
article
can lead to many more when you're
finding scientific articles the goal is
to find out one article you like on a
topic
well structured be sure to look at the
sources for potentially other related
articles as well look at their reference
list this can lead to an expansive list
but can help provide a well-rounded
education
also when you're reading the scientific
article there might be a little number
or last name
you can then match that up to the
reference list and then go research that
original article
it's a great way to kind of get more
into the details whatever topic
or subject area you're looking at
learning about
now scientific articles are provided so
when scientific
articles are presented here at least on
this channel debaco university
they come with the proper reference
citation apa style
you can easily find them and you're
welcome to use this as
a starting point so here's just one
example right here i give you
a screenshot of like the first page of
the article i give you the proper
citation
as well as a link summaries are provided
in the videos provided here
but you are welcome to go through and
research that article for yourself to
get more detail
if you're interested particularly in
that topic
now here at debacle university we're not
just a standalone area we are
utilized these videos are utilized at
the university of connecticut
the new york botanical gardens as well
as florida gulf coast
university at least ones that i'm
directly aware of
i'm sure there are many others if you're
watching us from another university or
another professors link these videos be
sure to comment
in the comments below this video here
uh hopefully it's always great to see uh
in information to be educating students
on cannabis as well as other topics is
biology and forensic science
it's always great to see where students
are from so if you want to comment by
always go right ahead but hopefully this
is helping
spread the positive word the good
scientific backed
information regarding cannabis education