now cloning is a common practice with
cannabis plants so we're gonna go over
if you were to dedicate an entire room
to that what would it look like you know
you can see many growers will and they
can be small operations they can be very
large operations depending on the
cloning just to point out initially here
on both of these instances you see the
labeling which is important to keep
track of those clones so you know
exactly what you have and where it came
from
now the general comparison of clone
rooms to regular rooms it will they
should be the smallest of the rooms and
this is including or comparing to
vegetative and flowering rooms
simply because the plants will be the
smallest and you want to control
humidity a temperature so keeping
everything small makes it a little bit
easier to go about doing that
then comparison to like a large flower
room clone rooms for as far as lighting
goes fluorescent lights are advised that
this is reduced power consumption and
minimal heat generated
however ceramic metal halides are
gaining popularity for the reduced
number of bulbs and ease in comparison
to fluorescents typically t5
fluorescents have been used however I
think going forward Cermak male halides
are going to be replacing t5 fixtures t5
fixtures with fluorescents require long
bulbs many bulbs this is one light here
when light bulb can do a large area very
similar to what two fives can do also
bulb life is much longer into mobile
ballast here so there's a lot of
advantages going to ceramic metal
halides over fluorescence in t5
fluorescence in particular again that
lighting that us this is at six hundred
and fifteen watts for male halide or a
thousand watt metal halide can be used
to efficiently cover a large area land
propagating large number of clones
keeping this light intensity low on
plants so the foliage is not burned can
be accomplished by paying this light of
good distance away usually at least
about five feet if you get two moveable
ballasts that's also a great option
because that was it hang it the same
height and just kind of go through and
adjust it there or hang shape anything
between the light and the plants that
can help again reduce the chance of
burning the tender plants if you're
trying to maintain or use the same
lights for multiple purposes so here we
see scaling up so clone room or a clone
tent in this case and staking up a two
by two
area.this the clones that are propagated
in this 2x2 area can support an 8x8
flowering law so when a plan accordingly
because remember in this small
propagation plants roomy very close
together I did this for a little size
comparison this is a 2x2 grow tent this
is only a 4 foot by 2 foot 10 so an 8 by
8 is a much larger area so if you pack
this small 2x2 structure and you want to
make all those clones to make it you
want to be sure that you also have for
at least flowering stage and 8 by 8 grow
tend to help support though all the
clones that are produced in that small
2x2 area prepare the material we want to
make sure that mother plant will be
providing the clones is a healthy plant
because that's critical to the success
of the vegetative process or the
propagation process here the cloning in
particular I want to make sure that
mother or stock plant is as healthy as
possible so in that clone room we want
to keep the conditions around 70 to 80
degrees Fahrenheit simply hanging a
thermometer would be great to help
monitor that make sure you're staying
within that range humidity 70 to 100
percent again depending how early in the
propagation cloning process 100 percent
very early and then reducing that over
time to 70 percent those higher amounts
early will help reduce the chance that
the Leafs are going to burn as things
are going to desiccate out yeah I want
to prepare for the outside if our clones
are going to go into an outside
environment for that transition plan
should be putted into larger containers
and deeper containers to allow for a
larger root development and profile to
be established before going the very
stressful outside environment the also
should be what's called hardened off
before being placed in the field by
exposing them to bright light again when
it work them up to brighter light before
we just throw them outside into the
harsh full Sun of the outside the use of
ceramic metal halides can reduce
hardening off time has printed
transition to the harsh again natural
sunlight so I want to be mindful what
lights you are using if you go from
fluorescents those are very subdued
lights and great for propagation
well if you're looking at ultimate going
outside you might want to use a higher
discharge light it's for reduce the
chance those plants are going to burn
when they hit the outside
the summary here these clone rooms can
be simple effective even use grow tents
in some instances Rockville can be used
as routing media humidity domes across
the nights are often easy and effective
we can also add a heat mat here to help
encourage routing here so we have the
humidity dome to maintain the amenity
and he'd met here to keep those rooting
areas a little bit warmer he is the
transfer clones to more light and less
MIDI to ease their transition to the
soon-to-be vegetative environment