welcome to another debaco university
video here we're going to be looking at
some of the details behind cannabis
sativa i'm going to be explaining some
of the morphological characteristics
where it might be used
some advantages as well as some of its
disadvantages as a strain in general
so looking first at the origin well this
isn't the annual herbaceous flowering
plant it's in goodness to eastern asia
but is now very
widespread throughout the entire globe
this is probably where it originated
from it's been cultivated throughout
recorded history and it's been
has a very diverse history of its use
it's been used for industrial fiber seed
oil food recreation
religious and spiritual foods and
medicine there's a whole bunch of
different uses that's been used for
each part of the plant is harvested
differently depending on what the
purpose of the use
is and it was first classified by carl
linnaeus in 1753
and the word sativa means things that
are cultivated so it applies to kind of
a lot of other
plants indicas and other flowering
plants just in general but
the sativa is thought to be one of the
more original
ones there the morphology of these
sativa strains they're typically very
tall growing 14 to 15 feet tall
their internode spacing is about three
to six inches and their leaves if you
took one off would be very long and thin
compared to some of the other strains
make sure you have the height to grow in
the area if you are planning on growing
a sativa a
strain of cannabis however remember that
they're also photoperiod dependent which
can limit their height so careful timing
and planting for outdoor locations or
manipulation of photo period
for an indoor location can to some
degree
limit their overall height that they
achieve now popular cultivation
locations for sativas
are outdoors because of the areas with
long growing season because of the
height that they get
this season also prefer to get maximum
yield from this type of plant
others will time it to be later in the
season to limit the height due to the
change in the natural photo period
if you are growing in a greenhouse or
high tunnel or something as a ceiling
limit there's also the possibility to be
mindful
for the potential limitations of how
tall that plant could get so it may
outgrow your location
pruning is recommended to help increase
the plant efficiency and ultimately the
yields
if you're wondering what are some common
sativa cultivars well there are many
it's an extensive list
a one is high in thc but sour diesel
very common
or famous on the east coast united
states as well as many
many others that just provided a quick
list of three there for some comma
sativa cultivars to help you understand
ones that fall into this classification