in this tobacco University video we're
going to go over cannabis edibles
[Music]
let's get into some understanding of
just what cannabis Edibles actually are
so some of the products mentioned here
are derived from CT Pharma and the
reason why they were chosen is they
offer a lot of publicly available
analytical reports that they produce and
you can go through and access those also
in this video the descriptions opinions
and uses are intended to provide an
understanding of some of the end
products of the cannabis plant and those
analytical reports will be provided at
the end and they're often a missed
component that should accompany any
product someone is interested in
purchasing
so let's get into the description of
Edibles well they are either ready to be
eaten or ready to be infused food items
with marijuana or a cannabis plant in
result they have multiple different
dosage and a multitude of different food
variations and because of this it is
kind of a word of caution if you're
going to be looking at Edibles to make
sure you definitely have them distinctly
isolated and kept only for adult use you
don't want these to fall into the hands
of children it can be very easy for that
to occur
so the options of Edibles we could see
very common products honey infused
baking mix drink mix olive oil
different doses associated with these
strings usually low to medium for the
most part and again if you've watched
other videos you see some have high
strength some have medium strength these
tend to be low to medium but keep in
mind that we do want to be protective of
these items labeling them sectioning
them similar different making sure that
kids don't come in contact with these
particular edible options
now the use of Edibles it can be
consumed orally for strong medical
effects it will set in about 45 minutes
to an hour after consumption that's an
important note to make that's not an
immediate effect there is a delay so you
don't want to be mindful of the dosage
that you're incurring you want to be
taking one dose and then immediately 10
minutes later taking another and another
because there is that delayed effect
infused olive oil and Bake Mix can be
added directly to any any sort of baking
recipe or cooking a choice to properly
Infuse with active in this case THC but
again you want to be mindful keeping
them away from children
so as I mentioned at the beginning those
importance of the certificate of
analysis and yes many people will
probably be looking at the cannabinoid
profiles or the terpenes and that's well
and good but we want to be mindful also
of looking at some of the other things
such as microbiology microtoxins heavy
metal and pesticides making sure we're
passing all of those you can also see
here the detection levels for different
pesticides making sure we're passing all
of those as well a lot of times these
numbers will come present on the label
which is a great thing as we can see on
all of these labels but it's also your
right as a consumer to make sure the lot
numbers are matching up to those
original analytical reports so that your
informed consumer