okay so here I'm going to talk about the
cannabis cup this is often mentioned
quite a bit and you might see seeds or
cultivars labels cannabis cup winner so
I should describe a little bit about
what this is all about well within the
cannabis cup there might be many out
there but kind of the High Times
Cannabis Cup is someone it's kind of
regarded as the most widely accepted it
has categories rules regulations and
everything I present here space in the
2017 competition there may be some
changes so use this as a point in time
reference guide always check the current
year's competition rules Edition only
some reason provided so consult the full
list of rules directly linked to the
rules for that used in the presentation
are right here if you want to go through
and find them this is a direct link to
them so again if any competition should
know the rules this is from 2017
so why the High Times Cannabis couple
it's large and well-established event
that has set some of the standards for
judging and competition that's why I
chose to focus on this one in particular
as with any competition our rules
established but there are also some
potential concerns I've attempted to
provide some opinions and potential
shortcomings of the rules that are
presented now the official rules
important notes all judging for High
Times Cannabis Cup is conducted by
doctor prescribed in state licensed
medical marijuana patients entries are
collected and distributed under the
legal frameworks of each state's legal
medical or recreational cannabis program
or guidelines so that's their official
kind of stated rules now a general
statement they do hold the human element
as a judging system is a variable
component in the process even so they're
measurable science component so they
typically have a qualitative and
quantitative depending on what category
and they want to have that experiences
like the driver experience with also
that kind of lab based kind of results
so the qualitative side of scoring sheet
accounts for about seventy percent while
the quantitative side accounts for about
thirty percent and against through
Sanders may vary by category but that
thirty percentage that quantitative is
more that scientific lab results
qualitative is more that human
experience so general categories are
listed here I'm going to go through them
for each category a summary of the
category and description we presented
followed by my comments the same format
will be used for judging and scoring
information
sections so here we're looking at the
flower category so I'm not going to bore
and go through all the rules you can
pause if you don't read those for
yourself but in this flower category we
limit to the sativa indicated flower
entries well right there the this is the
part where the use of sativa and
indicating indica categories continues
to exist you use as criteria to be
defined even though there are only
morphological differences not actual
chemical differences so this kind of is
part of just continuing that kind of
debate in that separation are that
thought of separation between indica and
sativa is when there's no scientific
basis for that the judging and scoring
for flowers the use of lab tests focuses
on the actual content of THC or CBD
however tripping levels can impact the
taste and profile kinda like a fine wine
also since this is the actual plant
product how it physically looks as taken
into consideration so it's again it's
that lab component that human experience
and also that visual effects
concentrates in non solvent hash there's
a category this again shows the
difficulty to change that you may need
to use the term cultivar they're using a
lot of like you know you can see the
terms of you know strains and you know
varieties and not necessarily cultivars
and get away from these category
classifications that may be established
but lack scientific support so just
because it's constantly settle indicas
and sativas this is again not showing a
strong scientific basis for that even
though it's commonly established in the
industry to the current point in time at
least now the judging the use of lab
tests focuses on again the actual
teaching in CBD have again those terpene
profiles can affect the taste this is
similar to the flower category but since
hash has been processed it has a certain
expected visual appearance for that
consistency now edibles is a category
has to be a very broad category takes
into account the actual product but also
the packaging is part of the scoring
criteria criteria which makes blind
judging that possible when producing the
product the packaging is also very
important in this category addresses the
need for quality product and also
quality advertising the judging as it
shows a very diverse marketplace here
and lack of consistency one
flaws at product labels in packaging are
simply graded on this criteria category
as being present and are not actually
checked or verified that what stated on
the package matches the test result so
that's a major issue because this can be
misleading and the miss this concept to
the consumer that what is on the label
actually represents what's in the
product so this misconception is kind of
like oh it's on the label it's got to be
in the product not necessarily verified
at least in this case for the edibles
CBD entries so this demonstrates that
there's more than just percentage of CBD
at play when selecting a cultivar also
getting into the look of you know not
relying solely on those lab results in
the past that they have they've
demonstrated it's just more than CBD at
play there's more to that however this
does add a variable to the category and
that can you know cause a different
rating system I mean hard to find but
the exact definition is for that within
the judging adding the human and lab
result speaks to the importance of the
experience or that kind of relates in
the terpene level as much as the quality
of CBD that is produced in that final
product
there's the vape pen category so this is
part of a larger challenges the ease of
use of such devices in flavoring
additives indicating the focus on
recreation unless on medical value so
again while this can be a great way for
very easy way there must be a way that's
too easy I was newly established in 2016
the kidding its popularity but the
flavoring additives kind of get that
focused more on that recreation unless
in the medical value also we look at the
judging the scoring an issue is that
extra points are awarded to a vape pen
that's more stealthier further dividing
the manufacturing to produce something
that can be hidden even if there's you
know exponential uses of these style
products by underage individuals so this
kind of favoring that concealing is only
driving that potential use by underage
users so that can be an issue that the
rewarding companies for making a better
concealed product also it's nice to see
that adding ingredients directions and
warning labels get bonus points
not a requirement so again it's kind of
speaks to and I lastly the shadiness of
this particular category and part of
reason why in such a bad rap is because
of these particular reasons here
topicals are becoming an increasing
popular which justifies their recent
inclusion for pain relief in particular
the judging of this category and if use
topical is required to participate but
keep in mind at the level or
concentration is not a classification so
as a user you need to keep the total
amount product contains as a
consideration it's not a requirement at
all topicals must contain X amount of
percent so again just important to keep
that in mind with the various
cannabinoid infused products that are
out there the judging process high x is
a scoring system so they kind of a
scorecard that gets placed employees
two-tier digital and online and score
sheet and of these score book includes
qualitative and quantitative scores each
entry score averages will then be added
to correlated with the lab results by
the uploaded data this system that
combines the judges averages qualitative
score with the quantitative lab score
get in the final total of possible 100
points chemist clef closing judging
statement at high times strives to
create most accurate and comprehensive
scoring system in the canvas industry
your participation in feedback as a
competitor is integral to the process we
hope you're proud to be a part of the
process and we thank you for your
support
patience as we continually evolve the
system into the world's ultimate canvas
scoring index so they do give
indications that they are willing to
change again this is just looking at
2017 as a point in time definitely areas
I think for improvement and as we get
more people on board here that we can
start to see some of the flaws and
high-time seems that they're striving
for that accuracy so it is that
potential for change
lastly cannabis cup winners are they in
the industry this is a high honor and
it's something that is a mark of
excellence cultivars are often regarded
as blank ears canvas cup winner you know
the 2010 cannabis cup winner of the 2016
canvas Cup winner you'll see that a lot
of the times so departing to go back to
the rules and see what that actually
means what they actually have to do to
qualify for that
it's more to understand some degree
which the grading system and to this
label so you have a meaning or what mean
making a comparison between two
varieties just because sometimes at
canvas a couple winner should be
regarded as a blanket statement look
back and see what some of the
requirements are for that and again the
yurt may have one if you can find those
rules for that particular year all the
better