on this debaco university video we'll be
going over canvas pruning options
things you might want to consider as
well as some of the advantages and
disadvantages so you can select the best
pruning method
that fits your growing situation
[Music]
all right let's get into cannabis
pruning options during the vegetative
stage of cannabis production
so first off the general concept of
pruning is that it directs the plant to
be efficient with
its production different methods can
direct the plant to best match the given
growing conditions
what you're trying to do is eliminate
any unwanted parts so
by removing these unneeded plant areas
this can help reduce the chance for
disease by simply increasing air flow
and it can also increase the yield of
wanted plant components
so for example these lower leaves here
could breed disease could help
reduce air circulation by removing those
we can get a plant that can maximize the
light exposure
reduce the chance of disease and
hopefully also maximize our yields
so the pruning techniques covered now in
this video i'm just going to give the
simple advantages and disadvantages of
each
however if you search this channel you
should be able to find
more detailed videos on each of these
pruning methods here
such as topping sea of green screen of
green the fin technique super cropping
lollipop and not pruning canvas plants
what will happen with that
so first off if you're looking or
considering plant topping
also called tipping or pinching the
plant the advantage is it's really easy
to do as we can see here you take the
find that main stalk and you just
basically
top it or pinch it off the is that
it limits the number of branch points
that you can have there
so here we're getting basically from one
we're going to two we're essentially
doubling that
but really we can see that once this is
pinched we'll determine
how we grow those out this could be part
or integrated as part of other
techniques but true topping or pinching
is really just removing that top apical
meristem
now the sea of green this helps improve
yields
and allows for a quicker harvest time
you can see here basically it creates a
sea or a kind of a good solid canopy
of all the plant tops the disadvantage
though it's not a good option
for limited plant grows meaning if you
can only grow
a couple plants not really kind of the
option
there it's also reduced effectiveness is
the plant can grow unevenly
so basically what we're trying to create
here it's kind of that kind of solid
canopy
of buds here with kind of really quickly
turn around
quick turnaround times for the plants
comparing that to the screen of green
technique well this can be applied to
many different strains but tends to work
best for those that have long
tall and a leggy habit such as sativa
morphology
the advantage is it really doesn't
maximize the space that each plant can
take up
often also also offers even light
exposure for all buds
so if we're looking here we have one
plant we're basically pruning it out so
that it spreads out this way
this is called the screen of green
reason being it typically involves some
sort of mesh
screen that mesh screen does require to
be set up ahead of time
and needs to be timed well with the
plant growth rate
greater space is needed per plant so
that's a disadvantage of this method
however unlike the sea of green where
you're kind of printing all your plants
to be smaller and quicker turnaround
times
this can be more advantageous also if
you're looking at limited number of
plants
you can take one plant you can really
spread it out over a large
area but it does take a little bit
longer then we have the thin technique
this technique is typically used along
with other pruning techniques to
maximize both
methods typically the screen of green
and sea of green pruning methods will be
incorporated
with this potentially the advantage is
it's very similar to topping
in the sense that you are pinching a
portion of the plant here but
instead it promotes a bushier growth
this can maximize
those looking to clone a plant because
instead of just pinching the plant
getting two
you're pinching it in a way that
basically allows multiple
branch points to come out this
encourages lateral side branching which
can make for a denser plant
and these plants will often require
staking so be mindful of that if you're
looking at adopting this pruning method
it's not advised for autoflowers because
this delay of this
time it takes to produce these other
branches this delay in pla
in plant growth is best to kind of hold
plants in the vegetative state for four
to six weeks
and with autoflowers when you have that
dedicated number of days until harvest
that delay can offset the plant timing
and reduce your overall yields per plant
then we also have super cropping and
here we see kind of it's like we're not
breaking the plant here we're bending it
pretty aggressively here
and this can produce high yields it
allows more light penetration down here
deeper in the canopy
it also helps reduce plant height
without removing plant material so if
you've got a plant that's getting really
close to a light
you can super crop it we're basically
bending it right over the disadvantages
it does require a bit of technique
because if done wrong the plant yields
will suffer in the sense if you're
breaking the plants off
that can be at a disadvantage the
advantageous point where you're kind of
pinching it getting it to here
looks pretty severe and it kind of is
but this plant will continue to grow
here you're not breaking it at this
point
it's also a stressful to the plant so
timing and care should correlate with
this pruning method
you don't always want to go through into
super crop you want to make sure you're
timing things
in reducing plant stresses as well
we also have the lollipop method and the
goal here is to maximize the buds
uh it's often used with this screen of
green technique it gets the
name lollipopping because you're
basically taking all the lower leaves
off you can see it looks like a bunch of
sticks
you kind of get that big bulge at the
top there so it sort of looks like a
lollipop
the disadvantage is it requires repeated
rounds of pruning and leaf removal
so this is relatively labor-intensive
you can see it here as well but the goal
here
is that the leaves will be the amount of
sun
or light exposure and then lastly
mentioned here just what if you choose
not to print your canvas plants well
it's an easy
method because there's basically no work
involved i think that's why some growers
do choose it
but the disadvantages is it reduced
plant efficiency and it can also
increase plant diseases because it's so
dense there's leaves on top of leaves
so keep that in mind that if you are not
going to prune your cannabis plant
you could be getting more diseases more
insect pressure
and basically not making the plant as
efficient as it could be
so with this brief exclamation
advantages and disadvantages of each was
helpful
there's one you want to learn more about
search this channel and hopefully you'll
have some more
detail provided for each