on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over some canvas
bud storage options some do's and don'ts
so hopefully you can have
uh select a proper location for good
long-term storage of what you've put so
much effort into
[Music]
all right let's get into canvas bud
storage options here ones to consider
well first off what not to store
cannabis in a daily would be plastic is
not advised
plastic can be used for short-term
storage but here we're looking at
long-term storage and in this case
plastic would not be advised
either in the plastic baggie form or
even in the plastic
container typically not advised for the
longer term storage great for short term
or transfer no problem with that
also the fridge typically not an advised
location
the refrigerator and freezer there is
likely an automatic defroster
that can cause swings in humidity that
could result in potential for plant
damage
particularly if you don't have a
completely good seal on everything
i want to be mindful of that
refrigeration temperature is a good
thing but sometimes directly in the
refrigerator there's too much
fluctuation of those
temperatures that occurs now what is
advised i do recommend using
humidity packs and two-way humidity
packs these are the bodiva ones
that can be used to help maintain
consistent conditions now they're
two-way
which means that they can help raise or
lower humidity
to try to keep it within that range in
this case both of these would be keeping
it as close to 62 percent humidity as
possible
now this does not mean that if you have
wild swings and humidity that you're
going to be able to regulate
if you're already kind of close by
inserting one of these packs it'll help
it
maintain definitely within the desired
range and they come in different
humidities
62 for cannabis tends to be one of the
more common ones that's utilized
and your general storage conditions well
stable inert storage container
i will talk more about those on other
videos on this channel minimal light
particularly uv light
and temperatures of 4 degrees celsius or
lower
now if there's all these different
specialty storage options as we can see
here
does not need to be some necessarily
some high-end
store here it can be kind of simple i'll
put in a
closed cupboard here as long as it's
stable conditions the
material it's made out of is inert
minimal light particularly uv light and
the temperatures
are relatively cool all good advice here
as far as keeping your cannabis buds
in nice long term duration storage
there'll be more detailed videos on this
channel you're welcome to search but
hopefully this gives you just general
an idea to consider and you can get more
into
specifics on other videos