so in part what makes cannabis such a
unique plant is here there's a job that
has nothing to do with the actual
production of the plant
but is still very important and that's
the process of
extraction so if you want to learn more
about what's involved with cannabis
extraction continue to watch this
debaco university video
[Music]
all right let's get into the
all-important job of extraction when it
comes to cannabis producing that final
purified
end product so first off the general job
description
the laboratory director is responsible
for engineering cps's cannabinoid
extraction efficiency and tracking
programs developing product sets and
continually creating efficient and
repeatable methods
for product production i want to ensure
that whatever we're doing is able to
produce while it may look like a goopy
substance in the end
is very repeatable this laboratory
director in the attraction room this
also develops implements
oversees the extraction purification and
formulation
of cannabinoid-based compounds they're
all about how do they isolate
one particular compound one particular
molecule from might be a
great mixture of molecules the
day-to-day activities
of an extractor is looking at ensuring
laboratory meets appropriate safety and
security standards
and some could be very simple some could
be very large operations
they're going to also direct the
extraction purification laboratories
within the company
and that will depend on the size
interact with suppliers for purchasing
equipment components
soils as well as amendments they're also
responsible for developing new products
to meet the demands of the market
and they communicate with third-party
testing laboratory for product release
testing
product shelf life studies and new
product characterization so there's a
lot involved
with those isolation processes they
supervise staff working in extraction
purification laboratories
as well as kind of looking through and
developing
those protocols and refining those
protocols on a day-to-day basis
now the qualities that a person must
have if you're looking at pursuing
um extraction is experiencing working
with extraction and purification of
botanical products for human use
very special skill set involved with
this so i want to have at least some
experience with this a working knowledge
of good manufacturing practices the
statistical processes
and the six sigma production
methodologies why because you're working
in such a stringent
area want to be very controlled and
directed with
your day-to-day processes proficient in
quality management systems
you want a working knowledge of human
drug production regulations
as well as industry standards to know
what to produce advanced
science degree 10 plus years of
experience in the cannabis
pharmaceutical industries involved
are required in some facilities
particularly those higher end
facilities so um this is a very detailed
process
can learn it you know throughout the you
know some of the processes at some of
the smaller
areas but when we get into the larger
scale production
very small room for any potential error
there
now connection to cannabis industry in
general
is that the chemist extraction jobs are
a necessary step in the future of the
industry
new extraction methods are continuously
being tested to increase efficiency
of extraction many consumers prefer
extracts over flour
as we push forward into the future the
extract industry will only get larger
so some are still about the dry flour
but a lot of people getting into the
oils
the crumbles shatters things like that
so as a result
there's gonna be a greater demand for
jobs with an extraction
for cannabis and being sure you're
dialed in to produce a
high quality final extract is going to
become
very sought after even more so than is
today