welcome to this debaco university video
here we're going to be looking at
cannabis seed selection options
comparing and giving some of the pros
and cons to the
diesel seeds we are 50 50 male to female
or
choosing feminized seeds which one might
be the best fit for your operation
we'll discuss here on this video
[Music]
all right well looking at our canvas
seed selection options as i mentioned
diocese or feminized seed which one
would you choose keep in mind those
delicious seeds typically have
a 50 male 50 female
ratio at least theoretically if you're
growing a small number you might not
quite get to that
exact 50 50 split but if you grow them a
large scale typically they'll fall right
around
those even split they're male to female
where feminized seed will produce
generally a female plant at least over
95 percent of the time
so again what are the pros and cons to
these well starting with diesel seeds
what's the advantage of choosing those
that will produce 50
male or female well they have more
genetic variability so that can be an
advantage to some people especially if
you're looking at breeding and they can
produce pollen of a chosen strain which
might be difficult to find or get
particularly those or that are breeding
and they can offer more varieties to
select from because not all
strains or types have been brought into
the
feminized seed option there so you want
to consider those as advantages of using
dietician seeds
however there are some disadvantages of
using dietary seeds in the sense that
male plants will need to be removed
if you're not breeding and that's going
to take labor in time
plants have to be cared for that may not
produce a viable valuable yield
say we're looking at those cannabinoid
contents from those female flowers
you'll have to purchase more seeds than
you need because you have to expect this
culling
process to occur so those are some of
the disadvantages to
choosing dice's seeds looking at
feminized seeds what's the advantage of
a feminized seed
well vastly reduce the time spent
culling out male plants doesn't
necessarily completely eliminate it
but vastly reduces it if it's 95 percent
means 5 out of every 100 will need to be
called out
it's 99 percent that means 1 out of
every 100 rough to be called out much
more advantageous there
you can purchase a seed number can be
more closely match the total plant
number
if you're looking at growing 100 plants
you don't have to produce
purchase 200 seeds you can look at
producing maybe just
over that number there and cost
sometimes feminist seeds can be less
expensive in some cases
but that can depend on the strain the
variety or the availability
of that seed they get into the
disadvantages of using feminized seeds
well
there's limited strain selection options
that's going to reduce the
types that you can potentially grow you
cannot use the seeds if you're a breeder
because you're only going to
ideally get female plants a potential
negative impact on chemical profile at
least that's thought of
even though that necessarily hasn't been
always proven out and i said cost here
is a potential disadvantage
in the sense that they could be more
expensive in some cases but as mentioned
earlier that could be based on
availability or particular strain
or type that you're trying to grow so
again if you're choosing the seeds
keep in mind there are still some
options do you choose the feminized seed
route or do you choose the diocesan seed
route that's up to you