okay here we are look at a cannabis
mother room which is where the mother
plants are stocked plants are kept try
to put these pictures here to kind of
give in to like a County Fair there's a
birthing center handing the mother
producing many offspring here so you see
little nice little piglets this is kind
of like all the nice little clones that
ideally that one mother or stock plant
will produce to go on into the other
stages of growth and development so the
basics of a mother room this is again
where the stock plants are kept and you
want to consider putting plants in
larger containers typically this means
seven gallon or greater seven to ten is
typically what most people keep their
mother plants in so this allows them to
be grown for the full year and it's a
full calendar year without becoming
really highly pot bálint often this
mother room or stock room while it may
contain many plants or it could be a mix
of genetics this is often off-limits to
visitors because it contains potentially
rare and unique genetics keep in mind
you're restricting that area because if
you have that mother plant there's a
reason why that's a mother plant it has
a unique genetic set or it's a unique
cross or something different than the
vast majority of plants that you may
have lighting of a mother room plants
will be in here and will be in the
vegetative state so looking at 16 hours
plus of continuous light is important
fluorescents will not produce enough
penetrating light so they shouldn't be
used ceramic metal halides or metal
halides are a good place to start
this is a ceramic metal halide this can
also be used for propagation purposes so
again it can be using the same light
potentially for multiple purposes or at
least the same fixture that you could be
running in slightly different ways and
reducing your amount of just difference
that you have it streamlining the
process a little bit more a health and
feeding of a mother plant
remember plants will be full-sized and
potentially older so keeping them in
good health is important they can easily
become stressed fertilizing is often
required but watching that happen
nitrogen you add as this will reduce the
ease of rooting those cuttings in the
future
inspect the roots you can see here nice
intensive root system good vegetative
growth a lot of branches a lot of great
clone opportunities here but if you over
feed this with nitrogen it will reduce
the rooting there's clone
so you want to be mindful of that to try
to keep everything as healthy and
efficient as possible