on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over canvas extraction
options
how we can turn this into this and what
process
we may go through or some advantages and
disadvantages some of the processes
to go through and turn canvas buds into
a final extract
[Music]
all right i'm going to go over some
cannabis extraction options give you
some of the advantages and disadvantages
of each if there's one you want to learn
more about search this channel here on
tobacco university and you'll find more
detailed versions
of that specific extraction method so
first off why would we want to extract
in the first place so extraction allows
for a purified product
from the cannabis plant that is showing
increased popularity among consumers
extracts also offer more consistent
dosing
than just using the dry flour there are
different methods of extraction each
with its own advantages and
disadvantages that we provided here
so first off just a quick advantage
disadvantage of water-based extraction
well the advantages of the elimination
of additional
sample cleanup ease of automation and a
cheap solvent because it's basically
using water
however the disadvantages are the long
residence time of extracts
it has increased risk of phytochemical
degradation as well
so if water extracts not for you then
we've got rosin
the advantage of rosin it's a near pure
concentrated
product that's produced relatively
simple and easy process with minimal
specialized equipment
however the downfall is it does for at
least high pressure rosin
presses can be extremely dangerous if
misused and it's very easy to burn the
extract
if not it's properly pressed so there
are some stepwise protocols to follow
there's also the distillation method of
extraction and this
is an extremely pure product when
compared to other extraction
methods complete control over terpenes
and flavonoids
easily automated and can really allow
for very specific
components to be extracted and put into
separate containers
however as we can see here this can be a
very costly and long process
with multiple steps sometimes it can
take days to pass one liter of crude oil
through the machine
the distillation process strips the
cannabis of all compounds
except for the desired compound which
can have dramatic effect on the terpenes
when adding them back into the mixture
so again that's one of the disadvantages
so these are the methods for you
you might want to consider alcohol or
ethanol specific extraction
this is a very cost effective for large
amounts alcohol extraction can pull a
broader range of compounds from the
plant
than other extraction methods there's no
risk of leaving toxic
residual chemicals in the final chemist
extract
however the disadvantages are that
ethanol has a much higher boiling point
than other solvents which could lead to
a longer process post-processing
is extensive several refinements must be
made to the extract before it's consumer
ready
and it can be extremely genius in a
significant fire hazard if being used
indoors
ethanol alcohol in general highly
flammable
then you get to carbon dioxide
extraction so this is a
less valuable material is wasted it's a
specific compounds with adjustments can
to heat pressure and run time can be
made
and there's no residual solvent in the
final product through the evaporation
of the carbon dioxide the disadvantages
it's much higher initial
startup cost when compared to the other
extraction methods
even once purchased the equipment
requires proper training and safety
procedures to be understood
and followed this is when you want to
use caution if you're going to be
utilizing this extraction method
the last one mentioned here is going to
be hydrocarbon extraction
this offers a wide range of extract
types and can be achieved through
hydrocarbon extraction
can be done with trim and flower
relative low equipment and run costs
however the downfall is extremely
dangerous butane propane highly
flammable and
extreme caution must be used when
extracting with hydrocarbons
unwanted compounds can make it tough for
the extraction process and would need a
later refinement
so again if each or any one of these
extraction methods you want to learn
more about
search the channel and hopefully you can
find some more detail
as you continue your education