thank you for attending another debaco
university video
in this video we'll be looking at
cannabis compounds
kind of a general introduction to the
three main classifications
of compounds that cannabis can produce
so the first
major category here would be
cannabinoids
this is the word cannabinoid refers to
every chemical substance regardless of
structure or origin that joins with
cannabinoid receptors in the body
and the brain so while this is thought
of to be cannabis exclusive
it's actually not two cannabinoids that
are produced in high amounts though
in cannabis would be thc and cbd and
these are chemical compounds secreted by
the
cannabis flowers that provide relief to
array of symptoms including pain nausea
anxiety as well as inflammation
thc has that strong psychoactive effect
meaning it makes a person high that
euphoric
and we see the chemical structure
located up in
this direction over here and then the
cbd down a little bit lower over on
this side is thought to have
anti-psychoactive effect that controls
or moderates the psychoactive high
caused by thc and anxiety it's also been
shown to have some potential medical
benefits
when we're looking at reducing seizures
just as one example
you can notice their chemical structures
are very similar so just be mindful that
small changes
in chemical structure can have profound
effects and we're seeing
most know everything the difference
between uh thc
and cbd located right here with the
bonds located in this region
then we also have something called
terpenes so terpenes are aromatic oils
that color cannabis varieties with
distinctive flavors like citrus berry
mint pine plants produce terpenes
naturally to repel predators and also
attract pollinators so again not unique
to cannabis
but definitely notice as you hear a lot
of people talk about
terpene profiles regarding a cannabis
flower or end product
the plant stripping profile can be
influenced though by many factors that
can be climate weather
the age of the plant maturation the
fertilizers the soil type
the time of day and also the season so
those can all
impact the terpene profile that a plant
may have
lastly we have flavonoids here and these
are a class of plant secondary
metabolites that have a polyphenic
structure
widely found in fruits vegetables and
certain beverages as well
flavonoids are responsible for the color
and aroma flowers and in fruits attract
pollinators
and sequentially fruit dispersion to
help in seed and sport
germination and the growth and
development of seedlings as well
flavonoids protect the plant from
different biotic and abiotic stresses
and act as unique uv filters you might
be associating that with maybe a
blueberry as it ripens
you can see there's different flavonoids
here as they go as they go through the
maturation process
some plants for example poison ivy will
produce kind of a reddish tone to their
leaves
and those are flavonoids to help protect
these young leaves from
the harsh uv light and they'll select
green up over time
so just a quick overview here of the
three main classifications of compounds
produced by the cannabis plant