welcome to this debaco university video
where i'll be covering cannabis cloning
options and particularly
the advantages and disadvantages of two
main options
one the cut and stick method into the
aeroponic cloner
so come join me
[Music]
all right let's get into the advantages
and disadvantages of some cloning
options for cannabis plants
so first off there are two main methods
being the cut and stick method
and then aeroponic cloner now both can
get you to the same end result but and
both have their own advantages
and disadvantages that i'm going to
cover here so first off the cut and
stick method
when we're talking about cloning reason
why growers typically choose this method
is it's very simple
it also requires a minimal amount of
materials so as we can see here we have
some oasis
blocks some perlite maybe a little
humidity dome some lighting
nothing too out of the ordinary great
advantage
of this cut and stick method we're
simply cutting those vegetative
propagation clones
and sticking them into the various
substrate
however there are some disadvantages
with this method as well
one you really cannot see the roots so
as a grower kind of guessing
and this can be a slower method of
rooting
if you're looking at where you need to
really be under the gun to go through
and
you know turn one over with the next one
this can be a little bit slower of a
process
now compared to aeroponic cloner a great
advantage of the aeroponic car
is it allows the growers to physically
and actually visually see the roots
it's a very efficient method of
production and it can allow for interval
individual clones to be transferred at
the ideal time
simply because the grower can actually
see the roots this can allow individuals
to be
transferred over to the next step at the
right or up to optimum
time however there are disadvantages
with the
aeroponic cloning method and this does
require
special equipment and an electrical
power source also growers can lose the
entire batch of clones that they may
have going
if there's an issue reason why this is
your minimal buffering system so ph is
really important to dial in
again can potentially turn clones out a
little bit faster
allow growers to see it but again
requires some special equipment
and does have a tendency for the growers
to be a little bit
more attention to detail with the
aeroponic cloner
so this gave you good pros and cons of
each if there's one you want to learn
more about
check out tobacco university for more
information