you want to look at some of the physical
attributes of cannabis with the anatomy
and morphology to basically fern to what
you can physically see here now the
terms in [ __ ] and morphology are
basically interchangeable anatomy is the
basic structure of an organism in
morphology is the relationship of the
organism and their structure so we're
not going to really spend too much time
on any of the specifics so for our
purposes these are basically
interchangeable terms we're looking at
the relation of the structures in the
function here major structures are
presented as titles and the functions
are provided in the descriptions so
starting with the chute in root systems
the plant morphology pertains to the
vegetative structures and the
reproductive structures use two main
systems the chute which is the upper
system here as what we mainly see or
associate with the plant and that can be
the nodes the inter nose the buds the
leaves we have the root system down here
which supports the upper growing portion
now there's a lot over it's there's tap
roots and also very important root hairs
starting with the roots here they're
responsible for absorbing water and
minerals we see a bunch of roots unit in
a propagator they're also important for
anchoring the plant to allow for upright
growth and they store food that is
synthesized in the leaves so roots have
a very important function despite them
mostly being below ground and oftentimes
not seen by growers the steps are
support the near structures that support
the leaves and they allow the leaves to
take the best advantage on capturing
light energy they also conduct water and
minerals absorbed by the roots in the
leaves and they can also store food and
water in their tissues we see kind of a
cutaway section in here and these in
that stem structure may differ depending
on what portion of the plant you're
talking about or how old that tissue may
be meristem the regions of sites at high
cell division the apical meristem are
the shoot meristem located at the top of
the plant
so we see an apical meristem here here
you see all of our meristematic tissues
of the shoots appear this most likely be
the apical if you're growing a plant in
one single way eyes could be laterals
here based on the different pruning
methods keep in mind there's also mer
stems in the roots and they occur to
very tips of the ever growing roots
here's a quick stem anatomy we have our
nodes which are a site here where our
leaves attached ideals attached then our
inter notes and that's the distance
between those two nodes some growth we
talked about keeping short Internode's
and that's keeping the area here or the
amount of stem between your leaves where
they attach to the stem as short as
possible this can be important for a
variety of reasons plants that have a
long Internode's tend to be very wispy
and can break easily the leaf structure
arm is possible for capturing light to
aid in the production of food or sugars
in the plant you can see here a nice
leaf structure in a pretty dense canopy
within there or supporting those leaves
we have a vascular tissue that is occurs
in the stems and also the leaves they
transport water and nutrients to the
plant and they act as a circulatory
system for the plant there's two main
components and they're located in here
they're highlighted here we have our
xylem which is more interior and that's
conducting water and dissolved nutrients
from the roots and upper portions in the
plant we have our phloem which is
conducting cells transporting sugar and
other plant products up and down the
plant so xylem is water only in the
upward direction phloem is moving food
up and down and throughout the plant
lastly we have flowers of their
reproductive organs that produce seeds
that will become the next generation
plants flowers of course of the site
seed production however in cannabis
often the goal is not to produce seeds
but the chemical compounds such as CBTs
or in other cases THC or flavonoids or
terpenes these flowers here are not
producing seeds going through the
process of cannabis most growers are not
looking to produce seeds they're more
interested in the chemical compounds
that the plant can produce