for those that developing a product that
they can ultimately sell to consumers
the packaging is important so for
chemists we're going to score some brief
cannabis packaging it's a way to kind of
market your product in what things you
should be looking for whether you're a
consumer or a producer in this case so
product packaging heavy-duty bags cans
containers can all be used typically if
you're looking for a long-term storage
they'll be nitrogen filled this is an
inert gas to help preserve the product
it's an example of a canned here can be
used in seeable bags even my nitrogen is
the most high gas of highest abundance
in the atmosphere these nitrogen fill
bags will be filled with near 100%
nitrogen there that just helps increase
the longevity of the product now within
the product packaging I want to keep
light out however a customer viewing
window is strongly encouraged as this
can allow for inspections by your
consumer without opening or breaking the
seal of the package so the seals are
very important I want to make sure
you're keeping those contents under
controlled conditions but take their
nitrogen filled but the consumer still
wants a way to view them so much like an
agro tank here we're viewing window you
can peek in and see what you might be
purchasing I might be growing in this
case the same thing should be applied to
packaging this window does not to be you
know super large but an area where the
consumer can look in and inspect the
product that they are looking to
potentially purchased without damaging
the seal ruining all the work that was
done to increase the longevity of that
product branding ensuring your customer
knows where their canvas is coming from
is important bringing your product as a
result and having it be effective is
important to you as a grower remember
though this can work to help or hurt you
so ensure that there's a quality product
inside in a consistent product inside
and if you produce a poor product and
people associate your name with poor
products that's going to work against
you but if you brand your cannabis and
consumers like it and it gets sold that
can be much to your benefit in the long
term mark
so not gonna get too much into this but
container size that you use the shape
the color the design of the label all
play into marketing the picture here for
right elbow food star I'm just showing
you all the different marketing that
occurs with all the different fruits and
vegetables and products here there are
many many options and while this is
important your first priority a priority
number one should be the actual product
if you're not producing a quality
product if you're reducing a so-so
product doesn't matter how good your
marketing is if it's not that great but
product they won't get sold people may
try it initially because of the great
you know advertisement or the great
color or shape of the container or label
but ultimately if they find to be poor
quality they will typically seek out
better quality product so that should be
your first step but you should still
have someone dedicated into marketing
and consider this because it can be a
very competitive environment out there
so you want to make sure that your high
quality product is being put in front of
as many consumers as possible to help
increase sales to drive the business
model that you have