now when looking at cannabis grow rooms
that can be a highly varied operation
even though it may be under the same
term to also see here the plants either
organize the lighting the venting some
of the insulation that's used one of the
things I would make note of this
particular grow room would be the amount
of power that's used over here so you
want to be mindful and careful about
where we're putting all of our power how
we're stringing everything together
wanted to believe have a cleaner and
neater than this and maybe in an area
that's in decreased humidity to decrease
the chance of you know having a
short-circuit or having the potential
for fire to start so again just because
you see a grow room maybe only focused
on the plants but also look at some of
the supporting structures and be mindful
that every room is not necessarily the
most efficient or the correct option to
go so just grow rooms in general these
are permanent rooms that are not like a
portable grow tent
even though grow tents are great places
to start to kind of experiment and then
you can kind of upscale to a grow room
these rooms are typically have pretty
easy access to power because they're
typically designed for that it's a good
think of it is one way it's almost like
a permanent rotate very large
impermanent grow ten by starting with a
grow tent and help minimize some of the
mistakes you'll make in this room
because this is a much larger operation
with a lot more upfront cost and also
reoccurring costs so there's small scale
grow rooms I always say kind of define
what small is so some people small is
like a small little grow tent some
people this might be a small operation
again your definition of small should be
looking at either square foot or number
of plants in these grow rooms they can
be surrealist media containers or even a
hydroponic setups can work efficiently
you want to only move plants in that had
time to develop sufficient roots from
the clone and propagation room this is a
veg room in this image here trellising
may be needed as a plant support so be
sure to use clean material that is
either new or each planting for each
planting or that has been cleaned before
reuse so you can see a couple stakes in
here you don't wanted to keep the stakes
and you want to clean them before
another
round of plants may come into this
vicinity now large grow rooms there's no
set definition of what a large grow room
is typically it's considered usually
about twenty five or greater plants and
it's often not recommended for a
beginner simply because there's just a
lot of expense and knowledge that is
required the dense foliage in a larger
room can reduce air circulation so we
see here we see these cam filters and
cam fans it can really help improve air
circulation when you're growing a very
large scale efficient way to kind of
move some air to prevent some of the
issues that can occur when you increase
plant size now for larger grow rooms
typically there's more forms of
automation that come in as it is
automatic watering fertilizer injecting
do humidifying air circulation however
just because you're adding in all these
wonderful systems is automated systems
this does not mean that the work
decreases if one person is running a
large grow room there's simply not
enough time to perform some of the
tedious tasks for all plants when it's
something might be very possible in a 1
to 4 to 5 plant operation may not work
in a very large grow room so this
automation takes care of some of those
daily maintenance tasks but you still
need to be kind of hands-on monitoring
trellising pruning and the daily tasks
there that something gets more difficult
as the plant number increases