so here I'm going to go over canvas
cloning procedure which came out to be
thirteen steps which I know may not be
the luckiest number but I try to break
it down easy to fall out to allow a
successful cloning procedure so the
first basic process of this is step one
and kind of most important is to select
a healthy plant when a healthy plant
that's a female at least two months old
and those young as one month but that's
kind of pushing it has not been overfed
nitrogen fertilizer so female at least
are about two months old in a slapping
overhead nitrogen fertilizer as that
limits the rooting process much easier
next step you want to cut me want to
clean this sterilized knife to cut side
chute that's about three to six inches
long and as a stem diameter about an
eighth to a quarter inch it can become
flat or at a 45 degree angle doesn't
mean it to kind of get out of protractor
and measure exactly that 45-degree angle
that doesn't have a great impact on
their rooting a 45 degree angle is
beneficial sticking into immediate it
will penetrate a little bit easier but
you can kind of do a flat cut doesn't
have to be perfect 45-degree angle step
three would be a leaf count sometimes
want to remove some lower leaves may be
necessary to allow enough stem exposure
we see a bunch of cannabis clones here
to be placed into holding media
this is an aeroponic cloner here the
ending should have at least two sets of
leaves above the media if making many
clones over a large area a store
recently cut clones in water or high
emanate with minimal light exposure the
whole point there is you want to reduce
this stress on it so if you're doing a
lot of clones like in this situation you
want to immediately get them in an area
that doesn't cause a lot of stress
however the time from cutting to clone
placing into cloning environment should
be kept as short as possible I want to
reduce that stress or under enough
stress as it is the reason why we want
to remove those lower leaves is you want
to keep in mind that's where the roots
are going to start or initiate from so
reducing that lower leaves allows a more
efficient area for rooting or sticking
in this case in these foam holders so
for be applying a rooting hormone so
apply chosen reading hormone according
to the directions the portion of the
stem where routing needs to be
encouraged and again it's to figure that
nice moment potion proportionately
personally I have used Kleenex gel and
produce great success any other routing
jela that I've used sticks really nice
it produces great results for me growing
media so have great media ready to go
for an easy transfer you might want to
add a heating mat to slightly elevate
the temperature above ambient should be
around that 70 to 75 degrees won't
encourage root development you go much
higher than that some growers acted only
up to like 70 it's good then 90
fahrenheit must be better
Manny's not good root zones really
rarely get that hot and it doesn't allow
for efficient root development so 70
degrees is just fine want to also using
propagation mix to help reduce the
chance of having air pockets I'm going
to keep good moisture contact with that
newly stuck the stem the stick so if
you're sticking into media first wake a
Dibble hole like a little puncture hole
could be done with a sharpened pencil
into Rockwell santos mixture or they're
fine substrate to reduce the chance of
breaking the stem when you go to place
that in there using the clone machine
they have collars ready and in place
have machine running and ready to be
loaded
don't take your cuttings and then get
the clone machine ready make sure that's
ready ahead of time so you can put the
collar on them and stick them right in
it's a little bit more advances here
route already popping out there but it
gives you just an idea of that quick
easy transfer i'll cutting the leaves
some growers will go through and cut all
the ends of the leaves take kind of trim
them all down to reduce the area and
transpiration rate i personal dont
advise this personally i discourage this
only because it increases the wound
sites and can increase potential for
disease if the clinic environment has
high humidity the leaf cutting is
unneeded really it can also cause some
other issues with the plants kind of
growing out and kind of healing up those
areas if you have enough of a humid
environment you shouldn't need to cut
the leaves humidity as I mentioned very
important when a place to clones in a
high human environment 95-plus
if taking multiple cuttings be sure to
label them in some way there were color
coding labeling different trays keep in
mind that some labeling methods
especially if you're using certain
labels they may fade in the Sun so just
keep that in mind and keep an eye on
them make sure you're not
using always always the pink in the
light blue those may fade over time
watering them in really heavy can help
increase humidity and then placing it we
need know if you're looking at it right
now consistency is key you want to keep
the clintons evenly moist the girls
consistent consistency and to avoid
excessively wet in dry pockets when a
nice fine mist over the area over that
leaf surface and growing in a little bit
larger of an area you can have a monitor
here to make sure you're maintaining a
certain percent of the environment
clothes perform best in 18 and 24 hours
of light diffused light provides energy
for growth but produces a chance than
the burning this tender foliage direct
high density lights not advised
fluorescents are great warm and cool
whites preferred work great for clones
one about 6 to 10 inches away from the
clones a high-power light it is high
pressure sodium metal halides from metal
heads can be used that shade cloth
between them or just hang them about
five feet away dimmable lights are
another great source they offer the
advantage of changing intestine II as
the clones develop after four days you
can reduce humidity levels to about 85%
be accomplished by partially removing
the domes where we do some automatic
misting events you still want that kind
of humid environment we're starting to
ease them off from that 95 percent or
higher humidity levels once roots are
seen through the media or I've reached
about six inches long they be
transferred to their growing media this
can take another from 7 to 21 days and
depending on the environment that you're
growing in some clones may be slower to
initially root and those should not be
transferred until sufficient roots have
been produced you could see here some
might be on the borderline edge might
want to let this go for a couple more
days did that simply take a blocker
tray of clones and progressed them to
the next step treat em is each
individual's to help increasing the
higher percent total that will survive
lastly the initial transfer there may be
some color change which is normal due to
transplant shock as clones age the light
intensities can be increased in the
duration of photo period should be kept
consistent so don't panic if you go to
transfer them in all this and they get a
little bit lighter in coloration they
usually will bounce back if everything
else is kept well established and
consistent
there was again a problem over
fertilizing and burning their tender
roots of their newly cloned plants
summarize these thirteen steps I'm all
kind of quickly labeled right here you
can pause the video and take a look at
in more detail with everything they went
over to hopefully have a successful
cloning process