on this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at cannabis based
vapes
[Music]
all right let's look at canvas-based
vapes as an end product of the cannabis
plant
so first off looking at ct pharma is one
company that does produce these
that i'm just going to focus on some of
their products as they have publicly
available
analytical reports and labels of the
products that they produce
in this video the descriptions options
and uses are intended to provide an
understanding of some of the end
products of the cannabis plant
remember those analytical reports are
important and often
missed component that should accompany
any product someone is interested in
purchasing
and you'll see an example of one of
those at the end
so far stuff what's it just a general
description of the vapes well
vape character is pre-filled with high
quality high potency
marijuana oil could be high in thc or
high in cbd
these cartridges are color coded based
on the strain type and come in
half gram sizes you can see here that
they
can mass produce them as well and we see
the labels being put on in that image
now what are some options of vapes well
cd farmer offers two different styles
the pure vape cartridges which are
standard cartridge that can be used with
a 510 thread type and battery or we see
here
the peak slim disposable vape and
they're pre-filled vape and a battery
combination
that once completed can be discarded so
they're offering those options as well
now what are the general uses for vapes
well vapes are alternative to standard
flour when it's used with a ceramic
heating element
within the cartridge evenly heats the
oil to the point of vaporization so it
can be easily consumed
vaporization is an easy way of
consumption as you still receive
a good taste in medical effects without
leaving such a large odor
as you would with regular dried flour
now these examples of certificates of
analysis i was mentioning
many people are going to look at the
terpenes and cannabinoids great to look
at
but also remember you also need to be
concerned with the microbial analysis
heavy metals mycotoxins and pesticides
to make sure your product is that you're
purchasing is passing all of those
now all these look kind of bland and
boring it's important to match up lot
numbers
and the numbers presented here should
also appear on
the label as well but it's you're right
as a consumer to make sure you have
access to the actual original reports
to back up the information in numbers
stated here
on the label just part of being a
well-informed consumer
and it's something many people overlook
but it is your right as a consumer to
ask for those analytical reports