welcome to this debaco university video
we'll be looking at carbon oxide levels
of 400 to 800 parts per million
and how it relates to cannabis plant
[Music]
production
okay you're looking at enriching your
area between 400 and 800 parts million
what should you keep in mind let's get
into the video content
well first off realize that 400 parts
per million is normal atmospheric
conditions and elevating the levels
above this
will require the use of several pieces
of equipment the goal is to
increase the overall plant yield now
those pieces of equipment may be the
ones including the picture
or it could be some other but something
is going to be needed to be added
so the equipment list in general is
going to be a carbon dioxide source a
method of delivering that carbon dioxide
in a monitoring system
options will be discussed in other
videos this video focuses on the chosen
range and its impact on the plants
the image that i have here just shows
what a bottle system might entail
so first off looking at that 400 to 800
parts per million
as the environment is enriched closer to
the upper end of this range
the use of high-powered lights becomes
more advantageous
under high light the plants become
carbon dioxide limited
higher light can relate to increase in
biomass
now here we can see light intensity we
can see a relative rate of
photosynthesis
the key part here is at different carbon
dioxide levels we can see that there's a
certain
light saturation point but as we
increase
the levels of carbon dioxide the
saturation point or the light intensity
is increased so if we're only kind of at
the atmospheric or lower end levels
we can get away with lower levels of
light as we increase carbon dioxide
plants can take advantage of that
and increase their photosynthetic rate
so the target range of 480 parts per
million this enrichment level
will cause the least amount of costs
associated with purchasing carbon
dioxide
no matter what source you choose to get
that carbon dioxide from
this level is also the easiest to
achieve this
can be the best for large grow areas and
also small areas that have regular
venting
so you're getting above those
atmospheric conditions and you will
potentially see that
increase in yield as well assuming no
other limiting factors
now you want to consider the entire
environment so again as i said no
limiting factors assuming other plant
factors environment are not limiting
there will be an increase in plant
growth compared to atmospheric levels
what are those other factors to take
into consideration light water
air temperature and nutrient all those
need to be
optimal and keep in mind when you're
supplementing carbon monoxide and plants
might want to grow more aggressively
they may need more nutrients they may
need more water depending how you're
adding the carbon accident you might
want to watch the
temperature the air circulation all
things to take into consideration
now this the cost to benefit ratio so
there's different systems that can be
set up but a grower must consider the
cost of the implementation
of carbon accident enrichment system and
also the expected rate of return
on that investment comparing a few
growth cycles of normal atmospheric
conditions can provide a good baseline
to develop your comparison to determine
is it really going to be
worth it so why would you select this
range of 400 800 parts per million
well this can be in initial range chosen
to check to make sure
all systems are working well with
minimum risk of wasting
carbon dioxide which can get expensive
often this can be
due to required ventilation to see how
much carbon dioxide is exhausted and how
easy or hard it is to maintain
levels even at this range also growers
can see just how quote unquote airtight
their enclosures actually are
it's important if you're planting
autoflowers because
maximizing each day of the limited
growing cycle is
very important so while many growers
will shoot higher
than the 800 part million level shooting
that four to eight hundred per million
can be a great way once you get
everything initially set
to kind of go through any last checks
just to make sure
you're ready if you're looking at trying
different levels or to determine
if this is going to work for your
operation