welcome to this tobacco university video
we'll be looking at carbon accident
levels of 800
to 1200 parts per million in cannabis
plant production
looking at elevating your grow area to
800 to 1200 parts per million
let's look and see how it relate to
cannabis production
well first off co2 levels in that range
while 400 parts per million
is considered normal atmospheric
conditions elevating levels above this
will require the use of several pieces
of equipment
goal is to increase the overall plant
yield so you can kind of see here
effective carbon oxide and net
photosynthesis realize that it's not a
linear progression it is kind of it
levels off it kind of plateaus at a
certain
level so the equipment list you're going
to need a source of carbon dioxide a
method to deliver that
a system to monitor the carbon dioxide
levels now keep in mind that options
are discussed in other videos this video
focuses on the chosen range
and its impact on plants and the image
right here shows if you were to use a
bottle system
but there are other options now the 800
to 1200 parts per million
well this level will allow growers to
justify using lights with high
outputs despite the increase in initial
and operating costs this will allow for
plants to pack on more biomass
in a shorter period of time note this
may require an adjustment when you flip
your plants from
veg to flower plants will also require
greater fertilizer to meet their
aggressive growing so this added cost
needs to also be taken into
consideration we see here just a general
par guy looking at when
carbon dioxide would be required you can
also see different
light levels at different distances
between the plant or leaf canopy to the
light source so why would you select
this particular range well this allows
plants to maximize highlight intensities
these levels have shown to maximize the
photosynthetic rate
plants can tolerate elevated
temperatures 86 to 90 degrees fahrenheit
simply put because the rubisco enzyme
which is a very crucial part to the
entire photosynthetic process it's an
enzyme and it can operate at greater
efficiencies with carbon dioxide levels
in this range
that's why plants are able to tolerate
those warmer temperatures
however like most biological systems
there is a theoretical maximum
and this is the optimum rate for the
enzyme so adding
more will not improve the rate it may
actually have negative impacts so while
it shifts a little bit warmer
you don't want to go much warmer than 90
degrees this is
very important if you're growing an
autoflower due to the fixed number of
days
from emergence to harvest so growers
should be
maximizing each and every day and this
is one highly recommended
method to be able to accomplish this
with autoflowers
that will produce a yield in a set
number of days this can help growers
maximize each and every day that you
have
within that fixed time span