welcome to this debaco university video
where i'll be looking at carbon dioxide
sensor placement
at plant height for cannabis production
if you're going to be enriching your
area with carbon dioxide you need some
place to put the sensor so what happens
if you put it at plant height let's look
at that investigation here
first off realize that carbon dioxide is
a natural
material is heavier than air
as a result it will have a tendency to
accumulate at the bottom of the growing
area
just as we see here with the tanker that
had a leak of carbon dioxide we see it
filling the streets here
we can still see the tops of the cars
okay that carboxylate is here in the air
and it's going to disperse
in that manner now if the sensor reading
offset
so when placing a sensor at the plant
height this will typically result in a
reading that is most similar to what the
plants are experiencing
so you don't have to have any sort of
offset idea whether it's increased or
decreasing from that
reading you get is determined to be most
likely or an average accumulation of
what your plants will be experiencing
now what's the advantage of this
placement well this type of sensor
placement is advantageous if the carbon
dioxide injection point
is just below the actual sensor typical
set of rain tubing
12 inches below the sensor placement we
can see an example of that rain tubing
here
as well as kind of a larger indication
of that going on here with larger tubing
this simply allows the carbon dioxide to
fall and the sensor to pick
up and determine the carbon dioxide
level
that is what the majority of the plant
is experiencing so the reason why you
want it just above if this is my kind of
co2 injection point that's going to
actually fall down so it's going to go
downward direction
with the sensor just above that if you
put it just below that what's going to
happen the co2 is going to come out
and go right to the sensor so you want
to get an idea of again what that plant
might be experiencing this is why this
is an advantageous location
particularly when using this kind of
rain tubing which is this
multi-injection point around the grow
area
now what i would suggest to growers is
that with this mounting location
since it's providing the most accurate
level of carbon dioxide concentration
growers should target the optimum level
to maximize plant production
also make sure that other factors are
not limiting there's no need to kind of
artificially increase or decrease the
level you pre-set it at
since that is probably what the plants
are going to be experiencing dial it in
to the right parts per million
that you're looking at having your
plants at and that's hopefully
what your plants will be experiencing
and assuming no other limiting factors
you should have an optimum rate of
delivery
of carbon dioxide for your plants in
your enriched grow area