welcome to this tobacco university video
where if you're considering adding
carbon dioxide to your cannabis
production this will go over the basics
to help you make an informed decision
and things to look out for if you are
considering this
all right let's look at carbon dioxide
basics for cannabis production
so starting first you have to understand
that cannabis specifically
is what's called a c3 plant similar in
structure for its photosynthetic process
as tomatoes would be the other types are
called
c4 plants they include corn and sugar
cane and cam plants are cacti
you can see there's different processes
that they go through
as they prepare carbon dioxide for the
calvin cycle
c3 plants is basically a direct
incorporation of carbon dioxide to the
calvin cycle
so keep in mind with carbon dioxide
it's heavier than air so dry is to add
carbon dioxide as you can see here put
it in the
suspended kind of container here well
this is not advised we can see that the
carbon dioxide in this case dry ice is
kind of going from the solid state to
the gaseous state and here it's falling
through the plants
but this is not going to really create
anything that's going to be very
consistent or really meet the plant's
needs yes we'll add carbon dioxide
but it will not add it in a consistent
manner now the environmental factors you
want to consider with a plant in general
is that light intensity
the amount of carbon dioxide and the
temperature keep in mind as the light
intensity increases there'll be a
certain plateau
same goes with the amount of carbon
dioxide you can increase the rate
of the concentration of carbon dioxide
this will increase the rate of
photosynthesis and then temperature
there will be a rise
in ideal or optimum temperature and then
a falling off
from there so you want to keep in mind
all these factors
for that your plant is growing in so
we're going to focus of course here on
the carbon diox
oxide aspect it's important input to the
photosynthetic equation as we can see
here carbon dioxide plus water plus
sunlight will produce sugar and oxygen
all the carbon that forms in the sugar
end product here
originated as carbon dioxide molecule in
the air that's why there's six of them
here
because we have to make a six carbon
sugar
so low carbon dioxide and equals low
growth rate and these little brackets
mean concentration so if you look at a
lettuce study notice that there are
changes in dry
mass or yield at different light
intensities across the range of co2
concentration levels so here's our co2
concentration
and we can see here different light
intensities so we can make the
conclusion here that increasing the
light intensity no matter what the
concentration of carbon oxide will
increase yields at least
provided in this study here but we can
see also the trend that as you increase
carbon monoxide concentration from
ambient
it's going to be around 400 somewhere
around this range right here
we can see that there is an increase
overall in the dry mass or yield
now this reference article that if i
included here
is looking at the photosynthetic
response of cannabis in relation to
variations
in photosynthetic photon flux densities
temperature
and for this video carbon dioxide
conditions but you're welcome to check
this out for more details
now net photosynthesis in cannabis so
when we're looking at specifically
cannabis
the optimum temperature for
photosynthesis is around 30 degrees
celsius temperature higher than 30
degrees has been
has adverse effects uh on the
photosynthetic rate it actually starts
to curl over and start to decrease
at 25 degrees celsius the rate of
synthesis is increased
but with increasing ppfd and that's
we're looking at the light intensity
measurement
but this trend was peaked at about 1500
micro moles of pdf
of ppfd which is the light intensity at
30 degrees
celsius and decreased at higher light
intensities
so this means as you increase light
intensities there's kind of this optimum
here based on intensity and temperature
and more is not always better looking at
the optimum temperatures around 30
degrees
celsius and 1500 micro moles for light
intensity should be around your target
levels
now carbon dioxide levels in this case
pn is net
photosynthesis we see this column here
and w-e-e
is water use efficiency on the leaves of
cannabis sativa
and here's the carbon dioxide levels
here we can see that there's a change
we can see there's also alterations in
these now as we're looking at what has
the highest net
photosynthesis well we can see here 750
uh micro moles of concentration of
carbon dioxide
just as a reminder around 400 is what
would be considered atmospheric levels
now again comparing here to our light
levels notice
how at high light levels plants can be
better you can better utilize the added
carbon monoxide
if adding carbon dioxide make sure
plants are not
light limited so just adding more carbon
dioxide is okay but we could see here is
that ambient level
uh here with low light well we could add
a lot of carbon dioxide
and really not get any more kind of
increase in the rate of photosynthesis
and we can see that these all of these
even the highlight level does have a
sort of
plateau to it so this should be the
light intensity should be measured with
a par meter to ensure that adding carbon
dioxide will actually be utilized
where are your light levels at and this
is just an example of this study
showing what's considered low medium and
high light levels
now concerns about carbon dioxide from a
grower's standpoint keep in mind that
concentrations above 5000 can be harmful
to
to humans and when we're looking at
enriching an area with carbon dioxide
for
plants we're looking really not going
much more than a thousand so it is not
necessarily going to cause
any sort of harmful effects or hopefully
any of the conditions labeled here
we're looking at the volume of the air
really not getting into any of that here
the levels that would be acceptable for
plants
now how do you estimate your carbon
dioxide usage everyone wants to know how
much you're going to use
just providing a random example here for
an area looking at a 32 foot by 40 foot
high tunnel that was 32 foot wide 40
feet long and 12 feet at the peak
operating at about a thousand parts per
million of carbon dioxide with the
system turned off during venting
periods of high heat it uses 50 pounds
of co2 per week
and again this is intended to simply be
a rough estimate looking at if you're
using carbon monoxide from compressed
air bottles
you can expect if you have this area to
go through about 150 pound bottle a week
plus or minus from there but just a
rough idea there
now when should carbon dioxide be added
in short from emergence to harvest
uh people say i want to save it for the
harvest i want to do at the beginning
really for the entire life cycle and be
definitely utilized
however if it's not possible that for
the entire life cycle then it actually
may be more critical in the early stages
to get the plants established early
seedling phases is great time because
often plants might be slow to get going
but the carbon dioxide can help
increase root mass which of course is
very important especially
in the early stages of plant growth now
autoflowers and carbon dioxide well all
strains will benefit from the adding
carbon dioxide but it's highly
recommended for autoflowers
because there is a set number of days
between when they emerge
and when they will be harvested growers
should be seeking every possible way to
maximize each day
and carbon dioxide enrichment allows for
higher light intensities to be used
again assuming all other factors are not
limiting
which will result in a greater biomass
production this will translate into
higher
yields on a plant that only has a set
number of days to complete its life
cycle
so if you're looking at well what i want
to try it try it with autoflowers
because you have a set number of days
you want to maximize
each and every day so will carbonacci
increase
plant production i say yes but or
yes if there are no other limiting
factors
if your plants are receiving optimum
light optimum nutrients water aeration
then carbon dioxide can be used to boost
your plants
in need keep in mind that with the
addition of carbon monoxide the plants
will be able to take advantage of
greater light intensities
and will likely require more nutrients
to meet the increased growth rates
so if you've been growing a plant or a
certain type of plant for an extended
period of time and feel you have
everything dialed in
and now you want to go through and add
carbon monoxide some of those things
may change particularly watering
frequencies or nutrient consumption
might be higher so have records you
should be keeping
compare those records but realize carbon
dioxide may
speed things up but a lot of times
growers can utilize that to their
advantage