here on this tobacco university video
we're going to look at the most simple
form
of carbon dioxide dosing and that's with
a time
timer release here to be able to
calculate the duration
and frequency carbon accident will be
added to the growing area
all right let's look at carbon dioxide
timed release for cannabis production
well first off by far this is the least
expensive option
by simply attaching a carbon dioxide
regulator
or even a co2 generator to a timer the
growth space can be enriched with carbon
dioxide
and what these are basically your cycle
timers and you set for
how long you want the timer or the timer
to set to be on
and then what for what duration of time
you want it to be off for in the sensor
or the timer will go through and
regulate that throughout the entire
duration now what we're noticing here
which i like about this one it has a
light sensor
so what it's going to do is it's going
to go through its cycle timer sequence
when it senses that photocell since
there's enough light there
other timers will just go through 24
hours a day this one actually has a nice
little sense a light sensor
to ensure you're only going to be dosing
carbon dioxide during the light cycle
which is when plants can actually
utilize it
however a word of caution without
monitoring the carbon dioxide levels
this can cause uncertainty the levels
could be too high
or too low without you knowing it you
will be providing only an estimation of
the carbon dioxide levels in your growth
space
a carbon dioxide detector should be
installed to avoid potentially dangerous
conditions
which is above 5000 parts per million of
carbon dioxide to human health
otherwise you're just taking random
guesses as far as what the carbon
dioxide levels are actually
now adjustments during the growing cycle
so if you're using this timer-based
system
keep in mind that as plants grow they'll
be consuming more carbon dioxide
so you want to make adjustments during
the grow cycle when plants are smaller
they're going to be using less as plants
get larger you might want to up the
either the duration
or the frequency that you'll be dosing
the area with carbon dioxide enrichment
now basic controller is highly
recommended over a timer
even getting a simple or very basic
timer
this can help provide a much more
accurate form of carbonxa delivery
want that controller because it offers
many advantages over estimations of just
a simple timer
i will have it on for this and offer
this duration even the most simple or
basic of co2 controllers
can be much more advantageous over a
timer for consistency in a growth setup
the cost
of a timer should be factored in so the
rest of the cost of setup equipment can
be
maximized so initially some of these
controllers may cost more
than your cycle timers but in the long
run it can actually save you more money
and also create a better growing
environment overall
so if our goal here is to maximize a
cannabis yield in the end
over the course of a growing cycle
campbell's plants will become many times
larger
than they were at this very small
propagation stage so it will be
difficult to make these adjustments with
a timer
as the growing season progresses if you
have a controller that's sensing the
environment
you can automatically make those
adjustments make those changes
to ensure the environment at least from
carbon dioxide enrichment standpoint
is consistent to your plants over the
entire growth cycle
maximizing their yield assuming all
other factors are not limiting
in this small uh additional investment
early on
can produce big yields in the end
of your growing cycle so it's important
to investigate all
options yes timers are great if you want
to explore initially but a controller
based system
with or even without fuzzy logic would
be highly recommended over
a timer recycle timer dosing system