on this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at carbon dioxide
sensor placed below plant height
for cannabis production and how that
will impact the readings that you
[Music]
receive
if you're looking to place your carbon
dioxide sensor below the plant height
let's see what effects that will have on
your readings
first off you need to realize that
carbon dioxide is heavier than air
you can see here's a tank that had looks
looks like a liquid carbon dioxide had a
leak and we can see how it fills the
streets here
this carbon accident will naturally
accumulate at the bottom of a growing
area simply because
it's heavier than the air surrounding it
so
the sensor reading offset well when
placing a sensor below plant height
this will typically result in an
artificially higher reading
than the plants may be experiencing so
you need to keep this in mind if that's
where you're going to be mounting your
sensor
the readings that you get the sen the
controller is only as good as the sensor
placement
you'll get usually readings that are
artificially higher
than what the plant might be
experiencing and that's at the plant
height
leaf area so this why would you want to
uh
mount your sensor below plant height
well this is only beneficial
this type of sensor placement if the
carbon dioxide injection point
is higher in the structure and you want
to get a read of what's passing by the
plants
meaning if you have your sensor down
here and you have your plants growing
and you have your injection point only
at the top and you want to get an idea
of how much carbon dioxide is going past
the plants
that's what your sensor is going to be
telling you
now i would suggest or just grow
suggestions is that
if this is the only mounting location
you have you may want to set the target
level a little higher
than the optimum simply point being to
take into a
into consideration the fact that they're
reading in this area of the growing
space
will typically be higher than what the
plants are experiencing
so aren't making it artificially a
little bit higher will ensure that the
plants
hopefully are getting the optimum level
which will be a little bit
under what your sensor or readout is
providing you
again i would only use this if this was
the only
location you could mount it for a
variety of reasons because you are going
to get that artificially high reading
with this sensor placement