welcome to this debaco university video
we'll be going over carbon filters for
odor control in cannabis production
facilities
[Music]
all right if you're looking at reducing
odors of your cannabis plants
with carbon filters you've come to the
right place so
first off how do carbon filters work in
general have you ever kind of inspected
one it's kind of what you may see
and carbon filters simply bind to odor
molecules and prevent them from
remaining free-floating in the air
activated carbon has a high amount of
surface area per volume
so it is a great contact while still
maintaining a high porosity
so you're not restricting your airflow
all that much a single gram of activated
carbon
features a surface area of over 3 000
meters squared so that's kind of an
amazing amount of surface area
and what that translates to is contact
points that you can have
to reduce the odor now fans and filters
that we may have in our grow facility
exhaust fans will pull or push air
through the carbon filter before exiting
the grow space entirely
this is why we typically see our fans
going to be moving air anyway attaching
a carbon filter can reduce odors and
ensure those air being cleaned
to the outside environment there now
keep in mind that humidity does impact
the effectiveness
in humidity levels above 70 it's kind of
the limit of effectiveness of carbon
filter so if you're getting
70 or 75 or above the effectiveness is
going to be severely reduced
simply because the water molecules in
the air essentially clog
up the carbon pore structure not
allowing contact with the air
think about this really fine droplets of
water eliminating that
high surface area of the carbon really
to interact with the air molecules
now push or pull air through a carbon
filter it's kind of like the option do i
pull the air as we see over uh here do i
pull the air kind of through that carbon
filter
or here am i pushing it kind of through
so some growers will pull air through
the carbon filter first
and then to a fan before exiting out the
structure
other growers will have the air enter
the fan and then the filter before
exiting to the outside
but for maximum control or odor control
at least
growers will utilize both systems where
they'll pull air through
take out the odors and then they'll run
it through another carbon filter to
absolutely ensure
no odors are escaping their grow tent so
where would you place your carbon filter
so keep in mind that should be mounted
high up in the grow space
so the hottest air will be removed this
will provide also a cooling effect so it
helps with your ventilation system
just kind of adding it as a component in
addition if you're enriching the space
with carbon monoxide
this will remove the least amount of
carbon dioxide since co2 is heavier than
air
so mounting that carbon filter high
removes the hottest air with the least
amount of co2
still allowing ventilation but without
allowing kind of all
competing systems lastly for your carbon
filters a lot of times they look like
they're white cotton based filters
but really what that is is the
pre-filter
and before air comes into contact with
the carbon it should pass through a
pre-filter
we'll simply filter out particulates not
the odors
why would you have a pre-filter if
you're not really doing odor control
well this is important because
if the air with high amounts of
particulate come in contact with the
carbon
despite its high surface area it will
actually clog up the pores and reduce
the effective
life of the carbon filter also keep in
mind pre-filters are not very expensive
they extend the life of the carbon
filter and are easily washed and reused
all good positive aspects
which is the reason why they should be
added and if those get dirty you can
simply
wash them out clean them throw them back
on and it really will help extend the
life
of the more expensive carbon filter and
extend the life of your ability to
reduce
odors from your grow space