in this tobacco university video we're
going to cover carbon dioxide
methods of delivery for cannabis
production we see a couple
in this view we'll go over some of the
advantages and disadvantages of each
and there'll be more details of each of
these methods
here on tobacco university
[Music]
all right let me go over some methods
for carboxylic delivery so you can make
an informed decision
so we have rain tubing the advantages
are it can allow for even distribution
across
the area and it also makes for
an easy point of injection below the
leaf canopy
it's basically tubing that has small
little pinholes in it
at equal intervals however the
disadvantages of using this system
is that the max tubing length is 100
feet and it should be in a loop so the
total area is
limited particularly for large growing
operations
it should also have a fan to help for
the distribution process because over
that long
area you won't have any accumulation on
extremely oscillating fan
to help ensure that you're getting an
even mixing of that
despite it's being distributed pretty
over a large area
you want to make sure you're getting a
mixing as well
then there's also passive point
injection so the advantage
is that this is the simplest setup in
the sense that there's just one little
end of a tubing and that's where your
carbon oxide comes out the disadvantages
it may cause high concentration pockets
to develop in the grow space
because you're really only having the
distribution of that carbon dioxide at
one
central point then we also have
injection point behind a fan so this is
like the
next step above the last one simply put
the injection point and put it right
behind the fan
to help again help that mixing process
advantages it's really easy to set up
most likely you might have a fan in your
growing space already
ensures distribution throughout the
growth space that's another advantage
however this may have challenges in
getting an
even distribution in an odd shaped room
or one that's particularly
long so might be good for a very small
potentially grow tent operation
but not necessarily for a larger growing
area
and lastly we have our heat source as a
point of carbon dioxide
so the advantages of using a heat source
is that if you need to heat the space
anyway
want to get some added carbon dioxide to
your area
however the disadvantage if the heater
comes on only at night
for the addition of heat the added
carbon dioxide that it provides your
plants will not really
provide them any benefit because keep in
mind plants can only utilize carbon
dioxide
during the light cycle so when the light
is lights are on or the sunlight is out
that's when they can use carbon dioxide
they can't utilize it at night
so if you're using this as a heat source
it's only coming out at night when the
lights are off because you have less
heat in the area
not going to provide you with as much
benefits as it potentially could