welcome to this tobacco university video
here we're going to be looking at carbon
accident enrichment levels and cannabis
production
while this beginning picture may show
rice is also a 3
c3 plant much like cannabis so we're
going to develop some conclusions
and we're looking at enrichment levels
is more
always better
[Music]
all right so looking at just a picture
here of the rice we can see
400 or about 390 to 400 is considered to
be atmospheric or normal carbon dioxide
levels and we can see how there is a
difference in rice production
definitely as we go below that we see it
kind of dwindling off
and above that we are seeing an increase
in yields or at least in biomass
so how does this apply to cannabis so
first off if we're looking at what level
we want to keep our plants at there's
some considerations
well the first consideration is
basically atmospheric levels which is
about 400 parts per million
this is offers the advantage of no
additional equipment would be needed if
you were looking at enriching your
plants with 400 parts per million
simply want to just keep air circulating
the disadvantages
is this can limit yields to the whatever
the atmosphere
is able to provide and if you're in a
closed growing area you definitely want
to make sure you're moving air around
because there is a chance that foreign
parts per million that is normal
atmospheric levels
in your growing facility it could be
lower
so what if we enrich to the 400 to 800
part per million range
well the advantage is increasing yields
however this does
start to require specialized equipment
even in the 400 to 800
part per million range so what about 800
to 1200 parts
what's if a little is good why don't
just go a little bit more the advantage
this can also or still increase yields
it can use lights that produce a greater
intensity as well
to take advantage of this increased
carbon level
the disadvantages is the cost of the
equipment and actual the carbon dioxide
however you're going to be
using or producing it in the sense that
as you get higher levels it's going to
require more
and more carbon dioxide to be added to
your growing area
and then we have the upper end of the
range 1200 to 1600 parts per million
well advantages is that ensures carbon
exit will not be limiting
however the disadvantage it will have
the highest cost simply because you are
adding
a high dosing level from a plant
standpoint
of carbon dioxide so we have to weigh
all these different factors
what range of carbon monoxide levels are
you going to keep
your plants at