okay I'm going to discuss carbon dioxide
enrichment so first off it's part
remember that carbon dioxide is in the
air naturally you can see there's a lot
of nitrogen is the highest percentage in
the air or even breathing right now I'll
come back so it is in air but at low
levels so enriching that is particularly
can help plants grow because of the
increased amount of carbon which they
need to produce these sugars so first
off let's start with the basics so what
is co2 LLC a two-stroke for carbon
dioxide carbon oxide is heavier than air
so it will sink it's a non flammable gas
that occurs naturally in the atmosphere
at levels of about 405 parts per million
ppm however when the levels go below 200
parts per million growth constant in
plants as a result of the reduction in
the photosynthetic process this is why
trying to maintain 405 parts per million
or even greater can affect plant growth
but specialist growth can stun if those
levels go too low and the importance of
co2 in a plant
well carbon in the carbon oxygen is
converted into sugar or glucose
molecules that the plant produces the
carbon in organic matter originates as
carbon dioxide in the atmosphere so that
carbon dioxide is coming the atmosphere
plus water and light producing sugars
and oxygen well those sugars can be
stored in the leaves and where did that
come from that ultimately can compost
down the form you know organic matter
well that carbon source originally was
carbon dioxide from the air so plants
are so good at assembling that into a
more stable compound here the sugar but
it can be used for a whole host of
reasons come that's in Richmond Opperman
acid provides carbon for the plants
biomass and sugar production so that
c6h12o6 that glucose is also important
for building components of the actual
plant itself
in addition to those sugars it can be
used for other purposes the lack of
carbon dioxide so if we reduced carbon
dioxide can often be a limiting factor
in this process so in rich in a
greenhouse or grow facility with carbon
dioxide has been around for many years
because that is directly can impact
plant growth swimming water and light
are all at sufficient levels so
photosynthetic rate that's what PS is
short for
in light in different carbon dioxide
levels so adding extra carbon dioxide
will be the most beneficial for plants
that are receiving high light levels so
in the example here of low light levels
we could see higher low levels of carbon
dioxide really don't make any difference
however once you buy the low light
levels and increase that light intensity
we could see the low level of carbon
dioxide levels off at a much lower rate
of photosynthesis higher level of
Carmack said here will increase the
photosynthetic rate here so again at
those low light intensities can be a
limiting factor in this case if you're
adding co2 there's gonna be really no
benefit to that we see the same thing
here where we have insufficient so
you're too excessive co2 but in a lower
light and a higher light and we see the
same pattern here higher light levels
with higher co2 levels can result in an
increased rate of photosynthesis
assuming water and nutrients are all
above optimum so co2 enrichment can
impact yield adding or enriching an
environment with co2 to about 0.12
percent or 1200 parts per million can
increase plant growth by 30% no research
often debates the ideal co2 level many
will consider this to be too high
typically levels we're talking about 700
to 1200 is kind of where you're seeing
an increase in potential for yield
however what is agreed upon is levels
above 1500 to be about here on the graph
are not economically viable that 700 to
1000 is a general range recommended some
are running this high is 1200 depending
on what controller units they're using
to ensure they're always within that
seven to a thousand part per million
level but about 1500 as we can see here
we're kind of having that reduced growth
and it's simply you're wasting money on
carbon accidents and that beneficial to
the plant
now dangerous levels of co2 is replying
particularly to humans there is carbon
dioxide toxicity
however those hulls have to approach
5,000 parts per million and above are
not advised for people to be in this
result and my headedness or worse due to
lack of oxygen you can see some of the
symptoms here as increases in co2 level
but as far as what we're trying to keep
our plants at 0.12 percent would be
ideal
and you can see that it takes even 1%
here to start having any terminated
toxicity for humans so it's well below
and it didn't get any concern but when
you start getting higher levels that's
where we start getting those cautioned
the ideal temperature was co2 so when
enriching with curved ax head the ideal
temperature can increase from 85 degrees
Fahrenheit to about 90 and above 90 then
we'll start to see a decrease in the
photosynthetic rate so the increased
carbon dioxide allows our to run our
plants a little bit warmer take
advantage of potential heat that we may
be trying to exhaust anyway an increase
in plant production the importance of
ventilation and grow space of people and
ventilation is still important
co2 depletion especially in greenhouses
or grow tent environments can be quite
common because of the confined space the
area should be sealed to better regulate
co2 levels so you're not wasting co2 out
some vents or something so it's
important to keep in mind that
ventilation is important and which
creates a delicate balance between
venting out hot air in this case a
particular and exhausting out the
precious co2 that you've added so here
I've chosen to add the co2 about midway
through the grow tent in my exhaust port
here at the very top of the tent the co2
can increase plant metabolism which is
great because that can cause more rapid
growth increased nutrient consumption
filling the space quicker and greater
water usage so keep in mind that when
you are facing with co2
there's my tubing right here it can also
cause that rapid growth which is great
but that can cause increase in nutrient
consumptions who want to be make sure
we're feeding them appropriately I fill
in the space quicker so that could
adjust your time if you're new to adding
co2 and greater water usage because the
plants are simply growing faster so
you'd know when you change one thing
wanna be mindful of all the potential
conditions you could be changing to keep
your plants happy and efficient through
the entire lifecycle