here on this debaco university video i'm
going to look at
a carbon dioxide controller that does
not have fuzzy logic
and provide you with some details about
this style of
co2 controller
[Music]
all right let's look at a carbon dioxide
controller without fuzzy logic for
cannabis production
so first off what would these be used
for and while they can be used with
bottle systems
they're probably best utilized for
carbon dioxide generators
because even if your controller does
have fuzzy logic which i'll mention here
at the end
it needs to be turned off if you're
using a generator
as this will not work with this type of
co2 generation
only bottle based systems should be
utilizing fuzzy logic
so here we can see the generator is an
on off
system bottle systems allow for pulse
dosing which you cannot use with a
generator system
there's different forms of generator
systems you can see here we have
invented here here
and here we have one in a greenhouse
setting
so when we're looking at these
controllers
they are set up much in the way that
ones would be with fuzzy logic in the
sense that you would set a deadband
and what's a deadband well this setting
decides how tight you want the control
to keep the carbon dioxide levels to the
target setpoint
essentially how far the controller will
allow carbon dioxide levels to deviate
from your chosen setting before
targeting your carbon dioxide source
to switch on or off most
controllers default around 50 parts per
million but you may want to increase
this to 100 parts per million for a
generator system
as it will naturally fluctuate the
levels more than a bottle-based
system selecting 100 parts per million
as your deadband setting
will allow the growth space levels to be
essentially over or
under by 100 parts per million before
the controller turn on or off the
generator
now we'll notice the one the controller
over here next to me
has a deadband setting set to 25. this
would be a little tight to run for a
generator because it's going to have a
lot more ons and off
cycles which could add unnecessary wear
and tear to your generator
when in doubt start with 50 and you can
regulate from there
going as low as 25 is possible but it
might see your generator running
on and off with greater frequency so
make sure on the sensors of your
controller
that there is a presence of a photocell
we see that here
see that labeled right here we see that
here as well this will help ensure that
co2 is only added during the light
period which is only when the plant can
actually utilize it
a time a timer could be used if you have
a regimen
light schedule but the photocell is a
great fail-safe option to ensure carbon
dioxide is only added
when the plants can actually use it a
lot of growers some are some controllers
had growers trying to dial in the time
so it flights on lights off period
but the photocell is great uh for
kind of forgetting about the exact timer
setting in case timers were a little off
also if you're growing in a high tunnel
or greenhouse environment this can also
allow the control to automatically
adjust to seasonal changes in duration
of sunlight or photo period now what is
this fuzzy logic that you'd be missing
out on
well keep in mind that fuzzy logic can
maximize
a growing cycle with bottle based
systems and what it simply does is it
allows for continuous adjustment
and to automatically ensure efficiency
the reason why this can be used with
bottle based systems
is the controller will automatically
adjust the frequency and duration
of its pulse dosing this is not possible
with generators because it needs to be
on
or off so just keep that in mind that if
you are looking at potentially going
into
using a generator for now but looking at
a bottle system down the road
make sure you get one of the fuzzy logic
so the fuzzy logic can be utilized when
using the bottle based system
but make sure that physiologic is off or
you get a controller that does not have
fuzzy logic if you're only going to be
using a generated source of carbon
dioxide