okay here look at different carbon
fixation pathways for what's called c3
c4 and cam plants for the most part
we've been talking about proposed
synthesis and relating to c3 plants
there's actually two other pathways that
go through however please realize each
uses carbon dioxide and ultimately all
three of these produce glucose it's how
they go about doing this that's
different the one I've been talking
about so far is the c3 plant and that's
the most simplest of forms c4 plants use
the bezel fill to have a four carbon
intermediate and in the calvin cycle
actually occurs in the bundle sheath
cells cam plans to have a day/night
cycle to be able to compare the two so
these are just things to keep in mind as
we go through and compare them so just
giving a little bit of orientation the
mesophyll may remember this from the
cross-sections illipe this compromises
the bulk of internal leaf tissue in the
majority site of the photosynthetic
process and plants since they contain
large amounts of chloroplasts the inner
tissue parenchyma of a leaf containing
many chloroplasts is located right here
bundle sheath cells see here layer of
cells and leaves in stems that surround
vascular bundles remember vascular
bundles here are Zalman phloem and c4
plants the bundle sheath cells contain
chloroplasts and are the site of sight
of the calvin cycle so again be able to
compare c3 c4 and also PM plants here
just give me the example of each c3 is
most plants and they follow the steps
presented as what we call normal it's
located right here Kalen cycle occurs in
the mesophyll and occurs it's co2
directly and produces glucose c4 plants
Carmack's aid is incorporated to a four
carbon compound in the mesophyll and the
calvin cycle occurs in the bundle sheath
itself in the cam pathway common
actually is actually stored as an acid
at night and it is fed through the
calvin cycle during the day and again
the talon cycle here is occurring in the
mesophyll
give you an idea what these plans to
make connect to c3 plants so beam
example of a tomato plant c4 plants
would be like corn
and cam plants would be a cactus so c3
plants common plant type of the Calvin
cycle Biden carbon dioxide to the
Rubisco enzyme most efficient during
cool and moist conditions with normal
light this is compared to c4 and cam
plants most plants live in cool moist
conditions with normal light this is why
most plants are c3 plants here's just a
couple examples typical garden plants
maybe got a field of crops all c3 plants
see for now is we're starting to differ
c4 plants have an intermediate before
carbon dioxide binds to the Rubisco
which benefits the plants in hotter
climates corn sugarcane crabgrass are
examples of c4 plants stomata are still
open during the day which is an
important step which is different than a
cam plant no such intermediates asilah
acetate in Mele I try to highlight here
in little blue circles this is an
intermediate step before carbon dioxide
binds with the Rubisco this intermediate
before it goes through that process see
here come accident corporate into a four
carbon compound a steel acetate here
four carbon sugar I'm sorry for common
compound here in order to make
ultimately our sugars come to activate a
Shell via malate or aspartate from the
mesophyll cells to the bundle sheath
cells in these bundle sheath cells
carbon dioxide is released by
decarboxylation of Maui so what does all
this mean we have our carbon oxide
coming in we have this kind of
intermediate that's occurring remember
if you remember from our regular post
synthetic process instead of the three
carbon PGA compound in c3 plants region
this acid as an intermediate to bind
ultimately this four carbon compound so
it's going to feed the carbon from the
carbon dioxide into the Calvin cycle
now the calvin cycle doesn't change it's
the same it's just the preparation these
plants go through to be able to deliver
that carbon has this intermediate step
with high light in temperature c4 plants
for synthesised faster than c3 plants c4
plants have better water use efficiency
because the use of the PEP carboxylase
brings her monoxide in faster and can
keep the stomata closed longer so this
is the advantage to the 4 carbon
intermediate is that in high light and
water stress conditions c4 plants can
take up carbon oxide more efficiently
they're also better in highlight in the
Gandhis temperature conditions because
they're able to keep the stomata closed
longer eliminating water loss in corn
plants to be this example vs. Arce c3
plants which should be in this case an
elm tree here we have this direct
binding of chrome accenting the
mesophyll cells and closes stomata and
then the carbon dioxide can essentially
will say be processed before entering
the calvin cycle here just a comparison
of c3 plants at low light and high light
and the rate of opposite synthesis we
notice that the carbon acid
concentration that differs between our
c4 plants even had almost no carbon
dioxide the rate of carbon oxide uptake
is greater in c4 plants simply because
they're slightly more efficient at it we
keep their stomata closed longer
complaints are crassulacean acid
metabolism succulents and cacti are
examples commonly found in very hot dry
areas such as deserts in these plants
corrected is stored in the form of an
acid before the photosynthetic processes
can occur the stomata are open at night
and the question is well what's an angel
opening stomata at night why don't they
do it during the daylight just about all
the other plants there's a specific
reason for that because they're in such
hot and dry environments the water loss
would be too great opening stomata at
night allowing the co2 to come in
eliminates lots of water loss but keep
in mind that we need light to form the
photosynthetic process and this creates
a challenge in plants sticking with
those complaints day versus night
there's definitely differences between
the two here's our day we know it's her
stomata are closed here during they it
is open his allowing
next need to come in but water vapor is
also leading but because it's at night
not a lot of hot and sunlight intensity
the amount of water lost is definitely
reduced but they need to have steps in
place to be able to utilize that co2 to
be able to use in the light reaction
give you a little bit of an idea at
night the operation rates are typically
lower reducing water loss carbon oxide
is converted to an acid and that's the
key part here our malate acid before
being used in the light dependent
reaction you can't plants during the day
the acids broken down and the co2 is
released e 2 for pisco or imposes a
synthetic process to occur simply put
that stomas opening corrects it's coming
in that carbon is being stored as an
acid then during the day the stomata are
closed and this acid now is being fed
into the light dependent reaction and
that carbon dioxide is being released in
the normal cart the c3 plant
photosynthetic process occurs but the
stomata remain closed that carbon F is
being released from the acid and that
close to mana during the day eliminates
the water loss of the plan in general
summary corrects it stored as a Ford
carbon acid malli in that cools at night
during the daytime
the malli is transferred to chloroplast
where it's converted back to carbon
dioxide which is then used for the
photosynthetic process the pre collected
carbon dioxide is concentrated around
the enzyme rubisco increasing low
synthetic efficiency and that's what we
see here's our day here's our night
cycle at night our common acids coming
in we're storing it as an acid in the
vacuole then during the day we're
releasing that acid we're breaking apart
the co2 run out to the calvin cycle to
generate our sugars in this case and
remember this occurs with plants at an
extremely dry and arid conditions like
these cactus here