if you've heard about carbon dioxide
based extraction of cannabis
you've come to the right place here on
debacle university because we're going
to go through and explain a little bit
more about this extraction
process
[Music]
all right let's get into carbon dioxide
based extraction of cannabis
so first off what's the description of
this method well the plant materials
first ground and then place into an
extraction
vesicle co2 gas undergoes intense
pressure and heat until it becomes
supercritical and a pump then forces the
supercritical carbon dioxide into the
extraction chamber
where trichrome and cannabinoid
breakdown occur so this is involving not
just regular co2 in the air
there is that getting it into that super
critical level
this is why specialized equipment is
required
now this goes on to this shows another
image down here
the pressure release valve forces
material into a separate container
where the temperature and pressure can
be precisely controlled this will cause
the molecules within the initial
mixture to bond to the co2
many systems will reroute the co2 back
into the tank causing
uh it to be used during the next batch
so they can kind of like almost
go back and kind of like reuse that the
extraction that was then moved to a
collection dar
such as a beaker we have separate
collection jars here and collect
separate fractions here we're seeing
that co2 is going back to recycler where
it could be potentially reused
so this is important to know that it's
not just
as simple as co2 from the air we are
having that supercritical
level of co2 and this says what is part
requires the specialized equipment
so what's the resulting end product well
the co2 extraction results in a crude
oil extract
that must be further refined through
other muscles such as
the distillation process the potency of
the extract typically ranges from 50 to
70 percent cannabinoids
the advantages of this method is higher
yielding than alcohol-based extraction
less value material is wasted specific
compounds with adjustments made to heat
pressure and run time
so we can kind of determine what we kind
of get or extract from this
no residual solvent in the final product
due to the evaporation of the carbon
dioxide
that's a great way kind of quote unquote
to dispose of
the waste there however the
disadvantages are that
much higher initial startup costs when
compared to other extraction methods
once purchased the equipment does
require proper training and safety
procedures to be understood and followed
mainly because you are creating that
supercritical carbon dioxide
so again there are some advantages
disadvantages of each but typically this
process
will require additional steps after but
this can be a great way to kind of start
the refinement process
start the extraction process and may be
worthwhile exploring
for your operation