okay here are we looking at cardiac
muscle now hopefully this is the first
one you're watching there's two others
on skeletal muscle and smooth muscle by
the end of watching all three of those
you hopefully can develop an
understanding for what makes each unique
and also where is each typically found
so this one's gonna focus on correct
muscle which is found in the heart
so our cardiac muscle it's composed of
chains of single cells each with its own
nucleus these chains are interconnected
forming a latticework
each heart cell is coupled to its
neighbors by a gap in junction so if you
remember from the skeletal system these
striations are found in both cardiac and
skeletal muscle however what makes
skeletal muscle here unique these kind
of little lines here so it's a zoomed in
version of that and what this is is an
intercalated disc this is allowing
electrical signals between cells to
occur we want our heart to contract at
you know regular intervals and these
help cause orderly pulsations of the
heart that electrical signal is able to
travel through these cardiac muscle
cells now the cardiac muscle is striated
muscle it's present only in the heart so
this is a very unique type of muscle
it's found only in the heart the fibers
have a single nucleus and are branched
and joined by one another by these
intercalated discs so that's a very
important and distinguishing factor of
cardiac muscle that makes it unique
compared to smooth and skeletal muscle
Lassa here these very important discs is
intercalated discs are part of the
cardiac muscle they contain gap
junctions of these desmosomes desmosomes
is a cell structure that anchors the
ends of the cardiac muscle fibers
together so the cells do not pull apart
during the stress of individual fibers
contracting so we could see a little bit
of an example here desmosomes are our
cell to cell junctions it's kind of
holding everything together remember
that we have cardiac muscle we might
Andreea located here here's an example
of our nucleus so be able to distinguish
our cardiac muscle compared to the other
two also keep in mind because we have
this rhythmic contractions in the heart
also have those regular electrical
impulses going through and ensuring our
heart has those nice regulated intervals
and pulsations