okay here we're gonna go over some
common cardiovascular diseases give you
a little bit about what's going on
behind them so you can have a greater
understanding of what's going on and how
the typical process of the
cardiovascular system is not working
properly starting with a very common one
heart attack or myocardial infarction
this is the leading cause of death in
the United States it's caused by an
insufficient supply of blood to one or
more parts of the heart muscle so while
the heart does go through and moves
blood throughout the body because it
itself is a muscle it needs to be
supplied with its own blood supply
coronary arteries can become blocked as
we see here with Platt and this can lead
to damage to the heart muscle leading
ultimately to a heart attack here is the
heart disease death rates from 2011 to
2013 in adults over 35 over the country
we see an increase rate of heart attacks
in this particular region of the country
how we negate heart attacks or how they
may be hopefully prevented if detected
early such as blockages in the coronary
artery would be through an angioplasty
angioplasty involves placing a wire mesh
to hold the artery open they will insert
this wire mesh through a long tube
typically in the groin region will
Gateway up to the heart ultimately
getting to the blockage region and then
literally like a balloon they kind of
open this up and they plaster the plaque
against the side walls they will then
leave a mesh in there to help hold that
artery open wide so that blood can
easily flow through there allowing the
muscles of the heart
dig it adequate flow of blood so they
can perform their very necessary and
continual function continuing on the
strokes they typically result a blood
clot in your brain but can it also occur
with pressure on the brain as a result
of inflammation so it could be an actual
blockage or this is why if there's head
trauma swelling with the brain is a
major concern because that can also lead
to stroke like symptoms we're looking at
the stroke deaths rates across the
country again adults over 35 years old
in 2002 to 2007 and
you see a concentration in this
particular region of the country now if
you think someone's experiencing a
stroke the despot Authority is the
acronym here fast for one is the face we
begin to kind of weaken or droop in one
side they will do the toll to put their
arms out and keep them level and
oftentimes one become weak and fall down
and slowly the ability to speak might
become a challenge for that individual
so they're often told to kind of keep
talking and to monitor that and if this
is found out be time to call 9-1-1 so
this stroke and those things to look
forward numbness or weakness in the face
arm or leg especially on one side of the
body typically it's not both sides more
evident on one side there can be
confusion or trouble understanding or
speaking send trouble seeing or blurred
vision trouble walking dizziness or loss
of balance I included a link here where
you to see an individual actually have a
minor stroke and are actually explaining
to you in the video while it's actually
happening to them so a pretty
interesting video they're now monitoring
blood pressure we have a sig you know a
size fitting monitor which is used for
two measurements I'm sure you've had
this done in doctors office where they
put the cuff on and they build that
pressure up and are basically stopping
the blood flow and what they're doing is
they're listening for the pulse and
they're measuring the systolic in distal
pressure the High Point and low point
and they're using this to gauge your
blood pressure and ultimately your heart
health
now those blood pressures you may hear
those numbers of you know 120 over 80
and it says millimeters of mercury is
what they're measuring blood flows with
pressure through your body however too
much can cause hypertension we have
negative impacts such as damage on your
arteries as well increasing heart
attacks and strokes so if you know your
numbers you can compare to this want to
be in this normal green region here we
can see elevated hypertension stage 1
stage 2 and a crisis mode here with
seeking emergency care and this is
numbers
by the American Heart Association
continuing on to stay healthy seven
steps eat the healthier heart and take a
moment to pause the video and read them
here smoke for your life monitoring your
blood pressure healthy weight watching
your cholesterol controlling your blood
sugar
staying active in having a healthy diet
are all components of the healthier
heart it doesn't involve just one thing
it's important have a healthy lifestyle
in general wearable devices have become
all the rage and it's helping people
keep track of their exercise but you
don't need to go through this hike
technologically advanced stage you just
want to calculate your normal heart rate
this is the mathematical equation you
want to feel your pulse is the second
hand of a watch or clock to time 10
seconds while simultaneously counting
your heartbeats then multiply the number
of beats by six to get your heart rate
per minute or number of beats the equals
that time six hit your beats per minute
factors it may affect your heart rate
the exercise meditation illness and
anemia stress so on and so forth looking
at the age groups here I'm in the ranges
of heartbeats you can do it to yourself
you want to use three fingers to know
the image here leaves is to threes a
little bit better and calculate your
heart rate value your beats per minute
and see where you fall on this range
hopefully you're in the athletic to kind
of good range above average average
below average and Poor's be more
negative here you might want to consider
living making adjustments to realize
you're living a healthier lifestyle so
go through calculate your normal heart
rate see see where you fall