on this debaco university video we're
going to go over some caterpillar
identification and control
as well as at the end show you two
different species of caterpillars
feeding on cannabis plants
[Music]
all right let's get into caterpillar
identification and control on cannabis
well first off there's many different
types of caterpillars sadly all that in
some way negatively impact cannabis
these would be the issue covered here
but realize there's are even more
than these just in the list provided
so first off painted lady identification
so they're typically
two to five leaves may be webbed
together you might kind of see this kind
of like
like cocoon like structure and and this
is kind of this ragged chewing injuries
will also
be evident in that particular area the
caterpillars
within the webbed leaf kind of shelter
there are notably
spiny and early stage larvae are pale
brown
as they age they become variable marked
with black and yellow
with considerable range in the overall
coloration you can also see kind of the
what the butterfly looks like
as well as that kind of spiny look here
to the actual caterpillars it's
important to
identify this as well as others at all
stages of their life cycle
we also have the salt marsh caterpillar
identification and this is
damage to hemp by salt marsh caterpillar
is likely to be minimal
peak feeding occurs late in the season
and is limited mainly to the foliage
so here we see some saltwatch
caterpillars shown
some of the range in colorations so it
is a little bit more variable it's not
just kind of like one standard look
um so just be aware of that when we're
looking at identifying the caterpillar
you might be finding on your cannabis
plant we also have the yelly
yellow woolly bearer for identification
and does have a yellow coloration it
does look very woolly
damaged by hemp is likely also thought
to be minimal uh by this
caterpillar peak feeding occurs also
late in the season
and season and is limited to basically
the foliage
so keep in mind that just because you
find a caterpillar on your plant doesn't
mean they're doomed
some of this feeding occurs late in the
season some of it might be minimal but
still worth
a proper identification the zebra
caterpillar identification
here in hemp damage limited smallmouth
foliage scattered throughout the
planting
damage to hemp by the zebra caterpillar
can be expected to be minimal
and insignificant to crop yield kind of
a distinctive one
both in the caterpillar stage a little
bit
less so in the actual adult stage there
now more brown a little even more able
to blend in here
kind of that neat bright yellow stripes
those very distinctive
black lines on white background then we
have the variegated cutworm
and this appears to primarily feed on
hemp leaves
however it is known to tunnel into
developing flowers and fruit of other
crops so be sure to inspect
developing buds it is known to be a kind
of tunneler
so it happens on other species why not
and hemp you know it's typically found
on the outer portion
it has the ability to tunnel uh so just
be mindful of that
then we have the managing of the
caterpillars so calpers are
most effectively controlled and they're
small most pesticides will have little
to no effect on bigger caterpillars
most are based on bt as the active
ingredient bacillus thyroid genesis
chemical control should be used as a
last resort as proper fertility
irrigation sanitation should all prior
be prioritized over pesticides there's
also on some of the larger ones in small
applications
could be hand removed now let's get into
actually seeing some of these
caterpillar sadly in action
feeding on cannabis plants enjoy
all right in this video we see an army
worm eating a cannabis plant
now the audio is not necessarily true to
the actual what's going on but we can
see in real time
just how aggressive one of these
caterpillars can basically be
these worms are how quick they can eat
and devour a plant
uh you can see here really close to the
bud so that's of course of concern
and usually where there's one well none
pictured in the image here
i'm sure there's a few more and this
implements more scouting as well as
control
in addition to army worms we also have
another caterpillar pest here
this is a winter moth of feeding on a
cannabis plant
located in a high tunnel