humor provide a brief overview of what's
called cation exchange capacity or CEC
needed to Inchon the exact of the
details of the chemistry of the
interaction here whatever basic
understanding is come this is something
very commonly provided in soil test
engross didn't have questions about this
so cation exchange capacity or as I said
is abbreviated CEC this is the measure
of the soils ability to hold positively
charged ions those are important we see
the positive charged ions mentioned here
are a lot that are associated with major
nutrients needed by the plants the CEC
influences the soils ability to hold on
to essential nutrients and provide a
buffer against soil acidification so we
see that the soil particle here is that
typical permanent negative charge and
that's going to attract or hold these
positive ions which tend to have a lot
of nutrients that the plants need so
first off that cation that I'd mentioned
lesson Adam with a positive charge
it means it's lost an electron so we go
back to hydrogen atom here one proton
one electron protons have a positive
charge electrons have a negative charge
so if it's a cation that means it's lost
an electron in this case it loses an
electron called becomes oxidized or this
becomes now positive ion which would be
properly termed cation in contrast to
that atoms a negative charge it is an
anion so here we're gaining another
electron electrons have a negative
charge it's being reduced and we have
the hydrogen and ion here
so anion negatively charged cation
positively charged since this is cation
exchange capacity its ability for soils
to exchange positive ions some of those
base cation so you mentioned the
important nutrients such as calcium
magnesium sodium and potassium these are
all involved in those cations that are
interacting with roots in the negatively
charged soil particles what influences
CSC the soils with higher clay fraction
can have higher CC organic matter also
has high CC so you're looking at just
increasing CC well for an organic matter
in clean materials well that's just
naturally gonna increase that CC you can
see here in contrast sand is a very low
CEC I'm so just again something to keep
in mind if you are growing the same
medium that your CC naturally is it's
going to be lower by the inherent
particle size solo CC what is this cause
well soil is comely sanding in texture
with low CEC are more likely to develop
deficiencies in potassium and magnesium
as well as other cations and having that
low cation exchange doesn't allow this
to be held very well it's not a plant to
be able to tape them up so some of the
drawbacks to have the CC see the
nutrient deficiencies can incur