this tobacco university video is going
to cover sometimes called the mysterious
cbc or cbca cannabinoid
all right so let's get into cbc and cbca
cannabinoids here produced in cannabis
plants
so first off a great research article if
you want to learn a little bit more of
information
you have the proper citation here so you
can expand your knowledge even
greater than what this video lecture
will provide
so first off as i said kind of
mysterious kind of
uh cbca or cbc of the major side-chain
cannabinoids the least is known about
cbca or cbc
similarly to all of the other
cannabinoids it has shown to have
some antimicrobial properties but again
we're trying to understand this one a
little bit more
it is synthesized by cannabis in the
same way as thca
and cbda and is synthesized uh it
also produces the phytotoxic byproducts
so we know a little bit about the
pathway we know a little bit about what
it's how it's produced
about the side products that are that
produce the byproducts
but still remains a little mysterious
however to provide you some information
about this particular
cannabinoid since often asked what is
cbc well it's a powerful
non-psychoactive cannabinoid meaning it
will not cause the
high feeling pre-pre pre-pre-clinical
unpublished so again keep that in mind
uh study
did demonstrate anti-tumor effects of
both cbg
as well as cbc against gastrointestinal
cancer cells
so again unpublished research pre kind
of clinical trials but give some at
least some indication
of potential good for future research
both these cannabinoids were shown to
induce significantly higher rates of
cancer cell death
compared to other cannabinoids and
suggest the need for further
investigation into synergistic
efficacy all important there and has
some early promise
for something that we currently don't
know a ton about
also relate to inflammation so cbc
battles inflammation by activating the
cb2 receptors
however because it does not activate cb1
the healing properties of
cbc could be enhanced when combined with
cannabinoids that do
such as thc so again you're getting into
this kind of
synergistic effect there not knowing a
lot about it but early indications
do have some potential medical promise
as well as potential combination
with other cannabinoids to get the
greatest positive effect