in this debaco university video we're
going to go over cbg
in cbga cannabinoids and some of the
more advanced processes that these are
involved
as the plant goes through and produces
various other cannabinoids
and where does cbg fall in that
particular process
[Music]
all right let's get into cbg and cbga
cannabinoids
so here is a research article if you're
looking for more information on this
cannabinoid as well as
others here's the proper citation you
can go take a look at it for yourself
getting into the specifics of this
article this video lecture
i've derived from information from that
article as well as others
we're looking at the cbga pathway so
kind of looking at this before i get
into the details looking at cbga
being located right here on a quick
general sense what you're noticing is a
lot of other pathways a lot of other
things coming down the chain uh kind of
getting to this bottleneck a restriction
point
and then we have cbga and we have a
division from there
this is why cbga is so important i've
got a bunch of ancillary processes that
come down
to cbga and then there's a division step
from there as well
it's kind of that restriction point
molecule now that cbj is produced
you can see here from the gpp and oa by
the synthesis of aromatic uh
pyrim transferase or just
ap these biochemistry takes place in the
plastid
which is also where the net pathway
produces the gpp
and terpenes so we're seeing some
overlapped other plant
processes gpp shared substance in both
cannabinoids as well as terpenes again
showing some overlap in these pathways
within the plant
after the cbga is synthesized is
transported out of the plastid
to the hyaline glob into the apoplast
this is all occurring
again within that trichome structure
this is where the conversion of cbga to
subsequent cannabinoids takes place
and those subsequent quenavionoids can
be thca
or cbda the cbg cbga
is not converted into subsequent
cannabinoids which will accumulate in
the trichome now heat may cause a
conversion to its neutral active form
just cbg because heat will cause cbga
to basically be converted to cbg so the
taco message here is for
more familiar with potentially thc or
cbd
if we're looking back at the chemical
processes of the plant
it all kind of originated in the cbga
production of the plant
so if a plant can produce cannot produce
a lot of cbga or support producer
it is also be a poor producer of some
other potentially cannabinoids you might
be more familiar with
so the interaction with the cannabinoids
and the receptors is important
cbga and cbg have been shown to interact
with cannabinoid receptors that bind to
cbd
and also thc modulating their effect
so we're getting into this could also
potentially kind of get into
competing with effects of other
cannabinoids
based on how they bind specific
receptors in the body
this is why research needs to be done to
better understand these potential
interactions
as well as binding steps now there's
anecdotal reports
so many anecdotal reports have shown
that cbg
has similar effects to cbd medical
studies have shown that cbg is a potent
andro receptor antagonist and other
studies have shown cbg
is has antibiotic properties it is worth
noting that
all of the general side chain
cannabinoids have shown to exhibit
potential antimicrobial properties
so this would make sense if this falls
into the same category
i mentioned these are from more
anecdotal reports and kind of anal
reports
really aren't valid we need clinical
trials uh even though you may say that
oh
enough people say it must be true well
we need those clinical trials to
have a double-blind study to actually
prove uh potential effects
and maybe find other pathways or
sequences we may not have
originally considered lastly looking at
the cannabinoid biosynthesis
pathway cbj is a cannabinoid precursor
again we see all these kind of
cannabinoid processes going through
all arrows leading to cbga and then from
there all arrows coming from cbga
this bio synthesis pathway leads through
or at least can be restricted by cbga
this is why it's an important kind of
precursor to understand
not only how plants produce it but how
it goes
on to produce other compounds in the
plant
that restriction point there can be
vital
and great for future research