okay this is a short video lecture on
cell Junction there's three major ones
we're going to go over so starting with
the first one tight junctions this is a
specialized connection of two adjacent
animal cell membranes usually
eliminating space see here's our tight
junctions really close together
basically you can think of them kind of
like fusing together super tight
junctions looming in a space in this
case we're two hands to be touching here
here are tight junctions that we're
looking at basically eliminating that
space set that may be present there
desmosomes is the other form of cells
the cell Junction a structure by which
two adjacent cells are attached forms
with protein plates in the cell
membranes linked by filaments these
function like rivets so if you've seen
the underside of like a bridge the
bridge will have rivets these little
areas here are rivets and that's kind of
the same concept that's occurring here
our desmosomes have these rivet like
structures or these structures
homologous to the rivets that hold up
the bridge to be able to adhere one cell
to another cell the last form of cell
junctions would be gap junctions in the
animal cells these are specialized
intracellular connections that join the
satellizer of two cells we see here is
one cell down here this gap junction is
this little kind of protein like channel
allowing communication to occur from the
lower cell through the upper cell now in
animal cells are called gap junctions
however in plant cells they have a
different name they're called plus
plasma des Matta
their channels through the cell walls
remember plant cells have the cell wall
that allows molecules and substances to
move freely as needed this is
advantageous for the cells so it reduces
the energy when it's looking to move
particular nutrients or could be waste
products or signals from one cell to
another they look just like this they're
holes in the cell wall these
plasmodesmata are holes however while
this is great in allows things to move
freely viruses really enjoy plasma does
in the sense that they can move through
a leaf structure very quickly and this
is one of the downfall so plasmodesmata
remember the same basic structure of
kurzon plant cells as possible desmona
and as animal cells as gap junctions
even though they're basically the same
thing plant cells have that cell wall
that nice comparison between these three
here
remember gap junctions providing the
cytoplasmic channels from one cell to
adjacent cells for communication
desmosomes are function like rivets
fastening cells together in our strong
sheets in our tape junctions rotate
junctions our membranes at adjacent
cells are very tightly bonded together
forming seals around the cells these are
some examples of the three main types of
cell junctions