here we're gonna look at cell membranes
so this is an example of one a lot of
going on here keep in mind the cytoplasm
is on the inside of the cell and the
extracellular fluid is on the outside
this is the membrane that's dividing the
two and you can see there's a lot going
on here was our phospholipid bilayer and
our protein channels we're learning
about a little bit and hopefully explain
what some of these are so starting with
what we're focusing on that membrane
it's the area located right here you
could see these large bluish purple kind
of ovals represent proteins so now we're
just focused on this perimeter of the
cell we've gone over cell organelles all
these wonderful things on the inside now
we're focusing just on the perimeter
so first the overcoming the cell barrier
so the cell membrane is a barrier but
nutrients have to get into the cell
because the cell needs those to be a
survive and products and waste must get
out of the cell so while this is a
barrier it can't be completely solid it
has to be exchanging certain things
permeability determines what moves in
and out of the cell and here we have our
red blood cells
what's co2 in this case coming in and
then it's translating transported
through Co tool that have to leave the
cells so this cell barrier this membrane
is allowing certain things to come in
but also needs a lot of things to go out
of it so the cell barrier would think
about this is it is not impermeable
which means it would let nothing in or
out like this rock wall it's not freely
permeable well if it lets anything past
select this revolving door and you come
in and out it's what we call selectively
permeable it restricts the movement like
the bouncer here at the nightclub or bar
so overcoming the cell barrier sometime
is selectively permeable this is the key
term here for cell barrier it allows
some materials to move freely restricts
other materials so we could see here the
larger molecules are kept on one side
the small molecules are let through same
thing here only certain molecules fill
it through some are repelled
so restricted materials semi-pro
restrict certain materials based on
could be their size their electrical
charge their molecular shape their lipid
solubility any one of these can restrict
the materials to come in hydrophobic
materials our lipid Seibel can pass
right through the membrane rapidly polar
molecules do not cross remain very
rapidly now polar number of water lipids
are kind of like those waxy coatings and
transport proteins are allow passage of
hydrophilic surfaces across the membrane
so these transport proteins these are
those things we saw embedded in the
membrane they can allow certain things
to come through membrane function all
cells around a plasma membrane cell
membranes are composed of a lipid
bilayer with globular proteins embedded
in that bilayer so again look at another
example of this picture of this cell
here we have our phospholipid bilayer
here with our heads and tails from our
lipid based tails phospho base or
charged base polar heads clean this
bilayer in here we have our integral
proteins they could be channel proteins
peripheral proteins to sexists on the
outside glycoproteins are protein as the
carbohydrate remember glycol think
glucose a glycolipid is a lipid or the
carbohydrate attached certain things
here and these are important for
recognition and also allowing things to
pass through so here's that same picture
on the function again the membrane the
external surface carbohydrate groups
Jordans lipids from inform glycolipids
and with proteins are from glycoproteins
these functions per cell identity marker
so this is an important aspect want to
make sure we're identifying things that
are occurring it's kind of like you in
school when you're wearing your IDs this
is a way for cells to identify what
they're bumping into or what's what's
one cell differ than another cell this
membrane is not absolutely rigid
structure like we saw with the rock wall
so we call it fluid mosaic so fluid like
water and the waves here and mosaic all
these little pieces
together to form the mosaic of the eagle
flying so what this fluid mosaic is is
we have our hydrophobic remember fearing
water tails mana lipids and our
phosphate heads this fluid mosaic this
reading bottle cap shows our rotating
care this shows a little bit better of
an idea that it's kind of like moving
it's not a rigid structure it's got this
fluid mosaic like model it's able to
move a little bit and this mosaic like
appearance is what's causing the overall
look so looking specifically at the
details we have our hydrophilic head and
our hydrophobic tails remember our
saturated and unsaturated fatty acids
from our macromolecules and our
hydrophilic head the phosphate and the
glycerol here know was saturated
everything is single bonds their tails
are very straight and if it's mixed with
unsaturated you'll know it's a double
bond forms and our unsaturated causing
this little kink of this old kick in the
tail the phospholipid bilayer mainly two
layers of phospholipids then non-polar
tails point inwards here and the polar
heads and the surface some of these
contain cholesterol especially in animal
cells it's fluid a lot of proteins to
move around within the bilayer so
there's proteins that we saw are not
fixed in one location they can move and
push out some of these and move their
way through the phospholipid bilayer
they can form the sheet or some of these
kind of circular vesicle like locating
structures the cholesterol effect
membrane fluidity within animal cells
and their membranes you can see here's
cholesterol down in there so we want to
keep our cholesterol low but we want to
don't want to be zero we want to have
some cholesterol next it's going to
affect the permeability of our
phospholipid bilayer in this case in the
cholesterol that we're getting measured
in our blood is different than us this
is actually bound up the cholesterol in
our blood is moving through our vesicles
and involving in coming in contact with
red blood cells this
is embedded in all animal cells and
membranes membrane proteins membranes
are this kind of embedded Parshin here
in the lipid bilayer peripheral proteins
are proteins that are opinions that are
loosely bound to the surface of the
membrane so these peripheral proteins
are on the outside okay they're not
going all the way through it could be
important for recognition doesn't mean
they're not important integral proteins
could pass the entire way through and
channel proteins also pass the entire
way through the phospholipid bilayer
keep in mind is peripheral proteins as
well as these integral and channel
proteins can work their way and move
through the lipid bilayer just like you
moving through a busy crowd same thing
with these proteins are proteins
penetrate a hydrophobic core in a lipid
bilayer often transmembrane proteins
completely spanning the number in the
car channel are an integral proteins
here there's mother of renditions and
showing that there is the external and
internal conditions of the cell being
spanned by these proteins solutions and
transport remember solution could be a
homogenous mixture
competiveness two or more components
this cell vent and the solute the
solvent is that those is the dissolving
medium and the solute is the components
and smaller chronic in the solution so
an example here of salt water solvents
the dissolving medium that is the water
our solute in this case would be the
salt intercellular fluid neoplasm inside
a sovereign inside the cell and
extracellular fluid it's on the outside
can be flat a platform we're talking
about blood cells I'm interested inside
in this case it's tissue fluid could be
your extra cell fluid is an example of
that and it's exterior of the cells or
tissues so something I want to the thing
about when I look at ourselves and our
recognition and some of the other videos
might be helpful is are some moments
like nightclubs are they allowing and
certain things to come in and basically
bouncing or rejecting other things from
coming in and how do they go about this
how does recognition in cell
communication and I
these come into play here so the cell
membrane is important that it doesn't
want to let anything just come in and
out wants to help regulate that so how
are these integral proteins and the
basic structure of the phospholipid and
pay attention that word phospho and
lipid bilayer coming into play good
questions to ask and related to cell
membranes