okay here we look at cellular nuclear
components and we see a couple cells
here with well-defined
nuclei and others that have just or
chromosomes because they're going
through the process
of cell division well here we're going
to kind of focus on that well-defined
nucleus to start with because it is the
command center of the cell that's
separated from the cytoplasm by a
nuclear envelope
it consists of a double layer membrane
nuclear pores permit the exchange
between the nucleoplasm which is the
interior
and the cytoplasm which is located on
the exterior of the nucleus
now this nucleus contains semi-fluid
nucleoplasms they just said that
interior space
and chromatin consists of dna of genes
and proteins
this condenses to form chromosomes this
is important
as cells going through the process of
division those chromosomes are formed
during that
process so we have our dna our kind of
isolated kind of patches and particles
that are going to be condensed because
every human cell has about six
feet of dna in every cell and it's
ultimately going to be kind of
condensed down to these chromosomes that
we can recognize
as this densely packed dna the nucleus
itself has a nuclear envelope and that's
that
lipid bilayer it's two layers here
and it's a membrane surrounding the
nucleus it also has an inner membrane
coated with
laminate which is a fibrous protein that
helps keep everything
organized that's where the chromatin is
physically attached to
we have the outer membrane which is kind
of ties in with the endoplasmic
reticulum we have very important
nuclear pores which regulate the
transport of proteins
and rna in and out of the nucleus
they're pores not holes because they
are a regulated step now the reason why
these cells
or nucleus have these pores which are
very important
um they're large protein complexes and
they do allow for necessary proteins to
enter the nucleus
from the cytoplasm because they have
special sequences that indicate that
they belong
in the nucleus a lot of viruses and
other
things that want to take over the cell
want to enter or find a way to get into
the nucleus so these pores are kind of
that regulation
step now small molecules such as ions
freely pass and diffuse into and out of
the nucleus but those larger ones
have to go through the pores and those
are regulated
in a nucleus we have a small darkened
region here the nucleolus
and that's composed mainly of rrna which
is ribosomal rna
there's at least one sometimes many can
be seen depending what cell you're
looking at
this is the site of transcription the
site of rrna where those ribosomes are
synthesized
and processed looking at a kind of
cartoon image here we have that
nucleolus
it can cause some of the chromatin and
ribosomal subunits
region of intensive ribosomal or rna
synthesis that's that darkened region in
that nuclear envelope that's the surface
of the nucleus bounded by two
phospholipid bilayers
it's a double membrane with pores and
that nucleoplasm which is that inside
that semi-fluid medium inside the
nucleus
those chromosomes the dna of eukaryotes
is divided into linear chromosomes
and they exist as strands of chromatin
except during cell
division histones these little
blue spheres here are associated with
packaging
proteins and they help the dna wrap
around them
so they can help increase the density
and compact that dna
without it getting tangled