okay in plants and animals cells go
through the process of division and it
can be through mitosis or meiosis
depending on what end product they're
producing mitosis they're gonna produce
two identical copies of the original
cell meiosis is going to produce gametes
such as pollen or egg now cell division
results in increasing the total number
of cells and I said there's two
different end products the gamete or sex
cell production is through meiosis in
identical copies would be through
mitosis
now meiosis produces four total cells
that are genetically different with the
goal to produce new offspring these are
cells that are producing either pollen
or egg cells there's actually two phases
of division and that's how you go about
getting the four total cells in the end
what's happening is the chromosomes are
spreading out and being pulled to
different poles and then the centromeres
are breaking causing different copies to
be resulting in the end products to
increase genetic variability of the
offspring to increase ideally the odds
of survival now mitosis is a little
different mitosis is cell division
resulting in two identical cells from
the original there's a result of typical
plant growth by by and large mitosis
occurs much more frequently as the cells
multiplies it's inheriting the same
chromosome and genetic material as the
original cell if it doesn't that's what
we call a mutation that would occur
ideally there's no different engine from
the original and that mutation typically
ends poorly for the cell so there's
steps and measures in place to allow
cells to divide but allow them divide in
a way that helps ensure they have the
same genetic material as the original
cell meristematic tissue is found it to
shoot tip this is the growing tip here
and also at just behind the root caps
this is a root microscopic view of the
root these meristems are a site of high
might hydrate of mitosis you can think
about that logically the apical the very
top meristem is a site of growth because
that's what the plants can be growing
upward and the root area is also going
to be a high rate of cell division
because that's gonna serve as that root
growing through the soil
to increase the plant's ability to
observe water and nutrients the root cap
here is a protective structure that
pushes through the soil so it comes to
contact with rocks or some other debris
it's not damaging this very sensitive
and important area of mitosis cell
elongation occurs so this is looking at
the room to talk about the air people
call meristem a plant growth is not as a
result of cell division here elongation
here the roots growing by those same
cells same number of cells simply
stretching on this allows the plant to
grow in size as root cells in long gates
the pressure pushes the root through the
soil and in the apical meristem as we're
getting more cells than the elongate in
this area now cell differentiation this
allows cells to take on a very specific
function depending where they're located
in the plant so just as you originate
from one cell and cells in different
areas took on parts of the circulatory
system or nervous system the same thing
happens in plants the imple cells and
leaves may take on the function of
producing food cells in the stems may
take on vascular tissue and cells in the
roots may take on the very important
task of water and nutrient absorption it
all this occurs this differential occurs
after division this allows our cells to
become specialized to perform a function