okay here I'm going to provide a brief
overview of cellular respiration focus
mainly on glycolysis kreb cycle and the
electron transport chain here so the
quick overview of seller respiration is
controlled sequence of steps with
releasing energy from sugars essentially
glucose is converted back to carbon
dioxide way to think about celery
respirations it's the opposite of the
photosynthetic process celery
respiration occurs in active cells
meaning both plant and animal cells in
the mitochondria the organelle where
this process takes place so if you look
at kind of the equation in glucose plus
six oxygens through the process of
cellular respiration yields carbon
dioxide water and energy again this is
occurring in the mitochondria heat and
ATP or energy are being essentially
released and it's taking in glucose and
oxygen
okay that's made for the process of
photosynthesis and it's releasing carbon
dioxide which is then needed or combined
with sunlight or solar energy in water
to form the glucose and oxygen that then
the mitochondria need to use and the
circle goes around and around so if you
can memorize the photosynthetic reaction
if you simply put the arrow the other
way we'll notice we have is the cellular
respiration equation now we're gonna
take the general sense of this but want
to have you comparison because
respiration occurs kind of in two ways
aerobic in the presence of oxygen or is
also anaerobic when there's no oxygen
aerobic is when there's oxygen present
it's very efficient produces a total of
38 ATP's 36 our gain there's a little in
ATP investment there the final products
are water coming outside in 34 ATP
molecules you might be wondering I just
said 36 is what we gain for ATP right
well the final product is 34 to those
ATP's come from the anaerobic portion
initially started when it's aerobic
we're talking to mitochondria remember
ATP's are adenosine triphosphate in
anaerobic without oxygen we have very
low efficiency morally gaining a total
of two ATP's
implants at ethanol carbon oxide and
four ATP's were produced and this is
kindly called like fermentation we see
here with the fermentation of wine our
grapes into wine
that's an anaerobic respiration process
in animals you generate lactic acid
their heads sore muscles and feel that
you know sore muscles after a tense
workout that's because your muscles went
through and generated lactic acid that's
an anaerobic process and that acid is
what you feel on your muscles and it's
kind of like sore and you're stretching
and that's what you're feeling it's the
literally burnin effect it's an acid and
anaerobic portion of respiration occurs
in the cytoplasm respiration both types
start out in this with the same
glycolysis glycolysis is the first step
in the breakdown of glucose to extract
energy for cellular metabolism no oxygen
is needed this generates small amounts
of energy
now our glucose can be broken down to
our fructose or a pga tour pyruvic acid
I'm not gonna get into all the details
here please realize that this is a very
complex sequence of steps that's
involved perfect acid which is without
oxygen of fermentation does not yield
much energy it's a take-home message
here most is tied up at the end alcohol
or the acid ethanol would be an example
plants convert ethyl alcohol or ethanol
animals produce lactic acid so you can
see here's our ethanol with our floor
plant with waterlogged roots and there's
our muscles after vigorous exercise
we're producing a lot of lactic acid
only 7% of the energy in glucose
molecule is removed in a fermentation
process so there's a lot of
disadvantages there's only two ATP's
gained nad plus becomes fill electrons
quickly can't make more ATP that's the
disadvantages so you millander why would
this even occur in the first place well
there's a couple of meanders in the
sense that glycolysis can actually occur
very quickly produce thousands of ATP's
in a few milliseconds it doesn't require
oxygen because it can occur in
environments that lack oxygen so this
availa during ATP's quickly is important
when you're at vigorous exercise because
your muscles aren't able to get oxygen
efficiently enough so in ordinary
some energy
your body's gonna go through this
glycolysis process
sadly the aftereffect is that acid that
is produced now when in the presence of
oxygen we have something called the
citric acid or Krebs cycle this is
aerobic respiration 39 percent of the
energy is stored as ATP versus only 7%
of fermentation so much more efficient
high energy yielding 36 ATP's are gained
for one glucose molecule 602 s are
converted to six carbon dioxide's
and reminders also six water molecules
are produced we have to balance our
equation so it's high energy found a
nice little overview movie animation if
you want to view that you're more than
welcome to this is showing just
glycolysis pyruvate oxidation the citric
acid cycle how these are all involved in
aerobic respiration lastly for those who
really want to know about the citric
acid cycle or the Krebs cycle and the
complexities this is a image of that
keep in mind because it is a cycle we do
see this kind of rotating event where we
need to regenerate what we started with
intensive purposes I want you to know
just the general information about the
respiration process and in this video
I'm not going to get into all the
specifics