okay this is very short a video here
going over the central dogma biology
there's three main steps replication
transcription and translation this is
kind of give you an idea of the bigger
picture and put in all the parts
together so DNA can replicate that's
generating more DNA DNA can also go
through the process of transcription
where it's written differently and you
could think of this is DNA being written
as RNA it's being written differently
remember thymine is present in DNA
uracil in RNA and then translation we're
translating our RNA sequence is
something completely different in this
case at protein in this process here of
replication transcription and
translation is what's called the central
dogma of biology
you should be very familiar with each of
these terms here's a little bit more
detail for each DNA making more DNA is
in the B replication that's producing
identical copies and that's key for that
transcription is DNA being converted to
RNA and the opposite of that we call
reverse transcription going from RNA to
DNA some viruses may do this the
telomerase is at the end our chromosomes
go through this reverse transcription
and that's going from RNA to DNA
translation think of translating a
different language is the conversion of
RNA to a protein and remember that
reverse transcriptase is basically going
backwards typically we think of going
from DNA to RNA to a protein again a
central dogma here this presents it in a
slightly different format we can see the
same terms used replication
transcription translation in general
moving from DNA to RNA to a protein
there are special cases where we can
kind of skip certain steps on certain
viruses mayanna go backwards from there
might be a DNA base and I'm going to
make RNA so reverse transcription and
other things in the cell gene
expressions use of information in DNA to
direct the correction of proteins this
is a person's to take two stages one is
transcription tuning of the letters the
other is writing a transcription you're
actually writing in translation is
conversion to another language
nucleotide language two amino acids is a
way to think about that so we're going
from our DNA to our RNA
ultimately our protein and same things
shown here we have our double-stranded
DNA being transcribed to RNA and we know
that's RNA uracil and it's being
translated now to a sequence of amino
acids again it's a very short video in
the central dogma be familiar with the
various terms used such as replication
transcription and translation and
reverse we look here we also wanna keep
of the idea of the reverse transcription
so hopefully this makes a little bit
more sense be able to recognize these
terms and provide definitions for them
which we'll go into more detail in other
lectures