all right so here on this tobacco
university video we're gonna be looking
at the chain
of custody and how this relates to crime
scene in the processing and handling of
evidence so first of all what is the
chain of custody well chain of custody
is a record
a recorded list of all persons who come
in possession of an item of
evidence so the goal is to maintain
a document that includes exactly what
happened to the evidence
from the time it was found to the time
it is presented
in court anyone that goes to see it and
when that gets passed on
that chain of custody that chain that's
you're able to follow a paper trail
of where the evidence went now the
requirements of the chain of custody
here
we want to have the list of evidence
including the item number and a brief
description
this identifies the location the item
was stored the date and time of all
transfers that may have occurred
signature from the individual releasing
the evidence to another individual or
location
the signature of the individual
transporting the evidence if if it
applies
the same trade individual receiving the
evidence from the other individual or
location and the reason
for that transfer so as you can see
there's a lot of requirements associated
here with the chain of custody
but it is a very important process here
now the presentation of the chain of
custody
well when we're looking here the
evidence container must have identified
markings the collector's
initials should be placed on the seal as
well if evidence is turned over to
another person the transfer must be
recorded
as an evidence of transmissional sheet
and it is very important that
documentation is made
so that that piece of evidence that was
collected can uphold in
the court of law lastly what is one of
those transmissional sheets look like
well here's just an example of one
and they're all documents the chain of
custody for a list of items of evidence
that are numbered consecutively
so we see kind of these examples of
these transmissional sheets here
all the information that's required so
all the hard work that went into
acquiring the evidence to begin with and
ensures it isn't tampered with in any
way and it can hold
up in the investigation of a crime scene