welcome to this debaco university video
we'll be looking at challenges
estimating yield for indoor cannabis
production
[Music]
so a lot of growers asked well how does
indoor compare to outdoor what's going
to be my yield for an indoor
i'm going to go over some of the
complexities while there's not just a
quick
short answer to that question so first
off looking at this
reference article here which is where
i've pulled the data from that you're
going to see
keep in mind that this article was kind
of looking at it more from an
investigation forensics kind of
angle but it does provide some good
information
so they first looked at of course you
know looking at gross revenue
when we're looking at gross revenue for
our indoor grow operations
and they had four areas for rooms i
should say
that were under the investigation here
they're looking at the
room numbers the number of cycles number
of plants were grown
sales this was in the netherlands so it
is euros per kilogram
yield per plant in grams yield per cycle
total yield and gross revenue
the multiplication of the later prices
and the total yield in the table above
reveals the gross revenues we see here
obtained in each
growth room according to the court with
a correction for the assumed
number of growth cycles in the first
growth room there
so again there are some assumptions
being made here we can see the number of
plants
being as low as 266 and as high as over
5 000.
the total gross revenue from all grow
rooms together is an estimated to have
been
over 5.5 million euros over the period
from august 6 2005 to march 2009
this is again what they were
investigating as part of this article
so why is it again so hard to kind of
like look in all these suspected pros
here
well the judicial file on the case study
also mentions revenue estimates provided
by the grower based on its claims and
yield
number of growth cycles and prices paid
by the buyers
so these are just more confounding data
points
that make it difficult to pinpoint or
get an exact
number now what's the total yield yeah
that's one thing what's the number of
plants
where are the buyers willing to pay for
it so this is what causes that source of
potential confusion
now if you're looking at what can we
glean from this what can be information
can we get
what data should we be collecting so if
the courts are collecting it's probably
a good idea for us to also be collecting
it
as a qualitative data gathering on
cannabis cultivation activities
focus on directly observable of
observable and measurable data to be
collected upon confiscation of cannabis
plantations are strongly encouraged by
police and judicial actors
so what information are they collecting
what information should growers be
keeping track of and that should be the
number of plants it seems kind of
obvious the plant densities so how big
of an area how many plants
in per square meter per square foot
what's the surface being cultivated it's
the pot volume it's in the container
volume being grown in
the lamp number how many lights the type
and power of those lights
the type of number of installations i
know the lights but maybe the hvac
system the
cooling system the heating system
equipment and fertilizer containers
as well as many other things but these
are just some key points
growers should be keeping track of to
ensure they have a successful operation
but with just the
short list provided here we can see the
variability and that's why it makes it
very difficult to estimate
yields and especially yields over a long
period of time because some of them will
these will have a lot of upfront cost
but then reduced
reoccurring cost so again a little
difficult there
but this just gives you an idea of some
data presented in the information for
this article that was presented
in a court setting