welcome to another video here on debaco
university
today we're going to be looking at
characteristics of common fibers looking
at both
natural and synthetic fibers in this
presentation
now natural fibers while there are many
the ones we're going to be focusing on
here in this presentation are going to
be wool
cotton hemp jute and silk we can see
that there are many other fibers however
these are typically
made into clothing and likely to be
found
and analyzed for comparison purposes
now the wool fibers themselves are
typically in natural hair grown on sheep
and composed of protein substances such
as keratin
wool fibers have crimps and curls which
create pockets and give the wool a
spongy feel
and create insulation it creates kind of
that air spaces that allow
to have great insulating properties the
outer surface of the fiber consists of a
series of
serrated scales which overlap each other
we can see that image here
this is a microscopic view but they kind
of look like scales of a fish
and this makes the possible for these
fibers to cling together
and produce felt and this insulating
factor is great here for the sheep
and llamas and alpacas but they have
that very
similar insulating property with their
fibers
going on to plant material looking here
at cotton it's the most important
textile fiber in the world
cotton is a natural vegetable fiber and
produced on the cotton plant
and it kind of looks like cotton balls
on the plant
however this is in its natural form this
would be harvested here
cut and magnified about 100 times you
can see some of the fibers are rather
flat and looks like a ribbon when it
twists let me see that evident right
here hemp or flax fibers
they are cellulose fibers with
properties that are similar
and are scarily differentiated
at the fiber form so this
differentiation between these two
as far as identifying specifically which
one that we have
is complicated by the treatment process
so sometimes it can be difficult to
identify
whether you're looking at a flax or a
hemp fiber
now jute fibers themselves are one of
the most important
and affordable natural fibers and it's
harder than other textile fibers
typically they're made into for example
burlap bags
in jute twine because they're
environmentally friendly and normally
used for these kind of materials
or tufts of carpet where there's a lot
of structure
that's needed also the fact that they're
biodegradable is great that there can be
used outside a lot of times to buying up
tomato plants we use a jute twine
keep in mind while it is biodegradable
it doesn't break down necessary very
quickly and can be left in the field for
a little while
before it naturally over time will break
down
there's also silk fibers so silk fibers
also made of proteins these are secreted
by a caterpillar specifically a silkworm
and they feed on selective plants and
they actually spin cocoons
they form this silk as a protective
shell to perpetuate their own
life man interferes with the life cycle
of the cocoon stage to obtain the silk
which is a continuous filament for
commercial importance
and it can thought of to produce very
high end fibers in this case
looking now at synthetic fibers so rayon
acrylic polyester nylon and spun glass
are the ones we're going to be looking
at here that fall under the
synthetic fiber category now rand's the
first one
here it's brand will absorb moisture
more so than cotton it's also breathable
comfortable to wear and easily dyed into
vivid colors this is what makes it a
popular choice
for clothing for example it also doesn't
build up static electricity
nor will it will it develop that pilling
unless the fiber is made from short
low twist yarns rayon shares the
properties similar to those of cotton
rand fiber itself is comfortable soft to
the skin and has moderate dry strength
and abrasion resistance
so again all properties that make it
very favorable to made into different
textiles particularly clothing
acrylic can be thought of as artificial
wool imitation it has wool's warmth and
softness but does not absorb water
but wicks moisture to the surface where
it evaporates
so that's important know if you're
looking at you know type of clothing or
something that may have involved
water this shows an example of acrylic
fiber
showing the melt termination in the
lower right right right here
and the mechanical damage determination
in the upper left up here so again we're
looking at the microscope
there are ways to help identify this
polyester so polyester is the most
commonly used
synthetic fiber often blend with other
fibers like cotton to get the best kind
of of both worlds
because while polyester fibers have good
elasticity and wrinkle resistance
shape retention excellent wash and wear
performance and durability
if it's widely used however polyester
fibers are as poor in moisture
absorption its clothing makes the wear
feel hot and sticky which people don't
want to feel
but does have a lot of other advantage
properties
so as a result this is why it can be
mixed with other fibers
so that polyester alone kind of produces
that static
electricity easily when result of
clothing absorbing dust clinging to the
body and has poor comfort
this way to be have a blend of this but
it alone
sample plaster fiber sample here
polyester thread
inference color is high order white
which can be seen here with multiple
interference orders evident where the
fiber cross at right angle so we can see
that evident here and here
and here we're looking at this bar would
represent 50 microns for looking at size
nylon does not absorb water but also
means that the
movement combined to create static
electricity
so this is again something else where
may not be a
pure uh garment made only of nylon and
some of the look and feel of silk as you
can kind of see the shininess to
the twine kind of here it's made of
nylon it's used in sheer
it's used in sales parachutes gallons
veils
swimsuits car tires so it has a lot of
uses
different types of nylon that also can
be
replaced wool as the fiber used in
carpets
here's a sample of nylon fiber from a
furnace air filter we can kind of see
how we're getting those what it looks
like when it crosses over
and also the distance here we can also
get it looking at it woven here
on the microscopic scale lastly we have
spun glass
this is one of the strongest textile
fibers
having the greater specific tensile
strength than steel wire
and the same diameter at a lower weight
so just that alone
speaks to its rigidity and its strength
now the glass uh fabrics have excellent
heat resistance
with a softening point of about 1 55
degrees fahrenheit or 846 degrees
celsius
and a melting point it's very high of
over 2000 degrees fahrenheit and over
1100 degrees celsius glass fabrics are
non-combustible highly resistant to
attack
by most chemicals and unaffected by
sunlight fungus or bacteria
so this is great if they're going to be
used in
areas that maybe have a lot of sunlight
exposure
need resistance to chemicals so they do
have some great properties
and it's very strong however it may not
always be the case that we may need it
has a different kind of texture or
feel and this is why some of your other
fibers are more commonly found in
clothing
but for specialized tasks spun glass
definitely
has a purpose