so when growing plants it's always wise
to have a check-in balance system just
like the government here between the
Justice we want to make sure that we
also have a balanced system waited just
a check to make sure everything's
running efficiently as possible so
having a system to check conditions it
could be a checklist mental checklist or
written checklist all good ideas sitting
timers that are friendly to your
schedule so just lights and irrigation
also benefit this meaning it could be
getting up in the morning make sure the
lights are on or at night making sure
the lights go off something that's
friendly to you your schedule especially
if you're growing in completely
controlled conditions just so you have a
way of just kind of double-checking to
make sure that the timers are all
working properly consistency for plants
and for growers is a good thing this can
help ensure accuracy predictions for the
plants and also provide the growers with
early identification when something
isn't going right having anything right
and lying and I'll set something that
gets out of line it's very easy quickly
to identify that to minimize the impact
that will have on the overall growth
cycle of the plants plan for failures so
how the backup products ready to go if
you know while they're eventually going
to fail so for example don't just have a
one water pump and that's all that you
have have the backup of the same size so
it clicks here quick and easy change
light bulbs you know they're going to
aged reflectors you don't have to be
changing those as well as timers any one
of these things could fail without
notice so you want to make sure you're
going through and changing that out as
quickly as you can identify the problems
have having to order that and having
inconsistencies or having something
that's not able to work properly
ventilation you want to make sure you
have sufficient ventilation as this will
cause thermo stratification and will
expose Prince to variations in
temperature too and make sure you're
having a fan to help move some air
around help decrease disease pressure
also making sure the carbon oxide is
getting mixed well in the air also
having a fan will help reduce the chance
of getting weaker stocks because if you
don't have a ventilation weaker stops
will develop and this could be a fan
goes out you're not planning for that
and the plants going through a rapid
growth
is weaker stocks could develop as the
end result lack of light so poor light
can reduce yields reduced light can also
increase the plants tendency to stretch
and get leggy is going to be an extreme
example a really stretchy leggy clamp
this can also increase the odds of plant
damage not only in place but if you're
going to removing it from a vegetative
room to a flower room lastly I want to
have consistent irrigation to the plants
because not having regular irrigation
can cause undue plants trash you know
these plants are gonna be drinking these
plants are going to be needing
irrigation and water want to make sure
they're constantly shed that is you
don't want to stunt the plants because
that can lead to long-term damage
especially if it occurs early in the
growth in development of those plants
also does not allow the grower to know
if or when something might be going
wrong or failing so having the system of
checking if using a barrel system a
meter some way of assessing the
irrigation or the water moisture content
in the irrigation medium that is all
very important there's irrigation events
should be regular should have an idea
when they're coming on show you know how
much water you're giving the plants and
keep in mind this may change over the
growing season as the plants get bigger
but having that check in balanced system
for all of these parameters is advised
because it helps you identify issues
early on decreasing the chance that it
could have a negative large negative
impact on your final product