okay he were to discuss a little bit
that is often debated should I be using
chemical fertilizers or should I be
using organic fertilizers so I gonna
give you a background about a little bit
of what defines each and to give you
this that appreciation for when it might
be best to use one or another so first
off chemical fertilizers I put those in
quotes here because all nutrients come
down to chemistry but chemical
fertilizers is typically what's
referring to a manufactured product a
man-made man created product versus
organic is tends to refer to something
that naturally occurs so within those
chemical fertilizers are often
water-soluble so if you add in the water
look kind of diffused through and mix
very well this makes because they mix so
well this makes the application process
very easy this form is very friendly to
a variety of irrigation methods Kuzmin
hydroponic setup drip irrigation systems
used a water tank as a reservoir
overhead for example all of these
irrigation methods are applicable for
most chemical water soluble fertilizers
now with the ease of application this
can help agora maintain a very clean
operation usually in a bag it can take a
spoonful take an exact amount out and
keep everything nice and clean and neat
growers can also precisely it's called
spoon-feeding additions where they're
taking the exact amount very small
amount here and exactly adding it to the
hopefully happy plants however caution
must be taken that to over apply these
fertilizers which increases the odds of
burning the plants so chemical
fertilizers because they're easy to be
added sometimes can be over added and as
a result there's a chance a girl could
burn their plants if they don't follow
the right ratios and the right feeding
regimen now in contrast to that organic
fertilizers are not mint at manufactured
we're typically found in nature in one
form of another they're considered to be
natural fertilizers such as soui newer
worm castings bone meal blood meal
there's a whole bunch of a variety but
they're typically thought of as
occurring naturally in nature net
circuits the term organic the nutrients
release is typically a slower release in
those chemical based fertilizers in the
applications can be more limiting may
can be very difficult for example to
spread manure
as I say run that through some
irrigation systems it could clog drip
tapes it could be you know cause a odor
to develop and reservoirs so again as a
result would be more limiting however it
is still possible to over add and create
toxic conditions to your soil and plants
especially with some manures we notice
looking at phosphorus in particular
while it is organic and natural over
application can still lead to toxic
conditions for some nutrients so keep in
mind because you're using organic
fertilizers it doesn't mean it's free
range and you can do no harm now for
unit fertilizers that organic has main
definitions and some actually contradict
one another so scientific definition of
organic are compounds containing carbon
that's kind of a central part of organic
means carbon such as organic chemistry
misleading definition is like organic
farming and it's produced without the
use of chemical fertilizers pesticides
are our other artificial agents so
organic does not mean no sprite I want
to get that point kind of across that if
you're buying something that's
organically produced it doesn't mean it
wasn't sprayed with anything it means
typically the items it could have been
sprayed with come from a limited list
now that limited list most organic
growers using kind of Omri may have
heard of that term since for the organic
materials review Institute they have a
list of over 5500 products approved for
organic production based on the USDA
National Organic Program standards don't
you see this USDA Organic seal 189
results contains some copper base to
them so of this 5500 list of potential
products almost 190 of them contains
some sort of copper base copper can
accumulate an environment and does not
contain carbon so you have to be mindful
of whatever situation or whatever kind
of definition you're using while Omri is
considered by many to be the gold
standard it does contain products such
as those can that contain copper that
can potentially harm the environment you
just want to be mindful of and
understand all about the nutrients and
all about the products that you have
access to and utilize them where they're
best used but realize just because it's
organic doesn't
you can't over add to the environment or
cause potential toxicity issues the
organic material breakdown with many
organic materials especially manures the
goal is to use them after a sufficient
composting process fresh manures can
easily burn plants they're called like
hot manures hot nitrogen also under
Organic Standards is often a required
number of days from Lenoir application
to harvest of any crop this means you
can't apply manure and then go harvest
that field there can be 120 days 180
days restriction from when you first
apply that manure to when you can
harvest off that field we want to know
your source of material also and if you
do get it fresh be sure to compost it
properly or be sure this source is
following a composting procedure here
they're nice they're turning their
compost here it's kind of a stagnant
pile coming down a barn so just kind of
know your source not only what type of
manure it is but how it's being treated
before it comes to your operation
organically growing cannabis this is
kind of something that anecdotally
growers have reported if it's
organically grown there's a proof
tasters improvement Roma's compared to a
cannabis plant that may have been
treated with chemical fertilizer so
while this hasn't really been
scientifically proven that there's a
true difference between organically
grown and chemically grown the
difference could be in part due to the
overall grower practices in not solely
based on the type of fertilizer used so
keep in mind that there's more at play
than just saying oh I use organic
fertilizer I use chemical fertilizer
because even organic fertilizer what
you're adding are kind of chemical
components so be mindful of maybe other
growing practices because there's been
no scientific proof at least to this
point that organically grown cannabis
will produce any different aromas than a
chemically produced one so keep in mind
of the grower practices can also
influence on the plant production