nitrogen is very important to add to
plants here in debaco university
we're going to go through some chemical
forms of nitrogen fertilizer
you may want to be considering
all right let's get into chemical
nitrogen fertilizer options for cannabis
production
so there's many different types of
nitrogen fertilizer but i'm going to
cover urea
ammonium nitrate and calcium nitrate the
three we see pictured right here
so first off starting with urea is it
contains 100
of uh this chemical which converts to
ammonia in several days and that's the
important part
is that it's a very quick conversion
it's also very
potent because it's 46 percent nitrogen
we're going to see that comparing to
some of the other nitrogen sources or if
you're definitely comparing it to
organic sources
this is one of the most nutrient dense
forms
it's hydroscopic means it does retain
water it's quite soluble in
water which is a great property to have
and also has very good handling
properties as well
so these are all great considerations
and why urea can be used on such a large
scale
typically it is used in the warmer
periods of the year
and ideally should be incorporated or in
some way get into the soil profile
because it is possible for some of this
nitrogen to be lost through the process
of volatilization then we have ammonium
nitrate
so this is a 50 blend of two different
types of nitrogen
it is also hydroscopic which means it's
highly water soluble
it is explosive if mixed with
hydrocarbons which is a fuel oil
as a result 94 amino nitrate and six
percent fuel oil
is basically and file which is a highly
explosive as a result
of the most of the ammonium nitrate
fertilizer that you're purchasing
is coated in some way that reduces its
chance of being highly explosive
though carrot does need to be taken to
prevent caking which is kind of it kind
of all piling up and sticking to one
another
and becoming just a solid clump then
we've got calcium nitrate our last one
here
and this is also highly water soluble
strongly hydroscopic it's really a
tendency to absorb water and
cake does provide a readily soluble
available forms of calcium ions as well
so you're kind of getting the benefit
there of also fertilizing your plants
with calcium
keep mind this is only 15 nitrogen so
that may play into it
and typically this is used when soils
tend to be a little bit colder
particularly early on in the season this
can be a great option to have
available in case your plants are
showing any sort of deficiency
going through and adding some calcium
nitrate can really make them green up
really quickly
and forego any negative effects from a
nitrogen deficiency