as you can tell from the length of this
video this is a very brief overview of
chemical reactions I figured I put a
picture here some fireworks indicating a
chemical reaction you've probably seen
in a very familiar way
so chemical reaction is making in
breaking chemical bonds the starting
molecules of a chemical reaction are
called reactants and the final molecules
of the chemical reaction of called
products looking our example here the
reactants are methane and oxygen gas
producing our products which is carbon
dioxide gas in a water vapor make no of
this reactance the products has an arrow
pointing in one direction something
related to biology we have
photosynthesis which is a very important
chemical reaction here sunlight powers
the conversion of carbon dioxide in
water to glucose and oxygen and we see
our reactants on this side with the
arrow pointing one direction to our
products to sugar and oxygen now
something called chemical equilibrium
this is reached when the forward and
reverse reaction rates are equal this is
indicated by this kind of half arrow
pointing to the right and half arrow
pointing to the left this is indicating
an equilibrium is occurring some
chemical reactions go to completion
where all reactants are converted into
products as we saw in the previous
slides however all cut up reactions are
reversible the products of the Florida
action become reactants their diverse
reaction in chemical equilibrium the
reaction actually doesn't stop it just
reaches a point of balance so we see
here we're mixing two things in the jar
this chemical equilibrium and things are
the rate of the forward reaction is
equal to the rate of the reverse
reaction so I think this is some sort of
misprint where it's like I don't really
know what that is weird symbol it's
having getting half an arrow pointing to
the right and half an arrow pointing to
the left in the king there's no net
change nothing is visually changing even
though reactions may be occurring
they're going back and forth we call
this chemical equilibrium because the
forward reaction or rate is equal to
reverse reaction rate there's
essentially no change no net change even
now we have an equal
distribution of forward and reverse
reaction ones