this is going to be a very brief
overview of the functions of the
circulatory system the reason why this
image is pictured here is you may want
to think about some of the functions
that the circulatory system does that's
kind of like what a city may require so
let's get into it
starting with transportation that's
probably the most obvious one the
circulatory system is responsible for
transporting oxygen to cells for the
process of respiration and also taking
away carbon dioxide from those same
cells bring it to either the gills or
the lungs so it can be eliminated or
some way leaves the body system also the
circulatory system needs to absorb
products from digestion and bring them
to cells and the same thing as it's
bringing nutrients to the cells it also
needs to have a way to take the waste
products away from the cells this could
also be excessive water in the human
body this we brought to the kidney and
excreted in the urine two other main
functions are regulation where the
circulatory system is taking hormones
and transporting them from it's part of
the endocrine system to distant organs
it also helps maintain homeostasis in
the body by way of keeping a constant
temperature
lastly protection blood clotting
protects against blood loss and that's
important function along with caring
white blood cells around the body so
that there can be an immunity provided
against disease-causing agents so again
as promised this is a very brief
overview of the three main categories of
functions of the body's circulatory
system