so while all the animals pictured here
have a closed circulatory system the
each have their own different variations
that we're going to go into in a little
bit more detail here at how they move
blood through their bodies so I'm gonna
start with a couple comparisons that
most might seem initially confusing but
I am going to go through each and more
detail focus on each specifically here
we're comparing a fish to named Vivian
so a fish had the simplest circulatory
system of all the vertebrates
their blood flows one direction and from
a two chambered heart through the gills
and then to the rest of the body so in
all the images we start at the heart
looking at we're leaving the heart we're
going to the gills where we're having
that exchange of carbon dioxide and
oxygen that oxygenated blood isn't going
to the blood capillaries meaning back
here going through the heart going back
through the system here so it's a two
chamber heart and it's just kind of that
one direction going toward Ian's phibian
Sal they have two ways or two routes
that through blood can take one for
oxygenating blood through the lungs in
skin and the other to take oxygen to the
rest of the body the blood is pumped
through a three chambered heart with two
atria and the single ventricle so we see
here blood is pumped through a three
chamber heart with two atria there's one
located here this single ventricle and
here's our blood leaving going through
the lungs or the skin capillaries
becoming oxygenated returning back to
the heart here and then leaving and
being pumped here through the body now
the reason why this did not as is an
improvement from our two chambered heart
is we're now having blood returning to
the heart in distinctive areas so that
is going necessarily in one direction
you see already that's more complicated
but the fact that there's only one
ventricle means here a blood could be
going back to the lungs or could be
going out to the body so it's not
necessarily as efficient as it could be
comparing the reptile in the mammals of
reptiles have two secretory routes the
blood is only oxygen through the lungs
because there's no skin contact with the
environment the heart is also a three
chamber
Desai Karan pipiens but the ventricles
are partially separated so the mixing of
oxygenated and deoxygenated blood
kurz accepting crocodilians are slightly
different category there but the reason
or the downfall that we're seeing here
is Purple's is representing kind of our
partly deoxygenated blood and we're
noticing that in me that's mixing the
curd so here's our oxygenated blood
returning it's kind of mixing with our
deoxygenated blood making this kind of
in-between intermediate kind of
partially actually it partially
deactivated and that's being circulated
through the most efficient way here's
our mammals and they have four chamber
heart that's completely separating out
oxygenated and deoxygenated blood it
pumps only australian blood through the
body and deoxygenated blood to the lungs
so here's our blue deactivated blood
going to our lungs being oxygenated
turning to a separate portion of the
heart that is in being exited out and
goes to the body so this is the most
efficient this for chamber hurt because
it's allowing that complete separation
between deoxygenated and oxygenated
blood let's look at these hearts a
little bit more detail so first off that
two chambered heart for the fish it's
one atrium one ventricle single
circulatory root reptiles or amphibians
have a three chambered heart they double
the amount of a trio but still remain
only with one ventricle remember
ventricles pump is the portion of the
heart pumping it to the rest of the body
the reason why this is not quite as
efficient because we have both
oxygenated and deoxygenated blood being
mixed through a double so they take
circulatory process mammals have the
four chambered heart the most efficient
the two atria two ventricles
we're both oxygenated Indian blood are
separate and this is also double
circulated Strait circulation looking a
little more specifically at the
simplicity of the fish it's a two
chamber heart the single atrium receives
blood from the body cells a ventricle
sends blood to the gills so here's our
direction the blood flow we kind of have
this one way that the heart's just kind
of pumping going out here to the gills
and kind of working its way right back
around so simplest of all the
vertebrates to chamber heart
fish three chambered heart separated out
allows some separation of oxygen and
deoxygenated blood which is an advantage
on land organisms such as reptiles and
amphibians though the blood can mix in
the ventricle mixing is minimal some
reptiles have partial separation of the
ventricle so kind of that first step of
having that separation of that
deoxygenated in oxygenated blood and we
see that here is our flow of blood
here's the body we have that mix and of
courage before it's being sent out I'll
provide you with a nice cross-section
here was also labeling of all the
different portions of this three
chambered heart moving on to our four
chambered heart seen in mammals and
birds and this allows for a complete
separation of oxygenated and
deoxygenated blood this complete
separation allows for fast metabolism
found in human terms
those are organisms that are able to
maintain their own body temperature now
we are getting a little bit more
complicated we see that with our four
chambers two atria two ventricles they
have valves here separating out and a
separate physical separation here
allowing for oxygenated and deoxygenated
blood to be distinct and separate and
remember Dee actually blood is shown in
blue here even though in the body weeds
varying shades of red but that Dee
actually blood is sent directly to the
lungs it comes back as oxygenated blood
it's kept distinct and separate before
it's sent out through the body where
it's going through capillaries and then
the deoxygenated blood is then returning
back to the heart