now you're gonna be creating a cladogram
in class so hopefully this will be
helpful for you to indicate what it
should generally look like so clade here
looking at what an example of one is and
one example of one is here and both ends
the middle it's not basically if all
these little sections here is isn't a
complete area this here is a complete
kind of grouping same as this complete
grouping this one contains a split here
at divergent evolution but it ought
contains part of that so that's why it's
not considered a full classification set
so how things may look how to build a
family tree attack that may also enables
us to glimpse the evolutionary history
of life on Earth a phylogeny is the
evolutionary history of an organism ants
relationship to other species the
reconstruction and study of these
phylogenetic trees is also called
systematics we're going to be looking
only at one particular species and how
we look at separating that out do some
examples here of the divergent evolution
and how in certain environments and
predators made impacted changes that
occur over time so a common ancestors is
an important term it's any organism that
two or more descendents have in common
so I'm going to tell you what the common
ancestor is and through your cutouts
you're gonna have to determine what is
more closely related that common
ancestor and what is more distantly
related to that ancestor so the example
here of the wolf and all the dog species
that have derived from that this is all
of the dogs have this one single common
ancestor so might be related closer to
this than others but they all in some
way distantly or closely relate to the
common ancestor so how to build this
family trees clade here's a group of
organisms related by a descent on
cladistics is the construction of
biologically based on similarities
derived from common form a common
ancestor
examination of these characteristics
allows the construction and branching of
a cladogram so this is we'll be doing
again these two examples the
in here don't really fit the category
both of these do it can be a single
lineage or it can be the complete common
ancestor with the branch here here could
see here within this box there is no
necessary common ancestor the common
answer exists outside the box same here
this does not include all the
individuals that follow under this
particular common ancestor there's part
of reason why these don't classify over
here we would see the same left on the
title slide and again the two annoyance
are all-inclusive in the one in the
middle is not so we have two terms
called in-groups and out-groups
and his click Rams are not true family
trees so it's important to make that
separation or that distinction between
the tale they convey comparative
relationship information and its
clattering contains an out-group to
which the in-group is compared since we
are in grouped is all be closely related
and here's our out groups separated out
and use to compare to this in-group they
may have some similar some similar
properties because they all share the
same common ancestor but these are
grouped as the in-group these are
probably more closely related than
section a here considered the out-group
modern method attempts to assign extra
weight to the evolutionary significance
of key characteristics we call this
weighting characteristics so instead of
just kind of organizing we kind of give
weight to certain developments that may
be more complex that occurred all
phylogenies are constructed based on
large and lots of information about an
organism gathered gathered over the
years to constructors trees traditional
taxonomy used both ancestral and derived
characteristics class only use the
derived characteristics so again that
traditional versus the classification
which is a cladogram we see here giving
a little bit more weight to certain ways
to divide certain things here we see two
different ways of basically separating
out on things and the cladogram here is
using a little bit more specifics to
divide that so which approach is better
the traditional is when there's a lot of
information available to guide a
character weighting and the classics is
use when little information
how characters FEX the life over the
organism is used so in class you're just
going to get pictures so therefore we
can't really perform the traditional
taxonomy we don't have enough
information I don't know exactly the
ears or the duration of the species
diversities so that sort of undeveloped
is closed Essex's we're open to use
mainly based on phenotypic features so
two ways to classify at restful
vertebrates here notice here birds have
their own class and over here birds are
lumped with rough tiles so the
traditional alpha algae and taxonomic
classification if you remember flipping
me back that's when a lot of information
is used so we have a lot of information
where let's separate out birds into
their own separate category alpha we're
just kind of looking at comparative
features they get kind of lumped into
more with reptiles ovens separate out
into their own specific class here so
this is just important to keep in mind
the limitations of how we organize
things
it's simply based on the information
we're able to collect and use