okay here okay basic classification of
bones within our skeletal system no
there's many different types of bones
many different types of functions some
are very easily named like flat bone and
short run and long run some of a very
irregular shape and I get the term
irregular bone but each is able to
perform a unique function as part of our
entire skeletal system so again it's the
shape is how we're going to classify
them and that shape will relate to where
they're located in the body and the
function that they perform within that
particular location so classification of
bones I'll start with the long bones are
typically longer than they are wide and
that's something that the name long
bones highlight in red here now slowly
rotating skeleton allows you identify
some of the regions you can find these
long bones they have a shaft with heads
at both ends now the heads at both ends
might be different but it is a head
region at both ends they contain mostly
compact bone in examples to be the femur
in the humerus keep in mind the humerus
is located in the upper arm here will be
the humerus here and corresponding and
very similar looking in the general
sense down here would be where the femur
would be located so remember our humerus
up here and femur down here and we see a
lot of similarities between these two
long bones the head regions though are
different in between the two and it has
to result with the joints that each
attaches to so we're going to be
identifying some of the bones in our
body should be very familiar the humerus
and where the femur is located despite
them looking very similar so structural
long bones they consist of a diathesis
and in epithets asst the diathesis is a
tubular shaft that forms the axis of the
long bones we see that here to Ephesus
the long portion of the long bones it's
composed of compact bone surrounds us
medullary cavity and yellow bone marrow
that is contained within this cavity
unless we're talking about a very very
young individual physically an infant
this medullary cavity would be composed
of mostly red bone marrow but keep in
mind as we age that red
because replaced with yellow bone marrow
which is mostly fat the this is the
epiphysis expands ends of the long bone
that's referring to the basically the
head regions it's also exterior is
composed of that compact bone in the
interior which is majorities that spongy
bone as you see here reason why it's
spongy bone it's covered with hyaline
cartilage and this line here is where
the different regions meet essentially
something called up this middle region
not going to get too much into that the
key part is to understand that the
yellow bone marrow we see indicated here
is typically found in the diaphysis
region the Epistle line is the
separation between the toe the reason
why there's mostly spongy bone here
is simply because this is what's
allowing for that red bone marrow to be
housed and protected now on the blooms
they also have long votes now we have
our short bones you can see whether
where they're located and highlighted on
our slowly rotating skeleton up here
generally they're cube-shaped kind of
cube like we'll say and they contain
mostly spongy bone they're found in the
carpals and tarsals so carpals are in
our hand see here and tarsals are
located in the foot region also the
patella or kneecap is classified as a
short bone flat bones are thin and
flattened usually curved it helps give
them some strength
there's thin layers have compact bone
around a layer of spongy bone our skull
our ribs or sternum as though our hips
are also considered or fallen under the
classification of flat bones again the
reason why they tend to be a little bit
curved is that which gives them a little
bit more structural integrity lastly our
regular bones these having the regular
shape that's how they get their name
they really don't fit into any other
bone classification categories they're
kind of the odd ones of the group here
and the vertebral column would be a
prime example of that and that long
bones are not short bones they're
irregular
shaped it's more than just a verbal
column some portions of the hip also
some also of the head region can be
classified as irregular bones hopefully
this gives you just that basic overview
of some of the classifications of bones
by their individual and unique shapes