okay here all at the simple and
hopefully not over complicated of a
cloning method called the cutting stick
just as the name implies you take a
cutting and you stick it into a media or
some sort of area where you're going to
encourage root development so cutting
take the simple and easy it's the
easiest of methods you're just as the
name implies you're growing taking the
growing tip of the plant you're cutting
it and then sticking it into growing
media scissors typically aren't
encouraged usually we use a sharp knife
we stick them into media in this case we
have everything prepared we have our
cuttings and water ready to go and this
is a kind of important part of the
process and while it is easy when I'm
sure everything is set up ahead of time
what you're sticking the clone into the
media that can be a wide variety
material can be Rockwell we saw in the
previous image could be say end could be
soilless mix these foam key part is you
need a media that's going to support and
keep that plant upright you serve
rooting hormone surges clone exits
advise to help encourage rooting and
reduce the time to route some optional
materials with this you can use misting
or a humidity dome can help increase the
humidity and reduce water stress he met
is often used as well to help increase
the Runestone temperature and all of
these things help reduce plant stress
and increase the routing percentage some
of the drawbacks this method is
depending on the propagation environment
such as light temperature video most
uniformity and so on this method may
suffer from an above-average percent of
loss of clothes so sometimes you kind of
get trade that may look like this where
you get a couple that just aren't going
to make it and if some that do make it
the more consistent you can keep the
conditions the better odds that you'll
have sometimes you're going to take one
put it right in a glass of water and
sometimes little group right there so
some instance give some people some
extra confidence and things that it can
work but there's one of the drawbacks is
that typically this can result in not a
hundred percent as some other methods
but considering it's simple it's easy
sometimes taking the small percent loss
for not a lot of investment and other
things is advantageous for some growers