here we're looking at cloning with the
easy clone which is a commercially
available product in this case isn't the
easy clone low pro 64 meaning that it
will clone up to 64 cuttings at one time
it's a form of aeroponic propagation
here and we'll go through just some of
the basics of this so some growers have
a love-hate relationship with the ez
clone it can be very efficient put in
quotes here it can be the best system if
there's attention to detail by the
grower so some people see this easy
clone is just too intricate too much
detail kind of like these small gears
and a watch here and too difficult to
figure out so I'm here to shed some
light on what it takes to actually use
this properly the key part is to
optimize the EZ clean conditions with pH
being the first priority
knowing the pH you maintaining is very
important if the pH is not monitored
this is typically result of poor to
non-existent routing example here at pH
of 4.96 I'll be much too acidic and this
would lead to poor routing so I think
this is where a lot of people go wrong
with the EZ clone is they're just not
monitoring or aware of what the pH is in
the environment on managing heat is
another issue so location cloners this
place can contribute to the reservoir
heat this is the pump water pump that's
used in the spray bar this pump also
does generate some heat so that's
important to keep in mind well let a
slightly warmer water temp is
advantageous but only to a certain point
so it's good that there's a little heat
generated but if it's earning a warm
environment that could cause some issues
here
an area that may only have bottom heat
or only exacerbate the problem so you
want to just be mindful of the area
putting it in knowing that this pump
will still produce a little bit of heat
blue labs blue lab guardian monitor here
is a great all-in-one tool you can
monitor the EC which is to dissolve
solids in this case abbott in
parts-per-million you can also monitor
this temperature and go from Fahrenheit
or Celsius also the pH here this can
also there's options to be linked to
remote devices you don't have to be
present to watch it this is a standalone
unit in the image here look to add to
the reservoir so plain water can work
nutrient solutions can also help speed
up the routing to popular products are
the clinic's solution pictured here and
also Olivia's solution
now which would in solution to use or
I've run trials on both when the clinic
takes an extra day or so to route in
comparison to the Olivia's leave it does
read quickest
however the clinics is pH stable while
Olivia's does require almost daily
attention to monitor and maintain a
proper pH clone X based on the
recommended used by the manufacturer
does cost less well this is slightly
more expensive clone X does produce a
clean solution that's very pump and
filter friendly well while the Olivia's
does have left over a particulate which
can clog a filter if you use it over
time and don't take that step of
cleaning that on a regular schedule we
do control an easy clone so it can run
without extra Committee added which is
great this is if the lighting is not too
intense in the heat is kept to a minimum
so in certain instances it may be
unnecessary to kind of add some misting
system if it's already in the warm
environment but watch the amount and
size of the water droplets you use
because it is possibly to
unintentionally over fill the reservoir
stopping the continual water spray of
the aeroponics that's needed to keep
that rooting environment going this is
why you see examples here the plastic
bag over and help water sheet away and
not get caught in the cloner and over
filling it this is just a result of the
environment that was placed in again
want to eliminate water from
unintentionally being entered but if
you're not adding extra humidity or mist
this shouldn't be a problem how long she
believes your cuttings in the cloner
well you want to see till the roots
emerge while plants can grow in the
system once roots are about the width of
the supporting foam they should be
removed so at this point this would be a
great time to remove these cuttings
sometimes you'll also in that route
earlier and some that route later the
advantage of this system that you can
remove individual clones when you feel
already lastly the basic setup while
this is in a greenhouse since cuttings
do not need full Sun this is not a
requirement on missing system this
misting bar here was used as the heat
this is a greenhouse
but also notice that the electrical
outlets locate up here and the monitor
are kept above than this bar keeping
them out of this high mist environment
and only keeping the cloner in that
misting environment here to eliminate
the stress on the seedlings