in this debaco university student series
video we're going to see cloning from a
damaged plant so it can live on let's
see two plants that have endured some
physical damage and we're going to take
some clones from them that we may not
have considered otherwise first one got
damaged the top so we're going to kind
of top top that one and utilize that
plant material the one in the image here
that fell over we're going to see just
how many clones you can get from our
branch now while they may not all root
at least taking them and giving them a
chance to root would be encouraged
because this is a great way to continue
those genetics on a situation that might
be a little unfortunate
[Music]
so this
cbd plant was unfortunately trampled by
a mixture of both people and bunnies and
so we want to be able to salvage
anything we can from this so that we
don't just lose the entirety of what was
damaged by people and by
animals
so
typically like i said you want your
plant size to be about a hand but due to
the damage that it's endured we can't
really take the snipping right at the
node we want it to be a healthy somewhat
healthy plant
and so
instead
we're gonna cut it above the node still
pretty close but above so that there's
no damage in
right here
so now hopefully we could take what's
left of this damaged plant and repurpose
it into a new hopefully healthy plant
and allow this plant that has been
damaged to take less stress off of
trying to fix the damage on top and put
its nutrients into the rest of the
leaves so that hopefully it can recover
from this injury
so unfortunately this plant endured a
bit too much physical damage and has
been unrooted from the ground now at
this rate we're not going to get any
yield from this plant since it obviously
isn't growing but we've put so much
effort into it already so what else can
we do
we could take clones many clones now
many people would see this plant and
think okay i killed my cannabis plant
and it's over but i'm going to show you
just how many clones you could take from
a dead cannabis plant
so you're going to want to cut from the
nodes always and try to get ones that
have long stalks so here's one
and 20. by now i think you get the point
and realize that even though this may be
a dead cannabis plant there are many
possibilities that you could choose to
revive it and move on from this damage
[Music]
you