if you're considering cmh lighting
options
for your cannabis production this video
should prove helpful
in providing you some explanations so
you better understand
ceramic metal halide lights
welcome to this tobacco university video
we're going to go over cmh lighting
options
for the greater understanding of these
so first off they've increased in
popularity
so the use of ceramic metal halide
lights or cmh and light emitting
ceramics lec grow lights are increasing
in usage in both commercial
and hobby grower settings these lights
are typically 10
or greater energy efficient and provide
the same par or watts
as traditional metal halides or high
pressure sodium grow lights with less
heat
these are part of the reasons why
they're increasing in popularity
now the spectrum they produced but the
quality of lights and that they're
able to have and the options growers
have for bulbs
now the spectrum and wattages so the
spectrum that they're producing
is quite advantageous so
both of these lights emit traditional
par measured spectrum in addition to
infrared
and also uv spectrums this full spectrum
can make a visual plant diagnosis
easier for growers to their high color
rendering index or cri
the most common cmh grow lights are the
315 watt grow lights and the 630 watt
grow lights
now i mentioned this color rendering
index here we see an apple this would be
kind of 100
and true color rendering and we could
see as we decrease that
how it starts to look a little off a
little not quite as red not quite as
great contrast
this is very important for growers that
are looking at diagnosing or catching
problems early
a higher cri will make it much easier to
spot potential problems
earlier when it's easier to correct them
now as you mentioned those 315 and those
630 watt options
are commonly used their recommended
coverage area for each is as follows
for a 315 you'll get a 4x4 veg room or
3x3 in a flower room
if you're using the larger kind of dual
bulb
630 watt it would be a five by five
bedroom coverage area or four by four
flower room coverage area
now the cmh bulbs so quality cmh bulbs
will last for about 20
000 hours and still retain about 80 or
more of their initial
output in addition more specific
spectrum options are being offered by
manufacturers simply do the increase in
popularity of the ballast
to allow growers to simply change bulbs
and not necessarily the fixtures
as their plants progress through the
growing cycle and again i'm not
sponsored by them
but these phillips master color bulbs
highly regarded you pay for them they
are tend to be on the more expensive
side
but definitely well worth it if you're
looking at the ultimate cmh bulb
now cmh for canvas in specific compounds
so
some bulbs available will have increase
in the uv light or far red spectrums
which can help increase the production
of certain compounds to help boost the
overall quality
and final cannabis product these bulbs
can be used at the very end of the grow
cycle to maximize plant productivity
if you're really looking at maximizing
your potential harvest
or particular compounds produced these
may be worth investigating
and utilizing as part of your in your
cmh ballast
to help make sure your yield and your
quality is as high as possible