so even if you have the best controller
where you place the co2 sensor is
important for the function of your
system so here's a sensor we see you
liked it right here wired system goes
right to a controller box but where you
place that in your grow facility is
important to ensure that the controller
can work as efficiently as possible
so it's important to remember that it's
covered ox-head will sync because it's
heavier than air so it naturally wants
to go to the bottom of a grow space so
some growers like to inject it over
their plants kind of at the top and let
it kind of work its way through the
plants as it will naturally fall through
a system this is also important to keep
in mind when you're looking at mounting
or placing your sensor in a grow
facility so sensor placement is key
where you place your sensors important
to ensure the proper evaluation the grow
space environment or the sensor is only
gonna be as good as where you place it
be aware of exhaust systems as I have
here a carbon filter for exhaust on the
points of injection and the tubing
--here air circulation such as the fan
or other fans that you may have in the
positioning of the plants and how they
may impact certain aspects of the carbon
dioxide in air in general environment so
while there's a whole bunch of different
situations trying to give you the main
idea here also ideally a sensor should
be above the point or points of
injection so again this tubing comes
down here and runs through here is where
my co2 is injected as a result my sensor
is placed above that meaning because co2
is gonna sink it should fill up this
area and this will kind of give me the
assessment above that I put it below
here as soon as co2 starts injecting it
might be may get a false reading because
of the co2 naturally following by the
sensor you also want the sensor below
your ventilation so as I mentioned my
ventilations at the top here to help
exhaust the hot air on so as a result I
want to put it above that because if
that's pulling out co2 I don't want it
to be trying to fill the entire groats
in also you want to generally at plant
Heights I chose to come with the upper
portion of plant height here on so
that's also an important consideration I
also may want an area where it's getting
some fed or some mixing after the fan or
circulation that you have in the grow
facility so well each is unique these
are some general
ideas to keep in mind to ensure that
your carbon dioxide sensor is accurately
placed to allow efficient enrichment of
your grow space with carbon dioxide