okay co2 and yield myths so there's a
lot of kind of mystery sometimes around
co2 and there's a lot of myths and kind
of rumors about people who are looking
at supplementing with it and some of the
benefits that are claimed and made about
regarding carbon dioxide and richness so
first off yields are not always
increased with co2 so that goes against
a lot what you may hear Oh add co2
you'll get more yield
well precision addition of co2 to a
groom can dramatically increase your
yields it is true however this assumes
that all their factors such as water
light and nutrients are not limiting
factors that means is if you're not
feeding your plants right and they're
kind of nutrient hungry adding co2 is
not gonna help them at all also if your
light isn't intense enough they're not
getting enough light then that could
also by adding co2 now it helped
increase yields at all some girls who
run a minimum amount of light to save
money could reduce intensity could be
kind of playing right along the minimum
light that they give a plant or lights
are too far away we'll see poor results
due to light being a limiting factor so
that's just one example of adding co2
and not getting an increase in yield you
have to make sure everything else is
maximized detergent water your light
nutrients before you consider adding
termina exhale enrichment
now co2 levels in word world food
production so increasing co2 levels
which we can see here graph depicting
co2 levels from 1958 to 2009 measured
out Hawaiian can see a general trend
here vastly increasing so increase in
co2 levels in the atmosphere atmosphere
will increase world food production it's
often something that stated because hey
it's like look if I add more carbon
dioxide I'll be getting bigger plants
well that only holds true if the
limiting factor is actually the carbon
dioxide levels in not the water or
nutrients those plants are growing under
you can see here with a tree giving an
ambient which is about 400 parts per
million and then increasing that by 150
and over 300 and over 4 and 50 from the
ambience this would be about 850 we can
see that there can be an increasing
yield but again that means that or that
assumes that water and nutrients are not
limiting factors so that could impact
world food production in a sense that
water is often limiting in many areas
and also nutrients in the soil
so it doesn't necessarily mean
increasing co2 levels will automatically
lead to an increase in world food
production common myths about co2 relate
to cannabis while co2 does not increase
the percentage of cannabinoids THC or
CBD in the plant it can increase the
volume of cannabinoids produce but
doesn't increase the percentage so if
the plants gonna produce you know 12%
CBD and add co2 it's nothing - all
magazines didn't produce 20% it is gonna
consume simply because you'll have more
plant material there soo - results in
that more plant material which can
result in more total or more volume of
cannabinoids but will not change the
percentage of a plant so when we can
plant more potent essentially it's
another myth there of co2 so co2 can
provide some great things we've got in
plants but it is not the one cure-all
fix all