if you're considering coco coir for your
indoor plant production hopefully you
tune into this video to gain some
helpful information provided by debaco
university
[Music]
all right let's get into coco coir for
indoor cannabis plant production here
so coco for cuckoo for coconuts uh we're
looking here coco choir is made up of
the husk of the coconut you can see
right here and there's also other
products from it it's produced primarily
in sri lanka philippines indonesia
mexico and parts of the caribbean and
south america it's a very popular
growing substrate and it was once
considered a waste product due to impart
its very slow decomposition rate which
takes about 20 years however keep in
mind it can be a little bit of a
variable product because it is a natural
product so one batch to another may have
some degree of variation while similar
there is a
is a natural product so that variation
is to be expected
so just keep that in mind and companies
are getting better and decreasing the
amount of variability you get from one
batch to another
there are three types kind of presented
here there's the cocopith or peat and
this looks like peat moss retains water
very well to the point that growers need
to monitor conditions to avoid root rots
so keep that in mind if you're using
cocoa fibers these are not very
absorbent but do allow for great
aeration of the root zone but will break
down over time reducing the amount of
aeration if you're reusing that
particular substrate and the cocoa chips
that it does retain water but still
means porosity so this provides the best
of cocoa pith and fibers kind of like
the kind of in-between role
now the properties just in general if
you want really the kind of scientific
properties fiber lengths average tensile
strength specific gradient elongation
percentages all that's provided here so
in general cocoa can hold water while
still allowing the roots to have
sufficient aeration
hold their properties for longer than
standard soilless
options that are available the ph does
tend to favor the 5.2 to 6.8 range so
keep that in mind and this does lack
plant available nutrients but is still
preferred by many growers because of its
main property that is simply inert
doesn't really react with very many
things
so again it's popular because of that
aeration to the roots minimal pathogens
as well as a great benefit
reduced pest pressure
in the initial substance using it right
out of the bag or in this case using it
in a container
so when you're purchasing uh this
particular product this coconut choir as
you can see here is just an example you
want to look to see if the material has
been triple washed to limit the chance
of the substrate containing high salts
in addition having
an included sds
sheet which is the
safety data sheet helps provide
information about the product and also
shows a high level of commitment by the
company that they stand behind their
product and have gotten it tested make
sure make sure it has multiple rinse
cycles as salt content is possible with
this product and also to ensure
pathogen-free environment there can be
chemical treatments applied so reviewing
the sdsg can be very important to let
you know how that particular company
chose to treat that product
this product does aggressively hold
calcium magnesium and iron so be sure to
have these fertilizers on hand if you're
going to be using this as a substrate
now it's often part of a blend so some
growers grow in like a pure form others
use it as a blend and it is commonly
mixed with potting soil or also perlite
growers typically do a 50 50 mix of soil
or soilless mixes with the cocoa to kind
of get the benefit of both and we can
see here varying recipes some people
grow in the street some people have you
know the different
combinations so just be aware whatever
blend you're using it's going to have
slightly different properties
so be aware to be able to handle those
properties in your growing operation
now when you're using cocoa is kind of
the last statement hopefully you've made
it to the end here growers should be
feeding plants frequently typically
daily or at least every other day to
avoid nutrient deficiencies in this
media particularly in container growing
it's hard to over water this it offers a
great margin for air for newer growers
and make sure you have a calcium
magnesium product on hand
this is great that it also has a little
bit of iron as well so great product to
have on hand if using coco coir because
those fibers really do hold on to those
calcium those magnesium molecules
greater than what the plant's roots can
take up so supplementing with this
product will ensure your plants avoid
any chance of a nutrient deficiency