so here we're looking at comparing
coevolution in co-adaptation we see this
image here of this flower selecting for
a very specific pollinator or in this
case an insect so how are these kind of
coal valve and Co adapting together to
allow this perfect match to occur this
flower for whatever reason may want only
this particular type of insect to carry
its pollen so what's occurring between
these two species to allow this very
high degree of specificity so
coevolution is a term that describes the
long term evolutionary adjustments of a
species to one another this coevolution
is two or more species that exert
selective pressures on each other and
evolve in response to each other we see
a prime example of that here where these
flowers are a very small light a minor
and are very long which matches up
perfectly with the hummingbirds long
beak a bee would not be a great
pollinator for this but it's this flower
is designing its structures to
particularly match that of the
hummingbird
- coevolution to occur because each
species is evolved in response to the
other one important feature of evolution
is that the selective environment is
constantly changing to allow this to
occur over a long period of time now how
do we study coevolution alcoa Lucian
setting many levels adaptations of the
individual's interactions between
species and also broad evolutionary
patterns co-adaptation is the reciprocal
adaptations of two species this could
refer to species it could reach also
refer to adaptations possessed by
individuals and/or their genotypes and
so on so if you look at an example of
co-adaptation we have caterpillars that
are secreting honeydew for ants to drink
well why would they do this
well ants will go out of their way to
defend caterpillars against parasitic
wasps which can kill the caterpillars so
the honeydew secretion and defense are
Co adaptations the honeydew that is
supplied to the ants by the caterpillars
will allow or provide the caterpillars
with
physical protection from the ants from
parasitic wasps that can lay egg and
literally cause the caterpillar to die
this is an example of a co-adaptation
that's occurring so how this
co-adaptation and demonstrate
coevolution
well biologists often have a strict
definition for coevolution it's evidence
of parallel evolution between taxa which
is referred to broad definition or
classification is required so this does
co-adaptation demonstrate coevolution
adaptation is in the short term and
evolution is over the long term and here
we have different animal species
exhibiting different wings for flight