okay here we'll be looking at collecting
and comparing tool marks
which often are very important pieces of
evidence
in a crime scene so first off a tool
mark it's defined as any impression cut
gouge or abrasion caused by a tool
coming in contact with another object
and they are typically found in forced
entry
scenarios we see here in a door kind of
prying it open
you see the tool marks definitely left
here to help
open that door when it was probably in
the locked position
now when you compare tool marks again
there's a lot of different types of
tools but tool mark impressions can
reveal class characteristics or
or the size and shape of the tool
because for example a crowbar is going
to leave a much larger impression than a
small
screwdriver typically we're unable to
connect the marks to one specific tool
unless there's a random nick or break
that tool has acquired
giving it individual characteristics
if we look here at a pair of bolt
cutters that were used to cut a left
shackle
the comparison micro photograph shows
evidence of the lock shackle on the left
side
and the test cup produced by the bolt
cutters and a piece of lead on the right
you can see that there's definitely a
pretty close match
on many of those ridges and valleys
there
we're looking at unique wear patterns
the edges of a tool display
microscopic irregularities that look
like ridges and valleys as a result of
the manufacturing
process it's just a normal kind of end
product
damage and wear of the tool when used
creates a variety of unique
patterns which again can help with the
identification identification or
matching
process these imperfections can be used
to identify individual tools you can see
here
a knife edge of a suspect's knife when
compared or matched to a piece of a
rib cage from a victim and we're
noticing these origin valleys have a lot
of similar characteristics
and almost directly match up so again
this can be used to help tie in a
particular knife
to a crime scene not just a knife to a
crime scene
then when we're doing these comparisons
it's important that when a tool is
scraped against a softer
surface it may cut a series of striated
lines that reflect the pattern of the
tool's edge as we can see here
income and compared using a comparison
microscope with test tool marks made by
the suspect's weapon
to see if there are in fact uh ridges
and valleys that can be
matched up and in the image we see here
where the line splits the left to the
right
you can see a lot of consistencies there
in that comparison now problems with
tool mark
comparisons or that they can be
difficult to duplicate
the tool mark left at the crime scene in
the laboratory
must make test marks of various angles
and different pressures
to see if a match can be made there's
also a lot of different kind of
cut mark shapes there's y cuts and t
cuts and v shapes
and a lot of this comes down to the
pressure or the angle
and it can be hard to recreate that
because all those exact kind of
factors in a lab and this is why
typically multiple lab
laceration marks need to be made
multiple impressions need to be made in
the lab
to be able to compare it to what was
found at the crime scene
now it's collecting of tool mark
evidence the entire object or part of
the object bearing the tool mark should
be submitted to the laboratory for
evidence
when the tool mark cannot be uh from the
cry it can not be removed from the crime
scene
other options such as taking a picture
or making a cast should be implemented
liquid silicone the best material to use
for casting and a lot of detail can be
lost when you're forced to use
a photograph and a cast so it's best at
the actual image
but something is better than nothing
so lastly when we have that piece of
evidence that is found
we want to be sure that we're handling
it with care never attempt to fit a
suspect's tool into the tool mark
as it could alter the mark and question
the integrity of the evidence
the suspect tool and mark are packaged
in separate containers to keep from
destroying their individual
characteristics
this can be trace evidence like paint
chips on the tool or
impressions must be careful when
handling packaging evidence so you don't
lose any potential trace evidence and we
can see here
of a nice little storage area for a
knife
that may have some blood evidence that's
why it has the biohazard symbol but this
is going to help
maintain all those potential individual
characteristics
without causing any alterations so it
can be entered as evidence
in a crime scene