here I'm going to cover some common
cannabis nutrient deficiencies and some
of the characteristic looks that these
may have we could see here all these
plants leaves don't look quite right
some of it is due to light damage but
other abiotic factors some is also
related to nutrients being able to
distinguish and identify those is
important to any efficient rural
operation so first off we're looking at
nutrients we want to consider mobile
versus immobile nutrients mobile can be
translocated from older growth to newer
growth tissue this means that the
deficiency of these nutrients will first
show up in the older plant material it's
kind of being stolen from those older
leaves and shifted to those newer
growing leaves immobile nutrients are
essentially fixed in place as kind of
the broken-down car kind of represents
in the plant and as a result they don't
translocate very well so the newer
growth will tend to show those first
signs of deficiencies when we're looking
at nutrients want to classify them
there's three main categories the
primary nutrients are the major
nutrients needed by the plants in large
quantities this is the three numbers on
the fertilizer the NPK the nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium secondary
nutrients are needed in smaller
quantities and primary nutrients in the
three secondary nutrients are calcium
magnesium and sulfur lastly of the
micronutrients and these are required
nutrients by the plant but in very small
quantities some in micronutrients are
boron chlorine copper iron manganese
molybdenum nickel and zinc now these
were look at fertilizer options there's
chelated of fertilizers and these Gilead
fertilizers are often more stable and
plant available sources of nutrients so
something if possible to get these are
usually advised because this improves
the fertilizer use efficiency by the
plant fertilizers in this category can
often be used as fullier applications
applied to the leaves in addition to
being media applied which can help
reduce the time the plant remains
nutrient deficient so let's get into
some of the nutrients division see here
well we'll start with nitrogen it's a
mobile nutrient often associated with
the degree of green at the plant
as the efficiency is yelling of lower
leaves and fertilizer recommendations
our urea calcium nitrate or blood meal
if you're looking at a pure organic
option now looking at this example here
of nitrogen deficiency you could see the
newer growth is green and the older
growth is yellow because that nitrogen
is mobile so it's being stolen from its
older leaves and pushed to the newer
growth at least at the early onset if
this is allowed to continue eventually
all the leaves will turn yellow but the
initial onset that matters is being
moved by the plant to that newer
material here this is why it looks nice
and green phosphorus is also mobile
nutrient it's often associated with
adding for increased root growth in
flower production deficiency is
characterized by a purple coloration of
the leaves as we see here even though
this is not the only possible cause for
purple coloration other stresses can
also call purple color that is something
that's typically associated with
phosphorus triple super phosphates a
great fertilizer to remedy that and also
manure with the amount of bloom
fertilizers most growers use this tends
not to be an issue it's typically the
other case where growers are over adding
the phosphorus potassium is a mobile
nutrient often associated with sugar in
production of fruit yield deficient in
Zemun by yelling of the leaf margins and
what is that well the margins are the
very outside of the leaves here that's
what we see in this image these margins
are yellowing and this is a clear
indication that this plant is probably
done showing potassium deficiency as a
result a sulphate potassium of deaths
and chloride are recommended as
fertilizer
keep in mind potassium chloride has a
higher nutrient content about 10% more
somewhere around 60 percent of potassium
but also has a greater salt content than
potassium sulfate which is about 50
percent potassium so again they want to
weigh different fertilizer options but
at least knowing this plant is potassium
deficient gives you a great way to
target particular fertilizer within your
plan so that this doesn't happen in the
future
calcium is an immobilization with cell
division and formation deficiency is
evident by 70 of newer growth that
typically has brown spots in our pearly
forming a flower or blossoms we've grown
tomatoes very from those calcium
deficiency as
awesome and rot where the calcium simply
not getting through all the tissue
fertilizer recommendations Botanica
cal-mag Max and biome in calcium are
examples of plants available calcium
fertilizers they can help remedy this
potential deficiency magnesium is
another one this is a mobile nutrient
often associated with proper chlorophyll
formation deficiency is evident by
what's called interval yelling of the
leaves you see that here fertilizer
recommendation are epsom salts and that
enter kind of you know yellowing this is
a good comparison while not cannabis
plant between adequate magnesium to low
magnesium the veins maintain their green
color and in between them we start to
get that yellowing that develops this is
magnesium sulfur is another immobile
nutrient often associated with nitrogen
fixation in a plant deficiencies looks
similar to magnesium but tend to be more
even yellowing not broken up yellow
spots like the magnesium and it can be
of greater concern in colder soils in
particular typically that newer growth
will show kind of that overall dulling
or yellow in coloration absolute salts
is recommended you want to avoid adding
straight sulphur and this will also
change the pH of the growing media
copper is another immobile nutrient and
while not very common it can have severe
negative impact on yields often
associated with blood formation and
development in deficiencies and the
younger leaves the tip or margin or
discoloration we see the kind of tip of
this leaf curling up and looking kind of
that brownish this is kind of
characteristic of a copper deficiency
copper sulfate or other chelated copper
products would be advised if you are
spraying them on the leaves to be
careful because it can cause a chance or
greater chance of leaf burn iron is
another immobile nutrient often
associated chlorophyll production and
great plant metabolism deficiencies
effluent by the upper leaves turning
yellow and is often confused with
nitrogen deficiency as a young looks
similar to nitrogen but again lower
leaves in the iron for the upper leaves
so nitrogen will occur in the lower
leaves iron occurs in these upper leaves
here we want to watch the pH and
particularly high phosphorous can
negatively impact the
bility of iron to the plant chelate
forms of iron would be advised to
correct this potential deficiency last
thing we have manganese MN in in mobile
nutrient often associated with
photosynthesis respiration and root cell
elongation deficiencies have some
reasons to iron deficiency as its
interval yellowing chlorosis of the
newer leaves because he it looks a
little different than the iron is kind
of that more even tone fertilizer
recommendations would be manganese
sulfate or if you're using age old grow
the grow blend has shown elevated levels
of manganese based on tissue tests so
again some fertilizers will have higher
of one of these kind of more minor
nutrients so like tissue testing and
testing your plants you can have an idea
of exactly how that fertilizer may react
to the plant and what for love you may
use if you are starting to noticing the
beginnings of a deficiency the earlier
you can catch it the quicker you can
correct it and the reduction in the
problem you'll have in your end result
in yield