on this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at things that go
beyond just disease that can infect
plants
we're going to look at some abiotic
issues which can also reduce yields
and increase plant stresses
[Music]
all right so here we're going to look at
common ability issues for cannabis
plants
looking at abiotic factors being those
non-living components of an ecosystem
wind
sunlight soil temperature atmosphere and
water are just a few that fall under
this category
it's not always a disease that causes a
reduction in yield
so general abi characteristics so
typically symptoms will appear
suddenly if it is an abiotic issue a
uniform pattern can also typically be
observed
and it's though not common to be only on
a single plant meaning
not like you just have one plant that
has an infection you'll see many have
this
issue if you're growing more than one
variety it's possible for there to be a
distinctive difference between varieties
though not always the case lesions tend
to have distinct
lines of impact and not impacted tissue
so when these we're looking at our
lesions they tend to have these kind of
harsh lines versus it was a disease
they can kind of a spreading appearance
to them abiotic factors tend to have a
little bit more of a harsher
line associated with them now what are
some stresses when we're looking at
abiotic stresses well
they can lead to secondary plant
stresses heat cold heavy metals
nutrients
salinity drought flooding all these can
cause abiotic stresses that lead to
secondary stresses on the plant
this is a result this causes the damage
of the plant that can be seen
all these factors these secondary
stresses can lead to cell death
accumulation survival and other negative
impacts
so looking at shoot related about this
is what's occurring on the top of the
plant
well heat can come from light that could
be artificial or even the sun can cause
heat stress
there's also cold which is a
particularly concern early in the late
in outdoor growing for indoor grows
watch the lights off temperature
and be sure you're moderating that as
another video here on tobacco university
looking at the
relationship of frost which is cold
damage on
outdoor grown cannabis now root zone
about x dresses
there are many we see the nutrients
oftentimes growers over feed their
plants leading to nutrient toxicities
which is a plant stressor there's heavy
metals this is tested in the final plant
material so be sure no
your substrate and your inputs are so
you're limiting the chance of having any
potential heavy metal stress on your
root structure
salinity this can happen with chemical
organic fertilizers
so be watchful for the of this in
flushing plants is advised to reduce the
salt concentration
if it does get to a level that is
causing plant stress
drought which is sometimes not
intentional but be sure to check each
plant to ensure the irrigation system
you're using is fully functional
as well as flooding which can be caused
by damage to an irrigation line or
simply over watering plants so be sure
to get a feel
for the substrate for each individual
plant to make sure you're not over or
under watering it
all these are kind of root zone stresses
with the above ground stresses
eliminating and being mindful of these
and reducing these stresses on the plant
will help improve plant efficiency as
well as yield