with any growing operation mistakes will
happen but here are some common grower
errors that I find in grow operations
we're talking a little bit more than
just kind of spilling the morning coffee
on the daily news here let's look at
some common and I love them listed here
grower errors so first off often growers
do not like to admit that they make
mistakes but it does happen you're
allowed to make mistakes I'd want you to
be too tentative and not do anything but
you can only make each mistake once
I don't allow for repeat so if you make
one mistake when I definitely make note
of that and don't let it happen again
so pruning errors is one example putting
us off in a combination of both an art
and a science and remember you can only
remove plant material once you can't
kind of put it back you can think of it
almost like a haircut you can always cut
the hair off yet may grow back but it's
gonna take a little while so you want to
decide on a pruning method early on and
stick with it for the duration of the
growth cycle don't want to be switching
from one type to another a lot of
growers will read up on one and want to
prune that way when they've been kind of
training the plant one way and that can
cause some issues long range that
switching Midway will reduce the plant
efficiency I'll make it very difficult
potentially to prune opinion which
you're changing from or to under
fertilizing this can result from a
miscalculation or in some cases were
simply just get cheap they want to skimp
on the total amount of fertilizer to say
about cost
now how much they skimp to they go ten
percent off the recommended twenty
thirty forty eighty percent of that can
kind of impact the potential on the
plant there however especially early in
the growth cycle is consent plans which
may offset the growth cycle currently in
damaged plants in contrast to that we
have over fertilizing in this community
of very similar plant problems is under
fertilizing by stunting and damaging of
plants often this isn't regarded or
thought of as being an issue but yes or
fertilizing can stun plants a lot of
times or fertilize fertilizing comes
from a miscalculation or often growers
think more is better so they add and end
up doing more harm than good
if the fertilizer is like an ounce to a
gallon they may had announced a quarter
ounce and a half making a little more
insurance that would be good for the
plant
there is a reason why that's an optimum
or ideal amount so you're just wasting
money it could potentially harm the
planet or contaminate groundwater in
addition there's also mishandling of
plants so when moving want to take care
and handle those plants with care if you
mindful of others that you're working
with as you don't want to do any
unnecessary harm to the branches as this
will reduce overall year yields if
you're breaking branches especially if
you move them from a flower room or from
a bedroom to a flower room just be
mindful of that shift shuffling of
plants process also be careful the
amount of nitrogen fertilizer you add as
this can help pick the plants slightly
more resist resilient to damage in
addition continually adding silicates to
the irrigation water can help strengthen
the plant structure making them less
likely to break branches again something
that can't be added once and fixed it
needs to be continually added in kind of
accumulate in the plant but it can help
strengthen plants if that does become an
issue but typically we just watch the
amount of nitrogen and just be careful
at the plant so as you are moving then
I'll transmit chop this is often a
direct result grows we're trying to rush
plants along the production process
there are different types of shock that
can occur light intensity when changing
the type of light that can cause some
damage so be mindful of that photo
period the time of light exposure
flipping the lights can also cause a
little stress on the plants roots
transplant shock when the containers are
changed so just be mindful we are
changing containers now you're trying to
do it without disturbing the roots too
badly so that you're reducing the delay
or the lag time that plant may have
during the transplant process
lastly applicator blight a very common
error I see in growers and this is where
a grower sprays the plant for a benefit
but ends up doing more harm or at least
some harm than just pure the benefits
some possible causes are the wrong
dilution rate product interactions
trying to mix too many products together
apply too hard
with too much force application made
during high light intensity that's it
for outdoor application avoid mid day
spraying for indoor watch mid light
spray or when the lights just kind of
first come on they're a leftover product
not properly washed out from the last
yeast causing potential interactions
there so applicator blades it's kind of
a funny term for the grower kind of
cause
the error so just be mindful of if you
are going to be applying something to
the plants that you are sticking to all
the parameters and not causing more
damage than good to your plants