everyone has a particular terpene they
might be more interested in
and here on debaco university there are
specific videos on terpenes
this video though is looking at just
common terpenes looking at providing
with some great information
as a general overview looking at the
common terpenes
so you can develop a better
understanding in general of each
if you have interest in one or two in
particular search the channel
you might find some more detailed
information on that particular terpene
that is of interest to you
[Music]
all right let's go over some common
terpenes here so
we hear a lot about terpene profiles and
profile charts
like this table or wheel provide an easy
visual understanding in general
which terpenes produce particular
effects so you might hear a full
spectrum terpene profile that's
basically producing
a little bit of all the terpenes or
partial spectrum terpene profile where
only a few select
ones might be present in the particular
end product
so terpenes in temperature so
terpenes have different molecular
structures so their boiling points
will vary some terpenes require high
boiling points to turn into vapor
while others are in ineffective at high
temperatures
with the same holding true for
cannabinoids so here's an example that
thc's boiling point is 315 degrees
fahrenheit
and lionel's boiling point is 388
degrees
fahrenheit as a comparison if you're
familiar with other terpenes
we could see some here pining very low
temperature relatively speaking
compared to thcv having a very high
temperature here for boiling points or
different compounds
so this does play into a factor
particularly they're looking at
turning them into a vapor what
temperature you have that
vapor set at is going to impact the
availability potential the effect
that you may be getting from that
particular terpene it might be a little
bit more difficult to get uh pioneen and
thcv activate at the same time
because of just the span of temperatures
that they have here
we also see our tv and then the kind of
other colder temperatures to warmer
temperatures here relatively speaking
all
pretty hot we're talking about degrees
fahrenheit considering water boils at
212.
so here's just some more information and
again the goal here is to provide you
with some great information i'll shrink
myself down
and put myself right up here in the
corner so if you want to pause the video
or always look in the description for a
link to the slides as well as resources
if you want to download any of these
yourself you're more than welcome to
this is just to provide you with that
general guide in comparing
different terpenes again more videos on
this channel will cover them a little
bit more detail
but just just gives you a nice general
comparison
also some common terpenes these are ones
that will be discussed in other videos
so kind of that quick visual uh any of
these you want to research further
search the channel hopefully you'll find
a video with some more information
that you find helpful for you however
when scouring the internet there can be
helpful information and there can also
be um inaccurate or what's basically
unhelpful information
uh keep in mind that indica sativa only
has to do with plant morphology
and not chemical profile so we're
talking about indicas and sativas
yes taller slimmer longer leaves are
sativas
shorter bushier plants that are often
whiter or indicas we're talking about
head highs versus body highs sleep aids
creativity daytime nighttime use
none of this has any validity comparing
an indica to
a sativa indica sativa only has to do
with the morphology
not the chemical profile of the actual
plant
looking at this research article here to
get into some more
information it's another great research
article to kind of look at some of the
information was pulled from it but when
you look at
it for yourself here is the proper
citation
so here we see again some more charts
and comparisons
so great research article here now here
we're seeing some more charts and
comparisons again just presented down
that research table looking at
form of pharmacological activity
cannabinoids as well as where you
commonly may encounter them
the general structure and the terpenoid
name listed here
chart was a little bit to put on just
one slide so this is one slide and this
is the second slide there giving you the
full kind of
gamut of everything keep in mind some
are not well completely understood but
definitely gives you at least a good
starting point as well as many of these
discussed in other videos here in debaco
university
now common terpenes for the ones if you
really want to learn about them in more
detail
these are individually covered so
probably just type in one of these names
into the search on this
channel should be able to find the
information you're looking for but again
as far as a comparison quick little
rundown of the terpene
where you're likely to find it
therapeutic effects and the aroma
typically associated
with that particular terpene very
complex a lot of people
great interest in this so hopefully this
provides you
with a little more information