here we're gonna look at the
communication between neurons because
your body has so many neurons are all
interconnected it's very important that
they are able to communicate and relay
signals from one to the other now first
off we have to understand the basic
anatomy of a neuron now we see a prime
example of one pictured here you see
highly branched region leading to kind
of a central point into this kind of
central fiber here then another kind of
area that branches now the first part
here we call this the dendrites these
are fibers that receive messages from
other neurons they then will take that
signal will continue down we know where
the dendrites are located we see the
cell body which has the nucleus it's
important also to remember that these
message will only travel in one
direction starting with degenerates
going this to the cell body ultimately
leading down the axon but the accent is
is the fiber that sends a message to
other neurons you can see it also
branches here at the end but the signals
will only go one way they go in the
dendrites which is okay the area where
the cell body is down the axon and it
will be passed on to other neurons the
passing on that occurs between neurons
there's at the synapse now it's
important to remember that neurons don't
actually touch one another it's actually
a gap between them called a synapse let
me see that evident right here so while
it may look like they're touching in
these diagrams they're actually not
there's a synapse there now these
messages that are going traveling down
the axons are sent across the synapse
through special chemicals called
neurotransmitters and we see those
evident here there are the what's being
passed on through this area here this
physical space between our two neurons
keep in mind that the end here is our
axon and here is our dendrite of our
next neuron now the use of
neurotransmitters causes an electrical
current there's actually enough
electrical current generated in your
brain to power a flashlight they came
just how many of these neurons are being
actively fired and these synapses are
actually transmitting these
neurotransmitters my familiar with some
of our ions that are being transported
are we
scepters are very important that's
occurring in this region synaptic cleft
again in that physical space between the
axon terminal and the dendritic spine
here of the next neuron and
neurotransmitters are chemicals
responsible for signal transmission
between individual neurons most neurons
make one or more neurotransmitters which
are released at different stimulation
frequencies while 50 or more
neurotransmitters have been identified
I'm only going to cover a couple here
and they're classified by their chemical
structure and also by their function
you'll notice here we see the same axon
in synaptic cleft and then the dendrite
of the next neuron
it's important to remember with their
neurotransmitters it's foreign port we
also have receptors here for those
neurotransmitters now just touching on a
couple of the neurotransmitters again
they're chemicals that carry nerve
impulses across the synapse
they bind the receptors in a
postsynaptic cell causing chemically
gated channels to open some you might be
initially familiar with are adrenaline
that's kind of your fight-or-flight
response and they're produced in
stressful situations dopamine is kind of
the pleasure neurotransmitter associated
with movement and motivation and
serotonin is the mood neurotransmitter
can be associated with well-being and
happiness it also in AIDS in the sleep
cycle in digestive system regulation
gives you a little bit of idea of how
they may look initially they may look
very similar but you can see there's
very distinctive differences within some
of the binding that occurs between these
so adrenaline dopamine and serotonin are
three three other major ones are G a B a
and that's the counting or
neurotransmitter comes the firing of
nerves in the central nervous system
helps improve focus low levels can cause
anxiety acetylcholine there's a learning
in our transmitter involved with thought
learning and memory something maybe you
want a little bit more of and lastly
just the one that I'm gonna cover here
kind of over 50 possible options is
endorphins know the euphoria transmitter
they're they're the ones that are
released during exercise and points of
excitement and they can help reduce pain
this is why I ever kind of been doing
something
and kind of in the heat of battle and
you have really seen endorphins and you
kind of cut yourself or injure yourself
you may not realize it or feel the full
effects of the pain until after after
the endorphin levels have been reduced
hopefully this gives you a general idea
of how neurons communicate