okay so here I'm gonna go have some
common cannabis cultivars and cultivars
we've become strange varieties cultivars
probably the best term to use is its
botanically correct there are some great
variability and you can see here just
morphology of these plants but there's
other differences so general a cultivar
overview well-well some highlights are
provided in some cases little is known
about the origin of some of the
cultivars I'm even going to present here
this shows the lack of definable
traceable family trees which is why
incorporating genetic testing is so
important going forward you can see here
on some very commonly varieties there's
not a lot of great background
information on them keep in mind also
that the use of the term cultivar is a
relatively new concept to cannabis but
it's botanically correct method and
should be used at increased rates of
adoption so there's so many to choose
from more breeders are not only
extremely plant material such as clones
but sharing what they produce this
increases the diversity of plants
available and part of the challenges to
have an accurate lineage records we know
where these plants came from or what
resulting cross they may be so general
classifications we can see our THC group
and our CBD group burning it to the CBD
group and explain a little bit of kind
of some of the issues with some of these
varieties in the THC group then I
provide some links to offer some other
information to kind of get some
background on on these in addition to
what I provide so first off THC
varieties these are strains that
produced a psychoactive high income
associated with marijuana these that are
high in THC are not the main focus of
this class we're going to focusing again
on that CBD hemp varieties however
there's come variety names that you may
recognize I want you to realize what is
actually classified as marijuana and
what is more of the hemp variety so sage
sativa Afghan genetic equilibrium is a
high THC variety okayed by Adam Dunn is
considered to be the main staple of th
seeds contains over 20% THC so it's a
very potent strain again it's sa GE not
sage as in the
herb placed second in the 2001 cannabis
cup and more information presented here
this is with the sage plant and a kind
of relating to a herb look would look
like I'm not quite too similar to the
sage in the canvas variety but that's
again different derivative of that name
Blue Dream original California even
though the exact Creator is unknown so
we get into this variety too which again
hi teach you're not gonna focus on it in
general but it's want you to realize
here we don't know the exact creator has
become a West Coast legend and we still
don't even know who created it then for
potency and high production Sour Diesel
established itself McCann was seen in
early 90s with increased interest on the
East Coast in particular in the United
States the emergent by a girl who had a
sour demeanor has nothing to do with
this taste of the cultivar so again
sometimes these names can be misleading
and again even though this is in the
marijuana classification Sour Diesel
because the person was a sour person
pungent odor when growing typically
produces THC levels well above 20%
purple haze buds of shades of lavender
which is part of the name derive comes
from known for high energy created and
blissful effects made popular in 1967 by
Jimi Hendrix with a song Purple Haze and
yes it does have this kind of purple
coloration these anthocyanins are much
higher in Purple Haze and also THC is
high cush oh gee cush is one of most
popular and potent strains in the world
it's a broad category but and generally
can expect cush to have dense buds
rust-colored pistols see here that had a
brown coloration a lemon fuel skunk and
kind of spicy smell smooth for Bhatia's
flavor and sedative effects again also
high in THC
Girl Scout cookie are being abbreviated
now GS C short for Girl Scout cookie
which is a hybrid across between OG Kush
and urban poison little is known about
the origin other than its star in
California fairly recently 2011-2012 and
again this just points to the fact that
these names that become very popular
little is known about their origin so
this is increasingly kind of unknown and
the variability that we have even
some well-established well-accepted
variety names okay then we get to ones
that are low in THC these low THC
cultivars are ones that will not get you
high they don't produce very high
amounts of THC I'm not going to get to
in that psychoactive high they may be
considered low in THC often this is
considered to be below 5 percent THC but
keep in mind in order to be classified
as hemp the levels need to be less than
0.3 percent THC so some arguing that
federal maximum level of THC should be
around 1% as this will provide more
cultivars to be used medically and it's
still not produced the psychoactive high
so I have the picture of the limos here
simply because we're looking at where is
that bar where should that bar be placed
right now at 0.3% very low so that's
limiting the amount of cultivars these
next varieties I'm going to show are low
in THC cleaning there below usually
around that 5% but are not acceptable
from the federal standpoint so it would
still be classified as marijuana under
the current law so Kenna tonic a wild
high in CBD against the medical benefits
six to 17% there is still enough
teaching not to be considered as
cultivar as hemp typically has around
that six percent THC how it's still a
highly regarded medical cultivar and has
been used to treat pain in anxiety but
again still above that federal level
well above that federal level
despite its high CBD production so here
we're looking at a CDC in this cultivar
is derived actually from Kenneth tonic
there's a ratio of THC to CBD of about
one to 25
he's typically around half to one point
two percent THC which is so very low but
again still above that federal limit
this unique ratio induces little to no
intoxicating effects it can still have
the CBD percentage around 16 to 24
percent however typically tests just
above that threshold for was defined as
hemp so it's being replaced by
Charlotte's Web again a CDC we have the
band we have a CDC types of power
conversion also have some great links
located below here that's CBD varieties
Templar high CBD
and low THC which is low THC is defined
as less than 0.3 percent THC are the
main focus of this class well there are
many different varieties I have chosen
to highlight really just a few wife and
abacus are two examples varieties being
grown at UConn
so you see medical marijuana that we
find that slash through it it's kind of
a misleading statement because marijuana
is indicating of that high THC string
we're focusing here on CBD and hemp
varieties so Charlotte's Web is probably
one that gets the most attention its
biggest selling point is that it's
classified as hemp since it is less than
0.3 percent THC and also still remains
high in CBD has been shown to reduce
seizures without any mental side effects
its names actually derived from a young
girl on whose name is Charlotte who is
having epileptic seizures and that were
reduced with this cultivar which has a
web-like appearance so Charlotte and
Webb that's where it comes from
it's a relatively rare cultivar but is
highly sought-after in the medical
community leading to increased attention
and I have some great links here Dylan
the article about it and some more
information about Charlotte's Web if you
want to learn more so a variety here
we're growing at uconn is entitled white
and this is a high CBD cultivar that's
high in CBD to THC ratio and the exact
genetics actually though do still remain
mainly unknown as far as a lineage edit
came from communities for chronic pain
and did with native effects from
chemotherapy
they said this is one of the varieties
being grown here at yuca