in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over the some of the
compounds produced by the cannabis plant
[Music]
all right let's get into some compounds
produced by cannabis so first off can
produces many compounds i can't cover
them all here i'm just going to touch on
some of the major highlights because
cannabis is a complex plant with over
500 chemical entities more than 100 of
them are cannabid compounds alone some
of them actually have opposing effects
even though cannabis has been used and
cultivated by mankind for at least 6 000
years our current knowledge of its
pharmaceutical properties is based on
studies which may have taken place only
since the end of the 19th century so
basically we have a lot more to learn
about this plant and some of the
compounds that it's producing and how
they may best be utilized
so first i'll start with some of the
physical structures the trichomes as we
can see right here these are the
physical structures that contain the
cannabinoids of flavonoids and terpenes
so while these chemicals are going to be
produced or chemicals will be produced
over the course of the plant really it's
these trichomes these structures here
that we're going to be looking at these
small looks like little white almost
like sugar dots so to speak these areas
right here these trichomes and that's
where most of the cannabinoids that
we're looking for pharmaceutical
purposes are going to be produced in the
plant
so let's start with the first one kind
of the one probably most people
associate with cannabis and that's thc
or tetrahydrocannabinol
this is the psychoactive compound that
generates the marijuana or typically
high feeling as generated it's the
greater percent thc the more potent the
strain thc can also act as an appetite
suppressant with also some medical
benefits such as anti-anxiety and this
is kind of what the chemical structure
here looks like of tetrahydrocannabinol
now cbd something else you've probably
heard a lot about um cannabidiol that's
how that's pronounced i try to pronounce
provide a pronunciation i should say
here
so you can kind of
deconstruct these very long and complex
terms
the cbd is a non-psychoactive chemical
component basically doesn't get you high
has many medical benefits such as
suppressing seizures pain relief and
improved sleep often cbd extraction is
used to make oils edibles or topicals
for different medical benefits with also
the ease of application for the user
more so than just the dry flour
then can get to the thc compared or
versus cbd and these are both
cannabinoids produced by cannabis and we
could see here kind of the
if you will the original molecule cbga
can then be through the plant made into
thc or cbd so a lot of growers were also
looking at cbg dominant varieties so
they could make whatever ratio that they
were that they deemed desirable
keep in mind though plants with high thc
produce that strong euphoric high can
also do
feelings of anxiety as well as dizziness
plants with high cbds
lack that euphoric high and have great
medical benefits potential for pain
inflammation epsilon c as well as
seizures so cbd a lot especially
younger children has been shown to
reduce seizures and that's what
hopefully helps gain some popularity
here in the medical community
now in addition to just those we have
thcv
tetrahydrocannabin which produces a
trippy high that comes on quick and is
often associated with a caffeine rush
because of its high energy compound
however keep in mind that thcv must
reach
428 degrees fahrenheit in order to be
activated it may help with blood sugar
regulation as well however if you suffer
from anxiety it would be advised to stay
away from varieties that have elevated
levels of thcv just a word of caution
there
they may have cbn which is
cannabinol not well documented at the
current time but shares some
characteristics of cbd with less potency
it does show promise as a sleep aid and
is typically found in low percentages
and needs to be professionally isolated
from the plant material then we have cbg
so as i mentioned before one that gains
some popularity simply because it's kind
of that stem cell molecule of thc and
cbd and it's pronounced cannabinoid
this compound is gaining popularity
since it's the precursor to thc cbd as
well as cbc as well some other minor
cannabinoids it's not present in high
amounts because it's quickly converted
by the plant to other compounds but it
does show promise to reduce inflammation
as an ant also can be used as an
antibacterial agent and along with some
other medical benefits vossen often been
referred to as the stem cell of cannabis
and could serve as the building block
for many compounds and this is why some
growers get really interested in
breeding this simply because it's that
starting point it's that early point
that then if they had a lot of that they
could then figure out these different
synthases and produce
the ratios of compounds they wanted in
the
end then we get to terpenes so
terpenes are aromatic
organic compounds which are typically
oils that are increased in the trichomes
of the plant they naturally occur in
plants to reduce herbivore feeding and
increase odds of pollination these
compounds produce the unique flavors
colors and smells of the plant but of
course are not limited to cannabis you
can see here pine sap
we are familiar with that
aroma associated with pine trees that is
an example of another plant producing
these terpenes and then lastly we have a
flavonoids here
and these are a group of natural
substances with variable phenolic
structures and are found in fruits
vegetables grains bark roots stems
flowers tea and also wine these are
compounds that are responsible for the
color and aroma of flowers and can also
help attract pollinators in addition
they can protect plants from different
biotic and abiotic stresses can act as
uv light filters for example
anthocyanins we can kind of see that
here poison ivy might be feeling with is
usually a green leaf
here when it first emerges has a lot of
red tones to it that's its way of
protecting or shielding itself from the
harmful effects of the uv light until it
gets established in cannabis flavonoids
may offer some synergistic effects but
of course more research is needed and
hopefully that research will be
occurring uh with the gaining of
popularity within the medical community
of just unlocking some of the powers
that the cannabis plant may have