so on this debaco University video If
you're looking at detecting whether or
not you have hot plate and viroid I'm
going to provide a brief overview
comparing PCR to RT lamp for RNA
detection which one you might choose and
why
[Music]
all right let's get into a brief
comparison of PCR to RT lamp where we're
looking at detecting hoplate and thyroid
so first off we have to understand what
these actually refer to in mean so the
first one we're going to look at is PCR
which stands for polymis chain reaction
this has primers that are specific to a
nucleic acid region and if present and
positive binding occurs it'll be copied
multiple times exponentially producing
the original sequence this can not only
determine if the sequence is present or
not but with other detective
instrumentation the severity or how many
particles were present at the start can
also be known this can allow us to
determine whether there's a low or high
viral or in this case viroid load on
that plant so it kind of goes through
and repeats repeats repeats this can
exponentially produce and then how many
cycles you can tell how many sequences
we originally started with
now PCR is also referred to as a
thermocycler because it takes one or at
least theoretically one piece of DNA or
RNA and makes many many many copies of
it it's a cycle it's a thermocycler it
changes temperature this thermostat
cycler is known to maximize a
replication cycle
and temperature is changed to allow the
attack polymerase to effectively bind
and replicate The Strand so by having
different temp temperatures cycling
through those are allowing for different
rounds of this nucleic acid replication
that's how it gets the term thermocycler
we're getting that kind of Cycles goes
through here temperatures and it repeats
and it repeats and it repeats and
repeats
PCR testing itself is a molecular
testing that has to be performed if
detection of a viroid is the goal this
can also work for viruses as well
they're done in very very small tubes as
a result you can do many many tests at
one time going through that same
thermocycler
now RT lamp a little different a little
more uh longer name stands for reverse
transcription Loop mediated isothermal
amplification that's why RT lamp is just
so much easier of a word to say now
loopmiated isothermal implication is DNA
application method that allows for rapid
and sensitive detection of a specific
Gene lamp merge with reverse
transcription that's how it gets the RT
before it has been successful for use
for the detection of several respiratory
RNA viruses and now it's being also
applied onto others use a different
enzyme and PCR that offers the advantage
of being effective at one temperature
and not the cycling of temperatures as I
said PCR is also known as a thermocycler
it's changing those temperatures this
can operate at a consistent temperature
making it a little easier there
now what this allows to be a little
easier for is actually field testing the
lamp is similar to PCR uses a
specialized enzyme to amplify the
thyroid if it's present the downfall is
this enzyme is less sensitive and RT
lamp compared to the more sensitive PCR
though it's good at finding positive
it's not really a good at detecting true
negatives you might get some false
positives associated with that keep in
mind also it is a field testing so
sometimes it's a color change you know
how much did the color change there can
be some interpretation with that as well
that needs to be taken into
consideration
lastly a lot of people ask well why
don't you just kind of use an antigen
test I've got very popular with the um
stars cov2 virus this test for proteins
so this cannot be used for viroids
unlike viruses because they lack a
co-protein viruses do have a coat
protein thyroids do not so that's why
this particular test cannot be used
you're dependent on PCR or the RT lamp
now of those uh which one should you
choose well PCR is the standard for a
reason is considered to be the most
reliable also provides very quick
results does not need a high number of
virus present in the original sample
technically could work with just one
present but it would still come back
with a positive indication because it's
the amplification process so this is why
this one typically is the one that's
recommended though if you're looking
quickly the RT lamp might be a little
bit more advantageous kind of like in
the field testing per se but really if
you want to get a true positive or even
a low level positive particularly if
you're looking at veg plants or early
plants PCR would be the one I would
recommend