on this debaco university video we're
going to go an in-depth
look at comparing types of fertilizer
[Music]
let's get into comparing types of
fertilizer options uh for growing plants
so first off we with fertilizer we have
what's called a guaranteed analysis
and all fertilizer labels have three
distinctive numbers displayed
which is the guaranteed analysis these
numbers represent the primary nutrients
and are presented in this consistent
order here we see nitrogen
followed by phosphorus followed by
potassium and in this case this
fertilizer has no phosphorus
but is still listed as a number in this
case zero this allows
nutrient ratios to be compared of any
fertilizer specifically the forms of
each that the plant can uptake
can be listed as well first number is
the amount of nitrogen
second number is the amount of phosphate
in the form of p2o5
and to get the actual amount of
phosphorous uh you take the p205 and
multiple it by 0.044 to get the p
and the third number is potash k2o
to get the actual number of just
potassium to k2 and multiply it by 0.83
however because growers are typically
looking at what's plant available
this is why they're presented in these
forms you'll also notice the guaranteed
analysis down here
lists water soluble nitrogen with water
in
soluble nitrogen and that four percent
of water insoluble nitrogen
is slowly available nitrogen is derived
in this example
from biosolids so what if there's a
fourth number
what if you kind of see the three
numbers and then there's a fourth number
well the fourth number may appear in
some specialty fertilizers
this will usually represent either iron
or sulfur
so be sure to check the label in this
case we're looking at kind of this
multi-nutrient blend here
these nutrients are supplemental and may
be a value
under special conditions and this is why
there's typically only those three
numbers
kind of listed there those specialty
fertilizers now we're looking at
fertilizers can contain only one of
three primary nutrients
in this example we have nitrogen sources
such as ammonium nitrate
which is 35.5 nitrogen with no
phosphorous or potassium
urea sodium nitrate or liquid nitrogen
as well
all these are very fit much favoring the
nitrogen
with no phosphorus or potassium which in
certain cases might be
beneficial then there's a phosphorus
source typically super triple phos 046
zero a very potent source of phosphorus
and then potash or potassium sources
here potassium chlorine potassium
sulfate 60
and 50 um potassium respectively
i think it isn't blending fertilizers
it's jax professional
a 20 20 20 and even blend of nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium so we get into
those water soluble and insoluble forms
uh here
so labels will often state how much of
the nitrogen is either water insoluble
which is slowly released over a long
period of time typically several weeks
months months or even potentially years
as opposed to quickly available water
soluble nitrogen we see that listed
right here typically fertilizers will
contain a combination of both forms
because if it all contained one
either will be waiting a really long
time or it'll be available
in a very short period of time quickly
available water soluble forms
allows for quick results only days about
three days after application you can see
a
change in the plants word of caution
with the water cybel forms as these have
higher odds of plant damage
if applied too concentrated in addition
the slower released forms often have a
coating or other mechanisms to allow
that slow release to occur
so often these forms have an additional
expense associated with them
and again here's just another example of
a label we're focusing on nitrogen of
course
but we see there's other nutrients as
well in this case there's also
other non-plant food ingredients
included
as well as some of the bacteria so again
there's a lot that can be
gleaned for information from the label
now this fertilizer ratio
again things are still in the same
nitrogen phosphorus and potassium form
the ratio fertilizers is the
relationship between nitrogen phosphorus
potassium content
in those fertilizers the ratio basics
the fertilizer with a three one two
ratio contains
more than half the times as much
nitrogen as it does
potassium and three times more nitrogen
than
phosphorus it kind of gives you that
ratio there fertilizer example for
lesser grades of 45 15
30 have a 3 to 1 to 2 ratio these are
important potentially for different
stages of growth the nutrient
concentrations are pound for pound a 36
12 24 fertilizer contains twice as much
nutrients
as a six as an eight six twelve
fertilizer so keep that in mind as well
when you're looking at your application
rates here we see some grades and some
ratios as some examples
and nitrogen is typically kind of meant
to be for greening up the plant again
these are just general examples
phosphorus we think kind of down in the
sense of the roots and blooms
and potassium products kind of all
around so it's the up down all around
nitrogen phosphorus potassium kind of
lingo there just to get you an idea of
what generally each can do now how much
is in the bag of fertilizer so
the fertilizer ratios does not usually
reflect the elemental nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium as i mentioned
before
only in nitrogen is expressed as the
elemental basis p
and k are expresses the oxidized basic
compounds because those are the plant
available ones
this means that a fertilizer that reads
eight eighteen
six twelve as we see right here eighteen
six twelve this contains 18
nitrogen 6 phosphorus and 12
potassium as far as plant available
concerns so if you purchase
a hundred pound bag of this it would be
18 pounds nitrogen six pounds
and 12 pounds respectively if you
purchase a 20 pound bag
that would have 3.6 pounds nitrogen 1.2
pounds
phosphorus 2.4 potassium so you can see
how those ratios play
and that's going to be important when
you look at your application rates
so looking at solid fertilizer we see
here a granular form if you will
uh it's known for good handling
properties and allow even distribution
because it's like little pebbles or
rocks
this form does not cake or form fine
dust
which can make applications challenging
so
this is a typically easier form to apply
blended fertilizers we see down here as
a result of a combination of single
element or compound fertilizers
to achieve a certain ratio or blend
that's created to match the results of a
soil test
some fertilizer companies will make a
blend if you give them soil test results
however this can cause there to be a
size and color differences between the
different types of fertilizer
which can sometimes lead to uneven
applications if one particle is really
big and one particle's really small
that can lead to uneven applications
this fertilizer does help ensure that
resulting field is fertilized with
nutrients that's needed
in the ratios based on the soil test and
reduces
the potential for over-application of
one nutrient so it's better than just
applying one single nutrient even in the
custom blend all the better
there's also liquid fertilizers and
there's clear solutions
which have nutrients that are completely
dissolved in water to make handling
very easy for the applicator however
these are
only available in relatively low
concentrated nutrients
then there is suspension fertilizers
these are
basically nutrient suspensions in
solution and have higher nutrient
concentrations
and can be used as a regular fluid
however these types of flies require
repeated applications
both while in storage and even during
applications they need kind of that
agitation
so they don't usually settle at the
bottom because you want to ensure you're
getting an
even application of your fertilizer then
there's also gaseous forms
of fertilizer used only in limited
applications due to special handling and
safety precautions that are needed
anhydrous ammonia is a great nitrogen
fertilizer
and is a common gaseous form of
fertilizer however to be effective it
must be injected into the soil
so and hopefully that soil has limited
rocks to prevent the gas from escaping
so when you put that injecting that
nitrogen
down below the soil surface well there's
a lot of rocks those tips are basically
going to get
broken this is why you can only apply an
area with limited rocks
because it wants to be covered up and
sealed so it's kept in the root zone
hazards involve the handling of an
hydrogen include the kind of serious
credential for chemical burns and
affixiation as well
so again be cautious with this type of
fertilizer
then there's organic material
considerations so often these have
variable properties so each must be
evaluated
independently key properties to consider
with any fertilizer particularly
organics
is solubility meaning how well do the
nutrients dissolve in water
fish fertilizer for example can take a
kind of hard or very low solubility can
be hard to get into solution
then there's a particle size this can
relate to simply the application method
but also the speed of a bill
availability to the plant
with smaller particles being quicker to
become plant available compared to
larger particles sometimes you pay more
for that finer
grounding but it will be more plant
available faster
then we want to consider also soluble
salts and this is
pertains to organic as well as inorganic
forms
of fertilizer high salts can cause
damage to plants but if fertilizer
applications
are evenly distributed and amounts
follow the guidance of a soil test
the odds are low of plant damage however
concentrated applications placed near
germinating seeds
can increase the odds of damage
especially if applied in a band or line
so here we see example of the seeds
being planted here and here we're
banding that fertilizer we're putting it
about five and a half
inches away from the plants seeds 11
inches is our row spacing
so those roots can kind of grow out to
that fertilizer this can happen with
organic fertilizers such as manure in
particular
some people will broadcast their
fertilizers some will subsoil ban
meaning they put the seed here and they
put the banana fertilizer below
others will go kind of put the seed here
and put the fertilizer over on this side
so those roots will grow out
and when they're more developed and
ready to uptake those nutrients this is
called
banding fertilizer typically with
soluble salts if you put it right next
to the seed it's going to burn that seed
or that tender root
when it initially germinates so when
we're looking at that salt we want to
look at the consider the salt index so
you want to know the salt in the index
of the fertilizer you're intending on
using
you could see some have very low salt
index some a very high salt index it
doesn't mean that you just stay away
from the ones that have high salt
just be aware because that's going to
maybe affect how you
apply it or how much you will apply it
to limit the chance of plant damage
lastly we have fertilizer grades here
and this is when we're looking at
purchasing fertilizer
manufacturers produce different grades
of mini-fertilizing
for plants we have the granular which is
often the largest for field applications
due to typically the lowest
cost due to the particle size will be
the largest and technically the most
variable generally it's about 22
millimeters just to give you an idea
then we have the mini granular which is
highly uniform
medium-sized particles about 14
millimeters green's grade
is micro-sized particles commonly used
in greens and golf courses
very finely ground about nine
millimeters in particle size very
consistent
typically you're going to pay the most
for the greens grade even though it
might be the exact same fertilizer that
you can get in the granular form
and also soluble quickly dissolves in
liquid fertilizer solution
basically it's like a wettable powder so
you can then mix and go through and
rapidly apply and be very quickly
available to the plants
so while these might be of the same
fertilizer the different grade of
fertilizer can impact the cost
the method of application and the
availability to the plant
so hopefully you enjoyed this kind of
very detailed look at fertilizer options
so you'd be well educated and make an
informed decision
to the benefit of you and your plants