if you're shopping for hps lighting here
at tobacco university i'm going to
provide a comparison of some common
light fixtures so it can help educate
your
process as you go through and make your
final selection
let's get into comparing hps light
fixtures for cannabis production
so first off as a disclaimer i've not
received any financial compensation for
writing the following product review i
have no material connection to the
brands products or services that i have
mentioned
so it's a standard for comparison so
we're comparing apples to apples or
oranges oranges
all the following are double ended 1 000
watt fixtures for each light i'll
provide the good
the bad and recommendations so starting
with our first one here the gavita pro
the gavita pro generates 2 100 micro
moles per second of light
light maintenance of over 96 percent per
hours so you only need to replace it
once a year and there's a variety of
reflector options and they're easy to
change
the bat is minimum hanging distance is
one meter and it's best for areas that
are not
ceiling height limited the phantom
low profile is another example of a high
pressure sodium light
and they use this kind of european arc
tube material that outputs 2100
micromoles
per second the ppf of in the 400 to 700
nanometers
and 2 330 micromoles per second
of the 280 to 800 nanometers area when
operated at a thousand watts so very
powerful light 10 000 hour service
lifetime reduces operational expenses it
is
a long light in shape for um size and
mounting
and it has a side mounted uh power cord
there so it's kind of
not really the best we can string them
together might create a little bit of
an issue when you're trying to go
through and make everything clean neat
and tidy in your grow area
this is a low profile that allows
ceiling height limited growers to
utilize the light so that's an advantage
to this one
now if i was only to select one and
again i didn't provide a ton of options
but the gavita pro would get my
recommendation
i have purchased these lights at least
in the 600 watt area
no growers that have used a thousand
watts and i find them simple reliable
and easy to change reflectors so for
that that gets my initial recommendation
and the sense that's a good sense for
comparison hps lights are getting a
little bit harder to find with the
influx of other lighting sources but
still can produce a high quality crop on
hps lighting
don't even tell you otherwise it is
still possible and
with the reduction in price of the
fixtures overall it is
worthy of a consideration if you're
looking at still producing high yield
we're trying to reduce costs