in this debaco university video i'm
going to present a study where they
compare
two cocoa based substrates and
fertilizer rates to maximize cannabis
growth and you're going to see
and i'll share with you some of the data
presented in that study
[Music]
all right let's get into comparing some
to uh choir based
substrates so first off as always here's
the article here's the kind of front
page here's this proper citation here's
a link
so if you look or want some more
information about it this is where you
would go through and look for i'm only
going to provide a brief
summary here so first off chemical and
physical properties of the substrate
that they use so what are some of the
specifics and this again this is
in the very important materials in
methods
and we can see the total porosity uh
presented here plus or minus that
they're close
also of to make note of the growing
substrates
you see a u1-hp and just a u1
these are the different types of
substrates that they used they're both
based from a company out of canada so
again if you want to research those
further
these do provide you with the also the
ec it which stands for electrical
conductivity
ph and nutrient content here measured
so you can just see that for basic
properties of these two substrates that
are used in this
study now the response to cannabis yield
to
fertilizer so i think this is a very
important point to understand
is that they did use a fertilizer as a
nutri plus organic grow liquid
organic fertilizer a 4 1.3
1.7 that's a nitrogen phosphorus
potassium
and here's kind of their fertilizer rate
and their floral dry weight and i think
this is important for growers to realize
is that as they're increasing fertilizer
rate yes they did get an increase in
floral dry weight to a certain point
once you hit that kind of optimum level
as they kept adding or increase the
fertilizer rate you notice the floral
dry weight
of grams per plant did decrease
so after about 400 micrograms of
nitrogen per liter
we're noticing a decrease here in the
floral dry weight
now this is important for growers to
understand why here we are increasing
our cost
while also decreasing our yield not a
direction that is very profitable
so there is the optimum rate more is not
better
so what's the relationship between thc
and the dry flour and fertilizer
we're kind of seeing that same
relationship here more fertilizer is not
better it will actually reduce the
floral dry weight
and also not the mass but also the
percentage of thc
in this study the goal is to fertilize
this with the optimum
level and not get into the excessive
level
so we're the optimum rate here we can
see for this study where that lies
adding more is not going to produce more
contrary to a lot of growers think
so what are the researchers conclusions
based on the study well the optimum rate
for fertilizer for them
supplying based on the math that they
did was close to that 400 but that 389
milligrams of nitrogen per liter
for the fertilizer that they chose to
use in the vegetative growth stage of
cannabis using
aqua based organic substrates so again
very specific here but provide you with
a good starting point
and a good understanding hopefully that
over adding or adding more
nutrients than this level that was
suggested by the researchers will not
only decrease your
mass of dry weight but also decrease
your percentage of cannabinoids
potentially produced
so find that optimum rate fertilizer at
that rate don't add more
because you might end up getting less