one of the advantages of using cmh or
lec
lights is that the available lamp
options or bulb options that growers
have
so in this tobacco university video
we'll provide you with some comparisons
of some of the options that are
available
[Music]
let's get into some of the options you
have for lamps when you're looking at
cmh or lec lights
so first off i want to understand that
yes many options do exist
it's not just by one light and that's
what you're stuck with growers choice
are provided as a representative sample
here but i'm not sponsored nor is there
any connection with the company as part
of this comparison
they were selected for this comparison
simply do the options they provide in
lamps are a consistent cost with an msrp
is of this
video of 139 each full spectrum sheets
for each bulb is provided
for each as well the summary of options
in the 315 watt
are a 3100 kelvin full phase
3000 kelvin r which is red enhanced
4200k which is a daylight and a 10 000
finishing bulb and we can see them all
quickly compared here provide with a
little bit more detail on each
so first off that three of 3000
compared to the 3k r which is the
3000 kelvin so again it's referring to
the color temperature
so 3k overall is a good spectrum similar
to high pressure sodiums in that you can
grow a plant full term under it
but it is a little bit better suited for
flowering much like a high pressure
sodium
that's the 3 000 kelvin right here item
number provided
now the 3k r uh slight increase in the
uv light in comparison to promote resin
production
the 3kr has a taller peak in the far red
spectrum
as well so again slightly different or
slight shift
there on both the uv light and also the
far red spectrum
as well which might be advantageous for
some growers
now if we look here specifically at some
of the information provided by the
company
this is the 3k light it gives you all
the information here
spectrum and some of the details here so
you can pause the video
and take a look at uh that can compare
these different light or lamp sources
and there's that r you can see that
shift in the spectrum a lot of things
stayed the same
but what does change might again be
advantageous if you're looking at more
of that uv light and far red
end of the spectrum so looking at the 4k
light
again this is the 4000 kelvin similar to
natural sunlight i try to do a little
comparison here
it would the company says it's a metal
halide replacement
good if you're going to be moving plants
outside after propagation in the sense
you'll be already exposing them
to similar wavelengths that they'll be
getting outside hopefully reducing
your hardening off time and your chance
of leaf burn as they transition to the
outside natural sun environment
now here's that 4k option there
and again that's 4000 kelvin different
little spectrum
and again you can see the similar
information here and you can compare
this to the ones previously shown
now the 10k finishing light this is kind
of an interesting one the goal here is
for
increased resin production as it
increases the plant's natural defense
response
to the increased amount of exposure it
has to the uv
light suggested to use only for the last
7 to 14 days of the flowering cycle
this light can be used for about 25 plus
flowering cycles before it needs to be
replaced
it's intended for growers looking to
maximize the quality of their cannabis
delivered end product so again it's a
major shift towards that uv
spectrum stressing the plant out
hopefully stressing in a good way
to increase some of the finishing
end resin compounds that a cannabis
plant would naturally want to produce
in response to this kind of wavelength
now here's that same kind of data sheet
that you can go through you can pause
look at a comparison
so here's just an example of using the
same ballast the same fixture
having these different lamp or bulb
options can really allow grow to dial in
their growing area can allow for very
easy kind of transition without having
to mess with all the ballasts just pop a
bulb out put another one in
and hopefully this helps provide you
with some information on some of the
options that exist
that you may want to take advantage of
to maximize your production