have you ever wondered about
concentrates and live concentrates made
from cannabis
well this debacle university video will
provide you with some information so you
can develop an understanding
about these products
[Music]
let's look at concentrates and live
concentrates made from cannabis
so first off i want to thank ct pharma
here because
they're providing current and publicly
available and analytical reports
for the products they produce and the
descriptions options and uses are
intended on this video to provide an
understanding of some of the end
products of that cannabis plant
it's important to understand at the end
that you should have
an analytical report with anything
you're looking at purchasing associated
with cannabis
ct farmer does a great job of showing
that and i'll show you an example of
that at the very end
so first off what's the description of
our concentrates and our
live concentrates well they can be
extracted into many different ways
and come in all different consistencies
and textures they are highly potent
concentrate mass
that often has a color similar to like a
buddy of butter or
honey there also are many different
forms of extracts
ranging from glass-like textures or
shatter to soft buttery textures such as
batter to ultimately a soft crumbly
texture as
the name implies a crumble live
concentrates are extracted in a unique
method involving flash freezing
this method preserves many of the
flavors and trichomes from the original
plant material
when compared to other original methods
now concentrates in life concentrates
what are some of the options and this is
just kind of a brief overview here
again it was found on ct pharma's site
welcome to check them out
if you want to learn more but there are
several options and we see them all kind
of
listed here but concentrates located at
the top
and then live concentrates what's
important to keep in mind is if we look
at the strength of all of them they are
listed as high
simply because this is a concentrate so
they are
concentrating just that profile
concentrating that
cbd concentrating that thc in the sense
that a
little can go a very long way now what
are the uses of these concentrates
well the concentrates fail on ct pharma
can be vaporized or combined with flour
vaporizers are available in many forms
such as electronic like an e-rig or
glass versions now when i talked about
earlier that is
important of the kind of paperwork that
goes along with it
and here we're seeing our microbial
analysis heavy metal microtoxin
pesticide all passing those
as well as the terpene and cannabinoid
profile many people will just look at
this
we also have to be mindful of matching
up product descriptions and lot numbers
to also the passing of all of the
microbiology
pesticides microtoxin testing as well
now this
often comes summarized on a label or
should come summarized on a label as we
see here
but it's important here looking at the
label realizing it
understanding what it's showing and also
having access to
or knowing where to find the original
documentation where those numbers came
from
this is just again that combination
there of being an
informed consumer