so you want to grow your cannabis
indoors well what are some
considerations for indoor production of
cannabis
i'm going to go over some of the details
here and if you are considering it
hopefully give you some ideas to think
about if you are growing animals indoors
already
some review of some of the key aspects
you should be having under control
[Music]
all right let's get into the
considerations for indoor cannabis
production
so first off with our indoor environment
the goal should be
quality and not quantity if quantity is
your goal you want to consider an
outdoor operation of a separate video on
that here in debaco
university you also have control over
conditions in the indoor environment so
the goal is to maximize
production remember that there are
different pla environmental
target ranges as the plant grows to
maximize the end product the grower
should make sure
that they're adjusting to those changes
to match the stage
of the plant development you don't want
to keep the temperature always the same
the humidity always the same
from the seedling stage or the clone
stage all the way to the harvest stage
you want to maximize that target range
as that plant grows and develops some of
those are going to start to shift and
change for example humidity
very early on might need higher humidity
and they're going to be decreasing that
as the plant grows and develops
and we're talking about this plant
growing for an indoor environment
it tends to have greater upfront cost so
you want to know what your budget is and
you know that from a very early on so
you can scale your operation
both the initial investment and also the
ongoing cost
consider the electricity to run the
lights just because you spend all your
budget on lighting
well you're gonna have to also supply
that with electricity
also have to supply money to cool that
looking at carbon dioxide enrichment you
know buying the bottles yes buying the
setup great
but then also supplementing with more
carbon dioxide as the growing season
goes on
now a simplified indoor growing kind of
checklist
you want to make sure of your size your
growing area appropriately
have proper monitoring systems growing
substrate containers air circulation and
ventilation such as hvac systems
lighting carbon accident enrichment and
irrigation are just a few things
you want to be making sure you consider
and have a plan for
so we're going to go into those just
briefly here and going to be more videos
on this in more detail well first
off the growing area we're talking about
indoor operation or how big
are we talking to grow tent and grow
tens can be very small to quite large
we're talking just to grow room here we
can see a much larger
area here so what's going to be the size
of your growing operation
also what type of monitoring systems are
you going to be using i'm using a
digital system as we see here or an
analog system again both have their
merits and pros and cons
it'll be more videos on tobacco
university here
to explore some of the details and kind
of weigh some of the advantages and
disadvantages of each of these
now for a growing substrate are you
being are you going to grow in soilless
mix
are you going to choose to grow rock
wall maybe a cocoa car
maybe sand you know there's different
growing substrates again which one are
you going to choose which one's the best
fit
for your operation containers you might
just think good put the plant in well
what are you going to put the plant is
going to be a plastic container is it
going to be a solid wall plastic cleaner
is going to be an air
pot is it going to be a grow bag a fiber
kind of a fabric material to be a
biodegradable one
what's going to be the size of the
container all these are important
considerations
for that air circulation in ventilation
uh what about the horizontal airflow
you see here multiple fans going what
about the vertical airflow
uh the cooling of the lights how are you
going to mount the different
fans and how you're going to make sure
you're maintaining a proper temperature
what type of hvac system you're going to
have
all important considerations the
artificial lighting is you're growing
indoors you don't have the advantage of
the sun you're going to use led lighting
high pressure sodium lighting as you can
see here led high pressure sodium
ceramic metal halide t5 fluorescence
you know what's going to be your chosen
artificial light to use and are going to
necessarily use the sum
same one for the full uh growth cycle of
your canvas plants are going to
transition them from one to another
to another and why would you do that uh
carbonated enrichment
so we're looking at kind of enriching an
area elevating our carbon dioxide levels
what level are we going to chew for
where we're going to place our sensor
how are we going to deliver that we're
going to be some sources of carbon
dioxide
is it going to be a heat source is it
going to be a compressed bottle
what controllers and regulators are we
going to utilize are we going to be able
to use something called fuzzy logic if
we're using a bottle system that would
be advised
different ways or things to consider and
then lastly kind of on our just quick
general checklist provided here
irrigation how we're going to be
supplying water to our plant it can be
hydroponic layers can be hand wadding
we use a certain type of water
purification
you know what are we going to be doing
to help ensure that our plants not only
are receiving water
by receiving quality water and at a
regular basis so that doesn't restrict
their production
so again if you're thinking about indoor
growing or are looking at indoor growing
this provides a quick general overview
but there'll be more videos here on
dabaku university for you to check out
and learn some more of the details of
each of these
best of luck