if you're interested in learning more
about outdoor cannabis production
to come to the right place here i'm
going to go over some of the key aspects
and considerations if you're looking at
growing your cannabis
outdoors here on debaco university
[Music]
all right let's get into some of the
considerations for outdoor cannabis
production
so the outdoor environment in general
can be very challenging there's many
aspects that are out of your control so
be sure to maximize the conditions that
you do
have control over soil evaluation and
modifications
are important or controlled aspects with
outdoor production and this could be in
a field situation
or it can be even in kind of like a soil
in these
fabric pot containers that are growing
in an outdoor environment
be sure you have all the basics covered
you want to know what plant type you're
going to be growing what nutrients
you're going to be using
and how you're going to properly
irrigate the plants
now outdoor growing a scouting is very
important there are many unknown
variables
so be sure to take a look out for
anything that is out of the ordinary
and this can be looking at the soil this
can be looking at after they're planted
scouting for insects getting for
potential for disease also looking at
just the general area what weeds are
growing in
in a particular area there are a lot of
trees a lot of stumps so there's things
to consider rocks for example
all variables that people want to take
into consideration
if you're looking at growing your
cannabis outdoors
now a simplified outdoor growing
checklist and again it can be very
variable and there'll be a plethora of
videos here on this channel
to help cover some of these main topics
so you can learn
about it in more detail we want to do a
general site evaluation you want to like
look at a site and kind of evaluate it
look at the hills look at the area look
at the drainage
prepping the field once you decide on a
site how do you go about that
the plant layout how you're going to
organize your plants properly taking a
soil test
not only properly taking the soil test
but getting that soil test and
results in interpreting that soil test
are important
weed management because they're always
going to be weeds are going to grow and
then
irrigation are all important
considerations when we're looking at the
outdoor environment
now that site evaluation well
identifying the fields section
allocating subsections you need to soil
sample areas
differently are going to be planting one
area earlier than another is there a
change in topography a change in soil
type
all these need to be a part of your site
evaluation
for your cannabis production then it
gets into field prep so potentially
using a cover crop as we see here you
know if you're able to get into the site
early
uh prepping that with having a good root
structure here for cover crop
preparing the biology preparing the soil
structure for your cannabis crop to come
later then i said plant layout you can
see here what's going to be your plant
spacing
what's your plant density per thousand
square feet per acre
what's your row orientation and that
could deal with the kind of the change
in topography of the land the angle of
the sun
different tree lines what's going to be
your seeding rate
and what's going to be your planting
date and are going to use seeds are
going to use clones all important
considerations
now when you're taking a soil test you
want to make sure you're following the
proper methods
for a mineral test and then if you're
taking a june nitrate test
slightly different methods for that so
you want to make sure you're going
through
and reading those protocols ahead of
time and making sure you're
properly sampling the soil for the
intest
that you're going to be sending that
sample out for
now when you get that sample results
back hopefully if you took a good sample
you'll get some field representative or
growers often say quote accurate results
looking at ph organic matter salt
particle size potentially for nitrogen
phosphorus potassium micro nutrients in
cec
cation exchange capacity they'll come
back in a soil test that might look
something like this
so how you go about interpreting the
soil test and what adjustments you make
are going to be important
to ensure that your canvas plants have a
good
start and a good environment to support
their growth
now to want to have good cannabis plants
and good growing cannabis plants
weeds are also going to be a problem
most likely so you want to be sure you
have
in-row weed management as we can see
here with use of black plastic
but also between row management so we're
maximizing the production
of the crop that we intend to grow and
not getting bogged down in
example here with some grass species and
lastly we want to be considerate of
irrigation what type how are we going to
get water to our plants or use a drip
irrigation system
or use an overhead irrigation system we
can't always depend or rely
on the rain great ways with to be have
some method so we can supplement water
if we need to particularly on
a high value crop such as cannabis so
hopefully this didn't scare you away
from any outdoor productions
in the sense that there are a lot of
things that growers need to be aware of
even the outdoor applications
not just to get all the free energy from
the sun is plant and walk away
to maximize that harvest these are
things you need to take into
consideration
and i welcome you to look at other
videos here on tobacco university
so you can educate yourself on all these
different aspects to hopefully
have you avoid some initial mistakes and
maximize your production