okay here we're gonna go a little detail
about controlling co2 levels what we see
in the image here it is an actual
controller brainbox
we see a remote sensor here you see a
power cord all these can work in unison
to help regulate co2 levels in a grow
facility here so what are the co2 levels
while monitoring co2 levels is critical
to maintain an efficient grow operation
no matter the size so is we're talking
it could be a small grow tent it could
be a large room could be even a
warehouse monitoring the co2 levels are
important however it's important to
remember it's one thing to know the co2
levels but it's another thing to do
something about it
so just monitoring didn't know the co2
levels is one step in the right
direction but being able to correct
those or maintain those at a certain
level would be the next step or logical
progression of growers should take so
there's co2 controllers we see the one
pictured here quality co2 controllers
are directly connected to a delivery
system which can offers the greatest
level of control over the co2 levels in
a gross space so they're monitoring and
they're adding or taking on the system
when they need to when the co2 levels
are getting too low and turn off when
it's getting too high these controllers
are the best for maintaining levels of
carbon oxide within a certain or
predetermined range now when you want to
add co2 well so you can benefit the
plant through all stages of growth so
even pretty much it from just beyond
seedling phase all the way to the end it
is beneficial to add co2 however it
should only be added during daylight
hours because this is when the light
reaction of photosynthesis is active and
this is the plant when it's consuming
carbon dioxide so as far as far as
stages of plants go the entire stage of
growth as far as when specifically on a
day to day basis when the light when the
Sun lights out or when the lights are on
is the best time to be dosing carbon
dioxide now when we're looking at dosing
there can be timers or controllers as
options timers are by far less expensive
and they release carbon dioxide at a
consistent predetermined intervals and
durations
this requires calculations and
estimations of plant consumption and a
photocell is advised
only daytime dosing is I'll provide it
we can see that here on this timer here
there's a photocell meaning this will
only activate this repeat cycle timer
when this is getting exposed to light so
that's a good option to have if you're
going with the timer system however they
do tend to lead to kind of estimation
and they can lead to that loss or
wasting of co2 but a little bit better
is controllers they've actually given
current conditions this allows from
adjustments to be made to maximize
efficiency and help ensure co2 levels
are being maintained as a result these
controllers are preferred over those
timers you can see the one pictured here
can work with generators can work with
tank systems has a lot of options that
can be utilized there the controllers
are much preferred over timers now
controllers have you select a max and
minimum and maintain within this range
this is improvement over timers but it
can still lead to wasted co2 by
overshooting the maximum and over the
course of changing conditions so what
you want to look for in a controller
what the best controllers are are ones
that catch something called fuzzy logic
and it's kind of listed right here
looking for controllers are definitely
an advantage over timers and the
preferred controllers are ones that have
this called fuzzy logic mode they help
maintain this kind of efficient levels
of co2 without over or under dosing the
grow facility now have a separate video
on that if you care to learn more about
the fuzzy logic