okay here we're gonna state-controlled
indoor environments for cannabis
production so his indoor environments I
have some pictures here some like
sterilized lab conditions while it may
not necessarily be this extreme in some
cases this is advantageous to reduce the
chance for disease see the advantage of
being an indoor environment you can
control a lot of factors you can also
pack plants in but with this if these
conditions are unclean disease can
spread very rapidly through that area so
controlled indoor environment generally
has no natural sunlight it's kind of a
seal kind of growth chamber it can be
computer-controlled I monitored
especially for larger operations needs
to have good air circulation so anything
about this room and wanna think about it
completely sealed up there needs to be a
good air circulation that does occur
also typically when we're adding air
circulation humidity can become a factor
should be monitored not getting too low
or too high to pay what environment
you're in typically they're good
candidates for adding supplemental
carbon dioxide because they're sealed
because there are so many controls this
is why adding this extra steps is
sometimes deemed to be worth it and
documentation and cleanliness is very
important so in terms basics the grow
room can basically cost as much as you
want to spend at the example here you
know I can go very cheap or you know
really expensive however quality plant
material the lights that you choose to
grow if there's especially if there's no
access to outdoor Sun and the growing
media should be the top priority so what
should you spend your money on well
these are kind of the three main things
the good quality plants to have good
supplemental lights for them and a good
media this is where you should be
spending your money first and then
adding in some other things from that in
general the room should have that
cooling this again is a priority and
that's consistent cleanliness throughout
the entire grow good air circulation
both inside and outside ventilation
reflective wall so you're maximizing
your lights that hopefully are off high
quality temperature control so things
aren't getting out of whack and carbon
filter to eliminate odors especially if
neighbors are a concern on a small scale
to his harvest should be a priority so
I've had one room that changes lights
and conditions with a planting will
limit your total harvest
once every four months or so so girls
always have rooms in different stages so
you're kind of getting into this
continual harvest of plant material not
going into like boom and bust springing
all flowers and then all veg and then
all clones and repeating that cycle
always having some in different stages
in this small scale multiple rooms are
tensile I too have one dedicated to
clone and propagation one vegetative
growth and one flowering the same
concept is used for a larger group
facilities as they use large rooms
dedicated for each of the three
distinctive properties so think of it
like in your house you want to have you
know a baby's room that's kind of your
clothing in your propagation room
vegetative room that's kind of where
you're looking at growing and expanding
and then flowering which is considered
like the Millennium I'm worthy you know
all the work is really done is that
plant goes into flower producers those
very useful cannabinoids lights
determine the gross space so a three
foot by three foot area can effectively
be lit by a 400 watt high intensity
discharge light typically abbreviated
hid and a five by five area requires
though a thousand watt HID light so the
type of light or sizer to use even since
they give either pro a thousand de it's
a double-ended bulb this could light a
five by five very very effectively but
there's other lighting options this is
just an example regardless of the number
of lights can dictate the total square
foot of row in space
so just because you have an area to grow
in if you can't effectively light it you
start to push the styles and want to do
a seven by seven foot area well it's
just not going to be as effective five
by five is the kind of the recommended
maybe pushing it to six by six but much
more than that is not recommended
estimated yield will tolex expected
grams per watt after about two months of
flowering minimal target is about 0.5 to
1 gram per watt example if you're
running a 600 watt light bulb it should
produce about 360 grams of dried buds
this just gives you kind of an idea of
what that error should be using and if
you're using it effectively
air circulation as I mentioned is very
important having stands to move air
within the grow space keep in mind
exchanging air from the outside
environment it's also necessary adding a
carbon fifth filters we see here to
reduce odors is highly recommended so
here air is being drawn through the car
unfilter taking out the odors coming
through the duck tank cooling this light
that's producing a lot of heat and then
going in venting out this is a small
grow tent operation but this same
concept can be scaled up the ceiling
height is a definite consideration you
want a minimum without five feet height
is considered a space needed for the
container of plant that's growing in the
space for the light to end too late you
don't want to cram it too short
especially with the high discharge
lights minimum is usually about five
feet eight or nine foot ceilings are
ideal wherever possible to give you just
more air more availability for cooling
walls of mirrors are not a good idea
this is kind of a misconception
especially in small rooms but want to
reflect the light so I think I should
just put a mirror well these mirrors
current create hot spots they're not the
best choice since they create hot spots
and do not scatter the light well should
be white or have some type of mylar this
is an example that mylar but this
reflective material does is will
increase the lights used efficiency and
eliminate the amount of wasted light
that is you're basically paying for and
this can help disperse that evenly
through the canopy make sure most of the
plant is getting a light even some of
the lower leaves again if you hang
mirrors to promise you get that one kind
of bright not a hot spot there and that
can kind of increase the chance of
burning or damaging a portion of the
plant mylar is a great material tools of
the trade so it's also important have
good just general tools pruning tools of
course for the plants but also just
general tools looking at the setting up
of the process or maintenance of your
room or a small operation even large
operations having that toolboxes
properly find fix and make adjustments
as needed just kind of an odd set of
tools but having it all so well
organized and know where it is you can
easily find it test and monitor before
installing the plants to run all systems
if there's any plans I'm sure everything
is fully operational for at least two
days this is important to the monitor
heat of a mid max thermometer here just
to try to monitor heat sometimes turning
the lights on me to go to law works I'm
gonna save power and then you go to put
the plants in and you overheat the area
adding some water to make sure all
electric systems are safely installed no
circuits are also overloaded
and to make sure if the heaters coming
out our cooling systems coming on the
trout overloading the circuit also light
leaks if you're in small operations
you're not getting that messing up a
photo period as I mentioned temperature
regulation is another important thing to
watch you know shock or kill your price
graph lastly a location Location
Location for both small in a large rooms
location is everything small rooms D
consider proximity to electrical outlets
also for air exchange large operations
need to consider the flour room size and
dynamics as well as the ability have
both propagation in a drying room to
allow for that continual harvest so here
we have outdoor locations there's the
last part they need to give severity
environmental factors that may occur so
all of these no matter what site you're
growing in you should be very familiar
with your general location so that
you're able to maximize it but not
overload it and end up throwing plants
out that you didn't plan for