in this debaco university video i'm
going to be going over the container
types for cannabis production
we see a couple labeled here shown here
in the images
but we're going to go in them in a
little bit more detail giving you some
of the advantages and disadvantages of
each
[Music]
let's get into the video so first off
the goal of all containers
is to hold a growing substrate in an
area where the roots will grow
and develop the type of container
selected can depend on the growing
conditions
and also possible points of transplant
that's planned as the plant grows
where are you going to move this plant
potentially going forward
that can influence potentially your
decision or allow you to make the best
decision
to allow an easing of that process now
starting with the kind of the most
obvious one you're probably most
familiar with and that's plastic
containers the reason why they're
probably most familiar or most obvious
is they're cheap they're easy to get and
they come in a variety of sizes all
great advantages
however some of the downfalls can be the
storage particularly in large scale
production
shipping if you're buying them by the
pallet and then we're looking at just
transporting them to the facility and
also disposal of them
when they're gone through at least one
growth cycle or some are reusing them
uh but disposal when they've kind of
gotten past their shelf life
then we get to air pots which is kind of
like a division of plastic pots to some
extent but we notice that they look very
different
they allow for the air pruning of roots
so they're kind of
allowing or preventing the roots from
getting pop-bound so allowing air to get
in and kind of self-prune those roots
before they come in contact with the
edge of the container
this increases the root branching and
maximizes the use of container area
with roots however the downfall because
there are little holes
here on the sides as well as underneath
is that they can dry out quicker
and growers may need to adjust their
irrigation frequency and or durations
then we get to fabric containers so for
our fabric containers
they store well in small places they're
very easy to move
they can also increase aeration of the
root zone all great
positives however the fabric depending
what fabric you get they can break down
over time particularly if used in
outdoor production
they also can be hard to clean because
that fabric tends to bind and hold onto
things
and the bottoms can rot that's the
bottom of the actual pot because it
usually comes down a container because
it comes from kind of with the surface
that's been growing on it can trap a lot
of moisture in there and as a result it
can cause a rot
of the container itself then lastly we
get to biodegradable containers and the
advantage is that they're
environmentally friendly
they can make transplant very easy just
plant the whole pot container
can also minimize the root disturbance
all great benefits
however the time to break down can vary
depending on the type of biodegradable
pot you select
they can dry out faster do the wicking
of moisture and their costs can be
higher than some of the previous
items mentioned so for all of these
container types if there's one you want
to learn a little bit more about because
you
like the advantages and can dissuade
some of the disadvantages you're welcome
to check out this channel for more
detail
explaining each of these container types