we have been hearing a lot about the
corona virus from a wide variety of
sources but human provide a scientific
investigation related to the corona
virus well where do you get information
you know it's constantly changing the
situation as at least those right now
oz is a great link to a website that
provides you a lot of scientific
articles that maybe a little detailed in
the reading definitely worthwhile and
are staying up-to-date so a great
information center on this novel
coronavirus as the situation develops
now key terms that are used so you'll
hear a lot of terms used here or here
love them in the news epidemic pandemic
and endemic in might things are all
interchangeable and in fact they're not
the the epidemic for example refers to
an increase often sudden in the number
of cases the disease beyond what is
normally expected so as it visually
local of epidemic could be like a region
here showing a lot of signs of disease
Ebola went through an epidemic pandemic
is a worldwide spread of disease and
that's kind of depicted here where you
see it's showing up all over other
regions
yes localized in certain areas but
overall spread over the world in an
endemic first a constant presence or
prevalence of a disease so here you can
see it's not necessary a large cluster
which is kind of showing up all over us
is kind of nice visual representation of
how these three terms differ in addition
we have pathogen sed virulence and
mutation so path of pathogenicity and
virulence comparing those two S's offers
a good comparison looking at the ability
for ism to cause disease and virulence
is the relative capacity of a pathogen
to overcome body defenses this is kind
of how virulent is a disease that means
how likely is it to infect you and cause
a problem notation is simply a change in
DNA sequence which leads to a change in
proteins so it brings us to what's a
virus that means about the corona virus
well do we know what a virus is well
virus isn't infective agent to the
consists of nucleic acid molecule in a
protein coat they're very small cannot
be seen as a traditional light
microscope and they multiply within a
living host so we see here the viruses
finding the living host cause the host
to mass
by itself and then release many more
particles that seem viral DNA is being
injected into a cell and kind of
overrides the cells natural machinery
and we say the term viruses with the all
genic consist of but they could have
very different shapes here as we can see
here so viruses is a category but it not
there's many subcategories so why are
viruses hard to control well the answers
are continually changing and healing
mutating Crona virus have frequent
mutations and recombination events are
constantly going through changes in the
hopes that they'll become better fit for
the environment for the virus and we
hope to try to create conditions that
will reduce their fitness pre of studies
have shown that on SARS has mutated over
the 2002-2004 epidemic to better bind to
cell their receptors this is shows
here's a example of a virus going
through a mutation that would cause it
to be better fit new environment here
would be less fit for America see the
change in genes over time and at letter
C be the most fit a would be one of the
least fits here but again they're
constantly changing which makes them
difficult to pinpoint and control and
again at the bottom of all these slides
where I've used them tried to provide
examples here of the links of sources
that I've used as well as in the
description there's information as well
so national human fear viruses well it's
based on history the Spanish flu caused
by the h1n1 influenza virus affected 500
million people almost a third of the
world population and killed 25 to 50
million people
so again viruses we hear that term and
naturally there's a fear because of what
history has shown us so let's just take
the flu for an example here looking at
the CDC estimates that between 9 million
and 45 million illnesses Kurds in the
flu 140 to 810 hospitalizations and
12,000 61 thousand deaths since 2010
sozin back at the last couple of years
it varies a year-to-year we could see a
lot more illnesses less hospitalizations
and luckily less deaths the case
fatality rate is 0.05 percent that means
that's the percentage of people that do
die
from the influenza flu and the ro Valley
which we'll talk about later is 1.3 so
just remember these numbers we'll see
how they compare but this is just for
regular influenza a common cold that
typically spreads in the winter time
every year now take a better look at the
corona virus so getting to corona virus
well there's corona viruses yes and I
put the s here with a question mark
because it's not just one type of virus
that's named for a family of viruses
mirrors SARS and now corona virus all
fall into this same category
all three of these originating dots
which is kind of interesting
well general similar shapes also they're
all in the corona virus category now the
corona virus itself is kind of zoomed in
look it's named for the crown like
spikes on the surface and a group of
viruses that cause a significant
percentage of all common colds and human
adult's and children around the world so
again this is a classification of corona
viruses this is a general family and
they are known to cause diseases in
humans I provided with some of these
specific names here and as well as the
links at the bottom of the page now what
is known about the corona virus at least
currently well looking at the current
burgeoning
along china human human transmission is
typically via droplets or direct contact
and the incubation period can be as long
as 24 days with the immediate incubation
bearing about six point four days
ranging from 2.1 11.1 days two point
five is to 72 97.5 percentile what does
that mean well if we take things that's
here we're looking at the vast majority
of cases here this area represented here
and here would be that 2.1 to 11.1 days
24 days seems to be kind of the longest
chance and that's based on the sources
provided here at the bottom but to put
111 point is typical incubation period
being as long as at least one case 24
days epidemiology so we're looking at
here it is occurring as it's highly
contagious with within about two hours
survival time within the air all age
groups are cysts I've told to the virus
the very young to the very old elder
patient
with two chronic conditions at the same
time are more likely to experience
severe illness this is just common that
if an immune systems already compromised
are already bailed in one disease I
think it's infected with another is more
likely to cause death or more serious
effects because of the multiplication
here we could see just another example
here it's not just for coronavirus
looking at arthritis in heart disease
diabetes in being obese now detailed
replication the chromosome necklace got
a ton of time on this which you can see
here's a very detailed sequence of steps
just even the idea of the complexities
of a virus and I lived up buying the
cells transfer their own DNA kind of
invade the cells natural machinery cause
that cell to mass multiply the virus
particles and export those particles to
the outside of the cells so they can go
through and check other cells so again
pretty complex process this is why a
viruses can be difficult to control it's
not just as easy is killing them there's
really nothing to kill simply because
you have that protein coat in DNA
they're not living breathing necessarily
particles now reproduction number this
is the auro factor here looking at
little comparison gene earned by r-not
and it refers to viral transmissibility
so how many people's one person likely
to infect the epidemiology definition of
ro is the average number of people who
will catch a disease from one contagious
person this applies to a population so
if you have an R nought of 2 and you
have the patient zero they look at two
people each of them can then go for it
and in fact about two people SARS has an
iron out of four and you can see how
this one down here can quickly multiply
in a much greater rate this is why we
take those are not values into
consideration now potential spread or
decline of disease what does these are
not to refer to well if it's less than
one each existing that catches causes
causes less than one new infection if
it's less than one in this case if we
just think about this logically the
disease will decline and eventually be
non-existent if our naught equals one
the disease will stay alive but there
won't be an epidemic I mean one person
will usually pass
to one person where diseases that get a
little bit of concern here is how much
greater is it than one this will cause
the disease to grow exponentially
potentially it cause an epidemic or even
a pandemic then the higher the number
here the more people that can spread you
could see weasels here's 11 to 18
he's one infectious person will likely
infect 11 to 18 people
now the ARRA value for the corona virus
here from what's currently now in the
calculator are not value of Kona vast is
severely greater than one
this isn't it be concerned the
preliminary are not estimate is between
1.4 and 2.5 was presented at the World
Health Organization statement and the
information here on January 23rd year
2020 in information here at the bottom
the case fatality rates about 3% it
means all of all those infected 3
percent typically result in that
fatality in the RNAP value of one point
four to two point five this is all great
numbers but how does this compare to
other diseases so if you look here at
the kind of the comparison to diseases
over on the side here we see the piece
of fatality rate so this is in
percentage so that coronavirus three
percent will die well compared to SARS
ten percent
MERS would be 40 percent avian flu forty
percent could be some really high values
here we also see some lower values as
well and they are not values entered
Crona one point for potentially as high
as five point five
I could see years here at a less than
one
avian flu less than one so these have a
very high fatality rate but very low to
transmit so again the corona not they
say the highest to be transmitted and
that the highest case fatality rate even
though it's being tucked up in the news
and it's spreading like crazy and
killing everyone look at the data here
and put it a little bit in perspective
HIV if untreated 80% I'm here without
therapy so again that case would tell
you much much higher so again something
to consider here at least put it in
perspective
so we're looking at a higher pathogen
destiny trends tends to have lower
transmissibility so look at the
influenza virus
the pandemic of h1n1 virus caused
relatively mild disease became endemic
in the population the found two
receptors in the upper respiratory tract
compared to h7n9 virus have a telomere
actually 40 percent very high and you
can go back and take a look at this and
has so far results of only a few small
clusters of human-to-human transmission
and that specifically bound receptors in
the lower respiratory tract
another example is measles virus and the
virus have strong transmissibility but
low mortality rate i'm so again kind of
get this trade-off of very high
mortality rate but very low to be
transmitted so it's kind of interesting
to see this trend occur again resource
there at the bottom so pathogenicity in
transmissibility of the corona virus
currently seems to have relatively low
pathogen pathogenicity and a moderate
transmissibility so here's a comparison
here of some other viruses here you can
pause the slide take a look at that also
welcomed and encouraged to look at some
of the resources here that I pulled this
information from and it just tries to
put it in perspective so just kind of
that reality check here the CDC Centers
for Disease Control's and World Health
Organization are working on addressing
the issue and providing updates your
goal is to inform yourself we'll be
cautious of new sources getting
resources from scientific papers may not
be the easiest it gets away from
opinions and catchy headlines kind of
these white papers are great to get some
data and some information rather than
just reading the flashy headline and
jumping to a conclusion and also keep
the situation in perspective have the
example here if someone looks here and
sees number six and someone over here
she's the number nine put in perspective
h1n1 had a very similar progression and
people are not too afraid of something
that has a potential to cause death
which viruses do but again how severe is
this you know what precautions are being
taken
well precautions can you take this isn't
something that's very very high
mortality rate percentage-wise so
working together as long as transmission
of the virus from one person to another
could be substantially inconsistent
interrupted if we could get through
means of isolating people and get that
are valid
are not valuing less than one it's
entirely possible as outbreak could be
controlled or even eradicated going
forward however this requires a joint
efforts of the entire society just as an
example polio was very high we could see
how those numbers crashed through a
cooperative effort in this has to be a
worldwide cooperative effort
lastly the importance is education so
educating the communities that
strengthen public confidence well this
would be important and that's hopefully
why you're watching this video here did
provide yourself with some education
crisis with some resources so you can
approach this from more of a scientific
and at a headline format so you can be
an important person and
inform others with quality information