okay here I'm gonna go over the correct
cordial chemical interactions sorry I
can come up with another hard seat here
but this is leaving the chemical safety
for you in general so step one protect
yourself personal protection is
important
most the time goggles are required but
depending on what you're working with
gloves may also be needed lab coats are
advised that was working continually
within the lab to limit exposure to
chemicals again can be we were dealing
with serious cases you can see here we
have the PPE personal protection
equipment completely sealed sometimes
you'll see sign is using these lab coats
gloves are required
depayne what you're working with they
don't seem too happy in general but
depending again what you're working with
will dictate what you need to wear and
those would be covered with you in the
lab also know that'll on the hazmat
diamond can be advantageous its intend
to find a quick universal labeling of
materials now you may see this on other
places is you're traveling around this
kind of diamond-shaped key take-home
message I mean after them all the
details of it these four colorations
four if you see any fours that's reason
for concern because they're health
hazard and be deadly flash points would
be very low in radioactivity or
reactivity be very high here so we're
looking at again different ways we can
easily look at any chemical and have a
general idea what might be in their
areas that natural gas also have this
because it's potential explosives and it
is hazardous the white area may have
nothing in it or it may have these
various markers to help identify what
might be in there so again just a quick
reference point universally accepted and
gives you just a good idea of what's
what's in that particular storage area
now the chemical the SPS or the safety
sheet safety data sheet it should say
these can be found for any chemical
substance including everyday items so
you can look up just about anything on
the internet look for SDS sheets and
you're able to find first-aid recommend
for it firefighting accidental release
the healing and the storage of that
offer just about any product that you do
by
label containers that you use of this
prize to being in lab when you're using
chemicals in the lab be sure to label
containers to avoid confusion
just simple marker you put a piece of
tape and label it I want to be clear
whether it's poisonous or concerning or
if it's food items so just having an
idea because clear liquids look like
water and a lot of people assume it's
water it could be a whole host of things
or what could be dissolved in that water
could clearly make it fall into one
category or another so it's important to
label that to avoid confusion and also
to avoid mistakes made in the lab for
you and the grounds around you know the
proper method of disposal so for each
chemical and resulting mixtures know how
to properly dispose of it the solid
waste organic solvents all these would
be clearly states beginning of lab I
stress here the chemical and also the
resulting mixtures sometimes you can
have too benign chemicals chemicals that
you know are pretty much unreactive when
you mix them that can create a substance
that needs to be disposed of in a proper
manner in the other way you can have two
sometimes more dangerous chemicals and
mix them together and develop a
substance that is not as harmful so just
know how to dispose of it so you're able
to put that in the right area you're not
causing potential contamination of not
only the experiment but groundwater or
the sewer system
when in doubt lastly when in doubt just
ask reader here and ask question look it
up asked a teacher so always good to
when you're in doubt just ask the
question and be able to direct you in
the right way to avoid any potential mix
health or hazards to you or those around
you