here on this tobacco university video
the procedures for the counting calories
lab will be covered
[Music]
okay so here we go over the basics of
the calculating calories lab for food
what we're looking at here is our setup
we have a ring
a ring stand with a ring on it we have
an aluminum can with some nails in it to
help support it in addition we have a
thermometer
we have a wooden skewer we have some
weight boats we have a food item to be
testing
we have a balance we have some matches
and we have a graduated cylinder so we
can precisely measure 50 milliliters of
water
we may also want to add a timer to this
setup so i'm going to go through the
basic instructions here
okay so now our next step is going to
involve putting the water here in our
can
so i'm going to go through
add our water right to the can that way
and then we're going to take the
temperature of that water taking our 50
milliliters of water and adding it to
our can right there
now how do we get the initial mass of
our food item well we take a weigh boat
we put it on our balance we make sure we
let it kind of settle out we tear the
balance
and we put our food item in in this case
it's going to be a marshmallow
here we're going to take our reading at
0.86
grams so that's it
0.85 grams so now we've got that we're
going to take our food item
take our wooden skewer and very
carefully
we want to be able to go through and
attach that right there
okay that's what we're going to use for
our next step now we just added the
water in our can we're going to take our
thermometer making sure not to keep it
at the bottom of the can to make sure
we're getting the temperature of only
the water there
so i'll put at the bottom and just raise
it up just a little bit and then we're
going to take a reading in this case our
reading is right around
22.4 degrees celsius so 22.4 degrees
celsius
that'll be our reading there
now comes the fun part so we're going to
grab our matches here make sure you're
weighing your safety goggles we have our
food item we're going to be looking at
placing that approximately
oh about that far under the can one
which we're not contacting the key in
our turn out too far we want it close
but we still want an ability for oxygen
to get in there to create an efficient
burn so i'm going to leave that down
there for a second we should also be if
we have another person be easier to time
how long this burns for so we take our
match
we light our match and remember the
hottest part of the flame is kind of
towards the top so we want to be using
that to help kind of get our marshmallow
here to catch on fire
and kind of want to rotate it through
blow that out keeping our food item lit
and you can see right here that nice
burn that we're getting
if it does fall you try to grab it again
and
and try to rotate it as best as possible
different food items i have a little
little issue there
and you could hear that the flame just
went out so i'm going to take this
marshmallow now that's burnt
grab a wave up put it in there be
careful that metal part of the skewer is
going to be quite hot
kick that off and it gets a little
sticky on the inside
i'll get that up there then before we
weigh that we want to make sure we're
getting the temperature of our water
relatively quickly
so we go through and now we're going to
assess the temperature of the water
[Laughter]
temperature water has gone up as would
be expected to
27.3 degrees celsius 27.3 degrees
celsius and keep in mind you don't want
the very bottom of the can at the bottom
just lift up that little bit so you're
getting the temperature of the water
itself
then we're going to come back over so we
got to get the mass of that food item so
i put an empty weight boat here we're
going to zero that out
take our burnt food item
put that in there and now we're going to
have a mass of only
0.60
grams our next food item on the wooden
skewer
i've got my matches ready to go we're
going to look at trying to time this as
well
so i go through i light my match
and remember we want to keep it at that
higher point in the match that's where
the flame is the hottest
work it back and forth
we'll slowly rotate it
and keep it just under that can there
again rotate so as much of a burn as
possible out of it
you can see all that carbon buildup on
the aluminum can
you don't want it right you want to
allow a little bit of a gap there to be
able to allow some oxygen for those
flames to go
you can see this is burning much longer
than our other item
that goes it's about completely burnt
out
it's gonna be a little bit of smoke left
you want to let that cool just for a
little bit
get our weibo
and kind of make sure it's not too too
hot
usually they cool down pretty quick
we're going to watch the metal
kick that there
we can get that weight in a moment
that's not going to change too much as
we're going to go through and get our
temperature of our water
and in comparison to when it started
while this one did have a longer burn
time we're now looking at 42.9
degrees celsius
so that's kind of that nice evaluation
there in the change so hopefully this
gives you a little bit of a basic idea
of how to run the cal the geometry lab
and looking at burning food and being
able to now take this data that we've
collected with the temperature change of
the water and to be able to go through
some math calculations to determine how
much energy was in various food items
now you can repeat this with many
different food items you're not just
limited to what i've shown you here the
wood skewers a good idea to be able to
support it safely
so keep in mind that this is a great
setup and you should also be doing
repeated trials because what would be
different masses for your food it should
all come out in the math because of the
calculations you're doing but always
good to have repeated trials it's fun to
think about too if you have a collection
of snacks which food and do you think
has the most energy to be able to go
through and compare to see if your
hypothesis or your prediction was
correct