there are many options when it comes to
cover crops and supporting plants
growing in the field on this tobacco
University video we're going to go out
and see how this CBG gurus do both their
cover cropping method as well as their
plant
[Music]
support all right so a lot of options
out there but let's take a look and see
one example here how a hemp grower in
Southern New England handles this so
first off who are these CBG gurus well
they are built around the belief of
producing a premium Quality Craft hemp
product they've with the manufacturer of
stability alignment and alignment with
nature they use uh wood chips uh
basically on the ground there to really
help improve soil quality and structure
and they also Implement many of the
Korean natural farming methods as well
in combination with modern science Sean
and Jacob have been great uh to kind of
work with and allow me into their field
I give you their contact information as
well as their website to take a look at
which will also be in the description in
addition to kind of the uh CBG groups
who they are some things we're going to
discuss in this particular video is
going to be the cover crops so while
different areas can have different uh
cover crop uh ideal cover crops to
utilize this is a great resource there
to give you um many different options
we'll see a couple mentioned today but
this is a great resource also um to take
a look at there if you're interested in
cover cropping uh fields and lastly the
plant support system that they utilize
they use trellis netting they simply
take trellis netting and mount it
horizontally kind of use a modified
screen of green method with the key to
basically make this system work is
really the heavyduty metal stakes that
they use on the ends and throughout the
field to really give that some support
there so hopefully you find this
information useful and interesting and
here we go out to the
field okay so what we see here is a very
unique cover cropping system not only do
we have um mulch here wood chips
essentially to protect the ground from
moisture loss and weeds we also see
integrated cover crops as well now we
have a diversified group of cover crops
so we've got oats here which you know
we're getting into Late July early
August and you know they're kind of
going by the wayside and they're being
cut down uh with a weed whacker also
have daon radishes as we can see right
here and something else unique has kind
of an interplanting we're noticing sweet
potatoes uh they're nice low growing
they're not really competing we can
clearly see the cannabis plants growing
up and then we've got our nice cover
crop here that's giving our soil
diversity that's giving a great way to
kind of get something established give
something back to the soil and then very
easy to manage from the grower
standpoint so both of those features
make it really nice to have this kind of
system working
together
so here we see the row uh it's just been
weed whacked and we can kind of see that
wood chip mulch there at the ground can
also see what an easy knockdown it is
for those selected cover crops now
here's a daon radish a little late here
in the summer but we can see one
actively growing right there can also
see remnants of past um crops as well
daon radishes as well as some old
potatoes all of this is giving this area
diversity and we're not really tilling
the soil here in this example
so that's giving everything kind of set
in place those oats go go down really
nice uh obliterate really well and you
can see we're left with this nice
walking path this is also going to
suppress soil Splash we can see drip
irrigation if needed and we also see The
netting here and that's allowing us to
kind of have this support for the plants
metal stakes are strongly advised
because they are so strong against the
winds and doing a couple layer system as
we see with some of the mother plants uh
allows us to kind of hold those plants
in place hold those uh in their
respective areas and then not worry
about it now if we do get a wind event
when the plants are below this netting
well they're usually too small to be too
harmed by it this is only about 2 and
1/2 ft up um so once they get to that
and start working their way through
that's when they need the support and
that's when they will get it with the
first layer of the
screening
now it's good enough to do once it's
good enough to do many times we can see
that nice replication here of the rows
of this nice screening nice TRS netting
it's pretty taut so that's going to hold
it very level it's going to allow us to
allow those plants to grow up it you can
see here second tier ready to go plants
just coming through that first tier this
is a great way to be very efficient with
your time and really to focus on one row
now to help the Growers also planting
the same Variety in each can allow you
to manage those well within each row in
different rows different varieties
different slight um different care that
they may need but keeping the same
Variety in the row or at least most of
the row will really help you go through
and be able to be efficient with what
you're setting up metal stakes again
very much uh advised we have taller
plants shorter plants older plants uh
seeing a nice little mix keeping Good
Records so we know kind of what works
and then hopefully repeat what works
next year on a larger scale now here
we're able to see our mother plants and
we're seeing three tier system of the
screen yeah space pretty evenly to give
those plants support we also have metal
stakes here um to really provide the
entire structure support CU it is on the
end here in case there's a wind event
see this plants grow right up through it
very well we got a couple just starting
to poke through the second layer we
already have the third layer in place
reason why you want that third layer in
place is you don't want have to be
worrying about it set it all up once if
you know the plants are going to get big
set it all up at the same time you have
to worry about it and you can spend more
time training those plants up through
it