okay there's gonna be a quick overview
of cover crops which are simply living
carpets it's an example of a cover crop
it's a crop that's grown to cover and
protect the soil so what does some of
the pros and cons to cover crop so the
pros is you get soil stabilization soil
rotation get different root structures
in there new treatment holding you can
attract beneficial and insects
particularly buckwheat's good at doin
this and the cons I really don't know if
any if you find out anything let me know
some growers may complain there might be
a little hard to deal with depending
what your groom other than that there's
a lot of benefits to these that I don't
really know too many negatives the
selection process is important and in
part it's season dependent and then when
you want to grow the cover crop easier
over the winter or during the summer if
you're resting in the area winter in New
England is most limiting because of our
simple lack of warm temperatures to grow
any sort of crop blends get a lot of
attention I say I want to do a blend in
there as well how many do you want in
there on there's basically three
classifications despite all the
different species
there's grasses there's legumes which
you shouldn't aq8 in some way and the
brassicas provided a link here you can
click on this screen and in the
description you'll find a link to the
lecture slides and also the sources for
all the images I welcome to click on
here it's produced by NRCS and they do a
pretty good job of summarizing some of
the cover crops but to give you just a
quick idea on New England standards for
the wintertime
winterreise name implies it can
germinate basically any temperature
above 32 degrees Fahrenheit any
temperature below freezing it can
germinate it'll be slow but it can
germinate hairy vetch is another option
the one here
it's great at fixing nitrogen but it
fixes most of its nitrogen just before
flowering late in the growth cycle when
we see the purple flowers that's the
sign it's fixing as much nitrogen as
possible and you want to go through kill
it other why it becomes like rope and
can wrap around your equipment so it is
a vine it can be an issue but if you
kill the right time there should be no
problems
winter I can get very tall and confirm
rates at very low temperatures typically
seed in the late fall on both of these
will our winter hardy will survive harsh
New England winters in the summer
never looking at resting an area we have
issues we can't get into a field and
want to rest that for the summer we have
buckwheat or Sudan grass to be two great
options both week was really quick but
be careful can reseed itself when you
see the white flowers here this is again
a sign you want to come through and kill
it some why does attract beneficial
insects you're kind of playing the line
there how long do you keep it up to keep
the insects in the area or risk the
chance of it receding now it has receded
at least in the situations that I have
seen it hasn't been really that
aggressive so it's not a major concern
Sudan grass grows very tall you need a
special equipment to manage it properly
think of this is like corn without the
ear hears it looks like here looks like
corn they can get really tall six feet
even taller and it can get really thick
and be difficult to deal with if you
don't have specialized equipment kind of
be able to get in there or I get down
beat it up pretty good mow it down you
wanted to make sure you have something
or plan for to have something if you do
plan on growing that other's red clover
tillage radish red clover is great
really low don't fix nitrogen tillage
radish getting a lot of attention to
kind of break up heavy compacted soil if
you do use tillage radish should be
careful don't over seat it with too much
other than the recommendation says
because when these do go to rot they can
produce quite the odor so being mindful
of your neighbors in that case keep the
plantings it is a pretty small planting
per acre
as far as seeds go keep it low don't
over add because they will they can
produce quite theater again when they do
go to rot after they perform their job
you're busting into thick soil should
you fertilize your cover crop the simple
answer
no I gave no and a bunch of different
languages here in fact if your cover
crop does not look a little deficient
odds are you may have over fertilize in
season anyway so your cover crop does
not necessary dark green that's a sign
you may have over added nutrients in
season but should you actually fertilize
it no let it grow it can actually show
you where some good or poor errors might
be in your field lastly consider cover
crops
in season two under seed under senior
cash crop at the same time
yeah clover this is a grass mix under
some corn here so it is possible to
actually have a living carpet under your
potential cash crop again depending what
it is clover confused in walkways or
lower growing crops your grass could be
used for kind of another grass corn just
a way to help stabilize soil and reduce
weed pressure again in certain cases