okay here i want to provide a systematic
data-driven review concerning kobit 19
in schools now all sources provided
on each slide it is mentioned with
direct links also in the video
description there is a link to the
slides for easy viewing and downloading
it'll allow you access to those links
the basic summaries are children are at
reduced risk from dying from covid19
children are poor transmitters of the
virus and do not just read the headlines
look at the actual data
and research studies high coveted areas
tend to match high
population areas as well and we'll see a
map of that
now destin covid 19 related to age
well equivalent 19 does increase
directly with age what this means is the
older you
are the higher risk of death from
covid19
you have under the age of 14
and really potentially under the age of
24 the odds of death from influenza or
pneumonia are greater than
covid19 and what pneumonia is is
basically
fluid filling the air space in the lungs
reducing amount of oxygen that can get
to the blood
and if the oxygen becomes too low that
will result in death
here's just a kind of combination of
leading causes of death in general
broken apart by different age groups
this provides not just diseases but
other causes of death based on 2016 data
with the higher causes of death being
located at the top
lower ones at the bottom influence it
pneumonia in kind of these orange boxes
and covid19 in the blue boxes there
this is the actual cdc data website that
you can
provided here at this link that you can
go to and access
what it is i took this data i was able
to download it as an excel file
and this is what i generated directly
from that data set we just saw
this just makes it a little easier to
read and it's looking at february 1st
august 8th for the united states broken
apart by age group
allocating coven 19 deaths pneumonia
influenza in total
i then took this data and compiled from
the age of 0 to 14
and put the cova death pneumonia in
influenza deaths for comparison between
the ages of 25 to 24.
and in both of these age groups is your
typical school age
children pneumonia is of greater risk of
death for people under
24 years old based on the cdc data
looking here at uh data from the
american academy of pediatrics
they stated at this time it appears that
severe illnesses due to coven 19 is rare
among children
and they have some information current
as of august 13
2020 here what is interesting of note is
that children were
zero percent to 0.4 percent of all covet
19 deaths
and 20 states reported zero child deaths
taking this information um the
definition of a child
does vary by state so it makes it a
little hard to do some comparisons
however the greatest age range for the
definition of a child is tennessee in
south carolina
and they state from between 0 and 20
years old is a child
however using the cdc data that i showed
i'm going to
add in from 0 to 24 and consider that a
child
which technically is going to overstate
cases or deaths but it's going to be
used for the comparison here
well the cumulative child cases is four
hundred and six thousand
one hundred and nine total child deaths
and again i'm dividing the child is from
zero to twenty four
would be two hundred and ninety one the
child mortality percentage is
zero 0.07166
and if we look at the united states
cases versus mortality percentage
based on john hopkins university
presented by cnn
you're looking at that math comes out to
3.135 percent
so you can see the child mortality
percentage is much reduced
now what about risk to teachers since we
are talking about schools
for those that have to work with
students and the concern is the ability
to
contract copin 19 from students while
the students may be at low risk of cover
what about students ability to transmit
the virus that's a great question
the possibility of carriers and at-risk
populations comes down to the degree of
transmissibility children have been
shown to be poor
transmitters of covid19 and we're
looking at the data provided here and
source down here
what does this data actually show so to
what extent do children transmit the
covid19 virus that's a great question
the evidence to date suggests children
spread
sars coveted v2 which is the copen19
virus relatively rarely
and that children are usually infected
by symptomatic
or presymptomatic adults in the first 48
hours
before they become symptomatic in
conclusion based on the study here
the available evidence to date suggests
that children are unlikely to be major
transmitters of sars
cov2 or the coronavirus this causes
causes covid 19. and again there's the
citation the links and everything
provided there for you
so what about an article like this that
was uh in
in the news if you're at this age you're
most likely to infect loved ones with
coven 19 and i provided
the kind of quotation here from this
article
what is they quote the emerging
infectious diseases and i went to that
source and you can see that here
so up at the top here is the link
provided to the best life article and
then down here is the link to the actual
study
well the age groups and this is the data
table too their age groups are
consistent every nine years which is
great to see if you look at the numbers
of contexts in which the percentages are
calculated from because this study is
focusing on percents
well in the 10 to 19 age group it's
based on 231
participants however the next age group
up the 20
to 29 age group is based on 3 3417
participants
so while it's great to compare
percentages does this really make a fair
comparison when there's a
14.79 fold increase in participants
between the two
age groups this is why it's important
again to look at the data
instead of just quoting percentages
where did those numbers come from
and what could be contributing to why
children are such poor transmitters
so we mentioned before they're poor
transmitters well why would this be
what's the potential explanation for
this
and some highlights here provided in
this study are that
asymptomatic non-coughing people realist
release less virus
loaded aerosols to begin with children
have less
alveoli and terminal bronchioles where
breast droplets are formed
and those are interior components of the
lung we kind of see them here they look
like
a cluster of grapes and they create a
high surface area to allow gas exchange
but children have less of them children
also have lower respiratory
minute volume and tend to have lower
viral loads
all this combined can explain why
children are poor covid19
virus spreaders now
when we're looking at confirmed cova-19
cases in the united states we often see
maps that look like
this and while maps like this look clean
and are easy to read
the stage borders are man made however
this isn't easy recognizable
and doesn't and does trans translate the
state by state data into a visual very
easily
however a more accurate description than
this we're looking at actual borders and
uh changes would be something that looks
more like this
and what this is is above me is the
tracking of covid
um 19 cases in the united states you see
all the bubbles
uh the bigger the bubble the more cases
but we also see in comparison i pulled
the 2016 u.s population
we see a lot of similarities indicating
that where we're finding a lot of
coveted cases are simply where there's a
lot of population
if we pick one area out in particular
the hawaiian island
of wahoo we're looking at the increased
population
well sure enough of comparison to the
other hawaiian islands
it has increased coven 19 cases so again
just take this into comparison when
you're looking at
states that look like this for example
montana looks really
large here as it's a very large area in
state
but relatively low population compared
to
other areas such as california or the
northeast where states might be small
but very population dense
in the united states people are living
longer and this is a positive but in
regards to coven 19 it does mean more
people
will be in the increased risk category
we see the demographics here of male and
female in the shift over time
comparing the census data from the year
2000 to 2010.
now if you look at desk by cause in the
world in 2017
i'm not going to bore you with all the
details here but you can see clearly
cardiovascular diseases is number one
respiratory disease is very high and
that concludes
and breaks out lower respiratory
infections as well
being very high normally and cova 19
falls into that category
of being a respiratory disease so
they're naturally high
and this is looking again at 2017 data
what's interesting of note is malaria
over 619 000 deaths in the world in
2017. now probably didn't hear a lot
about this
particularly the united states because
there's only about five deaths reported
annually in the united states mostly
from return travelers
with only about 1 500 cases so it's
important to remember we have to think
about things in a worldwide perspective
and if there's things that can be
resources that can be applied to
potentially cure
or definitely reduce the risk or death
rate of certain issues
that is definitely something that should
be considered keep in mind that malaria
is a mosquito-borne disease caused by a
parasite
so a little different than covid19 but
again we must be thinking
about more than just one single country
we must be looking at the entire world
and where can we try to make reductions
in
causes of death