okay in this video on tobacco university
we're going to be looking at crime scene
processing or at least a general
overview
of the how you would process a crime
scene
so starting with the processing scene
main objectives well the first is always
safety
i want to be sure be maintaining a safe
conditions no matter what the scene is
and that's going to vary depending on
what scene you may approach or what
scene you might be investigating also
the degree of knowledge of your
understanding of what's going on at the
scene
regardless you want to make sure you're
securing the scene
in some cases you might want to be
keeping a safer distance if we have for
example here
a car on fire otherwise you want to
prevent people from entering or exiting
a scene because it's going to include
just more variability potentially for
the data that you're going to collect
you want to maintain that protection of
the scene you just wanted to secure it
but you also have someone kind of
out looking to make sure no one is
unwillingly entering
that scene your next job should go
through in photography
to look at documenting the scene with
images making a sketch
particularly for talking seeing where
there might be a body located
want to be sure you're taking notes and
taking pretty well detailed notes as
well collecting labeling and packaging
any evidence you come across
and then ultimately you'll be writing a
report for this
so when we're looking at that safety in
particular that safety being first
we're looking at each scene is unique so
be attended and keep in mind of your own
safety obvious things such as glass and
sharp objects but there can also be
trip hazards unstable objects and you're
not sure exactly what you're entering
so always make sure you're maintaining
your own security and safety
so you don't become a part of the scene
yourself then you want to secure that
crime scene so as i said
the first officer at the crime scene is
responsible for securing and protecting
the area using the crime scene tape and
other physical barriers
the victim is alive medics should be
called and they would be allowed to
enter the scene of course
the goal is not to compromise the
evidence in any way that's why you're
securing and locking down that area
if a witness or witnesses are present
make sure
they do not leave the scenes you want to
get their report before they go off
and are lost potentially because they
can be great sources
of information when you're protecting
that scene this is a very important
step anyone who enters the scene has a
potential to destroy physical evidence
often damage may be unintentional so
keep that in mind that someone might
dance in the scene to intentionally do
anything
but unintentionally they can do a lot of
damage to the evidence collection
process
everyone should be excluded from the
scene including police officers not
directly involved in the process of the
site or
investigation that investigator that
maine crime scene investigator has
only a limited amount of time to work
and must complete the falling of the
crime scene
must be taking photographs providing a
sketch making notes collecting
document and packaging evidence so it's
a lot to do
and it always seems like there's never
enough time to get it done
when you're taking photographs you want
to make sure that there's of the
unaltered scene because objects must
remain untouched until photographed
if evidence has been removed or moved it
must be
mentioned in the actual report you can't
just have that
kind of having moving things and then
assuming that's where it was originally
found that should be evidence and noted
in the report process any proof of the
crime scene was compromised would cause
the evidence to be admissible in court
that's really the main thing you're
trying to protect and make sure all the
evidence you're collecting is able to be
used in court
now crime scene photography basics so
some of the
basics for photography there are other
videos mentioning them in more detail
investigators should be thought of
taking care of photographs in all areas
where the crime took place
and likely entry and exit points
remember to include
different angles and as you can see here
in the images included we see the eiffel
tower
presented at different angles it's
important to have establishing medium
range close-up and macroscopic
photographs if you're interested in
learning more about those there's a
specific video
on that all images should include a
ruler as a size reference to help
establish the general size of the
objects that's being documented
now the sketch basics so after
photographs are taken a sketch of the
crime scene should be generated
on a scene a rough sketch will be made
after leaving the scene
part of the processing phase is
developing a finished or final sketch
that is precise recreation of the scene
but while you're there you won't at
least want to get a rough sketch in
all sketches remember we'll need a
legend showing where certain items the
crime scene are located and also
indicating
where north is as well be sure you
include that in all sketches
general requirements looking at sketches
well of course you need to have a title
a legend for any abbreviations or
symbols that are used
compass direction showing at least the
northern direction
a scale and documentation with at least
location date and time
in the creator's name so make sure these
are also present in any sketches
created here are some just general
sketch examples just to give you an idea
of the legend and how things may be
oriented
always want to be sure that you're
documenting some of the important pieces
of evidence that might be found
entry points exit points uh distances so
these are all very important things to
be documenting and including
on the sketch here now remember we
should be taking notes as well
and these notes should include the
location of the crime scene the date and
time of notification and
information received and who it was from
the time of your arrival in your
departure
scene details will be more on the next
slide and a description of the victim
in names of the investigation team again
it's a lot to kind of take in in a very
short period of time so this is why
having an idea what you need to include
and making sure you're getting all this
in a relatively
efficient manner is very important
so lastly looking here at the detailed
description of the scene
well in this example we're looking at
this is of particular importance for
physical evidence
at the scene and for each item the
following should be documented you want
to make sure you're getting the time of
discovery
who discovered it how it was packaged
and labeled in a description of that
item because these will likely be need
to refer
to as further investigations are being
conducted
to better tell the story of what
happened at the crime scene