in this video at tobacco university
we're going to be looking at crime scene
overall processing protocol kind of that
overview
on how you go about processing a crime
scene
so starting with the investigation
investigation involves and always
involves that lecard's exchange
principle the fact that
something is always leaving that trace
and it's our goal
here as investigators to try to find
those trace evidence
keep in mind we don't want to overthink
things sometimes we want to use simple
logic to help direct our investigation
we want to use the scientific method
as well as far as going through the
problem-solving process and as always we
want to stay
organized organized so that we can refer
back to
notes refer back to diagrams photos
pictures
evidence collected so that we can find
answers
to questions that may be asked shortly
after or
a long term after the initial
investigation had taken place
we're looking at the diagram here just
kind of an example of problem solving
and if we give you the weights of these
objects in three different areas
can we calculate the weight kilograms of
the two cucumbers alone
so we're looking at forensic
investigation techniques
we want to look at recognition which is
that surveying the scene
document observations collecting
evidence then we have identification
which is the comparison to what is out
of the norm well it doesn't look
right then of our individualization
which is the evaluate and interpret
process
and then the last we have the
reconstruction which is involving the
report
and presenting of findings to kind of
reconstruct what we think
may have occurred based on all of the
previous collection of evidence and
organization of that evidence
now how to go about this well step one
is interview i want to interview the
first officer at the scene
or the victim to determine what
allegedly might have happened
ask what the crime took place and how
the crime was committed
um no however this information may not
be factual but it's intended to provide
investigator a starting place
it doesn't mean just because you
interviewed someone who is there you
take their word as 100
correct but it does allow to provide you
a starting place
then you can lead that can help you lead
and help the
examination phase or identify possible
evidence
select a point of entry and a point of
exit develop a general layout of the
crime scene
so all these can be very important in an
examination process and again that first
step of that interview
can help you at least initially plan and
organize
how you're going to go about the
examination step
then we look at documentation so this is
very important you want to create
photographic records and a rough sketch
of the crime scene
identify the exact position of deceased
victim and other evidence within
the crime scene this can be a very time
consuming and tedious process
but it is vitally important not to keep
things
organized but to also ensure that
anything you collect
is also upholds in court as evidence
and lastly here we're looking at the
processing step
so this applies to both physical and
testimonial evidence
technicians are responsible for
identifying evaluating collecting
physical evidence from the crime scene
as this will be further analyzed in the
crime
scene laboratory so this processing
point so we're collecting some more of
that specific
data and we may not be doing this for
every piece of data collected but based
on
kind of what we think may have happened
or what kind of events we're looking at
that can help guide the process where
that time is going to be spent
as we're looking at kind of recreating
what may have occurred
at the particular crime scene we're
investigating