so in this tobacco university video
we're going to be looking at crime scene
classification
and a couple examples as well as how we
would classify
certain crimes given some information so
first off we want to think about what
types of crimes are there whether it's
homicides burglary sexual assault and
there's drug offenses
and there's many more these are just a
couple examples
we can see here a list of types of crime
the frequency and percentage that they
occur so some definitely
more common such as burglary definitely
much more common
than some of the other ones listed here
but still we have to take all these
into consideration and know how to
handle these we're not sure what crime
scene we're going to be coming up
to when we're doing an investigation
so also looking at crime scenes we're
also looking at how age could play a
factor
some crimes simply are more likely to be
committed by certain age groups
so this is where it doesn't give us an
idea of
you know what individual committed what
crime but it can
increase the odds of when we identify an
individual or identify a crime
what age group might we be looking at as
far as increased odds based on the
information here in the data
to look at who we might be looking for a
potential suspect
then we have our physical locations so
keep in mind that we have
indoor locations we have outdoor
locations we can have car or vehicle
locations so all these
have their own challenges so we must
take these all into consideration be
able to handle any of these because
sometimes we even have
multiple physical locations involved
now a victim's location specifically
well we're looking at a primary crime
scene because this is
the original location of the crime but
they mentioned they could also be
secondary crime scenes and this is kind
of an alternate location
where additional evidence may be found a
body could have been murdered at one
place and transported to another
so keep in mind that just because we're
observing one particular crime scene
we might be thinking about the potential
for there to be another crime
scene that may also need to be
investigated
we can look at the size of the scene in
general so keep in mind that there can
be everything from
the macroscopic down to the microscopic
so
a macroscopic scene contains many
microscopic scenes within it
the macroscopic is basically where the
body is found in the field a gunshot to
a victim something we can see very
easily
microscopic has traced evidence such as
a gunshot residue trier treadmarks
or the whole host of trace evidence that
we could be looking at
investigating so keep in mind that we
want to be mindful and
of the large scale items but also don't
forget about the small scale items as
well
now when we're classifying a scene so
here's just a
one example where thieves break into a
jewelry store jewelry is taken the
suspect gets in a getaway car
and the stolen goods are taken to their
apartment again how would you classify
this scene this is kind of like example
a so if you want to think about this
pause the video here and
think about this the answer will be
revealed on the next slide
so looking at the scene how do we
classify it well with the information
presented here
we'd be looking at be a robbery it'd be
the type of crime it'd be located
indoors
primary scene would be the julius door
but we also have the secondary
scene of the themes getaway car and also
their apartment
so again this is just how we would
classify the example of that scene
provided there
as exhibit a for exhibit
b here looking at this scenario a man
was strangled
in his home the perpetrators used the
man's fan to transport the body and dump
it in a nearby
lake how do we go about the
classification of this scene as exhibit
b
pause the video here before i reveal the
answers
so looking here at our exhibit b how do
we classify this scene well with the
information presented
here's what we'd be looking at the type
of crime would be a homicide
the physical location or locations would
be both indoors and
outdoors the primaries seem to be the
indoor the home of the victim who is
stabbed or shot by the offender and is
in this case
strangled our secondary scene the
outdoors since this would involve the
van and the point at the lake where the
victim was dumped it would be considered
a secondary crime scene
so this just gives a brief example of
how we'd be comparing
and classifying two different examples
of
crime scenes