okay here in this debaco university
video we're gonna be looking at the
crime scene search methods we have a
couple pictured here
to give you a general idea of the
pattern you should be going through
but we're gonna look at this in a little
bit more detail so first off when
conducting a search
it's the whole point of conducting the
search is for evidence this must be
thorough and systematic
you do not want to make assumptions you
want to consider any permanent evidence
and do not overlook little details
because failure to do so can lead to
accusations and negligence or
covering up evidence so we don't want to
kind of like look up
up here we don't assume there's just
three because we look on kind of
the other side over here it looks like
there's four we want to be tried it
impartial but also
thorough systematic and detail oriented
now field evidence technicians are the
person responsible for conducting the
evidence search
they're mainly looking for fingerprints
footprints tool marks hairs fibers and
also possible trace evidence
carriers as well this should also be
photographed in the crime scene
documented because this is a really
important part
especially depending on the scene this
searching for evidence is
a critical part for any scene now before
the search can even begin before we even
get to that stage of looking for that
evidence
we want to ensure this scene is
controlled this
it also includes briefing all searchers
involved established
speed and areas of responsibility so
everyone kind of has a game plan going
in or hopefully a limited number of
people but so
even those that are in there so no one
interferes with anyone else's area and
they're searching
i want to determine a starting point you
want to establish a command post
you want to maintain communication
between all people involved
just to insert as anything comes up that
everyone is aware
i want to rotate people through areas to
ensure more than one person looks at
each area to reduce the chance that a
detail is missed
everyone's going to probably miss some
little detail we don't have a ton of
people going in there
but having someone go through and do a
second sweep of an area is definitely
well advised
now these search patterns so exactly how
you're going to search a room
well there's something called a spiral
search method and this starts at an
outer point and gradually moves
toward the center we're going to start
at an inner point and move outward
from that center as we kind of see the
images here
so depending on the room depending on
the area depending on the scene may
influence what type of search method you
use but this is
one example and this is called a spiral
search here
now moving on from a spiral search we
also have a grid method
so the grid method scene is divided into
grid and each grid is
segmented in the search just as the name
implies you have this kind of very boxy
like look
and you're searching and focusing on
those different boxes within that
overall grid
then we get to a line search which is
crime scene divided into strips
and each strip is searched again this
could be based on limiting factors
this is just another search pattern that
can be used
line or parallel search here
then we get into what we call a zone
search and this is a quadrant or zone
search
kind of has a similar properties to the
grid method but in this case
the scene is divided into quadrants in
each quadrant is searched so it's a
little bit broader based here
this is again more important documenting
where north is involved to know
where the zones are actually located in
a room and what evidence might be found
in those areas or how that room might be
set up can influence whether this one is
selected
the search pattern selection so as i
said kind of those are the general
overview but how we actually go about
selecting or determining which one we're
going to use is important
that can come down to the size type of
location of the area it's an
indoor location or is it an outdoor
location
how big is it if it's an indoor compared
to an outdoor there's a lot of trees in
the outdoors and open park
things to consider also the personnel
and equipment how many people do you
have
what equipment is needed and what do you
have access to you know we all like to
have the ideal amount but
a lot of times we're limited and
restricted so that's going to influence
what search we may
select the type of crime that was
committed if we can establish that or
have an idea of that early on
this can impact the type of evidence
that's going to be collected
and that can also influence how what
pattern you choose
so you can be most effective now
evidence from the victim
themselves well this may be collected by
a medical examiner
evidence often includes from the actual
victim would be fiber from their
clothing hair from their head
in pubic areas blood hand swabs for
gunpowder if that was
suspected to be part of the crime and
also photographs
so this is a lot of information just
from the victim
never mind the surrounding area as well
so just keep these in mind and we're
kind of going through and establish and
search a crime scene
to be effective and efficient because it
is
only a one-time shot at getting that
evidence undisturbed