here I'm going to go over a gene editing
technique giving a lot of popularity in
the scientific community called CRISPR
so CRISPR the basics of it is that it's
a gene editing method that exists in
living organisms the organs that it
exists in are it's a simplified
antiviral defense system found in
bacteria scientists have been able to
identify this and are now using this for
gene editing of many different cells
other than just bacteria CRISPR allows
for cells genome to be cut at
predetermined locations it's very
specific which is probably why it's
getting popularity and that result in
the removal or the addition of specific
genes so it's specific and it allows for
modification of their genes by either
addition or removal
now CRISPR stands for clustered
regularly interspaced short palindromic
repeats so try to highlight the words
here clustered is this kind of a
grouping regulates a defined pattern
interspace is just a distance between
objects it's small and short distances
so it's looking for a very short
sequence palindromic that's a sequence
that reads the same backwards as it does
for words such as mom or dad or
something a little more complex like
race car who spell the letters out
forwards and backwards you'll get this
same word remember though DNA will
always read in the 5 to 3 prime
direction and the last letter R stands
for repeats this occurs again in this
same form kind of like the post here so
a lot of times I hear CRISPR referred to
as CRISPR cast 9 the reason why that is
is that cast 9 is an enzyme that can cut
DNA so CRISPR cast 9 the complex allows
to the removal or addition of specific
genes which is great the possibility of
the Acosta 9 nucleus remember those
three letters ace can imply an enzyme in
this case it does this is a complex it's
created with guide RNA so the cassadine
in this image is kind of like the blue
areas that you see in the guide RNA is
kind of the green areas here and you'll
see that through some of the other
images in this presentation so this
guide RNA this G RNA guide RNAs
sequences that will bind to the DNA
sequence to be edited it's often
abbreviated
guide RNA as G little G RNA or single
guide RNAs G RNA this guide RNA is
non-coding too short RNA sequence that
will bind the complementary DNA sequence
we see the double helix double strand of
DNA here and here it's binding 5 to 3
prime this sequence which is the reason
CRISPR can be so specific looking for
these specific nucleotides that guide
RNA RNA is encased and wrapped here in
the caste 9 enzyme now the basic process
of CRISPR is first scientists have to
identify target DNA sequences so in the
genome that could be a gene that needs
modification it could be a disease
whatever gene is being identified first
by scientists then it has to be
identified so that guide RNA can be
created so that the complement of the
DNA sequence is very specific it's a
very short region so we identify the
gene and then it makes the complement
RNA for the guide RNA then the guide RNA
and the cassadine are attached to form
this complex and then this complex will
then be inserted into target cells as it
goes through target cells that will go
through and read other DNA in this case
we're reading that chromosome
and once sequence is found the DNA will
be cleaved I have a picture of a cleaver
here or nice kind of cutting it's gonna
cut that DNA whence it cuts that DNA
that can allow for the addition or
deletion of nucleotides to occur at that
specific region now the advantage of
CRISPR is some the possibilities it can
silence genes you can alter
disease-causing genes into a healthy one
there's just kind of an example here if
some diseases have been identified on
different chromosomes so once they're
identified if we get the sequence CRISPR
could possibly be used to alter the
disease-causing gene into a healthy one
not only to the benefit of the
individual but their offspring and
lineage can also be used specifically
insert a codon could be a stop codon
offer a particular amino acid into a
sequence it can also change or alter
gene expression silenced them or up
regulating them other than editing genes
CRISPR can also activate the
transcription process
remember transcription is DNA to RNA how
that's done is through the deactivation
the cast night cleaning abilities
meaning that in this case the cast night
will not be able to break or cut in any
way so it's just able to go through and
activate the transcription process can
also repress or silenced genes you would
see as a repressor blocking certain
genes from being expressed and the last
one here adding a fluorescent label to
visually identify physical locations of
DNA sequences this could be important
where we're identifying and then it's
going to add a little label this can
allow scientists to know the physical
location of certain genes so that they
can aid in development of a 3d model the
genome in tracking the chromosome
movement so that's another reason why
this degree of being able to
specifically identify certain regions
here visually marking them can be
advantageous to scientists in addition
we have to remember that when we're
modifying genes there's also the
potential for social concerns should
human genomes be altered in somatic
cells or embryos is a controversial
issue no matter how it's done and CRISPR
is just some of the latest technology to
offer this
what if undetectable off-target effects
occur they have not been studied
comprehensively what potential negative
impacts could that have well this could
change the human genome through a
generation in after generation even
cause disastrous consequences so the
thing about if you modify all the
genetics of a lineage or generation now
even if you don't do it in the future
those modifications will be passed on so
these cause worries included related to
mental health social behaviors designing
human capabilities such as intelligence
appearance personality vision eye color
a whole bunch of different things so
there's just social and ethical concerns
with this technology because it is
genetic modification there's also been
some research down in over in the UK
that shown reported some unwanted
results of CRISPR so while CRISPR is
often used to generate small deletions
as shown in that so it shows here
scientists have seen unintended large
deletions when I say larger docking
several
thousand nucleotides long in addition to
complicated DNA arrangements of distant
sequences being stitched together these
are all things not intended but can
occur so it must be mindful especially
we're looking at human gene editing this
phenomenon was prevalent and all the
three types of cells tested including a
kind of human gross cell in the
laboratory so again something just
weren't in caution and this is a
relatively new technology it needs to
community be studied so we don't have
any of these unwanted edits now with
CRISPR one that's been used in a
positive note is what's called precision
guided sterile inset the technique
kind of a long term there researchers
have developed a new way to control and
suppress populations of insects
potentially including those that ravage
our cultural crops and transmit deadly
diseases
insects can mass produce different are
selected species so by controlling their
populations that can be advantageous and
instead of spraying a pesticide that you
kill all insects this could be very
targeted the precision guides sterile
inset technique the P gsit alters key
genes that control insect sex
determination and fertility so how could
this possibly be used to control and st.
populations well when we take these
precision guided sterile insect
technique what will happen is we'll take
eggs and I'll introduce to target
populations where only adult sterile
males will emerge this results in a
novel environmentally-friendly and
relatively low-cost method of
controlling pest populations in the
future this is also very specific and
the screwworm fly was the first pest
successfully eliminated from an era
through sterile insect technique by the
use of this integrated area-wide
approach so it's not looking at spraying
some sort of chemical at me into the
environment this is using CRISPR to
specifically target this particular
species of fly create sterile males and
really reduce it and hopefully
potentially eliminate them from the
population lastly because this is such a
new technology so is looking at some
sources here and also some additional
YouTube views that you're welcome to
take a look at you're interested in
learning more about CRISPR