something that's typically thought of
more in outdoor growing operations is
crop consulting
however within the cannabis industry
this can also apply to indoor growing as
well
so stay tuned in this tobacco university
video to learn just more about this
potential job opportunity
[Music]
all right let's get into crop consulting
in the cannabis industry remember this
is applicable both to indoor
as well as outdoor growing environments
so first off the job description
consultants assist growers
the selection of plant material and can
offer what may work best
for the growers given conditions this
typically involves field-based
evaluations of growing practices in
season
but can also be applied to indoor
growing operations as well
as far as maybe ceiling height or area
as can be taken into consideration and
suggestions can be made as far as
what plants or what varieties what
cultivars might be the best selection
to choose to fit that particular
environment
the day-to-day activities of a crop
consultant address patient
concerns and questions regarding the
challenges that may be seeing currently
in the growing environment so if we're
seeing like a really windy area
or an area that floods easily you know
timing your plantings maybe going with
autoflowers
suggestions that way provide product
expertise and knowledge to growers by
offering suggestions
to help alleviate current issues that
may be observed
maintain privacy and confidentiality of
sensitive information because some of
this information might be
kind of kind of that developed
particularly an indoor growing
that might have certain patents
protecting it or things like that so
maintaining that confidentiality
accurately entering all providing data
such as soil tests yields
irrigation to help develop a
personalized plan of action
for that particular grower now qualities
a person must have looking at crop
consulting crop consulting in general
positive attitude and strong work ethic
because you do have to go out and
usually visit a lot of different farms
can hail the weather extremes while out
in the field during the entire year the
cold the hot the rain
the humidity the lack of humidity all
those need to be into consideration
familiarity with their state's medical
marijuana program and laws to know
what's legal what can be advised
to the people growing extensive
knowledge on the different strains
available and the conditions they may
prefer
some strains is good knowledge to have
to be able to pass on potential growers
ability to recognize signs of potential
problems in the future to mitigate those
or minimize their
total negative effect now the connection
in general to the cannabis industry
is that cannabis consultants are a
direct link between the growers
and their crop being able to recognize
current and potential problems and offer
corrective measures is very important in
addition being
available to growers to ensure potential
sudden problems that may not have been
foreseen
can be addressed when timing may be key
to control
is an issue and this could be based on
quick email photograph
something to offer that grower that
might be seeing a problem developing
very quickly
to hopefully get them ahead of that
potential issue and reduce the total
negative impact
so again crop consulting typically
thought of as an outdoor growing
environment with cannabis
can also be applicable to an indoor
environment as well