now while this image shows the curing
process for wine wine bottles the same
can be applied to cannabis on how the
importance of this curing process is for
the final determination of the end
product so blood should be placed in
seeable airtight container canning jars
are commonly used but watch out for a
light and when I have a curing process
to be a very dark and heavily shaded
process the full curing process may take
up to about two weeks and this is the
final step in the curing of cannabis so
be mindful of the containers and things
that you're using this is kind of like
the last step here as I said carrying
jars are very commonly used I'll carry
in containers typically have a light
block so you don't wanna do something
that's clear if you're gonna be storing
it where there is gonna be some light
exposure they do make some light block
containers as we see here in this file
otherwise you keep them in the dark
location and you'll be fine now the key
component is that it's airtight and many
growers are adding to a community
control packs typically the goal is 62%
humidity for cannabis curing now this
but that a humidity control is a two-way
control path this is commonly used for
humidity control reason why it's to
two-way meaning it offers the advantage
of increasing or decreasing the humidity
level to try to maintain at 62% as close
as it can put here within reason because
if it's extremely wet or extremely dry
this can only do so much but that
two-way control is trying to maintain as
close to that 62% you maybe as possible
maybe they're adding humidity or taking
it away from the sealed environment that
we have here in this canning jar now the
importance of media control during the
caring is that you want to retain those
terpene levels increase the shelf life
maintain the quality and reduce the
chance of mold forming in the buds goals
through proper humidity control and
proper drying proper growing process you
can end up with a premium quality bud
here that has all the high cannabinoids
and shows the true end product of the
plant in your growing ability