welcome to this tobacco university video
here i'm going to go over the cut and
stick method of
cannabis cloning and hopefully some tips
and tricks
to make sure if you're trying this
method you are successful at it
[Music]
all right let's get into the cut and
stick method for cannabis cloning
well first off we want to make sure we
have the necessary materials
to be successful so with cloning or
vegetative propagation in general
healthy mother or stock plant is
important regardless
of what method we're using definitely
for this method as well we want to have
a growing substrate we want to have a
rooting hormone
method of labeling and documentation in
a favorable propagation environment
so that growing substrate can be
variable some people will choose oasis
some people choose root riots some
people choose rock wool some people
choose sands people who choose
stairless media all of those can work
rooting hormones to the example here of
clonex there's many other different
types of reading hormone all of them
tend to fall into the category of the
plant hormone auxin
and then proper method of labeling and
documentation so here we see the labels
labeling the clones we also want to have
a backup for that
no excuse to be taking clones and forget
which one was which
have redundancies within your system and
also a favorable propagation
environment to encourage those clones
that are going through a stressful time
to go through and root well so they can
be transferred to the next step
now what does the environment look like
well here's just some examples here of
getting into what the
kind of environment you should be
shooting for or aiming for your targets
so first off your temperature 78 to 82
degrees fahrenheit
or 25 to 28 degrees celsius moisture
level around 90 percent
relative humidity at least to start and
you want to be decreasing that as
the clones are progressing and then
light levels 200 to 350
par reading approximately diffused light
is fine because they are going through
kind of that stress
typically i do not recommend cutting the
leaf tips i like to remain
keep the leaf tips there it actually can
help increase the odds of your routing
success
another video on that on this channel
but here we can see just the general
conditions now for 90
how do you know you're approaching 90
percent well if you're using humidity
dome there should be moisture on
that dome now that substrate that i had
mentioned
when i take the cutting that's about six
to ten inches long you can go shorter
but that's a good kind of healthy clown
especially if you're starting out
then you want to apply a ridding hormone
and then you literally stick it into the
media that's where this gets its name
the cut
and the stick method now i said that
humidity dome
you could use a large humidity dome over
entire tray or you could simply invert a
clear cup here
to increase the humidity around that
clone particularly on the early on
portion of the routing process so
hopefully this
if you're looking at propagating canvas
clones vertically with this
cut and stick method hopefully this
provides you with some basic information
to increase your odds of success