here we're gonna investigate the plant
hormones cytokinin
now as the image shows here it's two
cells dividing remember this process is
called cytokinesis so it's no surprise
and cytokinins are involved with cell
division so the main functions of
cytokine is well the first one is of
course promoting that cell division to
occur now cell division remembers
mitosis in that process so it's attic
items create more cell division or more
mitosis we know that more mitosis and
more cell divisions simply mean more
cells and more cells relates to plant
growth so cytokines are involved in
plant growth in addition to cell
division they also are responsible for
viral blood development so remember
along our strategy of these lateral buds
instead of cams will cause that to be
able to grow outward at that node along
the stem the last main function of
cytokinins is delays in essence what
senescence is is when leaves basically
age and develop and drop off the plant
so they can delay that process from
occurring that can keep leaves on plants
more useful and on the plant school
longer so the first one instead of canes
promotes cell division well cytokines
were actually first shown to stimulate
cell division looking at a root tip here
that's an area where there's a lot of
mitosis going on a lot of cell division
a lot of cytokinins that plant hormones
exist very high in this particular
region of the plant also germinating
seeds sedatives can be found in this as
reminders cytokinins said a Kinesis
sound very similar and that can help you
remember that a set of kinds are
involved in cell division so the kinds
increase lateral blood formations we see
here are lateral buds kind of branching
out set of kinds are involved in that
they've released buds from apical
dominance remember from the auxin video
lecture and talked about apical
dominance we see auxins instead of chi
minh's kind of play off one another when
auxins are in high concentration we see
routing on shoots we see root callus
forming as we're reducing our aux-in
levels were increasing our state of
chitin levels here we see exhilarate
buds developing society is responsible
for those lateral buds to form
that's in evidence that set of hands are
in higher proportion than auxins because
auxins are going to favor that apical
dominance so again you could see another
example here of how two hormones
interact with one another
keep in mind that these hormones to
exist in very small amounts but they can
have very large impacts on clan
behaviour saticons delay leaf senescence
called the Fountain of Youth hormone so
by delaying or even beaver seeing this
process plant leaves could maintain
their chlorophyll longer could delay the
protein degradation and increase the
lifespan and drought tolerance of
several plant species we see that here a
play that's been apply the cytokinins
keeps the leaves greener longer instead
of this plant here that has these dead
dried out leaves this is important here
in tobacco plants especially here in
Connecticut grow a lot of tobacco for
final wrappers for cigars and the goal
is to keep those leaves as useful and as
large as possible
we don't want plants going in to
senescence here and where they get kind
of crinkly and dried out they're not
really any good for the wrappers of
cigars by applying the set of cuttings
in some cases this could be a way the
Fountain of Youth hormone to keep the
leaves nice young and useful for a
longer period of time lastly this is
demonstrating cytokinins and induced
nutrient movement so we have three
different plants here dicots and it
could be squash seedlings for example
and we're having a cytokine and treated
leaf that shows the presence of a radio
labeled tagging amino acid which is
transferred from the untreated site but
tagged leaf site so what this actually
means here is we have three plants and
we've applied a tag the amino acid here
on these leaves will notice here we that
tagged amino acid remains in this leaf
this has been frayed with just a
surfactant which is basically a carrier
to put in water this indicates that
those radioactive labeled amino acid
stayed here here we applied the
radioactive amino acid also to this leaf
but we treated this other leaf on the
opposite side with acetic iDEN we notice
that basically moved
or call those nutrients / move those
radioactively labeled amino acids over
to the sleep Evan Bayh the dark green
color here just as a Chuck we applied
the radioactive amino acid in the set of
canons here we notice that they stayed
in that leaf so this shows the influence
that cytokines can have on calling over
certain nutrients in indicating that
cellular division
let's get an increased cellular division
that's probably require more nutrients
and that's part of the reason why set of
cones can influence plant behavior in a
sense of allocation of certain nutrients
hopefully that was helpful in explaining
a little bit about the Adept
cytokine it's going to have on plants