on this tobacco university video i'm
going to go over the daily light
integral
typically abbreviated dli in relation to
cannabis yield
so now they will be discussing this as
far as defining it
i'll also provide you with some
information on how you can calculate it
for your grow area
[Music]
all right let's learn a little bit more
about the daily light integral
so first off what is it well the daily
light integral or
dli represents
or describes the total number of
photosynthetically active photons in the
400 to 700 nanometers or par range
that are delivered to a specific area
over a 24-hour period
for outdoor locations this will be
seasoned and weather dependent
and for indoor locations it can more
easily be calculated by simply knowing
the light's output
in the hours that the lights spend in
the on position
again for our outdoor locations a little
bit more of confusion
in the sense that knowing what season
knowing what location
knowing where or what degree of latitude
can also impact this
uh so we've got to take into account a
little bit more
for calculating this for an outdoor
location now when we're going through
that calculation
process dli is the sum of the
per second ppfd that's both
synthetically photon
flux density measurements during the 24
hour period
if the photosynthetic light intensity
remains constant as with artificial
lighting units for a defined
time period which is a duration then the
dli can easily be calculated because you
have your lights on for a certain period
of time
producing this amount of ppfd it makes
the calculation step
fairly easy outdoor locations as i said
more complicated and require more
data collection over a period of time
however the end result can be the same
we see this kind of calculation of our
dli which is the ppfd times
the minutes or hours and times the
seconds
to get times the photo period and then
divide it by this 1 million micro
moles per mole to get to kind of
calculate a dli
but i'll be going through this and
giving you a easy
math equation so you can apply it to
your own situation
so when we're looking again at the
outdoor location the ppfd
in micro moles per meter squared per
second
the range is zero to 2000 and that would
be
no light to full sunlight so full
sunlight would be that 2000
but remember that sunlight is subjected
to continual variability due to clouds
passing by
and here we see the time of day at every
10 minute interval taking a reading we
can see a cloud definitely came by here
and we could see getting closer to
sunset here as the angle of the sun is
changing
for artificial lighting 500 micromoles
per meter square per second should be
considered the absolute minimum
to ensure when you're growing indoors
you want to be at least
510 really want to be higher than that
so what's how does ppfd versus dli
what's kind of the comparison here
well for ppfd it's the rate of photons
per second
way to think about it is how fast is it
raining per second is it kind of a light
little drizzle or is it a downpour
dli would be the sum of photons in a day
and that would be like asking the
question
how much did it rain today what's the
total so this is how we can compare
these kind of point in time readings oh
it's rating a little it's raining a lot
to kind of oh how much rain did we get
today that's how we compare
ppfd versus dli
now when we're looking at the target dli
daily light integral
this can vary with the stage of plant
development however if a grower is able
to keep all other plant requirements at
the optimum
dli can be increased above the suggested
levels to maximize production
overall yes you want to probably have a
little bit less light on your clones or
newly emerged seedlings
and increase that as it goes on but if
you think about an outdoor plant
as soon as that thing germinates you're
getting right into that full amount of
sun
so um we want to make sure we're
reducing the stresses on those
uh plants but we want to maximize
production you use these kind of as a
minimum we can always increase them more
again assuming
you have all other plant requirements at
optimum
for outdoor perspective on our dli here
we kind of see a little bit of a kind of
comparison here of the different months
note that summer full sundays dla can
reach
60 moles per meter squared per day the
image shows the amount of light received
across the united states each month
during fall and winter latitude has a
strong influence on dli again
higher up you are versus the closer the
equator will
greatly impact dli so keep that in mind
that you do have these variables
particularly when growing outdoors or
growing in a greenhouse where you're
dependent on some of the naturals on as
well
now i said there would be calculations
on helping you here's
an example of one so a plant receiving 1
micromoles per meter squared per second
for 20 hours will have a dli
of how much that's the question so the
answer is 72 moles
per meter squared per day so keep in
mind that we're running
uh lights we're going to keep this
indoors to keep it a little bit easier
at 1 000 micromoles per meter
squared per second for 20 hours so we
start with the output 1000
micromoles per meter per second we're
looking at
converting this to hours so we have this
many seconds in an hour
so we're able to cross our units out
there then we want to convert our micro
moles to moles
so we get at this rate we're producing
3.6 moles
per meter squared per hour so we take
that 3.6 moles
per meter squared per hour and want to
convert that to
the days of the moles per day because
we're running one day is 20 hours
so here's our moles we have 20 hours in
one day that's allowing us to cancel the
hours
out so we're simply left with 72 moles
per meter squared per day
so again how do we go about this we take
our output
and all right we need our output and we
need our time that they were run
here's our output we go through and we
calculate this
and then we go through we take that 3.6
moles per meter squared
we are running it for 20 hours so that
plant
will have received 72 moles per meter
squared per day
let's look at another example for
running that same thousand micromoles
per second but now only for a 12 hour
day or a flower cycle how does this
change and of course it would be less as
we expect and the answer
is 43.2 moles so we have our output
in micromoles per meter squared per
second we want to convert this to moles
per hour essentially we go through these
calculations we're still producing the
same 3.6 moles
per meter squared per hour if we flip
that for just one second we notice that
the output
is the same per hour 3.6 moles 3.6 moles
so how do we get this smaller number
well remember we're only running this
for 12 hours
so we take our 3.6 moles per meter
squared per hour multiplied now by a day
is defined as 12 hours
and that's how we get the 43.2 moles
per meter squared per day for a dli
now how does this light intensity relate
to cannabis production so we want to go
back and circle back okay
we've got our dli calculated is that
good bad or indifferent so at a certain
point in order for plants to take
advantage of higher
intensities of light there needs to be
carbon dioxide supplementation
if light is increased beyond this amount
the co2 becomes a limiting factor and
plants will not be able to use
extra light levels making it a waste to
produce typically for indoor situation
you're paying for this light so you want
to make sure it's efficient the
threshold for optimum growth and
photosynthesis
is a dli of 65 moles per day
kind of see this kind of like kind of
leveling off error bars here
are at the 95 commons interval for each
treatment we see our dli we see our
yield here
looking at different cannabis strains so
again keep that in mind we go through
and calculate that's great
do a little comparison really looking at
that threshold of optimum being 65 per
day
so light intensity during veg stage of
cannabis
production so since vegetative phases
can have some
variability do the grow duration of
light to dark to the maximums are
provided below here
notice that if you have lights that
produce less intensity they need to be
run for a longer duration while this is
possible in the vegetative stage
the light duration is fixed in flower so
you want to make sure you're getting
high quality lights to particularly
allow you to maximize that flower time
light dark schedule
in ppfd recommendation without co2
enrichment
looking if you're running a 24-hour day
i give some examples here to try to
reach that 65 moles per day
we better have lights that are producing
at least 752
micro moles per meter squared per second
if wearing an 18 6 schedule
you want to be at 900 micro moles and
still you're going to be closer that 65
but you're only still going to be
producing
58 moles per day to the plant for a
flowering photo period comparison that
12 12 hour schedule
at 900 here we're producing 58 well if
we're only doing a 12 hour day
now we're only going to have a dli of 39
moles so keep that in mind
the light dark schedule and ppfd
recommendations with co2 enrichment
to reach that target of that 65 moles
per day if you're running lights for 24
hours you only need a light that would
produce 752 micromoles
for if you're running at 18.6 you could
want a light that's producing
just over a thousand micro moles and for
the flowering photo period we need a
light producing 1505 micro moles per
meter squared per second
so again keep that in mind know what
light intensity you're producing light
intensity during flower phase of
cannabis production
so that flowering phases said that
critical flower phase
since it's defined only as a 12 hour of
a continuous light duration
remains the same what is variable is the
intensity which
impacts the light so we're running for
12 hours
that's a constant the minimum light
level ppfd of at least 510
micro moles per meter squared per second
optimum range without co2 enrichment
would be a ppfd of 800 to 1000 because
remember without co2 max intensity that
plants can use is no higher than 900
micromoles per second squared so you're
kind of like limited
capped at that level however if you are
enriching with your row area with co2
ppfd of 1000 to 1500 plus
micromoles per meter squared per second
can be used
does not seem to be a saturation point
even up to 1 800 micromoles per second
so you can theoretically go even higher
than that keep in mind natural sun would
be 2 000 so anything higher than that
probably not going to get from indoor
lighting or really at that point and
probably be excessive
so you're trying to determine where that
light saturation point is
and yes you could give your plants here
1500 if without co2
but you're going to be wasting that
light because the plants are not able to
utilize it because in that situation
they would be carbon dioxide limited so
here's just a general quick little
summary reference chart
looking at the hours run looking at the
ppfd produced
and then kind of trying to get an idea
of the dli is a quick little comparison
here
just to give you some idea and this
darker red region here would be over
that 40.
again we're shooting for that kind of 60
65-ish range
so the information presented here i want
to thank a couple people
just to go through and if you're
interested in this and want to have
do some more further research i
recommend you kind of search up some of
these names
you might find some very interesting
publications very interesting articles
some very interesting research and data
presented to help you make again
informed positions
and ask good questions and to be able to
understand
this lighting to help you maximize your
plant's yield