this is gonna be a short video here
because a lot of growers will ask well
yeah I check my plants every day but
what should I be looking for
since the daily grow space checklist and
something just as a good starting point
to consider so great slide to print out
here for just a general idea of what to
look for in all the various conditions
one a monitoring is very important so a
more monitoring everything many
different aspects to be checking up on
when I operate maximum efficiency when
everything comes together kind of all
systems go your plan should take off
just like the shuttle here so for air
ventilation and circulation why don't
you all the fans are working are the
blades and cages clean so initially
everything starts off nice and clean but
they tend to accumulate some dust some
other particulates so keep in mind make
sure you're going through and turning
them off and inspecting them making sure
everything's clean and working
efficiently humidity is going to change
based on the stage of the plant but just
have an idea where the humidity is and
are you in this acceptable range for the
various conditions or the propagation
vegetative or flowering phases
temperature looking at daily highs
between 1775 you can push this to 80
going much above 85 though is not
advised nighttime tents it's good to
have a little bit of a cool-down sixty
to sixty-five degrees Fahrenheit I also
put this Celsius here as well so
moisture areas to me the evenly released
across all plants can obtain what media
you use might depend on what your soil
moisture level is and if you're using
clay pebbles you may want to be
irrigating that almost 24/7 800 products
have their own parameters pH for most
grain media we're looking at a goal of
around six point five I'll play a
position as the plants need to be
rotated the light intensity or they kind
of leaning over to one side in six and
disease inspections check the tops the
bottoms the high low in the canopy it's
also yes you do carry with and just kind
of do a quick cursory look with a loop
with an LED light just spot any very
small insects or disease spores at the
very early stages nutrients make sure
there's no Ives deficiencies and a
feeding schedule matches the stage of
the plant a little more nitrogen to
beginning to increase that leaf growth
for example check the walls in the floor
make sure everything is clean make sure
all the leaves are swept up
I maintain light distance from the tops
are growing the plants
raising me be required also keep in mind
how old the bulbs may be here are the
reflectors to ensure that you're still
allowing the plants to achieve the
maximum amount of light so yeah and just
a quick little overview here of all the
things to be looking at and kind of run
a checklist to go through for your gross
space if you're hitting all these and
able to do this on a daily basis you
should be on your way to an efficient
and hopefully happy growing space for
your plants and the grower as well