welcome to this tobacco university
feedback request video where we're going
to ask for you to take just a little
time to give us some feedback on what
you like about the channel what
improvements can be made to ensure
quality content continues to come your
way
[Music]
all right so realize that your feedback
does matter and in a continual effort to
improve the education provided by devaku
university you're being asked to
complete a very simple feedback form
this will allow the collection of
comments in an organized format more so
than if you just put them below the
video here
this is only available for a short time
so if you're watching this please go to
the link below because we'll only be
open until august 17th 2022
at 5 00 a.m greenwich mean time link to
the form is in this slide set as well as
down in the description
it's only six questions so don't panic
and freak out and think there's a whole
you know long list three are open-ended
you know what do you like about tobacco
university what content do you want to
see and what improvements can be made
also there's some multiple choice
questions just a 1 to 10 scale how would
you rate the content provided what
playlist is your favorite and are you a
subscriber to the channel
and just closing here i want to thank
you in advance for your time is
appreciated and hopefully debacle
university can continue to provide
quality content for everyone