welcome to debacle University's 1,000
subscriber thank you here on YouTube so
subscribers didn't get names here chosen
the name subscribers to vacuoles kind of
sounds like molecules and it goes along
with the education and scientific based
theme of the channel if you have
subscribed thank you and if you have not
it's not too late by all means go down
click the subscribe button and help
build this community what subscribing
means so it may seem to you just a click
of a button but provide a general idea
of the community centered around this
channel and well you and I think much of
it subscribing or not subscribing it is
much appreciated so if you have not
you're encouraged to take the time to go
through and do that information about
the channel while it is educational
based the videos tend to contain a lot
of clickbait and are probably not likely
to go viral but the intention is to
provide quality video content videos
have been used in high schools across
the United States and also in college
classes if you want to share where you
are watching this video series and add
to the comments below that would be
great to just see where these videos are
being watched it's always encouraging to
see positive comments within the
channels are very much appreciated it
can be hard to find good questions have
been asked and it's creating that sense
of community within the comment section
which has been great to see going
forward in the comments below you may
want to add what video topics you may
want to see or suggestions for that and
what you like about the channel is also
encouraged to put in the comments below
just to give that sense and kind of
again share with those ideas amongst
other YouTube members and unless they
want to close are just telling others if
you see something you'd like please
share it and encourage others to
subscribe as well the goal is to keep
the channel growing it's just a general
thank you to thank you to those first
thousand subscribers