if you want to learn about deep water
culture then this debaco university
video
is for you
[Music]
all right let's get into deepwater
culture abbreviated dwc for cannabis
production
so the basics of deep water culture are
the fact that it does not use a growing
medium or
substrate but instead plants roots are
held in a special pot or container
we see that right over on this side over
here with a five gallon pail system
and some of the components that's
required on this other side we see kind
of represented in a cannabis grow
in what this system entails is that the
roots are essentially immersed in a pool
of aerated
nutrient-rich water which allow for easy
access to
oxygen and nutrients for the plant
now the attractiveness of this system is
that it can be automated
so there's no need and there's also no
need to worry about over or under
watering the plants the system can
easily be automated once initially set
up
however this may not be the best option
for new growers due to the lack of
buffering ability
of the water solution so growers have
little room for error
it's great when it looks like this and
this is definitely possible
but if there is potential for ph swings
that aren't monitored or a new grower
isn't attentive to those
this can cause the entire plant to die
in a relatively short period of time
the basic setup to this is that there's
a reservoir a dwc net pots
which kind of will support that
substrate water-soluble nutrient
and then an air pump as well and they're
typically sold as kits as we can see
here
now the water nutrient reservoir the
reservoir contains a water-soluble
nutrient solution
that the plant's roots grow in we see
that right here to help avoid potential
algal growth the container should be
light tight
but not necessarily airtight meaning we
don't want to have
light getting in here but we don't
necessarily want to completely solidly
sealed
we do potentially want some exchange of
air
some systems are sized for one plant
others are sized to hold
multiple plants since all plants will be
in the same solution it is advised to
only grow the same type of plant
at the same stage in the same reservoir
if you're growing one in flower one in
veg one propagation that could cause
some potential nutrient imbalances
or really reduce your overall efficiency
of plant production
now if we're looking at the dwc or net
pots these have a
wide or large mesh to allow support of
the root system
but still provide plenty of room for the
roots to expand there's nothing special
so they can be homemade but are often
store-bought to allow for
standardization as we can see right here
below me
and there's an example of some homemade
ones some growers may choose to fill
these with some inert medium
but this is often not required unless
plants are initially placed in these
containers when they're very small
here we see some growing pebbles used
sometimes rockwool is used
but you can some of the plants a little
bit older just basically put them right
in the pot with no need for any
additional substrates now the water
soluble nutrient solution you want to
follow the recommended rates of
nutrients based on the fertilizer
company's suggestions
because that is a great starting point
or when in doubt favor a little bit less
however the grower is responsible for
regulation of the ph
to ensure the nutrient availability for
efficient growth
the target ph should be around 5.8 with
an acceptable range of 5.5 to 6.5
typically a little bit more acidic than
we would in a natural
soil based solution to ensure growers
need to have
a continual water monitor for ph but
nutrient concentrations in temperature
are also environmental factors to
monitor as well ph is very important but
don't only monitor ph the concentration
of those nutrients and the temperature
of that nutrient solution
are other things growers should be
monitoring and keeping a continual eye
on
and then some will go through and add an
additional air pump
so a general rule the air pump should
apply at least double
the liters per hour of the volume of
your reservoir the whole goal here is to
keep the nutrient solution moving
and also allow fresh oxygen and air to
those root systems will be
in growing in those water environment
for example
if you had a hundred liter water tank
you should have a
air pump that would supply at least 200
liters per hour
growers are advised to get backups to
ensure quick change if a pump
fails because that is one of the
downfalls of the system that it is
dependent on electricity
so hopefully these little tips and kind
of
brief overview of the deepwater culture
gives you a better understanding
of how this can be utilized for cannabis
production