many of you may have heard of delta 8
thc and delta 9 thc and wondered what
the differences were
well here on this tobacco university
video we're going to go over and compare
just what delta 8 thc is compared to
what delta 9 thc
is hopefully you find this information
useful
[Music]
all right let's get into delta 8 thc
compared to delta 9 thc well first off
delta 8 thc can be classified currently
as hemp where delta 9 thc is what can
classify
a cannabis plant as marijuana so first
off let's explain the delta 9 thc
something
you might have heard a little bit more
might be more familiar with is an
activator of the cb1 receptor the delta
9 it's commonly known as thc and is the
main intoxicating component
to cannabis thc intoxication has been
shown to increase blood flow in the
peripheral frontal
cortex region of the brain which is
responsible for decision making
attention
motor skills and other executive
functions when thc binds to cb1
receptors in the brain's reward system
it can trigger the feelings of euphoria
much of tac's ability to relieve pain
is due to its interaction with the cb1
receptors
in the midbrain now we're going to talk
about delta 8
thc but here's just a little comparison
of the structures
we can see at first glance pretty
similar
look almost identical but the key part
here is the double bond here
or the double bond here that's the
difference between your
delta nine and your delta eight has to
do where that double bond
is located however there's also great
benefits and that's a switch of a double
bond there's also some
differences in the how these molecules
interact
so let's look at the delta eight thc
delta a is an isomer
of delta nine t h and as i mentioned
here it says changing of where that
double bond is located
only differs from the placement of that
atomic double bond it's only
structural difference at least on a
molecule basis generally this chemical
is produced in a lab
and not extracted directly from the
plant it is actually synthesized from
a cbd isolate this creates a legal
loophole though because the product is
being sold as hemp derived
even though it's actually chemically
produced thc
isomer so it's important kind of
distinction there
and this is why there's some of the
confusion why there's
some companies advertising a lot of
delta eight thc compared to delta nine
so we're looking at the kind of
extraction uh difference here
so delta eight tht is a major
cannabinoid
that can be found in abundance and is
easily extracted from
cannabis in comparison when we look at
extracting delta eight thc it is more
challenging
simply because it's a minor cannabinoid
so we're looking at the challenge parts
of delta eight it's simply
less concentrated so therefore it's a
minor cannabinoid
it's a little bit harder to extract uh
interesting article published and what
is the difference between delta eight
tht and delta nine thc
here uh that will be going through some
of that information as well as what
you've heard
already so when we're synthesizing delta
eight from
uh cbd delta eight can be synthesized
entirely from cbd
with the use of solvents deriving delta
eight from hemp ensures that the final
product is under the 0.3
thc level to be federally legal that's
kind of a key point there is that
they're staying under the federally
regulated 0.3 percent thc levels because
that's referring to delta 9.
so that's classifying it as hemp because
marijuana be anything really above
0.3 percent thc from a federal
standpoint
that's why you see these large signs
delta 8 thc because a lot of people are
familiar with the
the letters thc but this delta 8 is
classifying it currently
to be uh hemp which is has much more
legal options to be sold now if you want
to know the steps to synthesize delta
eight thc from a cbd isolate
they are basically listed right here uh
from a patent from
the website link here and it kind of
goes through a little bit of the process
and this is not a completely easy
process
you have to dissolve the nonpolar
solvent of choice common solvents
include
heptane add a lewis acid
and add a bunch of other things you want
to maintain certain temperatures you
want to stir for a long period of time
once the chemical reaction is complete
under phase separation you want to watch
and
neutralize a solution you want to test
for purity and contaminants using
high pressure liquid chromatography and
then the conversion still
despite all these very specific
scientific steps is still
never quite 100 so again keep that in
mind
this is not something necessarily easy
to derive
as a result there are different effects
from delta 8 thc
versus delta 9 thc delta 9 is
considerably more potent effects than
delta 8. paranoia delusions mental fog
impaired motor skills
increased feelings of anxiety typically
associated with delta
9. in comparison delta a is reported to
provide a more muted experience
with most users feeling a great sense of
common clarity however many have
reported a definite high
to the experience but not enough to
impair the ability to form coherent
thoughts
or focus on activities this also
provides a little comparison there
of delta 9 versus delta 8
listed effects again a little bit more
from anecdotal information
but kind of gives you that little bit of
a quick comparison between the two
and then also some similarities now the
onset time is different
so delta 9 has an onset that's more
rapid and instantaneous
delta eight works slowly and gradually
as it eases users to a more mellow state
so again keep that in mind that
delta eight can have a little bit more
of that delayed kind of
effect there hopefully not for your
airline
similar end products are being produced
from both because both can be smoked as
a flower inhaled
through vaping consumed as an edible
form also a wide variety of topicals
capsules tinctures edibles and other
products as well
but you'll see the delta eight usually
predominantly listed on
the label or packaging now we get into
legality of things and this you know
always subject to change but currently
delta ht in any amount over 0.3 percent
is not legal at the federal level state
level depends entirely on the local laws
delta eight is still technically legal
in federal at the federal level
simply because uh the kind of way that
the 2018 farm bill
is is written which legalizes hemp
production
and there is nothing within the of the
bill that prevents deriving delta eight
from hemp and creating products with
that particular compound
at least as it's stated in currently in
the books right now
so this creates that hazy area as i say
the psychoactive nature of delta a has
prompted
a fair number of bans at the state level
though so keep that in mind
they're currently as this particular
video and in the article cited
there are 15 states that restrict the
sale and use of delta 8 products
with another six states where legal
action is currently pending
so while delta a is more widespread at
the moment than delta nine
how long will last is yet to be
determined simply because it's caught in
that loophole
of the current 2018 farm bill
now the availability of this so when we
look at the availability delta a since
it's fed illegal can be shipped across
state lines
unlike delta 9. there's a lot more
online retailers for delta 8 products as
a result because they can ship it
and move it across state lines without a
problem however just remember that delta
a products are not regulated by the fda
so it's up to you to seek out lab
results tested from a third party to
make sure what you're consuming and
purchasing
is actually what you think you're
purchasing and it's also safe to be
using and consuming
so last little comparison kind of that
delta uh 9 versus delta 8.
delta 9 might be considered the classic
choice by some with the
within the cannabis community however
delta 8 is quickly
gaining popularity due to its miler
effects and legal availability
now since there's it's an isomer of
delta 9 is also likely to come under
some form of regulation in the future
even though that may not currently be
the case again that simple flip of that
double bond there doesn't look like it
changes much
you can see here with the changing of
effects but really how the current laws
are written
kind of in that hazy loophole area but
hopefully this provides you a little bit
more of an educational background
so you can understand better the
difference between delta 9 thc
and delta 8 thc levels