welcome to debacle university where here
we're going to be looking
at a video lecture to determine the
refractive index of
glass now refractive index abbreviated
ri
is looking at when light travels from
one medium to another its speed changes
relative to the density of the medium
which is
observed as the light bends traveling
from one medium to the other
the speed of light keep in mind in a
vacuum is represented by the letter c
and is always the same but when light
moves from one medium and travels
more slowly as it goes to another medium
as it's constantly being absorbed and
re-emitted
by the atoms in that material now the
ratio of the speed of light in a vacuum
to the speed of light in another
substance
is defined as the index of refraction or
refractive
index and it's represented in equations
as the letter
n for that substance so if you look here
here's
n this is going to be referring to the
refractive index now what does this
actually look like
well up here we notice that when light
travels from one medium to another it's
bending because we have a change in the
speed of that light what's kind of a
neat experiment here is we have a glass
with a piece of paper behind it with the
arrow pointing in one direction we fill
that glass full of water and the air
will actually flip the direction there
because of a difference in refractive
index
now the refractive index and probability
well there's a database
of refractive indexes for different
types of glass and this helps determine
an appropriate
statistical probability that two pieces
of glass share a common source
may not offer that exact match but it
can increase the probability that yes
it's very
likely or unlikely a high probability or
a low probability
that those two pieces of glass will
match one another
now how do we determining that
refractive index well we can use the
submersion method this is just kind of a
quick quote down and dirty method of
determining this
you'd place the glass or fragments of
that glass into different liquids of
known refractive
indexes if the piece of glass in a
liquid have the same
refractive index the glass fragment will
seem to disappear when placed in that
liquid
and here is a prime example we have a
beaker the liquid has the same
refractive index as this column in this
test tube and we could see everything
appears to disappear
simply because of the same refractive
index therefore they're kind of
disappearing because we don't have that
difference between those two substances
occurring
now we can also use a microscope
submersion along with a low power
microscope
now submerge fragments of glass in a
liquid and then view them under a low
power microscope using
particularly a compound light microscope
this is great for small
pieces or small fragments that are found
and in this case if the refractive index
of the liquid and medium is different
from the refractive index of the piece
of glass a halo-like
ring appears around the edge of that
glass and you can see that here
the halo-like effect is called the beck
line looking a little bit more detailed
at this
bec line you can kind of see an example
of that here
it appears because refracted light
becomes concentrated around the edges of
the glass fragment
and a backline is visible under a
microscope and the glass and liquid have
different refractive indices
so in this case in the middle image here
where they're both the same backline's
in the middle and they kind of all blur
together and they kind of merge and we
don't really see that backline
developing
however in this case here we have the
perimeter of the piece of glass
and we have the liquid being a lower
refractive index
than the actual glass piece this halo
like effect if you look at the perimeter
of the glass is located on the inside
of that piece of glass in contrast
if the liquid has a greater refractive
index
than the piece of glass we have that
same halo-like effect but in this case
the hill-like effect is on the outside
of the edges of the glass so it's
important not only to identify the
presence of a back line
because that will tell you that there is
a difference in refractive indices
between the
glass piece and the liquid medium but
where that halo
is found will tell you which one is
greater that can help you determine the
approximate
range of the refractive index for that
piece of glass that you're investigating
so here's some additional pictures
showing the refractive index of the
medium
versus the glass the liquid versus the
glass and that bending that's occurring
so here we see kind of that rays are
kind of converging here
this is because the glass has a higher
refractive index and the back line is
seen on the
inside you can see that right here on
that inside of that fragmented
glass now in this case is the opposite
where the glass has a lower refractive
index
the back line here is seen on the
outside of that perimeter there because
the rays are
diverging so it makes it a little bit
clearer kind of that true little halo
effect
here we're seeing the evidence of that
clear outside where that outside is and
where's the halo occurring in relation
to that
if it's occurring on the inside as we
see here that means the glass is a high
refractive index
and here if that halo is occurring on
the outside of that
glass this is a sign that the glass is a
lower refractive index
now here's just some examples of
refractive index of known liquids so if
you had
something or a piece of glass that you
thought what the refractive index was or
for comparison
these are some common liquids that can
be used
for that becca line determination
now lastly here we can look at tempered
versus non-tempered glass and when
trying to make a distinction between
tempered glass and non-tempered glass
particles process known as annealing is
used an annealing is the slow heating
and then cooling of that glass that
alters the microstructure
of the material causing changes in
properties such as strength and hardness
annealing alters refractive index value
for tempered glass greater than that of
non-tempered glass
so this can also act as a way for
determining that
when we're looking at knowing what the
refractive index is
for a piece of glass