okay I'm gonna go over two ways that you
can determine cannabis plants and gender
this respite visually looking at them
you can't tell whether it's male or
female so that can be an issue when
you're looking at mainly
I wanting to produce female all plants
for the buds and cannabinoids that they
can produce for you so this should only
be needed if you're starting from seed
if you're going to go through the labor
and equipment of an dis intensive
process of cloning propagating be sure
you know the gender of your plant ahead
of time males should only be cloned by
breeders who want to repeat a very
specific cross otherwise only female
plants should be cloned so after you go
through and kind of grow all your little
seedlings this is where you're trying to
determine whether these are male plants
or female plants from an early stage
then once you have a known female you
can use that and repeat this process
with that known gender that you're
dealing with so the most efficient
method would be something called PCR
this is what large-scale operations are
using it's called polymerase chain
reaction or that so it's short for to
take technique used to identify the
gender of plans and it can be done as
early as about them around the for truth
leave it stage what's great about this
method is only a very small sample of a
leaf sample is needed let me take a hole
punch and then you add add it to the PCR
and what PCR basically does is multiply
a and you're looking at using this to
determine the gender of the plant this
can allow for very early culling of
males and reduce the time wasted on non
target plants and virtually eliminate
the chance that pollen in the grow
facility from a plant that's a male that
could cross contaminate in most cases
female plants however that's a little
cost prohibitive so something that's a
little bit easier to do and scales down
a small-scale operation is to simply
grow a plant and this does take longer
and take a cutting of that plant they
take a small branch cutting and put it
in a cloner and put it in under a
flowering photo period
this will help induce flowering which
all I'd to clearly identify that plant
is male or female
now even if the plants get a little
stressed that's okay you're just looking
at getting them to produce flowers
now what makes this method work which is
can be a problem with some growers is to
keep good records you want to make sure
that you have all these plants labeled
you know which one it is you know what
parent it came from so if you do
identify one is male you are calling out
the proper plant and not having a
miscommunication on the records there on
some of these cloners do have a nice
abc123 system but I suggest kind of in
some way tagging the actual plant with
some sort of color tag or a little label
just to give you that extra redundancy
so that you're allowed to keep the good
plants and cull out the males without
making any mistakes