so welcome to this debaco university
video
we're looking at determining cannabis
sex using pcr using the pcr method
which is advantageous because you can
tell whether a plant is male or female
well before it actually flowers here so
we'll go over some
of the methods and some of the
background of this plymouth
chain reaction method or pcr
all right let's get into the video here
so first off we're looking at male
and female flowers so canvas is mostly
deices
what does that mean well for fiber hemp
varieties have been bred to be monishes
and when we use these terms what does
that mean well diocese means that it's
producing either
a female plant or it's producing a male
plant
miniatures will produce male and female
flowers on the same plant
so with this diocese we're having these
distinct female and male plants
separating out those plants as male and
females at early development stage is
useful
due to the influence of gender at
agriculturally significant
traits meaning if we're looking at
producing cannabinoids we definitely
want to be selecting for those
female plants and discarding those males
so we're eliminating
the presence of pollination limit the
presence of that pollen
to reduce the chance that seeds are
formed which would greatly reduce the
total cannabinoids produced
now with when we're looking at this pcr
method what's going to be utilized is
going to be dna markers
cell experiments have been done to focus
on developing reliable molecular marker
for sex determination in cannabis plants
dna markers for the detection of male
genotypes is utilized
and we talked about dna markers you
might be familiar with running things on
a gel with
electrophoresis here we also have
the utils utilization of these different
primers that will bind to specific
sequences if they're present
and replicate them so that we can
determine whether that small snippet of
a leaf
is a from a male plant or from a female
plant because those plants contain
all those genetic markers at the very
early age
so those male genes specifically the
exact markers used can be debated but in
general concept
is the same for all if the markers for
the male gene or genes are found in the
plant
will not produce the high cannabinoid
salt flowers that many growers are
growing
for meaning if we determine it to be a
male plant a lot of pollen is going to
produce but not a lot of cannabinoids
now why i've produced here kind of a
horse example looking at determining
males or females
keep in mind the mare mare is considered
to be an adult female horse
and a occult is a young male horse so
here we can see the genetic markers we
could see
our samples we could kind of make a
correlation of what matches with what
here
again may not always be a perfect match
but we could clearly see
s1 sample one here certainly looks like
one of the occult or a young
male horse and the same is basically
applied to cannabis
now why would you use pcr what's the
advantage here
well research implements chain reaction
that's pcr it shows
could continue in order to find more
advanced dna markers for sex
determination within cannabis plants
this allows not only for quick detection
time but also
very accurate results both things
growers are looking for
the plant sample required is very
minimal so it can be formed on plants
early on in the sealing stage to reduce
wasted care space and time on plants
that will not produce desirable end
products
the reason why i can work on plants that
are so small is it's using the genetic
level and it's able to screen for only
it really only needs one piece of dna
pcr would go through this multiple
thermocycler this cycle run
to amplify and it amplifies things on an
exponential form so technically having
only one sequence of dna
it would amplify that to be a very large
number to show up on a electrophoresis
gel
to be able to use for detection now can
the cost be justified so this is one of
those constant questions when we're
looking particularly
at pcr can we justify the cost of pcr
so while this can be expensive for some
growers they some can
justify the cost for larger grow
operations we'll often set
this up in-house meaning they can
conduct these pcr treatments
within their own grow facility as after
the initial cost the reoccurring costs
are actually quite minimal once you
purchase everything
reoccurring costs are quite minimal for
medium and small operations infill
samples typically will be sent
out for testing for a fee from a testing
lab
and the great question is in cost to
benefit analysis
is the cost of the tests going to be
less than what it would take to grow
that plant to
produce flowers to be able to identify
it and that is really up to the grower
to
to look at for their operation for their
particular um
kind of cost their particular potential
benefits
to make that decision that's the best
for their operation