all right in this tobacco university
video we'll be investigating
two scientific articles that will help
us address the topic of determining the
chemical profile of cannabis via hplc
and hrms methods we'll learn about what
each of those
is more detail here in this video
lecture
so starting with the first reference
article here again with any reference
article i try to give you that first
page
the proper citation and a direct link
there so you can go investigate it
further
if you want to look at some more of the
details so looking at canvas
variability and that's kind of where
these methods are looking at kind of
trying to assess that
the variability within cannabis in
general so cannabis strains
significantly vary in their chemical
compositions the concentration of
cannabis compounds depend on the plant's
tissue type the age the variety the
growing conditions such as
nutrition or fed the humidity and light
levels harvest time storage conditions
as well as many other things analyzing
the chemical content
the plants is of major importance
considering that the concentrations of
these constituents
and their interplay may determine
medical effects
and also potentially adverse side
effects so getting a good idea
of what the actual compounds are present
is
uh well worthwhile so what methods we go
through to evaluate those
so we have two presented here we have
the
gas chromatography or abbreviated gc
and they have hplc which stands for high
performance liquid chromatography
so hplc resolves the threat of the
phytocannabinoid decomposition as a
result of the heating
compared with gas chromatography we also
see kind of a great little quick
comparison here
hplc can be directly applied for
fractions of extracts
into separate pure compounds unlike the
grass chromatography fractions of
extracts are of high importance in
medical research
and for structure classification so this
is why
typically when we're comparing the two
overall the hplc
is typically favored over the more
traditional gas chromatography
particularly or especially in related to
cannabis
continuing on to another research
article if you want to look at some more
information
again same uh reference link and copy of
the first page here
if you want to look at this one in more
detail in this way we're looking at the
kind of the the comparison of extracted
ion uh
chromatograms here and we what we see is
these kind of like chemical signatures
we're liquid chromatography methods
coupled to high resolution
mass spec detection and this is where we
get the hplc
hrms that um high-resolution mass spec
is what hrms is standing for
these have been developed for the
identification of different cannabinoids
in
cannabis medical extracts the hmrs
technique can define the cannabinoid
profile of cannabis and products which
is very important
current focus is on the main
cannabinoids such as cbd
and thc along with some of the other
minor cannabinoids
which contribute to the final beneficial
effects so having these are
knowing these a very precise measurement
here so you can see look at some of the
differences presented
in that research study that i cited
before this is a great way to develop
this kind of
a detailed understanding of what is
actually in
that cannabis plant where it actually
has produced
now the macro to the microscopic views
as we kind of can see
in the example here the leaf of a
typical cannabis plant
if we zoom in i would say the lethal
typical chemist plant then we have that
zoom in
version here with the magnifying leaf
showing the individual trichome
structures
then we have the surface swab of that
leaf conducting right here in the lab
then the mass spec of that sample
collected so this is kind of the general
process
of how we go about sampling that plant
and developing
those various particular mass spec
graphs there this would be the process
that would be utilizing as you can see
it's actually taking direct samples from
the plant and getting an exact kind of
profile
which is great when we're looking at
trying to evaluate what compounds
particularly canvas plants may or may
not be producing