on this tobacco university video i'll be
looking at determining cannabis sex
using a clone in flip method this is a
very simple method that anyone can do
it also helps refine one's ability to go
through and do cloning
but this can be a very important process
to be able to determine
whether you're going to have a male
plant or a female plant and really
hopefully
reduce the care that you need to give to
your plants
that are male so that you can focus on
those that are going to be high
cannabinoid producers
[Music]
all right let's get into the video here
to show you how to go about this clone
and flip method
well first off why would you want to
know whether your plant was male or
female to begin with well keep in mind
that the male plants are going to
produce pollen
and really are only desirable by
breeders female plants will produce high
amounts of cannabinoids and those tend
to be desirable by growers
looking to produce high chemical and
terpene densities
so most growers are looking for female
plants but
early on before flowering it's very
difficult to tell
whether you have a male plant or a
female plant you have to take care of it
and that could be wasted resources if
you're growing a male plant that you're
not going to
have any return on investment at the end
so when we're going through and cloning
our plant the cloning process is the
same as if we plan
was to propagate the plant so if you
have a good cloning process
we want to refine that this is a method
that can help you with that
growers should take an early branch from
a plant to be able to determine the
gender before pre-flowers develop
naturally so this can be done very early
on in the plant growing process
however the goal is to ensure that this
is a quick process since growers
want to know what plants to call and
which ones to keep so keep in mind
you're
also labeling and tagging everything
unlike traditional cloning the photo
period for the clones or in the clone
room
should be under a 12 12 12 hours late
into a large dark
flowering duration so you can be able to
determine
or force flowers early so you might
determine we have a male or female plant
now we'll talk about forcing flowers
here was this kind of term forcing
flowers referred to
well the flying photoperiod will induce
flower formation and this can be very
early on in a plant's
life cycle or development the goal since
the morphology of the flower produced
will indicate the gender of the plant so
being able to
recognize those flowers early on will
definitely be advantageous
keeping records is important so growers
know what branch or clone matches what
stock or original
plant was utilized to be able to match
that up and we're talking about on a
very small level we can see the arrow
pointing right here
as well as flowers here both of these
referring to or showing
female flowers so how do these differ
compared to male flowers
well we see them side by side because
right here this is what we're looking
for in
flowers so over on this side here we can
see that these are all
male flowers here you can see the kind
of pollen sacs that will
develop in contrast we see the female
flowers we see these white
wispy cat like whiskers here this is
a high surface area and ultimately these
would capture the pollen produced by the
male flowers so once you kind of see
them side by side the morphologies or
how they look
very distinctive so keep in mind that
the earlier you can identify these if
you
are growing a male plant you can cull
that plant and go back to the original
and get rid of that one
so you're focusing all your time energy
and resources
on the plants that will produce high
cannabinoids which will be those that
we're looking for
that have female flowers morphology