okay so here what a look at diagnosing a
plant problem and how to go about that
not jump into conclusion since there's
nothing and a leaf for a plant and
saying oh that's clearly this properly
diagnosing going through some stepwise
process to classify the problem and
diagnose it properly so that control
measures can be implemented so first off
you have to know they plant know what
the plant looks like because in order to
diagnose a potential issue you need to
know what the normal is with the plant
look what's shouldn't the plant look
like and this could vary depend on the
cultivar take notes is good continuing
to document pictures because you want to
know what the normal of the plant should
look like edition and documentation is
important and this can help you track
trends and changes over time how the
plant look last week your memory may not
be as good as you think taking those
pictures will light or refer to that and
those pictures are great but also
including captions is also important
because those going to clean include the
conditions they're all important
information to include not only the
conditions the temperature what you
might be noticing at the time how old
the plant is all good things to document
then you want to classify the problem
this involves three main groups each
having subcategories the keys again not
to jump to conclusions and try to be
impartial proper classification will
help you develop a plan of action and
those classifications are is it a
nutrient issue it could be a toxicity or
a deficiency a disease or grower
implemented kind of problem so first off
for nutrients they tend to be across the
field or in the same kind of run that we
may see in that in a grow operation
important to notice the placement of the
issue in relation to the plants a new
girl or is it older gross this is an
example here in nutrient deficient this
is nitrogen in a cue Kermit field here
we could see low nitrogen and as we
progressed this way we get into more
nitrogen this is a field application
what's happening is that through heavy
rains the nitrogen was leaching out of
here and running down the hill a little
bit and kind of allowing these to have
the proper amount of nitrogen and needs
to become deficient you can kind of see
that trend occurring in the field and
trends are common with nutrient issues
now disease kind of a quick onset you
want to be sure you're checking both the
tops of the
and also the underside of leaves or many
diseases we'll start and lastly we have
a grower issue and this is usually
occurs in isolated cases could be poor
hand watering or consistency with
watering breaking the plant through
mishandling that's a spring improperly
causing spray damage here or applicator
blight would be one example here we see
an herbicide spray so these are ways
that we want to go about an approaching
when we're diagnosing an issue with our
plants