okay if there's one thing growers can
use continually improvement in
experience with its diagnosing Clint
problems in a very important skill and I
encourage everyone to continue to work
on it it's never a really perfect it's
always different you're never sure
exactly what the answer may be in some
cases but something you still should
still continue to work on and that
diagnosis thing going the process we go
through here I'm going to do a couple of
examples plies and gets you at least to
get you an idea what you may have so you
start developing a plan around it you
just want to say oh the plant died and
move on well I try to do what cause that
plant to dies you can better plan for
the future so if you're trying to
diagnose a problem or trying to help
someone else diagnose a problem first
you do do is you're trying to get a
correct diagnosis that's your goal you
don't want to make assumptions because
if you're just you're trying to get that
to the root of that problem or the real
basic cause to that try not to make
assumptions the key is to continually
ask questions of yourself or a person
you're trying to help that continual
questions because someone may see four
and then someone may see three so I want
to make any quick assumptions you want
to kind of look at the situation and
just collect some facts and some data
before you start going through and
saying oh that is X Y or Z if you
parties want try to classify that
problem I want to talk about each of
these in detail whether it's a fungi
that caused a problem a bacterial virus
water and animal the your yourself the
grower the environment classifying the
problem can really do a lot for as far
as helping you prevent that issue or
correcting that issue moving forward so
Simon's fungi it's a very common control
by fungicides so I've been up on the
sides control fungi they tend in warm
moist environmental conditions so
typically all your mildews you know your
powdery mildews is a good example of a
fungi that you may see very commonly
occur and it's likes those kind of warm
moist conditions those heavy rains of
heavy dudes and warm temperatures cause
these to really get growing quite good
bacteria is another one they did a favor
warm weather to the point of hot weather
they can multiply faster as the
temperature rises so if the problem
becomes increasingly an issue as the
temperature gets warmer and warmer this
season warms up could be a bacterial
disease some the sites remember don't
work on bacteria fungi and bacteria are
different you need a bacterial side to
combat bacteria so if you apply a
fungicide and that doesn't really work I
mean it because the fungicide it's broke
could it mean it because you don't have
a fungus to begin with so that's another
indication viruses these are typically
insect vectored plants lack an immune
system so you cannot control the actual
substance you can't control the actual
virus you need to prevent the vector for
bringing that virus in so insect control
and clean equipment are very important
this is tobacco mosaic virus got a very
unique look to it might be a little bit
more like common cold virus might be
used seeing what viruses are very tough
because plants lack the immune system so
we want to prevent the virus from even
coming into our fields new treatment
valves so this can be pH related and or
an over or under application of
fertilizer under application means their
plants are starving for a particular
nutrient over application means you
could be blocking certain nutrients
typically it's a field or crop wide
problem pH concerns tend to show up
early in the season if it's kind of
nutrient balance and relate to the pH
problem in nutrients tend to show more
fruit set again not always the case but
just indications that you may have this
nutrient problem going on here we see a
citrus crop having some nutrient balance
here's a corn plant corn plants now I
said it's kind of field or crop wide in
this case that's not true we see these
corns plants in the back doing quite
well the corn here kind of having that
yellowing appearance there so again not
always true but when we see this one
doing well one not doing well probably
net disease-oriented at least probably
nutrient oriented or it could be water
this is another issue too much or too
little same thing too much water could
be over irrigation could be a leaky hose
could be just excessive rain or it could
be too
I don't know how the water flows through
your field the example here conceived
probably where the water kind of
collects and certain plant species can
help indicate where it could be wetter
soil and where that's gonna travel
you can't expect good yields here you
might as well make walking paths or
split two fields in this area you want
to check your irrigation line for leaks
or clogs because that can lead to too
much or too little water in Zach's kind
of an imager here other variable each
one's got their own little special
properties but each has its main time
frame as they show up good idea of when
to expect them degree days can help
predict this very important for some
insects if you're looking at monitoring
and open control measures degree days
can help you predict and time your
applications in your scanning
accordingly animals they can be really
small like nematodes which I think often
get overlooked - very large this deer or
even in some case bare so you want to
determine what animals likely to be in
your area whether it's deer deer fence
electric fence for small animals like
chipmunks and squirrels in the Emoto
it's a little bit harder and want to
work on controlling them potentially in
this soil if you can environmental it's
kinda hard to plan for this some of it
might be obvious hail damaged
temperature extremes can cause cracking
in this case a tree trunk or wind damage
tropical storms or hurricanes these are
just saying maybe you can't control but
at least can identify hail isn't
interesting one if it's a distant field
we don't get to see every day I'm not
gonna see the hail or it could not hail
the home but at the field it could so
just things to consider you're not
saying hail is kind of obvious once you
see it well some fields are distant and
the last one is grower error these can
be the hardest to see or realize or
admit to that you messed up here or it
looks like a grower may have applied an
herbicide where they shouldn't have so
just be realistic if it was fine growers
rightfully so don't want to admit to
something that they may have done but I
also can get the data and collecting it
it's key part is just to realize what
you did and don't do that again