ha diffusion and osmosis two very
important concepts to understand and to
be able to distinguish the difference
between the two quick summary is
diffusion is movement of particles from
a high concentration to a lower
concentration to make it evenly spaced
out here and as Moses is the movement or
change of water through a semipermeable
membrane let's dive in more detail here
so I'm with diffusion so diffusion here
we have a bunch of blue molecules here
our extracellular spaces are diffusing
across our semi permeable look at
bilayer and over time they become evenly
distributed and the outside inside of
the cell good see here our little tin
spheres here slowly diffusing throughout
these molecules become more evenly
spaced out so it's a net movement of a
substance from an area of higher
concentration to an area of lower
concentration down a concentration
gradient so high concentration to low
concentration so you could think of this
if you're I'm gonna go watch a movie and
you're waiting to get into the movie
theater they have the doors closed
you've a very high concentration and
you're passing through the doorway here
ultimately getting an even amount of
hopefully that are on the inside and on
the outside there so that can be a way
of everyone that's in the movie theater
and those that are still outside waiting
for other movies to come and that could
be a way to think about this diffusion
process key part here is it's a
selectively permeable layer now this
diffusion process it can be simple
channeled or carrier mediated the
general process is the same channel and
carry mediated diffusion is specific and
subject to saturation
so what these two require is this
protein channel for example or this
carrier protein simple diffusion just
occurs with no energy and it just kind
of happens way to think about simple
diffusion if someone sprays perfume in
one side of the room
to work its way all the way over to the
other side of the room
channel or carry mediated involves these
carrier proteins and we're looking more
specifically on a cellular example here
here specific to size Chow and
interactions with the channel so example
this channel is transferring these small
green molecules and that these lighter
or oval-shaped ones it's very specific
to just these types of molecules this
other carrier protein is specific to the
lighter green wool shaped ones what
means is that you might say subject is
saturation make some channels
rate-limiting is if there's only a
couple of these proteins in the plasma
membrane it's gonna limit and there's
only so many that can get through it in
one particular time subject to
saturation if they're all busy doing
their job it's going to be slow to get
all those molecules to diffuse across
here we're looking at that saturation
point if it's not a lot of solutes and
they can all diffuse quite well so
diffusion in solutions all molecules are
constantly in motion
remember only an absolute zero are
things not moving we have yet to reach
Absolute Zero molecules in solution move
randomly and the random motion causes
the mixing concentration is the amount
of solute in a solvent in concentration
gradient is the more solute in one part
than another so we see the example here
we had a piece drop of dye here it's
very concentrated slowly over time it
diffuses without any mixing the simple
moving of those molecules around cause
that dye to get moved around into next
same thing here dye crystals in this
case are at the bottom and they're
getting easily mixed over time now if we
heat up though in this case if this is
water if we heat up the water this can
occur at a faster rate diffusion in
solutions our solutes move down the
concentration gradient molecules mix
randomly solute spreads throughout the
solvent it eliminates concentration
gradients here we have a concentration
gradient over time we have basically an
equal amount on both the left and right
side and this occurs just through them
movement of the water molecules
factors affecting our diffusion rates
you can see here distance the particle
has to move so going back to our example
of the perfum if it's a very large room
it's gonna take a longer time for those
further away in the room to be able to
smell the perfume molecule size the
small amount feels will move faster big
molecules take a lot of energy to move
and it can be a lot slower small
molecules can move a lot faster and
diffuse a lot quicker temperature as we
mentioned before more heat faster the
motion gradient size the difference
between high and low concentrations so
the greater the difference in this case
the more concentrated the dye is that's
going to affect our diffusion rate
there's a the difference between high
and low concentrations it's very dilute
it's going to take a little bit longer
for it to kind of work its way through
in electrical forces opposites attract
like charges repel for dealing with
something that's positive and negative
charges so diffusion across the membrane
each solute diffuses down its own
concentration gradient will be a net
diffusion purple molecules towards the
left in the example here you can see
they're moving towards the left through
the solute that was initially greater on
the left side so here we have 20% solute
10% solute see the movement in this case
it's going to be mainly to the left this
leads to dynamic equilibrium
he says the solute molecules continue to
cross membrane but equal rates in both
directions so at equilibrium I don't
want to think things stopped moving a
the molecules are still moving but for
every one that moves to the left one
moves to the right so there's no net
change this is dynamic equilibrium no
net change in the amount of purple
molecules on the left and right even
though one might be moving to the left
or moves to the right sitting with the
water molecules well most of the right
one was to the left so there's still
things that are moving but the net
effect is zero facilitated diffusion
this diffusion of sizes semi purple
membrane with the help of a special
transport proteins large pool molecules
and ions
pass through the phospholipid bilayer
they require these proteins this is the
facilitated diffusion typically teachers
were called faculty and we're
facilitating faculty comes through or
facilitating your learning process if
you need a little extra help we are like
the carrier proteins in the phospholipid
bilayer helping move this confusing
amount of information randomly around
through and getting it ideally to you
where you can learn it and then use it
for your own future studies facilitated
diffusion two types of transport
proteins here help ions and large polar
molecules diffuse to cell membranes
channel proteins provide a narrow
channel for the substances to pass
through care proteins physically bind to
one side of the membrane and release it
on the other side as you can see here is
our binding that's occurring carrying it
through and transferred it to this side
this is enabled our channel proteins
simply just a channel allowing these red
molecules to be able to pass through
carrier proteins are physically grabbing
and curing them across from one side to
the other this is an example of a
channel protein here so last part of our
facilitated diffusion it's specific each
channel specific to transport certain
ions or molecules only passive the
direction of net movement is always down
the concentration gradient and saturates
once all transport proteins are on use
diffusion can no longer increase beyond
that point assuming it's very
specifically in helping students it's
passive it's down low as the
concentration gradient from an area
higher concentration to lower and
saturates all the transport proteins are
in use that's as quick as the rate can
go all the teachers are busy helping the
students as as quick as we can help
people Osmos is a little different
diffusion of solvent across a
semipermeable membrane in living systems
solvent is always water so as most of
its the diffusion of water across a
semipermeable membrane here sorry they
got cut off here we have the amount of
molecules on the left and right staying
the same but we have the amount of water
shifting the water is trying to make the
concentration at each equal even though
they can't pass
this particular semipermeable membrane
as Moses again that movement of water in
this case for biological systems more
solid molecules lower concentration of
water molecules the memory must be free
material to water and selectively
permeable to the solutes in this case
the solutes can't move but the water can
water molecules diffuse across the
membrane towards the solution with more
solutes lung increases on the side as
more solutes we see here here's some
more solute it's useless
water's gonna move across because the in
this case this is alpha salt cannot we
see an increase in the height of water
in this tube versus the side same thing
here we have more molecules on this side
and over time it's part two
more water moves across so diffusion and
osmosis a great comparison between the
two here think of dye mouthfeel simply
spreading out as Moses is a movement of
water here an important concept
concentration gradients tend to even out
in the absence of a membrane diffusion
eliminates concentration gradients here
it's evenly distributes a homogeneous
mixture when different solute
concentrations exist on either side of
the selectively permeable membrane
osmosis moves water through the membrane
to equalize the concentration gradients
in this case here we have our equal
amounts of blue in yellow here we're
cousins mixing to occur and we can in
green here shows here different water
Heights again we're trying to make the
same number of molecules per area on
both sides as a result we've reduced the
water and it moves over to this side
here it is equally spacing things out
this is like students when they enter a
room they all equally spaced out over
time here we're keeping the same number
of students on the left and the right
side and we're simply giving these
students a bigger room and he's a
smaller room to make the amount of area
or square footage that a student may
have equal in both cases hopefully that
was helpful in describing the difference
in similarities between diffusion and
osmosis and how it relates to biology