in this debaco university video i'm
going to provide you with a brief
overview of some different types of
cannabinoids found in cannabis plants
as well as at the end to give you some
direction as far as some other detailed
videos
that go into some specific cannabinoids
to provide you with more information
on those particular ones if you have
interest in those
[Music]
all right so here we see a nice looking
uh canvas bud developing
and we're going to go through the
different types of cannabinoids that
this bud might be producing
so first off cannabinoids and chemicals
so research has found that
the cannabis plant produces between 80
and 100 cannabinoids and about 300
non-cannabinoid-related chemicals the
two main cannabinoids are delta-9
thc as well as cannabidiol or cbd but
here we can see that there's a lot of
other things being produced in that
plant a lot of other pathways going
through
we're going to touch on some of them
here and provide you with more
information on some of the specifics
for cannabinoids in other videos so
first off thc versus
cbds are probably the two most famous or
most well-known
cannabinoids and the main difference
between these is that thc has
strong psychoactive effects meaning it
makes a person quote
high whereas cbd is thought to have
anti-psychoactive effects that controls
or moderates the quote high
caused by thc cbd is also thought to
reduce some other negative effects
that people can experience from a thc
such as anxiety
and here we see kind of potential
benefits and side effects of both
listed here kind of in a comparative
sense there to provide you with a little
bit more information
now keep in mind that when we're looking
at cannabinoids it is more than just
thc and cbd there's thcv there's
cbn there's cbc and there's a whole
bunch of other ones um as well
so just keep in mind that there are more
cannabinoids and we're going to explore
those in more details on other videos
if you're wondering what type of
academics we're going to get into well
through devaco university you search any
of these particular
titles or cannabinoids you should be
able to find more information a good
comparison
just to give you an idea of some of the
diversity that does occur within
cannabinoids
to allow you to find a little bit more
detailed information
if you're so seeking that