thank you for tuning in to another
debaco university video
in this video we'll be looking at
different classifications
of cannabis and how we kind of define
some of those classifications as well
so first off it's all cannabis say in
the hemp sense that hemp
fiber marijuana all fall under the broad
category of cannabis
within the cannabis category though each
offer further classification
and has specific definition allowing for
distinction from the different
subsets within the broader term that we
call
cannabis so we have hemp being defied by
the fda and farm bill
particularly the 2018 farm bill that was
signed into law in december 20 2018
among other things this new law changes
certain federal authorities relating to
the production and marketing of hemp
they define hemp as the plant cannabis
sativa el
and any part of that plant including the
seeds thereof
and all derivatives extracts
cannabinoids isomers
acids salts and salts of isomers
whether growing or not with a delta nine
tetracannabidiol concentration of not
more than 0.3 percent of a dry weight
basis and that is thc if you were one of
delta 9 thc that you may be familiar
with
this is how they define hemp hemp is
basically
not more than 0.3 dry weight thc is how
the fda
and farm bill of 2018 define
hemp now we have also fiber hemp so
within hemp there's kind of all these
different kind of
subsets but fiberhemp is a sustainable
and high yielding industrial crop
that can help meet high global global
demands
for fiber so it's been used in this
sense as the actual kind of
twine here or fiber production for
clothing for example as well
hemp can be grown for fiber seeds and or
for
dual purpose in a wide range of
geographic zones and climates making it
favorable
to grow in different areas so it's not
just like it's got to be isolated to one
area
it is favorable over a large rain of
geographic zones and also the products
that it can produce can also be used for
a wide variety of
different tasks or different kind of
textiles foods cosmetics medicines
antimicrobials there's a whole bunch of
things
kind of looking at a potential for the
use of a fiber hemp
and then marijuana lastly here how we
how do we define marijuana then
uh this can be called weed pot dope or
cannabis just in the kind of quick term
and this is usually referring to the
dried flowers and leaves of the cannabis
plant
and this contains some mind altering
psychoactive compounds like
thc for example and this is as well as
other active compounds it can also
contain cannabidiol which is cbd
and they are non-mind altering but what
again defines it as truly
marijuana goes back to the 2018
farm bill and marijuana would be defined
as simply having greater than
0.3 percent tht and a dry weight basis
so immediately as soon as that plant
sees that flower goes above that
threshold there
it crosses the divide between what we
define here is hemp to what we commonly
refer to here as
marijuana so again important to make
that distinct
distinction and hopefully you were able
to learn something
within this video here