okay I'm gonna give you a brief overview
of the digestive system this image here
shows a great summary of the organs
involved and also their orientation in
the body this image here gives you the
same orientation but gives you a little
bit more description for some of these
areas so it's important to have a
general sense of what's occurring where
and why what the necessary functions are
of some of these essential organs now
why do we consume food well consume food
to gain energy and a healthy diet
contains more carbohydrates than fats
it also contains lots of proteins you
may remember from macromolecules
carbohydrates are important for storage
of energy but also provide energy
quicker energy that can be that simple
monosaccharides into sugars proteins
make up much of the structure of cells
and also can speed up chemical reactions
in the form of enzymes lipids are for
long-term storage of energy here's the
food pyramid indicating items at the top
we should be consuming less of and at
the bottom we should be consuming more
of which you can see the foundation is
based in daily exercise in weight
control for a healthy lifestyle
continuing on oftentimes we hear in the
news about someone being obese or the
obesity epidemic and the percentage of
people being obese well how is that
determined it's determined through the
body mass index and that's abbreviated
BMI in short what it does is it compares
someone's weight to someone's height so
if you kind of get an idea where you may
fall for your BMI based on your weight
in pounds and your height here and again
both metrics in US customary are
provided here
so you're looking to pause the video and
see where you fall in this area
continuing on essential substances for
growth so we do consume food but we have
some essential substances for growth so
many vertebrates aren't enabled to
manufacture one or more of the twenty
amino acids needed to make proteins so
while there's only 20 total humans are
unable to synthesize eight of those
twenty there's a couple listed here
leucine lysine phenyl alanine valine are
essential because those must be obtained
through the food meaning our body cannot
factories in addition we cannot
synthesize certain polyunsaturated tats
and we also need to be consuming trace
elements so a trace element there's a
couple listed here they are required in
small amounts nothing that we need in
large amounts but they are essential so
iodine zinc manganese are just a couple
examples here of trace elements that are
important for our body to function
properly
lastly vitamins essential organic
substances required also in small
amounts in humans require at least 13
different vitamins vitamin C or absorb
ik acid if not obtained in the diet the
disease scurvy will develop so it just
gives you an idea of some of the
importance of some of these components
that are essential for growth
it may not be needing large amounts that
are needed at least in some way
continuing on our digestive system
function to acquire nutrients we have
the ability to break down substances
here hydrolysis catabolism here what's
happening here is large molecules are
being broken down into small ones water
is being consumed in this this is
releasing energy hydro lysis using water
to lyse or break apart molecules this
releases energy typically valves
oxidation reactions in glycolysis would
be an example so big in our complex
molecule here and breaking it down into
simpler ones now if there's a way to
break things apart so you put things
together anabolism here using raw
materials that synthesize essential
components dehydration synthesis is the
process here small molecules are some of
them to large ones and water is produced
dehydration water is being lost here he
uses energy to construct new bonds and
typically involves reduction reactions
putting it all together here cattle ISM
and of like reactions here here's our
glucose here we have our two different
pathways so just to remember we're
cattle catalyzing something here
we're breaking it apart and here we are
putting things together so if there's a
way to put things together there's also
a way to break things apart and here
we're seeing our carbohydrates or sugars
broken down to glucose glucose can be
assembled into starch
which is a complex glucose chain of
molecules see the same thing here that's
being broken down proteins being broken
down to amino acids
you see citric acid cycle you see fatty
acids being assembled into more complex
fats and phospholipids so as you can see
it's a very complex system that
everybody has to simplify a little bit
more there's mechanical and chemical
digestion mechanical and chemical
digestion of food takes place in many
steps being in the mouth and ending in
the rectum and this provides another
quick summary of where mechanical and
chemical digestion occurs in the
different regions of the body so good to
kind of review that and have an idea of
what's being broken down where in
digestion handles each nutrient
differently so there's not just one path
that we can run all nutrients through we
had in the max hydrolysis again taking
our more complex molecules and breaking
them down we see proteins into amino
acids carbohydrates and the
monosaccharides nucleic acid into
nucleobases lipids ultimately into fatty
acids they can be reabsorbed we see the
liver playing a very important role here
have their lymphatic system here with
blood fibre and cellulose being broke
down into T C's large molecules our
digestion before absorption occurs so we
need to break them apart before we can
absorb them in the body they can be
absorbed some can be absorbed without
processing but many require special
transport for this to occur in digestion
breaking the molecular bonds into large
organic molecules carbohydrates proteins
lipids and nucleic acids our main
macromolecules process called hydrolysis
it's divided into target classes so
looking here we see proteases amylase
nuclease lipase all of these are enzymes
breaking things down
nucleus breaks and nucleic acids amylase
breaks down starch or carbohydrate
protease breaks down proteins lipase
breaks down fats for lipids so we can
see an example also here of what's
occurring in the esophagus the stomach
the liver the pancreas in the small
intestine see that pancreas is we may
not be familiar with does have a lot of
important enzymes to be released there
not as many in the stomach as some
people may think pancreas is very
important for that friend releasing
enzymes lastly here's our general
digestive system overview couple key
points issues should be familiar with
the mouth the pharynx esophagus and
stomach the small intestine the large
intestine hole in the rectum how are
these involved in the elementary canal
and what accessory organs are doing and
how they're important for a normal
function digestive system