in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over digital monitoring
systems for indoor cannabis
production
[Music]
all right let's get into the details of
digital monitoring for environmental
conditions in a cannabis production
facility
so first off the advantages of digital
monitoring systems is that they're often
uh offer very precise readouts they can
be preset with
minimum and maximum levels for alarms
that can alert the grower when something
gets out of the
intended target range they're also very
easy to read
which makes it great for people who have
to go through and document if there's
multiple shifts of people coming through
a grow area
uh digital precision so what's the
advantage again of these
digital systems well these digital
readouts provide precise readouts this
can be important when small details can
cause an
impact on the growing operation it can
also offer
the advance of having multiple sensors
in the same area to help gain an idea of
the potential
microclimate that may exist you can have
multiple sensors all feeding into one
computer
all one data logger able then to see
what's the temperature
closer to the container level top of the
plants above the lights below the lights
near the door
this can allow for a great accumulation
of
information and very precise information
as well
uh digital monitorings can also
self-monitor so that means that they're
able to go through and
it can be preset to provide more of a
hands-off approach to help ensure that
when conditions get out of range
an immediate reaction can take place
when temperature gets too
high you can immediately kick on a
potential alarm or potential sensor
or a fan as well this can also apply to
making preset adjustments
at certain times or given certain
conditions and this can help again
create the more ideal environment for
those plants
more consistently over a longer period
of time
now those digital readouts again in
operations uh that have multiple workers
due to rats can be preferred
simply because there is no
interpretation needed what was the
humidity when you walked in what was the
temperature
well it was the last 24 hours min and
max as we can see right here it offers
it very precisely
there's no trying to read where is the
line compared to to the dial so to speak
however despite the advantages of the
digital systems offer
many brewers invest in a full digital
system but may also have some analog
monitors to provide a backup
just in case something was to go wrong
what if the battery is tight what if
they lose power
having an analog system is usually
provided by a lot of growers as a simple
backup to their digital systems however
where digital systems should be used
or higher priorities for digital systems
would be ph because a tenth of a point
can make a large difference
carbon accident enrichment as you can
see here making sure we're getting to
the right parts per million
and then light levels to par reading
where
digital sensors can be used but are a
little less to a degree
our temperature in humidity long as
you're generally close
that might be good enough but as you can
see here some of the sensors that are
also doing some of these other things
also can log temperature as well as
relative humidity
so good again more data can be a good
thing here to log that
lastly though just to keep in mind that
no matter what system you're using a
sensor is only as good as its placement
there's additional video here on tobacco
university to go over where to place
sensors
that's very important to ensure the
reading you're getting
is going to be representative of the
growing environment