okay here I'm gonna go over dihybrid
crosses so if you've seen the punnett
square of basics this builds on that and
could see those were just monohybrid
crosses this is dihybrid we see our
punnett square getting ever larger here
so first off a dihybrid cross involves
two traits in a four by four punnett
square the example is a pea plant that
is heterozygous for round yellow seeds
itself fertilized what are the
phenotypic ratios of the resulting
offspring as we see here
so heterozygous round and yellow seeds
so heterozygous for yellow also what
happens if we cross two of these
individuals together we know how we got
that trait by in this case showing this
potential outcome for the cross working
out this f1 generation and what we need
to first do is determine the parental
genotypes and then the offspring where
the gamete of these can produce to
derive the gametes we're gonna use the
foil method and that's from math class
first outer inner last see this
distribution that occurs so as a result
from this heterozygous and heterozygous
traits crossed together two individuals
two parents both heterozygous for these
traits notice that parent one has big R
we go through and we cross it with Big Y
so to our big R and her big why the big
R also gets distributed though to our
little Y so big R little Y the first
parent then we need to also recognize
the other allele in this case the
recessive the little R little R goes to
Big Y and then little R goes to little Y
this is parent one now because they're
both the same the parent to us the same
potential gametes of her offspring so
big R goes to Big Y big art a little Y
little R to Big Y little art a little Y
these are our genotypes that we're going
to use in our 4x4 punnett square so in
this case this has a little slightly
different example but we did find that
would be the gametes for those
individuals now we're looking at
slightly different trying to make this
example a little bit easier we have our
gametes here and argument from this
parent was all homozygous recessive so
it makes it a little bit easier when we
go through and figure out this example
punnett square and just as we saw in
punnett square basics we did the same
cross the same drag down so big R would
be here here here and here
but we remember big art with little R
big R little R so on and so forth how
this is gonna end up looking is like
this now a lot of students I find put
the R and then do the R on the Y and
they are on the Y that's not how you
want to represent you want to put like
alleles together so in this case our big
R and our little R or put together our
big Y and our little Y are put together
go back and look that would stand for
around in yells be the phenotype because
round is dominant yellow is dominant and
we notice that carry through throughout
the same here you can remember this
individual different in the initial
example here is homozygous recessive but
you notice all the RS are kept together
and all the Y's are kept together the
reason we use that for organization is
when I ask for phenotypes or asked to
give the phenotype it makes it much
easier to follow and understand so
providing this with a little bit of a
picture here the cross this is the
homozygous recessive individual opposes
rough and green crossed in this case
with almost I guess dominant smooth in
yellow the results in all plants will
produce this heterozygote here and we
see that example here now looking at
taking these individuals and crossing
them together in the f2 generation and
here is our heterozygous and
heterozygous crossing those together
this are resulting offspring the cross
between two individuals from the f1
generation increases variation due to
the heterozygote and we can notice here
basically forms a 9 2 3 2 3 2 1 ratio
and we see that represented right here
again remember that yellow is dominant
so it's smooth rough in green would be
the recessive you see one individual
here from these two heterozygotes would
be that rough in that green color so I
know this is a little bit difficult to
follow maybe initially but if you go
back over and look at some of these
examples and follow where these gametes
come from either it'll be easier to
understand this is putting it all
together in a dihybrid cross
we have the initial generation the f1
and we take to these individuals who
went across and then together and that's
where it gets a little bit more
confusing and that's where we get to
this 4x4 remember the gametes are
distributed big R with big Y big R with
little Y little R with Big Y little R
with little Y in the same hand we just
simply drag and cross them together keep
like alleles together and a be a whole
lot easier trying here with some video
links if you want some to hear from a
couple other people some other ideas
some other great videos to watch we are
welcome to enjoy these supplement the
information presented here