in this debaco university video we're
going to go over direct soil planting of
cannabis so we're going to describe some
of the content some of the key things
advantages and disadvantages to consider
as well as show you
this actually happening in practice
[Music]
all right let's get into direct soil
planting of cannabis
so first off seeds can be direct seeded
but you do want to take some limitations
with those so while seats can be direct
seated it's often not done with cannabis
simply because of the elevated
temperatures that cannabis tends to
prefer to germinate
so yes it could be direct stated but may
not be the best practice
definitely depending on your location
seedlings or clones can be
is typically what's added to a field of
cannabis and they may be originated from
seeds
but as far as going right in this soil
and planting seeds
probably not initially at least advised
direct soil planting the advantage of
this
practice is that it's the ease of
planting and lack of need to supply
growing substrate
from outside sources plants can develop
deeper root systems and plants will
often require
less water we're looking at kind of
cannabis seeds this would be kind of a
good general
collection here of what would be
considered at least based on visual
inspection mainly higher quality seeds
you want to see that nice darker brown
some of that kind of like it looks like
a little veining like appearance there a
little shattered glass like look
um that dark coloration do they should
be pretty hard um
in solid there we don't want to see a
lot of white seeds or a lot of tan seeds
overall
simply because that darker brown
indicates that more fully developed seed
now the disadvantages of this kind of
method is that the soil
does need to be prepared ahead of time
and if the soil is waterlogged this can
stunt the growth of plants
weed control can also be an issue with
any outdoor operation
however let's take a look at this kind
of process going through
for direct seeding cannabis plants so
here we're looking at the planting of
cannabis clones
in soil and some seedlings here as well
and we can see that we're setting up the
field
so again field prep is very important
it needs to be a lot of organization and
that starts with getting your equipment
ready ahead of time
this could be large equipment or it
could be very simple equipment as we see
here simply
measuring devices shovels rakes the
basic hand tools
you can see everyone here getting ready
on the morning going through and rock
picking now the soil was very dry
so when we're going through and roughing
it up to till it initially that's why
you saw the person there
wetting the surface down just to reduce
some of the dust there you can kind of
see them chasing them
with the hose there and as we're going
through and kind of tilling that top
layer
rock picking you see on the left there
that weight string and we also have a
little auger
on a hand drill because it's going to
initially set the holes
how do we keep the whole space well
there's just a simple little steak
with a bamboo stake and two people can
easily go through
ensure that there's consistency down
that line in spacing
because that's very important when
you're talking about field applications
overall
it's a very large field you want to make
sure holes are very consistent
because it gets very easy for them to
get off you can see there we've
completed one row
and we've moved the string there to the
next row now looking at the field we
want to be mindful of the edges of the
field we can see a lot of rocks on the
edge of the
edges of the field and that indicates
kind of what we're running into
here in the main field you can see those
initial first two rows there
working right along and we're putting
the clones and seedlings
right in down the little line there we
can see everyone now working through
that initial area
uh finding sadly a couple more rocks i
think then
most people would like to find when
you're going through in
seating a particular field there again
working through
everyone's got their little job to do
and trying to make it nice
consistent and efficient of course we
have to bring in some more that manual
labor to kind of bring in and
pull up some of those rocks but once we
got the holes dug we can see
the little cannabis plant right there
going right in full nice blue valve root
system right along the strings
and adding in some initial amendments to
that planting hole
and they're going through easily and
covering it up making sure everything's
nice and consistent there and of course
knowing how many plants you have
and the spacing of the holes is also
very important
and you will notice that they're hearing
a lot of that kind of ting ting
there is a lot of the rocks here in this
particular area
trying to remove as much of those as
possible uh trying to you know plan
ahead
best if you can but try to keep that
spacing even
we see the two uh containers there they
look like drinking glasses they kind of
are but they're really meant to
ensure that the amendments added for
planting hole
are nice and consistent it doesn't have
to be a perfect measure
but kind of putting a mark there ensures
that there's some sort of consistency
going on
also allows growers to plan in the sense
that they know exactly how much they're
going to be utilizing they don't overbuy
certain amendments
or they're buying just the right amount
now as we're looking at that
continuation of the process going on
and see a lot of people working through
here again trying to have those
tasks made ahead of time sadly finding
more rocks than we'd
like to kind of initially thought we
were going to run into
but everyone's got their job to do and
it's going quite efficiently
which is the best you can do and luckily
this was a relatively cool morning
we can see the amount of rocks on the
side which is an indication sadly
we're going to run into there's a kind
of one of the cannabis plants there
again they're nice and consistent they
were ready to go in they were delivered
on time
because this is an outdoor operation so
keep in mind we also need to be aware of
our timing
and you can see here we're running into
a couple larger rocks with a couple
larger holes now we've got the plant
number uh precisely measured so we're
not over planting the density
and ensure everything should be
hopefully allocated out very equally
however as i mentioned those rocks and
here the surface got some small pebbles
and
rocks that's perfectly fine but going
through sadly running into some
larger rocks and when a little rock
becomes a big rock
well you want to go through and
typically bring in the larger equipment
as you can see here
this is an example of what was thought
to be initially a small rock we're
starting to dig around it
and it simply became larger it kind of
went sideways which is never a good
thing and when that rock doesn't budge
uh that's a sign that might be even
larger this was a field looking at some
of the history that there were some
trees as well
there were some additional roots in this
area we'd see a couple of those
rocks initially excavated out there but
plenty of them
in this particular location there it's
kind of good about that practice it
allows you to go through and see the
full soil profile as well
see what consistencies or
inconsistencies may
exist and this is why i want to be
mindful
and try to plan ahead as far as taking a
soil test ahead of time
having all that equipment ready to go
having the plant number
again not all that does everything
always go to plan with outdoor
operations
because there's a lot of variables not
only in the weather
but just in the conditions where you
might dig a test hold one area and
everything might go fine might find a
couple rocks perfect we'll just dig
those
out well here was one particular spot
that there was a large boulder found
so working through always nice to have
equipment
and to be able to go through and ensure
able to plant
the cannabis clones so hopefully you
enjoyed that and look in the video
description