welcome to this tobacco university video
where we're going to be looking at
direct seeding cannabis and using
mechanized planters for cannabis growing
at a large scale and while it is this
will be a talk specifically on canvas it
this has been used for many other crops
just here applying it to cannabis
[Music]
all right let's get into the video here
so first off we have to consider
uh germination and just the basics of
that this in the sense that you're
getting a seed from a certified source
keeping that temperature in the upper 80
upper 70s to low 80s
fahrenheit mid 20s to upper 20s degrees
celsius
moisture level around 90 percent
relative humidity air
roots and plants still need to breathe
and respire so about 10 percent
planting depth you only want an eighth
to quarter of an inch deep or three
millimeters to six millimeters deep and
light 150 300 power reading
particularly if you're growing indoors
outdoors they really don't have a choice
they'll have to toughen up relatively
quickly now timing of planting you want
to ideally
match ideal conditions i put ideal
conditions there in quotes because
while the weather cannot be controlled
trying to time the planting around
when it may be similar to ideal
conditions will help ensure maximum
chance of a good field stand
you don't want to knowingly plant all of
your plants in conditions that are not
favorable
sometimes that does happen but at least
you want to put the odds in your favor
looking at weather data looking at
timing of year
so hopefully you can time it with a good
weather pattern that you might be
experiencing in your area
so springtime so while planting dates
can partic
partially be determined by weather
however knowing what type of cannabis
category you're using will influence
your decision
what does that mean well using
autoflowers you want to try to select
the most ideal 70
days of the growing season for outdoor
production if you're going a photoperiod
dependent you want to be mindful of when
the photoperiod will change to know how
long your plants will stay in veg
before naturally going into flower
through the natural pattern of
reducing the light or light duration
that your plants will be experiencing
now utilizing feminized seed so when
seeding a field
to avoid half the field being
essentially wasted by producing
male plants you typically want to start
with feminized seed is highly
recommended
some growers may choose clones but here
we're focusing on looking at if you're
starting with
seeds realize though if you're using
feminized seeds
and if the seed is 99 female or
feminized
this means one out of 100 plants will be
male on average
so just keep that in mind like and then
it's close enough
um one out of 100 on average will be
a male so as a reminder 99
is not a hundred percent when there's
100 on average being male this means if
you grow 6 000 plants
and typically field plantings are quite
large using feminized seed
there will be still 60 male plants in
the field so scouting in colonies is
still a necessary process because having
60 males
in a planting of 6 000 might be enough
to produce quite a number of seeds
and reduce your overall cannabinoid
production
we're using mechanized planters so the
size consistency is important to help
reduce the chance of having skips
or doubles depending on your seating
equipment there might be
computers to help keep track of the
skips or doubles
skips is where that seed doesn't get
planted and doubles is where two gets
planted where one should
so this might take some time to kind of
dial in your equipment
however once dialed in this the method
can be very efficient
but be sure to take into account your
soil conditions particularly
on the day that you're planting or also
if you're going from field to field how
conditions may change
the field preparations are a critical
part of the process so consistent
conditions will aid in the formation of
an eaten stand or
referred to as plant emergence if you're
mechanizedly planting the actual seeds
be sure the field is ready for seeds in
advance of planting
this could be seeds or even looking at
seedlings in some cases the preparations
can be done soon
before planting or even just before
planting to limit your trips in the
field and the cost of production
so now we're going to look at an example
of a field that's been mechanized
planted
with small recently emerged seedlings so
you can get an idea of how this
actually looks on an actual cannabis
field enjoy
this show is a large scale hemp
production field
with its drip irrigation cannabis plants
spaced about every three feet
drip lines emitters are every one foot
approximately
you can see just the size or scalability
of this type of system