welcome to this tobacco university video
when we go over directly transferring
your canvas clones upon arrival to both
outdoor as we see the image here as well
as indoor situations
[Music]
all right now that you've got those
clones let's go through the transfer
process once they arrive
so first off when clones first arrive
you want to be sure to inspect the
clones make sure they're in good shape
and can handle
any transfer stress that they'll be
going through and this can be a very
efficient method typically you're
inspecting the tops of the plants as
well as pulling a couple samples out and
also inspecting the roots don't be
fearful some of the lower leaves are
kind of yellow or off in coloration that
can simply be because of if they were
packaged or grown together really
closely they might be getting enough
light that's fine but a good root
structure and a good top growing point
are all good things indicating that
those clones will be able to survive the
transfer process and grow into
full-sized plants
you want to make sure the clones again
have those quality roots so what are you
know when you're looking at quality
roots if the roots are not fully
developed this would be a reason to
potentially hold off directly
transferring your clones to the grow
site so if you have only a couple routes
coming out or routes that are kind of
weakly established might want to hold on
to them on an indoor environment before
you go through and transfer them to the
outdoor environment or hold them in a
propagation environment before they go
into a vegetative
stage of a grow tent it's gonna be a
little bit more stress for them you can
hopefully ease that transition get them
ready before they make that jump to the
next stage of development
now if we're growing outdoors weather
can influence how the direct transfer is
or when you go about that direct
transfer now transitioning plants from
the initial arrival to an outdoor
growing location may be best on a cool
and cloudy day this will help reduce the
overall stress the initial planting day
so if i was looking at this kind of
weather forecast looking at right here
we see some rain it would be good for an
outdoor location got to get the ground
saturated couple days of drying and
warming up that soil and then these
partly cloudy days would be great days
to transfer it followed by showers this
will help ease that transition of your
newly arrived clones
and this is all part of the process of
easing that transition so you don't want
to panic there's some color changes when
you make that transfer both outdoors or
indoor situations stems may even turn
purple indicating initial transplant
stress but especially if planting in an
outdoor environment don't take this into
a major reason for concern
those plants are just making that
adjustment to your growing environment a
lot of times that purple coloration will
go away the plants will start to
establish themselves and that will all
be just a history in the past now if
you're in an indoor location
it's a little bit easier because you
want to watch the initial light
intensities to reduce the chance of
burning your tender plants leaves so you
have a lot more control over that the
lights are not dimmable simply putting
the shade netting between the plants and
the lights can work
that thin little sheet can help reduce
the chance of leaf damage or if you have
a taller grow tent you can bring the
lights up so they're further away as
well
keep any materials closer to the plants
and the lights to avoid the chance of
fire so again if you're looking at
putting shade netting you don't want to
drape it over your lighting structure
you may want to put it just above or
support it just above your plants to
reduce the chance of anything catching
on fire so you have a nice safe growing
environment for both the plants as well
as yourself and surrounding environment