okay here we're going to look at some
diseases of concern for tomatoes elicit
kind of the major ones to be on the
lookout for here provide with a couple
pictures and if you can't identify these
pictures you'll see them a later in the
presentation well starting with our
diseases we won't look at initially how
to control them well there's the organic
standards and then there's a chemical
options for the organic standards
typically the use of copper should be
limited even though it is Omri certified
because it doesn't contain carbon and
can persist in the soil but is a good
option to have on hand in addition to
oxidate regalia in grande evo for
chemical set options it's not to say the
worst of all the options if it's used
with the careful IPM program integrated
pest management practices staple
chemical products would be something
like a Bravo
which is a cloth I know Manzi and topper
in the form of cosine 3000 which is not
army certified it has shown some
effectiveness now looking at the
specific diseases well one is powdery
mildew so what to look for is white
fluffy spots in the leaves and when
you're inspecting your plants well it
for shaded areas under leaves where
there's not a lot of sunlight
penetration and also high humidity and
moisture content how to prevent this
while spacing your plants out about to
reduce the leaf wetness and pruning can
also help with this throughout the
season how to control organically 40%
milk and 60% water can be effective as
well as oxidate which doesn't last very
long is an option in magelia chemically
rally 40 worked pretty good last year
and Bravo
Alton area or early blight will look
like this it's small black specks
located on lower leaves lesions and
everines like a tree so you kind of see
here we have this distinctive kind of
rings that's a key part for identifying
it to have early blight how to prevent
this will limit soil splash onto the
leaves and ensure good light penetration
oxidate or copper for organic Bravo
Manzi or copper for chemical control
options late plate so this one gets a
lot of attention I get a lot of girls
that think they have sleep lights so pay
attention to the specific images and
some of the key concepts here for late
blight lesions usually start
on both the leaves but can progress to
fruit in stem so typically people will
see them on the leaves first but it can
progress to the fruit and also the stems
typically occurs as large spots and not
small pinpoints see here a large portion
of the Leafs infected common during heat
waves and later in the season how to
really prevent this well resistant
varieties is a good first step
typically those seeds will cost more but
it's worth it if late blight does come
in and later in the year organically
copper and oxidate can be used oxidate
snot great coppers pretty much the only
option chemically if you can use mint
kazab that has been shown effective some
key images or classic symptoms I should
say for late blight would be the entire
leaf you see here looks perfectly fine
there's just one large lesion here but
see I have some other leaves it's also
on the stems also looking here at the
tomato this is a large area here that
it's infected I provided a link down at
the bottom if you want to look at some
more information about late blight in
particular bacterial spec so these are
very small dark specks that are circular
these small little dots they can be seen
both on the leaves and also on the fruit
you want to avoid soil splash and
because this is a bacterial fungicides
won't work very well so applying a
copper would be advised you could see it
kind of be consistent none of us is a
farm that I visited you could see how
it's very consistent in the lower leaves
and when you zoom in you see these small
little specks this would be bacterial
spec for distilling millet another one
affects the lower leaves they'll click
they're kind of burning there's a very
similar look to like a few cerium the
key part here is to rotate crops and
panel resistant varieties because
there's really not much you can do for
verticillium once you get it in season
because it is a systemic disease lastly
here is leaf mold it's a fuzzy kind of
top and bottom to the leaves but
especially look at the underside of the
lower leaf surface because you'll have
these kind of lesions that appear here
you're just looking from the top you'll
see kind of what looks like the
yellowing flip that leaf over and you'll
see actual the leaf mold there it's very
common in high tunnels in fields where
there's a lot of moisture a lot of
hanging fog early in the morning we want
to inspect transplants before they go
to the field if they are started in the
greenhouse or high tunnel maybe make an
application in there if you see it
before they go out to this field have
good air circulation and avoid feeding
plants with a lot of nitrogen can help
reduce this problem oxidate and Bravo
would be two methods that you could
apply to help control this disease