okay I'm gonna go over some diseases of
concern if you're growing squash include
a kind of a little list here of some
very common ones as well as some
pictures I've taken in the field
try to give you what these disease is
actually look like in farm fields to
give you that way to compare if you're
seeing something so first one we start
with this powdery mildew a very obvious
one if you're growing squash these fuzzy
white spots that typically occur on the
underside of leaves and shade your areas
key part when you're trying to control
this is to try to increase air
circulation and also apply products at
regular intervals now you want to start
at the very onset of this disease which
if you haven't seen it in your scouting
and you're into that first week of
August in southern New England probably
want to start your applications then
anyway this picture here I've taken in a
field where you can obviously see the
powdery mildew this is evidence of a
grower who's been making spray
applications as you see the center
portion of this leaf here where spray
products particularly organic ones that
work on contact only will collect you
don't see a lot of spores on the areas
where the Leafs curl up you see a lot
more higher evidence of these fungal
spores this is evidence of growers been
spraying and making regular applications
which is a good thing even though you do
see powdery keeping up those regular
applications is advised
now downy mildew somewhat much more
severe one it produces these yellow
lesions on the surface in the inner
cycle canopy this gray and tan fuzziness
now what makes this worse than powdery
as powdery lives on the surface of the
leaves downy is an internal disease so
printing resistant varieties and
planting early in the season can help
you get by potential late season downy
mildew threats because that's where it's
more common to occur cucumbers get all
the different strains of downy
other subsets which in the squash
categories it as watermelons and
pumpkins they are not susceptible
necessarily to all the six strains of
downy organically there's not a lot of
options
chemically you're looking at a systemic
like a phosphate and if you make an
application and it progresses after
about three days you want to make an
application with a different chemistry
and if that doesn't work then you may
lose the crop so keep an eye and
watching downy mildew trackers
talking with growers in your area this
is coming in pluck dysphoria produces
these white diamond street that legions
on the petals of the leaf it can
progress to the stems and also the fruit
itself usually not that much you can do
organically for spring copper products
that can help for chemical Bravo
chlorothalonil product to be the best
option then this is nice grand on this
off fabric here currents weeds and
allows for a clean harvest of the fruit
to cerium what to look for here is
wilting plants the vines and leaf stalks
will rot and the vines are cut ahead of
that rot internal veins you can look for
that orange kind of tan colorations we
kind of see developed here you want to
rotate your squash plantings with
monocots or grass species to reduce this
problem and also don't over irrigate or
over applying nitrogen as both of those
will encourage Fusarium to develop
bacterial wilt as the wilting of the
leaves as the name implies and this may
be the leaves may return to normal and
times of low light such as or at around
sunrise or just before the Sun
completely sets you want to prevent
cucumber beetle feeding on this occurs
because that is the main vector for this
and the control is harvest which you can
and then pull that plant out so that
other cucumber beetles no feed on that
infected plant pick up more the bacteria
and spread it to your other plantings
angular leaf spot you see here these
images are brown lesions on the leaf
that I follow the leaf vein causing that
kind of angular look to occur now this
can be seed born but it's also spread it
overhead irrigation if the catch of
early copper applications can slow its
spread in progression bacterial spots
also I want to talk about here you want
to look for small but numerous circular
lesions on the leaves and also can
appear on the fruit now it's not all
that common the high heat and moisture
can increase its spread and copper
applications would be advised because
fungicides will not work because keep in
mind this is a bacterial disease