so when I have a title that says the
distillation process we might be
thinking of distillation centers in
alcohol here with like a moonshine
copper still or the distillation process
here or we're taking heated crude oil
and producing gasoline or diesel or fuel
oil and while these two steps are part
of the distillation process and it's
basically separating substances out
based on different boiling points we
relate this to distilling or purifying
water so the distillation of water
results from boiling water into vapor
and condensing it back into a liquid
however this boiling doesn't necessarily
need to always have occur we can simply
evaporate water and condensed it into
clouds and then have it rain and then it
gets them to our rivers and streams and
lakes and then gets evaporated again
this is a natural process of the water
cycle so the distillation process while
we can kind of speed it along with
boiling the water and turn it into vapor
this isn't natural occurrence that
occurs as part of the water cycle now
typically when we're looking at the
apparatus required to form distilled
water typically takes a high energy
input to lose a lot of heat involved you
can see what the copper stills
temperature monitoring even here on a
lab a lot of energy required to heat
that water to boiling as a result though
it doesn't take a lot of energy it's not
a very fast process but the event is it
does produce as close to pure water as
just about any system out there so this
is important to keep in mind if you're
really trying to get that pure on h2o
this distillation process would be one
worth considering to try to get that
close to pure water as possible in
removing any potential contaminants and
impurities