okay here we're a look at the
macromolecule nucleic acids keep in mind
that this nucleic acid category is made
up of both DNA and also RNA we see DNA
depicted here on the right and aren't
affected here on the left we're gonna go
into a little bit of detail at how
you'll be able to distinguish these two
different types of nucleic acids so
starting off nucleic acids in general
the main function is to store genetic
information it's in the genes
it's a blueprint for the building of
proteins DNA will be transcribed into
RNA which is then translated into amino
acid sequence which will ultimately make
a protein this is responsible for
transfer of information it's a blueprint
for new cells and a blueprint for the
next generation see here are two parents
passing down offspring and the DNA or
the nucleic acids here will allow that
to be the blueprint for the next
generation to see certain traits certain
genes being passed on from the parents
to the offspring now on nucleic acids
here dNA stands for deoxyribonucleic
acid it's a double helix structure and
its structure was first proposed in 1953
about watson and crick RNA is a
ribonucleic acid it's a single helix
Lucy there's kind of one strand here now
both of these nucleic acids they're
monomers or what's the building block
for these in this case it's nucleotides
that's the building block for nucleic
acids here's a nice comparison between
our RNA and our DNA remember RNA is
ribonucleic acid DNA is deoxyribonucleic
acid sugar is ribose so we say ribose
and deoxyribose here that means without
oxygen for DNA and the sugar ribose here
has that oxygen built got into it the
bases are a GC in you for RNA and a GC
in T for DNA so what does this letter
stand for well that's adenine guanine
cytosine and uracil and I have that one
in blue cuz that's unique to RNA for DNA
we still had name guanine cytosine B
with thymine
and that's unique to DNA in addition
looking at these two structures we see
for the most part RNA is going to be
single-stranded for our purposes and DNA
is double-stranded so that's another one
you can't tell them apart key part here
if we look at our monomer unit our
nucleotides
your cell that immediately indicates its
RNA when we see thymine immediately
indicates that its DNA the distribution
of these nucleic acids in eukaryotic
cells well DNA is found in the nucleus
with small amounts in the manic Andreea
and also in chloroplasts if you're a
plant cell you have DNA in the nucleus
in a mitochondrion also in the
chloroplast animal cells we'll have it
in nucleus in the mitochondria in
contrast that RNA is actually found
throughout the cell so it's a plant cell
or an animal cells found throughout the
cell so RNA single-stranded basically
for our purposes or some cases we're
just double stranded and we should have
the big circle with the extra here as we
know Steinman is located so we can
clearly indicate that this is DNA in
that RNA seeing the presence here of
uracil up in this corner we see that
that is a characteristic that only RNA
has I mentioned for our purposes are
enabled be single-stranded keep in mind
that some viruses are actually
double-stranded it seems for
double-stranded RNA so it does exist
we're just merely going to look at it as
RNA being single-stranded commonality
between RNA and DNA
they're both negatively charged this
process allows gel electrophoresis to
separate DNA segments we'll do more
about this in the biotechnology lecture
series but what this basically means if
we apply a charge we have a positive
charge here
because DNA and RNA are both negatively
charged we'll be drawn to the positive
charge which allows us to separate out
fragments of these nucleic acids well
understand more in biotechnology why
that's important but for right now just
realize that they do have a negative
charge because of their backbone and
that allows them to be separated here
through the process electrophoresis
which is involving a difference in
charge and voltage