okay DNA fingerprinting as the name
implies is a unique look to DNA in this
case the fragments as you can see on the
screen it looks like of course I touched
the screen there and it's big
fingerprint here but we'll clean that up
a little bit later looking here at
deciphering out DNA and how it can be
unique to particular individuals and
what that can tell us all right so our
fingerprinting each person's DNA pattern
different it's a good question to ask we
have actually sections of what's
commonly referred to as junk DNA
it doesn't really encode for proteins
suite of repeated patterns each person
may have different number of repeats and
many sites in our 23 chromosomes have
different repeated patterns these
different patterns to set the patterns
on our fingers give us the what we call
the DNA fingerprint identify us as
unique this is just an example here of
looking at all the different G's and C's
College the different patterns that do
occur on how different individuals if
these two individuals have different
repeated patterns here I held those in
green see it hopefully stand out a
little bit better so do you need
patterns for a DNA fingerprint so we
have allele 1 and I've indicated a
couple things here are cut sites
remember our restriction enzymes are
cutting at very specific sites in these
in red and red are the same cut sites
the same restriction enzyme will cut at
both of those sites so we cut the DNA
you notice here try to separate it out
cut the DNA there a little bit here's
our section 1 our section 2 in our
section 3 how this would look and we run
a gel section 1 section 2 and section 3
but the yellow one here and our two
other darker regions here for allele 1
now differs between two people now we
have person 2 with more repeats I have
we go through we cut that section out
there's our section 1 or section 2 in
our section 3 and as we can see here
we're getting a different run of
these to cut sites one and three are the
same size but this section too is
different there's more junk DNA
essentially here causing it to be a
different run on the gel so our DNA
fingerprints are comparing our blood
samples of Defense clothing on that of
the victim you can see here's mom here's
dad and then we're looking at other
potential matches here on the offspring
and there are going to be differences in
offspring comparing because they're
through the comedy and a through
crossing over through independent
assortment and all that you're going to
get slightly different DNA sequences but
you're still gonna notice odds are some
similarities and the example here the
defendants blood the victim's blood and
then potential blood from defendants
clothes we're able again to develop this
fingerprint to get sort of a comparison
here we could see where victim's blood
may have gotten cross contaminated here
this is some of the power of genetics
that's used so this process is what used
to determine if two samples are from the
same source looking at DNA of two
sources of fragments with restriction
enzymes
remember those restriction enzymes cut
very specific regions fragments are
separated using the gel electrophoresis
and transferred to the filler and then
here we're able to probe and compare
them also used for evolutionary
relationships compare DNA samples from
different organisms to measure how
closely they may be related genetically
so we have our DNA fair sample to sample
three sample four and sample five
remember the larger segments are up here
the smaller ones are down here and this
allows us to see how a turtle a snake a
rat squirrel and a fruit fly all may
interrelate and what commonalities they
may have what may be similar on what
might be more distantly related so
medical diagnosis comparing normal
alleles to a disease allele here's a
chromosome with normal allele a disease
causing allele here we run those alleles
on the gel and we see they didn't do cut
of different regions the example would
be one of Huntington's disease we're
looking to identify those different
alleles again you say well they're the
same length right how can there be
different sizes to DNA fragments if
they're the same length while they are
in total the same length there's
different sequences in those restriction
enzymes are going to cut this different
portions giving it to different
fragments than this allele here
forensic siz where we commonly associate
things with comparing samples from a
crime scene if this has beckoned in a
victim here's our suspect here's our
crime scene sample I should say
volunteer here or our victim you know
and we're looking at three different
suspects so the victim typically will
volunteer with your sample we have the
crime scene sample and now we need to
determine potentially which one of these
three subjects if there's any
correlation or matching that occurs
suspect one suspect to suspect three
comparing to the crime scene sample so
we're looking for commonalities so
initially we look at this one we say
well suspect two and three both share
this however we need to compare all of
the bands to ver the true fingerprint
and we see as we get down here suspect
two matches not only this band but also
this band this band in this band became
suspect two is a very close match for
the sample at the crime scene that is
different than the victim and suspect
two is the most likely match here so
RFLP restriction fragment length
polymorphism and electrophoresis is used
in forensic science so we could be
getting a semen sample from a rapist and
a blood sample from the suspect running
against the standard and allowing us to
develop a sense of comparison of what
may match up because DNA fingerprinting
ZAR unique this can allow us to
eliminate other potential suspects and
get close to identifying an individual
or determine whether an individual of
interest has left DNA behind and
a potential to be there on the scene and
contribute something in some way so the
RFLP again these are just markers that
are used and we're looking at different
cut sites
remember those restriction enzymes are
going to read right along and cut very
specific regions as we see here there
are more cut sites indicating smaller
fragments here there's only one cut say
a very large fragment not running very
far in the gel so we can best do a
real-world example here and it's a
little Myrtle trial do you think the
suspect is guilty so here's our standard
manage what we're comparing so blood
sample 1 from the crime scene blood
sample 2 blood sample 3 and try to
indicate here okay I did get this
PowerPoint online look in the
description for the links ie where I say
the sources here I headed some pictures
which are also indicated as far as where
I got those so we're looking at it's a
little faint might be a little hard to
initially see but if we look at these
regions right here we clearly see
there's some bands occurring gender
marks there's some arrows there a blood
sample - from the crime scene and this
is a greater collection here and blood
sample 3 it's kind of those three
matching this match ding and mismatching
when we complain about sample 1 &amp; 3 we
see a lot of commonalities but sample 2
not as many so i'll blood sample from
the victim a little hard to see again
this image but very closely matching the
blood sample number 2 listed above bliss
you know from the victim here wow I know
it's a little bit of a different pattern
and blood sample from the suspect we
could see again the circles and the
colors hopefully try to match it up a
little bit closer and the blood sample
here was from OJ Simpson the victim here
was Nicole Brown and then Ron Goldman's
myself up here a little bit and we could
see where our suspects and victims in
crime scene how we're starting now to
develop a pattern of what we're kind of
seeing what matches up with a lot this
is some of the power that a DNA kind of
conserve
to try to help us correlate if someone
was potentially there because of the
unique fingerprints that individuals
have in their DNA and then on the Cobra
here so how Joe looks in real life again
that as you saw in that example they may
not always be perfectly clear there's
typically a DNA ladder loaded and that
tells us the what the size the bands are
that allows us to compare these thicker
bands here indicating there's more DNA
of that particular size present in the
sample you can see here they're not
always super easy to read so for
paternity test
here's mom's DNA here's the child's DNA
and we have two potential father mom
figures we'll hit determine which father
if any of these match up so his father
one there's fabric two compared to the
child - the child shares these bands in
these commonalities getting father to in
this case is the most likely father of
the child here whose DNA's been
sequenced so hopefully this was helpful
there's some other great videos on
YouTube you can also go through and if
you click on these links again the links
to these are provided in the description
go to the slideshow you can actually try
the process of PCR yourself virtually
and also electrophoresis my videos
posted on both of these that you're
welcome to look at hopefully supply you
some good information to develop a good
understanding