okay here i'm going to cover some
necessary dna
replication vocabulary you need to be
able to understand because these terms
will be used
as quote common knowledge in the process
of
dna replication we see a couple of them
labeled here
so if this initially doesn't make a lot
of sense hopefully after you watch the
video you come back to this
you'll be able to understand it more
fully
so starting with the basics of words we
have something called a helicase
it's an enzyme that binds to nucleic
acids and it separates or
unwinds dna into single strands this is
going to allow each strand to be copied
see the helicase here represented by
this triangle and that's taking this
double stranded
helix and separating out into single
strands
because we're looking at the process of
replication we know it occurs in a
semi-conservative way
we need to isolate each of those
individual parental strands into single
strands now when we're rejoining our dna
into the single strands making it that
double-stranded again looking
back in this region of the top lagging
strand and here down here the leading
strand
we have a process called annealing
that's when dna is rejoined
this can happen when dna is cooled as
well that annealing is just think of
it's like that sticking those back
together those hydrogen bonds are
reforming important vocabulary words
and these aren't necessarily words these
are numbers but really important to
understand the orientation
of dna we have a five prime that's what
the little
indication here is five prime carbon has
a phosphate group attached to it
and the three prime carbon has a
hydroxyl or oh
group attached to it so a lot of these
you'll see these little fives and these
little threes
this is referring to the number five
carbon and number three
carbon it's really important for
orientation
because there is a quote right and a
wrong way
that bases can be added so taking those
terms those 5 prime and three prime
terms and relating them to dna
polymerase
which is an enzyme that creates dna
molecules by assembling the nucleotides
this polymerase it's an enzyme ace this
is an enzyme that's putting things
together attaching nucleotides
it always synthesizes in the five to
three prime
direction so we see it looking here
here's the five
it's a three prime direction that's the
only way that
this enzyme can operate enzymes shapes
are very important
and these molecules we saw on the
previous slide can only bind in the five
to three prime direction
because it can only bind to and add
nucleotides to that three
prime end now when we're separating out
our dna we'll notice
that it is kind of like inverse one's
going one way one's going
the other way so when we have this
synthesizing in the five to three prime
direction
here's our leading strand the easiest to
understand because that's going through
and it's going in the five
to 3 prime direction now we're going to
say initially well what about this 3
prime here well because it has to be
anti-parallel
so we see a 3 prime here there's going
to be a 5 prime here and 5 to 3 prime is
perfectly
well how dna periods can go right along
and we see no breaks
in that sequence on this other strand
here we have a five primes we need a
three prime here
it cannot work in this same direction so
it's going to kind of work
backwards we call this the lagging
strand because it's going to work here
and get to the end and have to detach
and kind of come back over and bind here
and work again
there's these little kind of sections
these little fragments
these fragments are called okazaki
fragments and they're short dna segments
that form on the lagging strand during
the replication process
simply because that polymerase has to
work in the five to three prime
direction we can see here
helicase hasn't opened up the dna
molecule fully so it's working from here
to the end it's got a de-attach and
reattach here and come back this way
here the leading strand it can just keep
working right along because that three
prime
end is exposed and polymerase only works
in the five to three prime
direction we also have rna primers which
are very
short strands of rna that act as the
starting point they're kind of like the
little flags that say
dna polymerases start here and we have a
dna
ligase which is an enzyme that
facilitates in the joining of these
strands
ligase think of it as it links things
together it's
linking on those bonds together and
forming something very stable
which we want for our dna so hopefully
now if we look at our
beginning image here this makes a little
bit more sense we're saying leading and
lagging strands
and good vocab terms to review as we get
into the replication
process