looking at DNA methylation here looking
at the attachment of a methyl group
which is a ch3 component to a base pair
of DNA you can see it takes on many
different shapes here but methylation is
referring to the attachment of this
methyl group as we call methylated so a
methylated DNA molecule DNA methylation
is important for regulating gene
expression since its main purpose here
there's no change in the sequence which
is an important aspect to keep in mind
here that we're not changing the
sequence but we're still having a way of
regulating gene expression canopies
prevent genes from being expressed so
looking at these methyl groups being
attached here and indicated by these
kind of glowing areas on the DNA
molecule so during a gametogenesis
certain genes are methylated in tagged
as either maternal or paternal so how
does everybody know which one comes from
mom conclusion dad it can in some way
relate to the amount of methylation that
occurs developing I'm gonna read these
tags and express one version over the
other so genes that can be expressed
here's our promoter region in the kinam
gene can be expressed here's our methyl
groups methyl groups can cause students
to be inactivated in this case there's
nothing wrong here there's no mutations
that occurred but they're inactivated
because of the methyl groups attached
here kind of messing up that promoter
region not allowing those genes to be
made so methylation typically found out
it's called CPG Islands C in G should be
familiar with those are cytosine and
guanine so these citizen guanine which
areas are located upstream of the
promoter region if our promoter region
these are CPG Islands EB tree Islands
the P indicates it's a phosphodiester
bond so in humans methylation is the
result of DNA methyl transferase so
against an enzyme attaching these methyl
groups that's responsible for the
initial pattern during early development
and for copying the pattern during DNA
replication so not only does this occur
initially it can also be replicated
when DNA goes through that process and
our methyl groups typically represented
by these dark circles are unethical
aided groups by these open circles or
these white kind of circles here so this
phosphodiester bond not to get to too
much detail but what this is it's
between the nucleotides here and it's
which presents thymine and two molecules
of adenine so here's our thymine and
here's our two molecules aadmi this
phosphodiester bond is this what we're
looking at right here po4 the negative 3
in this case you can see right here are
thiamine and two molecules of adenine is
our phosphodiester bond it's occurring
now clone mice with different DNA and
methylation so genetically identical
individuals can look or behave very
differently based on the methylation
remember it's affecting the gene
expression not the sequence here we have
our two mice it looks slightly different
but if you look at the tails there's
definitely a difference in the tails
it's a nice normal tail here and this
one looks like it got run over or
something but this is because of the
methyl groups located in the tail region
of this mouse are altering the gene
expression so DNA methylation and probe
design so after a bisulfite treatment -
just a scientific treatment here we're
trying to determine what was methylated
or what was not the methyl group will
predict the cytosine otherwise would be
converted to year or so so this methyl
group when we have this bisulfite
treatment what's happening with cytosine
it would be converted to your cell under
normal conditions
that methyl group we know it's been as a
block it's like preventing that
bisulfite treatment from changing that
as a result cytosine is conserved after
the treatment they do would add a probe
and you would see if it would bind and
like in the case of the methylated probe
that G is gonna find that that C
indicating Oh lights gonna be given off
in the case if it was unmethylated and
if this unmethylated probe was added you
see this has nothing to bind to this a
is nothing to find that C just going to
be floating around this case it binds in
the original string
was unmethylated so this methylation
probe design as a way to determine
through a bisulfite treatment whether or
not these methyl groups were present
again if it was present it's gonna
prevent that cytosine from being changed
to a year so that's just the result of a
typical bisulfite treatment that methyl
group will block that and prevent death
from occurring and use a probe here to
determine and indicate whether that was
present or not so they called a cobra
combined by sulphide restriction
analysis adult stands for typically used
in microbiology labs it's a test to
determine DNA methylation levels short
general explanation into fall in terms
PCR which we'll learn about in another
video it's a quick way to multiply DNA
sequence and restriction enzymes cut DNA
at very specific locations so when we
have our groups here the little ends the
bisulfite treatment occurs the C's
stacy's because the methyl groups blocks
that and we use our restriction enzyme
digestion and breaks in this case the
DNA sequence and here it's unprotected
those methyl groups are not present
during the bisulfite treatment those
seeds are converted to hues which then
are transferred to T's and DNA and then
we have a restriction enzyme that will
not recognize the particular sequence so
this Cobra may have heard this term
Kerberos combined all side-by sulfide
restriction analysis it's how we
determine the DNA methylation levels and
what this is used for comparing normal
cells to cancer cells and notice the
cancer cells have elevated these levels
of methylation so doesn't that if it's
methylated it's cancer it's not the case
methylation levels are typically
increased in cancer cells here and
that's evident could see our cancer
cells a lot more peaks of methylation
levels than our normal cells here so
just one way methylation can help change
or regulate gene expression typically
located upstream of a motor vision