dna replication occurs in what we call a
semiconservative
method so i'm going to explore the
details of what does this actually mean
what's actually going on in the cells
when dna is replicated in the
semi-conservative replication
method so there's three possible methods
for replication there's conservative
semiconservative and then disruptive
well in conservative
the original dna molecule would be
preserved and you see that here where
the
parental dna is still present throughout
the first replication and also the
second replication
semi-conservative the daughter dna
contains one old
in one new strain we see that here where
original dna the parental dna we have
one old and one new
one and one new and that's replicated
throughout then disruptive where the old
and new strands are dispersed in
daughter molecules kind of in this kind
of random kind of pattern here
so the three possible methods for
replication
the one you really want to focus on is
this semi-conservative method
so how does it kind of look well this
kind of shows another rendition with
dark red and kind of a faint red
of semi-conservative where you still
have that one template strand
and then conservative or that original
strand is left untouched and then
disruptive where there's different
sections
keep in mind that conservative and
disruptive these little asterisks means
they're found not to be biologically
significant it's this
semi-conservative method that is the
process
for dna replication now evidence for
semi-conservative replication has been a
lot of
studies conducted to help prove this
here we have one where there's a
radioactively
labeled nitrogen base where we're having
this
nitrogen and we're going through and
looking at different densities over
different generations of e coli
we could see here that semi-conservative
is occurring because we have this kind
of blending
that's occurring we have this kind of
loss in percent of that original strand
on that original labeled i'm in the
sense and proving that
we have this semi-conservativeness going
on we have that original parental strain
but we have these new strands going
through
how does this look in like another
experiment well with any experiment you
could have predictions
and these predictions here show that we
have
what conservative semi-conservative and
disruptive would look like
so for conservative we would have that
same original strand
present at the end well that was proved
not to be the case
in disruptive we have that parental
strain but we'd have a continual
mix of them those splicings of those
daughter cells
doesn't occur this semi-conservativeness
we have that original parental strand
then we have that kind of replication
step where we're keeping that parental
strand
but we're getting new strands that are
developing this was found through that
radioactively labeling and allows
scientists to depict where did specific
molecules go
it allows them to trace them and this
kind of semi-conservativeness here
where we're seeing that original strand
all being this kind of heavy medium this
low in the test tube then we have this
kind of mixing we have this kind of
light medium it's kind of like
medium range kind of result and then we
have once we're making all of the new
strands which is made of that lighter
nitrogen we can see that blending of the
two
we see a lot of those new strands being
that lighter component but we still have
that
mixture of those original parental
strands for that first
generation those replication options
again kind of shows
the same kind of process here
semi-conservative you have those
one dark strand and one yellow strand
destructive there would be all little
different pieces
and conservative that dark strand would
stay the same and you'd only have
new strands so how does dna copy itself
well it's using that original base
here's our double helix
we're separating it out it's using that
original base as a
template which is very important because
it's able to use that template
it really reduces the chance of any
errors being made
now dna copying each cell division must
copy the entire dna sequence so each
star cell gets a complete copy
now the rate of synthesis is very fast
this kind of gives you that rendition
here
of seeing just how quick it kind of can
occur in bacteria they can do about a
thousand
bases per second and in mammals only
about 100 bases per second but still
a very quick overall kind of run through
here
as we see how quickly we can replicate
those dna strands
now the problem with a single
replication origin is that a bacterial
genome
is 4 times 10 to the 6th power it takes
about only
20 minutes to copy and we see that here
human genome
if we have that single point of
replication because it's so much bigger
would take 10 000 times
longer which would be basically
biologically just
inhibitive so as a result human genomes
many eukaryotes have these replication
bubbles or these multiple points
along the dna for replication to occur
not just one
single site now the copying solutions
region is an at that adenine and diamine
rich
allow easy separation remember those
only have two hydrogen bonds
eukaryotes have multiple replication
origins humans can have like 10 000
origin points and eventually these are
all meat getting into
our newly synthesized dna really helps
reduce the time
for this to occur so the copying
solutions a double helix to be copied is
through semi-conservativeness
which basically means one of our double
strand
one's being used as a template strand
and the other one is the
new replicated strand each daughter cell
gets one of the original copies
and then one of the new copies to help
reduce the chance for errors
unwinding at one point is used at the
replication site and in humans
and eukaryotes with long genomes
there'll be multiple replication sites
but they will all follow
this semi-conservative replication
method