here we're looking at the dna
replication process
and while initially this might look like
a lot's going on and that's true
i'm going to break it down step by step
for you
so starting here with the basics of the
process
so dna is double stranded and it unwinds
and there's two
unwound strands and there's a
replication fork that's where the
two strands are initially divided and
these new strands are formed by pairing
complementary bases to the old
strands we have that template strand
these complementary bases
uh being bound there to reduce the
chance for errors and make this very
efficient
in the end two molecules of dna we see
kind of at the end here are
create or made with each having one old
strand and one
new strand and this process is known as
being
semi-conservative replication
so how does dna copy itself well looking
back at that same image we saw at the
title slide dna helicase begins by
unwanting the nucleosomes we see here by
that little blue triangle
separating our double helix into
individual single strands
here the case untwists that double helix
and exposes those complementary strain
strands and the enzyme primase puts down
a short piece of rna
termed the primer keep in mind that rna
primer is kind of like the little flag
that says okay the dna polymerase are
going to start here
what dna's polymerase does is that reads
along each
single strand by adding the
complementary nucleotides
remember adenine binds with thymine a
binds with t and g binds with c
guanine with cytosine a
purine and a pyrimidine binding together
so this replication site may not does
not just occur in one area
this may occur in many areas and in fact
it does particularly for
eukaryotes each nucleotide strand serves
as a template building for the new
complementary strand
all these little bubbles will eventually
meet creating a replication
of the original form of dna in a
semi-conservative
nature now the process of dna
replication can be summarized
as that helicase first unwinding that
dna
then the primase putting down that short
primer we can see the rna primer
located right here and polymerase
reading along and adding
in the complementary bases keep in mind
that polymerase only works in the five
to three prime direction as it's going
through so this is a leading strand
that we're focusing on here now this
replication process this is
evolving dna copied by a replication
machine that travels along the
replication fork
that's where helicase is initially
unwinding the dna
one of the most important members of
this complex is that polymerase because
that is the one responsible for adding
the nucleotides
it's able to add those nucleotides
creating and making that new
dna sequence and we see that here with
them binding together
now realize that there is not just one
dna polymerase there's kind of a complex
of dna polymerases
but for right now there's no dna
polymerase is going through and adding
in those complementary forms of
nucleotides
now that polymerase all the interface
have two properties
only synthesize dna in one direction at
five to three prime
direction so in the dna vocabulary video
i talked a little bit about that
it's looking at the number of carbon
atoms there's carbons
atoms number five and number three you
can only add
to that number three carbon area so it
can only work in the five
to three prime direction now initially
you might be looking at this image
going well if it could work in five to
three prime direction
well why is it right next to the three
prime dna is actually anti-parallel so
we look at this bottom sequence here
here's a three prime
the other end of it will be five prime
here we see a five prime the other end
of that sequence will be three prime
because it's going to be anti-parallel
meaning it can only work in the five to
three prime direction this is going to
be
our leading strand because it's going to
be working towards the replication
fork and then this would be our lagging
strand because it's working away
has to detach and reattach detach and
reattach
these little fragments are called
okazaki fragments you can see all the
kind of individual components labeled
here
a being our template strand this our
leading strand
this is an example of our lagging strand
our replication
fork and our rna primer would be this
little kind of red region
we see located here and here and i
remember that's a little flag that says
start here
we have our okazaki fragments here's one
kind of independently here
but they would be on that lagging strand
now of those polymerases as i said
there's a bunch of different ones
right now you can just kind of focus on
polymerase doing this one job but
realize there are
four types in humans and three types in
bacteria
now this polymerase has a proofreading
mechanism built in which is great to
reduce the chance of there being errors
and checks for base matching making sure
adding spinning with thymine glotting
with cytosine
it will remove mismatched bases by going
backwards and ensuring that
corrections are made as it reads along
and proofreads
that dna sequence because we do not want
mutations to occur
the reason why it's not able to bind in
the
three to five prime direction is there's
no energy from atp
hydrolysis so this is looking at
the reason why it only works in that
five to three prime direction it's only
going to be binding to that three prime
end because you're getting that kind of
phosphate binding
now dna polymerase does is not 100
percent full proof it does make one
error in about
every billion or so bases so that is
important to remember that mutations
will naturally be occurring
but hopefully they occur in a non-coding
region of the dna so there's not any
chance of negative effects and it's
using that template strand there to go
through and build
that new strand now dna copying itself
hopefully now this is making a little
bit more sense here we can see this
some of those same images it could only
bind and strain in the five to three
prime direction remember that polymerase
can only work in the five to three prime
direction
uh indicating this is our leading strand
the
um is made continuously with one rna
primer and goes right along
the lagging strand here because it's
starting and detaching and restarting
and restarting
those are the lagging strand and that
has those okazaki fragments
and that's created a it needs multiple
primers
because here it started and it worked
its way to the end and have to rebind
here and rebind here
well now helicase is here once this
finishes detaching here it's going to
come back through
create another fragment here this is
because it can only work in the five
to three prime direction here just five
to three prime no problem because as
helicase is separating it's got a three
prime end right here it's adding the
next nucleotide adding next nucleotide
no problem this side a little bit more
of these fragments and ligase will be
needed to come in and bind those
together
now how nucleotides are added in that
three a five to three prime direction
they're only added to that three prime
uh remember they can only be added to
that three prime end
so here we see that three primeknits
where they can be added and built going
on
this way this is going away from the
replication fork and that's why this is
our
lagging strand and creating okazaki
fragments
so what happens at the lagging strand
well
okazaki saw one strand made continuously
determine that deleting strand and then
the other is that lagging strand
there's these discontinuous little
pieces known as these okazaki
fragments at least initially during the
replication process
during that replication process since
dna planets only works in that five to
three prime direction
continuously leading strain to
synthesize and this discontinuous
lagging strand
therefore we need dna ligase to splice
together these short
segments to create a continuous strand
of
dna at the end result and here's that
ligase going right through and just
binding them all together making sure
everything's
nicely fit together and stable so that
we don't have any breakage of the dna
in the newly replicated sequence here
rna primer is removed and replaced with
that dna to help bind everything
together so that there's
no evidence of what strand was the
leading in lagging strand at the end
ligase is the one that joins those
together and there is remember those
mechanisms for proofreading the dna to
reduce the chance of there being errors
no one occurs about every billion bases
so that dna replication new telomeres
are added
which are at the very end caps kind of
at the end of dna and they kind of
act as protective areas to those
chromosomes
this end getting of anything kind of
being at the end of a chance of being
damaged
this reduces the chance of damage
occurring to the central core
genome so simple animation of dna
replication we can see here his heel
case being the key that's separating it
out
we're going through we have our leading
strand going right along in the five to
three prime direction
we can see these little okazaki
fragments being developed here going
backwards and ultimately everything's
kind of being put together we see those
phosphate groups
again this one's the lagging strand we
have so we have ligase has to come
through and bind these together
and our leading strand going right along
the way lagnestry and binding those
okazaki fragments together
and ultimately what we'll have is a full
set of dna replication we had one
double helix strand now we have two