I was recently at CVS going through the
candy aisle when I flipped over one of
the labels and saw this where it says
product of Mexico I was a little
surprised at that and then as I looked
at some other candies on the rack you
notice there were other countries so
that asks the question do you know where
your candy comes from so the eight candy
said I was looking at and purchased are
the presented right here gummy bears
double bubble sour jacks peppermint star
lights so on and so forth but what
surprised me the most was these came
from totally different countries of the
world so I put a world map here so you
can take a look the eight countries with
little arrows highlighted here and going
through them these eight total ones the
first one Turkey is we're coming bears
come from
so the gummy bears here came from Turkey
product of Turkey kind of on second one
here Spain Spain is the sour of Jack so
these sour Jack's come all the way from
Spain the third one Canada favoring
country was the bubblegum the only one
of all these candies from the United
States worthy mini lollipops these are
the only ones that say product of USA
south of the border in Mexico thirteen
you saw before the jelly beans come from
Mexico Colombia down here
Colombia is where the winter remix come
from again a bit odd they've got a
travel all that way seven Argentina this
far down in the southern hemisphere
supplement not exactly sure why the
permit in Argentina but plenty of those
and the last one which is kind of a
little scary we're eight from China
strawberry kasi rope
came all the way from China a little
scary when it says reading food and it
goes through in the back and it is a
made in China we see enough stuff over
here in the United States made from
China getting our candy from China may
be worth caution that's with the dog
food isn't that we had of all these
eight different ones some are labeled as
being genetically modified specifically
on the lower area here down in that
lower area product of genetic
modification so a little hard to see the
side here produced with genetic
engineering and the date is there so
some of these foods do contain
genetically modified a lot of food that
we consume is genetically modified just
now we're starting to see the labeling
for it so I only made this video just to
draw your attention of all all these
like it's sitting on racks right in the
same aisle right in the you know think
they're all candies with all the same
packaging everything looks about the
same well if you start to look at where
it comes from you might want to
second-guess exactly where or what
candies you're purchasing so the
question is do you know where your candy
comes from