on this debaco university video i'm
going to take you outside we're going to
take a look at what different size
containers and the different size canvas
plants that they produced even on the
early stages because this is a question
i often get asked is what size container
should i be growing in and outdoor
applications have different
parameters than indoor growing
operations so we're going to see a
comparison between the 10 gallon about a
40 gallon container as well so you can
see in the image here the larger pot is
definitely making a significant impact
there could be multitude of reasons for
that but for outdoor production you
might want to be thinking a little bit
bigger than information you might be
getting from indoor growers so let's go
outside and let's take a look to see
our different container sizes and how
our plants are performing outdoors
[Music]
so growers often want to know what size
container they should be growing their
plants in here we're in an outdoor
location and these plants were started
in small little
containers and then what size you pot
them up to and how much kind of
repotting do you go through and do here
in an outdoor growing location that
should be kept to a minimum and
basically transplanted right from this
size to whatever your final container is
going to be now here we see a little bit
of a comparison we have a 10 gallon
grow bags right here and then we have a
larger one located right here it's
probably a 35 gallon uh bag here and we
could see just the difference
in plant growth that that larger
area is causing there to be a larger
plant now this doesn't mean that just if
we get 100 gallon pot it'd be that much
larger the advantage to the larger bags
in this outdoor setting now it is quite
warm today these smaller containers
they're going to heat up a lot more
that's going to cause your root zone
temperature to become elevated you know
we're going to be approaching 90 degrees
fahrenheit here today if not higher
so as a result that soil temp is going
to get much higher indicating that root
zone temperature is going to get warmer
anything above 72 degrees fahrenheit
really is detrimental to root growth top
growth can handle that we want to keep
that root zone cooler this larger
container allows a greater buffering
capacity allows this to take longer time
to go through and heat up as a result
that cooler root zone temperature will
allow the plant to actually proliferate
much greater than if you get a really
really hot root zone temperature you
might see this with clones if you're
going through and done cloning with
particularly aeroponics and you get that
temperature too warm you're going to
have issues that's going to reduce or
[ __ ] your total rooting and increase
your rooting time so just keep that in
mind that sometimes larger bags are
better but it's not a linear scale there
is that theoretical maximum there that
plateau
as a result that 45 gallon pot for an
outdoor growing setup with a compost
base
with some manure added to it medium
looks like it's performing a lot better
even in the early stages which i would
expect to progress as the season
continues