okay here we're gonna investigate the
domain Eukarya provide some examples to
show you how diverse this particular
domain is so starting with the basics it
appeared about 1.5 billion years ago
it contains organisms most people are
familiar with and they consist of four
kingdoms below the domain so first one
is animals plants and fungi and then
protist
the animals plants and fungi are well
defined evolutionary groups in a largely
multicellular protists are kind of their
own unique unicellular and very diverse
group here so all four of these though
are still under the domain Eukarya
but our four kingdoms within that can be
slightly different so Eukarya the
hallmark of eukaryotes is complex
cellular organization it's highlighted
by the presence of organelles
mitochondria and chloroplasts are the
most likely entered in early eukaryotic
cells through process of endosymbiosis
remember mitochondria descends of purple
bacteria and chloroplasts from its
cyanobacteria looking at this kingdom of
protists these organs are placed here
more because of what they are not been
what they are so this is kind of the
most diverse kingdom contains all
eukaryotes that are not plants animals
or fungi there's more than 50 thousand
species in all this includes unicellular
one as well as a few simple
multicellular eukaryotes this mode of
nutrition is how some of these protists
are classified so move around in search
of food
these are heterotrophic so make their
own food they're called autotrophs and
some observe absorb their own food which
are decomposers so these terms shouldn't
be that strange or foreign to you but
this just shows you some of the
diversity that does exist within the
kingdom of protists some examples
diatoms is a group of algae family
phytoplankton that looks very
interesting and if you look at some of
these they
have very unique shapes they're used in
art a lot
they're very symmetrical in some
instances and each are very unique in
this visual interest causes them to be
used a lot of posters or in a lot of
other mediums and these are diatoms
which are under the kingdom of protists
interest and other types of
photosynthetic protists are endemic of
some eukaryotic organisms see here this
prime example here's our coral which is
an animal and if you look inside this
animal we see there's an algae living
inside it so this is another example of
kind of this endosymbiosis and how these
two different organisms are coming
together for a common purpose ecology is
able to capture sunlight and produce
sugar from that and the animals able to
provide protection off of this algae so
chloroplasts enough symbiosis from our
chloroplast
are thought to be once free-living samo
bacteria that were engulfed by a
eukaryotic cell the presence of a double
membrane DNA both support this idea well
some other features but these are the
main two the sense that it was once
free-living and now incorporated into
the eukaryotic cell so a kingdom fungi
fungi are eukaryotes and most are
multicellular cells of fungi have cell
walls that contain the material called
chitin this includes molds and mildews
mushrooms in yeast chitin is also that
hard outer shell to insects or crabs or
lobsters or shrimp it's the same basic
material and they also produce some
mildews so they can be negative impacts
here on these grapes and yeast so cause
bread to rise we did a lab on yeast so
it was an example of an organism that
would be classified in the kingdom of
fungi within this kingdom of fungi it's
interesting is our heterotrophs and
obtain their nutrients by releasing
digestive enzymes into a food source
they absorb their food
after it's been digested by these
enzymes and broken down some they act
either as decomposers or as parasites in
nature this is kind of how they can look
here may have seen them
I'm bred kind of breaking that down now
these structures are very unique fungi
have things called hyphae and mycelium
mycelium are these large structures here
vegetative part of the fungus they're
clear composed of Heisei and it's a
collection that I pay is another way to
think about it looks like a patch of
threads or strands and function at the
macro level this would be an example of
mycelium specifically here this small
region here would be an example -
they're fine
branching filaments and they make up
mycelium there's a building blocks of
fungi may look like threads or strands
made function at the micro level so a
lot of times this to be the exact site
of nutrient absorption then my scene
would be the larger structure so our -
would be these very thin like straight
weak regions if we go back to the other
slide for a moment this would be an
example here of the mycelium will do the
proper term there'd be - this specific
region right here be hyphae this whole
thing would be mycelium and there's a
good comparison between the two kingdom
of plants plants are you care act mosses
multicellular in our autotrophs because
they carry out the process of
photosynthesis conversion of light
energy to sugars we're going to spend on
an entire lecture series on this process
it's very complex but plants are able to
perform this we see a very diverse
Kingdom here in our plants plants have
cell walls that contain polysaccharide
cellulose polysaccharide meaning many
sugars we see here Flint cells are
specialized for different functions such
as synthesis and transport of and
support materials the xylem and phloem
moving of water and sugars within plant
and here's our cellulose a very complex
polysaccharide composed of a long chain
and branched chain connected chain of
glucose monomers or monosaccharides this
is an example of kind of how the kingdom
is organized and how flowering plants
are considered more advanced and say
your losses or the rewards are
considered very simple in their
structure vascular tissue started club
mosses breasted ferns and we see seeds
we're gonna spend a lot of time on
classification of plants this gives you
a basic introduction of gymnosperms or
angiosperms being more advanced and
again here's our common green algal
ancestor and all of these plants are
thought of to have derived from that
common ancestor the kingdom of animals
animals are multicellular eukaryotic and
heterotrophic animal cells have no cell
walls this is a major point try to put
it in bold here black a cell wall so if
there's presence of a cell wall you know
initially eliminate the classification
or kingdom of animals some are currently
attached the surfaces such as sponges
and barnacles this includes fish birds
reptiles and tibias mammals and also as
humans the kingdom is also include
sponges jellyfish worms sea stars in
insects sometimes the jellyfish or
especially our coral and sponges here
are often thought of as being something
else other than animals so you can get
just beyond the kind of obvious animals
all of these are animals too