many growers go through and purchase a
drip irrigation system
but a lot of questions arise for how
long should i run it
what drip tape should i purchase here on
this tobacco university video
we're going to go over some of those
calculations to get you over and past
that learning curve
all right let's get into drip irrigation
calculations for outdoor cannabis
production
so first off realize that there are many
calculations that are possible
so many ways to go about calculating
water in regards to drip irrigation
the following that we presented here is
generally the suggested process to go
through
when it comes to planning for your drip
irrigation system not the only way
but it is at least one way and i'll walk
you through those steps
so first off step one is determine the
drip tape
required so take your plot design which
hopefully you've constructed
and determine the total number of drip
tape that you would need
are you looking at a very small area or
looking at a very large area
so for example if you had 12 rows of
plants each 80 feet long
12 rows 80 feet each you need 960 feet
of drip tape so again doesn't matter if
you're a small operation or a large
operation this calculation still needs
to be
gone through so you know exactly how
much to purchase
then step part two is to calculate the
source of water and your flow rate
so a simple way to calculate this is
simply get a five gallon pail
and a timer turn the water on full start
filling the pail up and start the timer
at the same time
when the pail is full stop the timer
this will provide you the time
it takes to reach five gallons take this
time and figure out how many gallons per
minute you have
you could also do this filled up right
to a gallon or two gallons
but kind of get you the idea of that
flow rate that you have so for example
if it takes 23 seconds to fill the pail
60 seconds 23 23.26 0.26 times the 5
gallons
would be 13.04 gallons per minute
it takes you 72 seconds to fill the pail
and again this is a 5 gallon pail
60 seconds divided by the 72 times it by
the five
gives you 4.6 gallons per minute
so it's a quick easy way to calculate
and what your flow rate is
now as a word of caution don't do this
right at the source if you have
filters or timers or anything that's
going to restrict the flow rate
do this calculation after all of that
equipment
so you're getting an actual flow rate
that's going to go to your drip tapes
then you want to select the drip tape so
there's a lot of different manufacturers
out there
but here we're just going to look at
some of the basics the emitter spacing
and flow
rate eight inch and minus spacing is
recommended for sandy soil
and high density planting so you've got
a lot of plants in a small area and very
sandy soil that water's going to
percolate through very quickly
eight inches would be recommended in
that situation however most situations
you're looking at 12-inch emitter
spacing is considered to be the standard
and we could see some of them listed
right here the flow rate there's low
flow and there's high flow
low flow is greater for longer run times
and allows for more tape to be run
uh is is the flow rate is restrictive so
low flow allows you to run more tapes
because they're flowing less water
high flow shorter run times for when
flow rates are not
restrict if you have excessive amount of
gallons per minute you can go with a
high flow and reduce your total duration
the plants will still receive the same
amount of water and here we see a
calculated
flow rate per 100 feet at 8 psi you
should be running your drip tape with a
10 psi
pressure reducer and we see the low flow
can run 700 feet high flow 460. so again
if you're a larger operation
sometimes that lower flow might be
advantageous
then the what's how long or what time
does it take
to apply um one inch of water
so here we're looking at time to apply
one inch of water in hours low flow
medium flow high flow rates emitter
spacing
drip tube flow rate drip tube flow rate
at eight
psi here gallons per minute per hundred
feet this is gallons per hour per
hundred feet
and the time it takes to apply one inch
of water in hours
a lot of times one inch of water per
week is considered to be the standard
and as an example drip tape with a flow
rate of 0.45 gallons per minute per 100
feet
will take about 5.8 hours to apply one
inch
of water so that would be running it for
approximately that just under an hour
every day would get you to that one inch
of water per week
and here again we see all the options
that we have which is great gets a
little confusing
but if you kind of go through and
determine what drip tape you're
purchasing what your emitter spacing is
this can again give you a very good
starting point
now situation one so i'm going to walk
you through some examples here uh if you
have more gallons
per minute from the source than is
required if you've got excessive amount
of water this is niagara falls
i don't have that much water but if you
have seven gallons per minute flow rate
and you're running 960 feet of drip tape
with a 12 inch emitter spacing
and you're choosing to get the high flow
drip tape which is 0.45 gallons per
minute per 100 feet drip tape
the time required to apply one inch of
water would be 5.8 hours
how do we go about calculating this well
drip tape flow
requires 4.32 gallons per minute again
we have seven
run drip tape for 50 minutes to deliver
216 gallons
running this for seven days equals four
point of
5.8 hours of a run time to match the one
inch of water per week recommendation
and it went through that kind of crash
but you can kind of go through and plug
in your own numbers and see how they may
fit
so you can determine exactly how long to
run your water for
again 50 minutes here times the 4.32
gallons per minute
gets you the 216 gallons which would be
about that one inch
per week now situation two is that what
if you have less gallons per minutes
than the source requires a little water
short same seven gallons per minute flow
rate but now we're trying to run three
thousand feet of drip tape
same emitter spacing same flow rate well
here now we're acquiring 13.5 gallons
per minute
but remember stated up here the source
can only supply seven gallons per minute
so there needs to be two
zones made with a valve so that 1 500
feet of drip tape runs at one time
run the drip tape for 50 minutes to
deliver 6.75 gallons per minute times 15
minutes
would equal 337 gallons running this for
seven days
equals to 5.8 hours of run time to match
the one inch of water per week
recommendation
so again here if we have 7 gallons per
minute but we need 13 and a half simply
dividing your area into different
zones will allow you to meet those
recommendations
and again this all comes back to
calculating your water source
so hopefully if you pause the video look
back at this it's going to provide you
with some helpful information
to go about applying your own flow rates
and drip tape to these calculations to
ensure your plants are at least starting
with
one inch per water per week and you can
make adjustments from there