if you're interested in learning more
about drip irrigation
this debacle university video is for you
[Music]
just as we see in the picture here let's
look at drip irrigation equipment for
outdoor cannabis production
so first off understanding with drip
irrigation is it can be
large scale or it can be small scale
it's important to know how many plants
you want to support with your system and
also what the layout of those plants
will be
because it will factor into the way you
design your system general
recommendations will be provided which
will include equipment
that is needed no matter the size of the
operation because whether you're small
scale or large scale
there's certain things with drip
irrigation you need to have
to make the system work properly so
first off what do you need we need a
filter
and there's high pressure filters which
will filter out dirt and other foreign
objects with a long
usable life span which is great having
stainless steel screen
and heavy reinforced frame allow for
reusability
and maximum durability and this is
important especially when out in a field
application
because you're going to be getting a lot
of stresses put on them
you don't want to have your filter fail
or break because you could jeopardize
the very small holes that you have in
your drip irrigation
keep in mind there are different sizes
and styles of filters allowing for the
proper one
to be selected for the intended
application that you have
and there are different mesh sizes
typically you'll find 155 or 200 mesh
filters
with the 200 mesh filter being the
recommendation
for drip irrigation applications so
others might be cheaper might be other
options
i'd recommend going with the 200 mesh if
you're looking at drip irrigation
there are different flow rates so ensure
that the filter is not the restriction
on the system
and typically you can upsize the filter
but make sure you're matching it
with the size piping that you have for
your system
now with looking at the system we also
have a psi regulator
a pressure regulator essentially pounds
per square inch regulator
for drip irrigation 10 psi regular is
necessary to avoid blowing out the drip
lines and if you think you can get away
with it you might get away for a little
bit
but if you're going much over 10 you
risk
the chance of blowing up the lines and
it basically sounds like a gunshot so
definitely don't want to be breaking
your lines 10 psi is kind of
the psi recommendation getting one that
can operate under constant pressure is
recommended as well those tend to be a
little heavier duty
and it may cost a little bit more
initially but can be worth it in the
long run
ensure that the inlet and outlet sizes
match the pipe or tubing that you intend
on using
using and we can see the one pictured
right here a little bit of the internals
that did you need to be aware of all the
internals but
just so you know what is kind of going
on in that filter or that
regulator i should say so the mainline
tubing this is another very critical
area and we see that right here
very large in this case it can be black
it can be white doesn't really matter
but what is important is the diameter
because that will be based on
the needed flow rate that can be
supplied by the system
check the exact tubing you will use
because many main lines either are not
rated for use under constant
pressure so it must be installed after
automated timers or valves
and all tubing is normally sized meaning
there's no industry standard really
refer to the inside diameter or the
outside diameter the id of the od
measurements for the exact tubing size
now what we notice here with this
large oversized is this is allowing a
very large field to be supported
potentially by limiting the number of
valves that are needed or the number of
zones that are needed to be allocated
with drip irrigation there are important
fittings to be aware of so
drip irrigation does need proper
fittings to allow for proper connections
in delivery of water
key fittings apart from effective system
include what's called the tape lock barb
fitting as you can see here where this
gets punched into the main line
and then the drip tubing will attach
here now we can have it here with a
valve or we can just have it free
flowing
the drip tape end plug particularly
important with thicker mill ratings of
drip tape
and it can be a foldable type or kind of
a plug that goes in at the end
on thinner types some growers may
tighten a knot but this is a little more
professional looking
and offers a very consistent and really
eliminates water loss
there's again the grip sleeve end here
different versions most growers now are
going with this type here
and then there's the tape block coupler
which is basically what happens or what
you need to have on hand
when you hit the drip irrigation with a
sharp tool or break one of the lines
there
basically you cut this you cut the area
there splice this in
and your drip irrigation will flow as
normal there's also a valve
option if that's fitting for your
operation now the drip tape itself is
how the water is actually delivered and
thinking you can think of it as
precisely leaky hose
even it's a little bit more complicated
than that it does allow for controlled
amount of water to be delivered based on
calculations
there's another video here on debacu
university to go over that
the benefits of drip tape reason why
it's so popular is it's very efficient
at watering
allows for uniform water delivery the
material is durable and can last for
many years if you get the thicker
15 mil for example and it can resist
clogging
in particularly if you're using a filter
ahead of the irrigation
it can be used above or below ground as
well so it offers some different
installation methods
now i say precisely leaky hose it's a
little bit more complicated than just
taking a pin hole in poking holes in a
hose
there is some inter kind of turbulence
that occurs
that does help it allow it to run for
very long
distances now when we're looking at
installing our
drip tape and we're kind of uh
installing it to the main line
we want to have a punch or to be able to
allow those fittings
those barb fittings go into that main
line there's many options
options that can accomplish essentially
the same task however pictured here
right here is what's called the miracle
punch and it's highly recommended
because it allows for
minimum fatigue and consistent results
if you're making five holes or if you're
making five thousand holes
i've used this myself and i really think
it is the way to go
save it it'll last for many years and
does make the process much easier
then there's hold down stakes and while
technically these may not be needed if
you're
there's a long run of drip tape that's
not under a plastic cover or
another method of support using cold
down stakes is advised
because if you get a high wind
especially early in the season all your
drip tapes that were
actually nicely spaced out go through
and start to overlap and they start to
twine and
intermix with one another which just
causes a whole mess
look for features such as galvanized
fittings these um hold down stakes i
should say that are six inches long
and u-shaped the u-shaped are wind
stakes and they're stronger than just a
traditional like a candy cane j-hook
as they hold down especially well in
heavier soils
they're typically offered in packs of 10
or 100 you can always get a couple more
there and put them all on the line to
make them easier to recover at the end
of the season
additional items that you may need or
you could use i guess i should say would
be timers
and they are optional we see a bunch
listed here but they're highly
recommended especially for larger
operations to offer consistency of the
plants
because this can allow growers to be
make better decisions
about making irrigation adjustments
there are also many of these may be able
to hook up to rain sensors so
plants aren't getting overly irrigated
with water
the basics had a setup here these
systems can differ yours may differ
but the basics are still the same it can
come down to the source of grower uses
and what they want the end result to be
you simply have that initial
water you have a timer potentially you
can have a backflow preventer
you want to have a filter or pressure
reducer as well fertilizer injector
is optional but recommended again and
then this connection to the header which
is in the main line there
so this is kind of just that basic kind
of simplified system
don't be kind of hesitant to adopt a
drip irrigation system because there's
new fittings there's different
components that are needed hopefully
this breaks it down it doesn't make it
quite as intimidating and allows you to
adopt this method for your own
irrigation setup
because your plants will like it and you
will like it once you get it all set up
because it's a very efficient
method it offers great consistency for
you
and the plants