welcome to this debaco university video
looking at drip irrigation specifics for
indoor cannabis production
[Music]
so as the image shows here here's some
canvas plants growing and they're
using a drip style irrigation system so
let's talk about some of the specifics
associated with this type of system
so first off the general basics of this
system
well drip lines are basically used and
with tubing as we can see going right
down the line right here
and its goal is to precisely deliver
water to the plants
and precisely deliver water plants in a
very even and consistent manner as well
this is often done with low pressure and
regulators
to ensure consistency even in a large
operation
as we see in the image here timers are
typically incorporated to allow for
automation
as well as potential for water sensors
to again help maintain consistency
amongst all the plants
now the advantages of drip irrigation
are that there's water savings
simply due to less waste there's also
reduced fertilizer loss to the precision
of delivery of to individual plants
and also the ability to automate to
allow for consistent conditions for the
plants
it's very easy to maintain a drip
irrigation system
and it also has a long life expectancy
of its components
so for all these reasons this is why
drip irrigation is
a system that's used by many growers
however there are some challenges with
any system and drip irrigation is no
different
so there's potential for salt
accumulation due to lack of waste or
leaching water there could be clogging
within the system
filters are not put in place or the
filters themselves could clog
if they're not checked leaks can also
often have
many fittings so be sure you're checking
the system for those leaks
and checking the system regularly should
be done in general
there's also a need for specific parts
and extras to allow for quick
replacements so there are some drip
irrigation specific
components that need to be purchased and
also purchased with a little extra
in case something was to break or fail
the equipment required so in general
we're looking at a
drip system drip spikes transfer tubing
main lines fertilizer injector timers
valves filters pressure regulators and
connecting fittings
now looking at this list it does look
like it's quite extensive
but a lot of these things come together
as a kit a lot of them
are just long lasting components that
don't necessarily
need continual replacement now drip
irrigation versus
hand watering why would someone choose
one versus the other well both deliver
specific amounts of water to the plants
individually hand warning requires daily
labor to accomplish this
drip irrigation can drastically reduce
the day-to-day
time spent accomplishing this same task
also since it can be automated the drip
irrigation it's easy for growers to
decide
to go with multiple watering events in a
day if it's needed
since it'll just be a quick program
change instead of going through and
watering the plants once a day
doing pulse irrigation might be
advantageous
and the drip irrigation is a system that
allows for minimal loss and allows this
to be very easily done especially if
timers are incorporated into the drip
irrigation
system for your cannabis plants