welcome to this debaco university video
we're going to be looking at drug
analysis procedures
for a forensics chemist so some of the
specifics some of the options that might
be used a little bit some of the lab
based
settings and procedures that be used to
analyze different drugs brought into the
lab
so starting with in order to get that
material in the lab it first needs to be
collected so collecting that material
that you're going to send to the lab
while individual labs may have specific
handling procedures the following
is intended to provide a basic overview
of the drug analysis procedure
so depending on the very specific type
of drug saying the type of lab you might
be going to there might be
greater detail this is meant to provide
a general guide
so step one is to determine the amount
of material more
is not necessarily always better
evidence submitted can vary widely in
the amount that's collected
so by finding the total mass of the
material this can determine what tests
can be
and cannot be done due to the amount of
material there is to work with
so where in doubt try to collect this
quote
much as you can within reason because
that may limit the amount of steps
that can be done or procedures carried
out but this isn't always the case you
want to make sure that you're only
collecting
the isolation of material you don't want
to have other contaminants in there
this is why more is not always better
but the amount that you can collect
will limit or potentially determine what
tests will be carried out
from there initially you might do a
presumptive
test so this is the goal of screening
out the material
to classify into a general category
common perceptive test
microscopic analysis micro crystal
analysis and ultraviolet
spectrometry as well as some in-field
test kits if you're looking at specific
drugs
that are typically commonly found so
looking here we have the
microscope analysis this is a visual
inspection of the general structure of
the material
the goal is to provide a broad
classification typically it's used for
larger materials such as plant material
because it's not really great at getting
at some of the molecular structures
just more what does it look like under
high power magnification
they can also lead us to microcrystal
analysis and this involves dissolving a
small amount of material
and then allowing crystals to form
viewing the crystals with the aid of
polarized light can help determine their
structure
and this can help classify again that
material and acts as another step
in that analysis process
they mentioned ultraviolet spectrometry
where we're projecting ultraviolet light
which is
that nanometers of wavelength of light
and measured uh measuring the absorbance
can help
provide a general classification of that
material so i'm going to react more to
the uv
light than others and it's also an easy
light source
to carry around and to be used in
projected in a laboratory setting as
well
then we get into what we call
confirmatory tests and these are used to
identify the material
and often continue where a presumptive
test left
off the presentative test will give us a
general idea and then the confirmatory
test will tell us exactly what it is or
that's at least the intention
is to use or develop a chemical
signature
and then match that up with a particular
type of substance
now one example that might be used here
is called gas chromatography
or gcs is very commonly used
in laboratory settings so keep in mind
that gas chromatography is a type of
chromatography
used to analyze a chemistry for
separating out and analyzing compounds
that can be vaporized without
decomposition
so this is where that representative
test might come into play because this
might lead you to use if you have
available gas chromatography
so use typically in forensic and
analysis with the main use for testing
bodily fluids
the use of the gc includes testing the
purity of a particular substance or
separating out
different components of a mixture which
is the relative amount such as
components can be determined so how much
contaminants might be there
what is the purity of the substance
detected a gas chromatography can also
be used to identify a compound or
residues from explosives
so again has multiple uses and is a very
common
method used then we have something
called liquid chromatography
which operates around the same basic
idea as the gas chromatography
except this is a technique used to
separate samples into its individual
components based on their interactions
of the sample with a mobile and
stationary phase
may have done separation on a very basic
scale like for example inks
uh of pens or for example plant material
separating out chlorophyll
um these are examples of liquid
chromatography
they have capillary electrophoresis or
abbreviated
ce and this is an analytical technique
that separates ions which are neutral
substances
are not affected so keep that in mind uh
separates these ions based on their
electrophoretic mobility in use in
applied
voltage so if they simply have to have a
charge
this is because neutral substances will
not be affected we need like a slight
positive or slightly negative charge
here
this mobility will depend on the charge
of that molecule in addition to the
viscosity
and the atom's radius capillary
electrophoresis is used
predominantly because it gives faster
results and provide higher resolution
separation
it's a useful technique based on there
is a large range of detection methods
available
so there's some specifics here the rate
at which the particles move is
proportional
to the applied electrical field so this
can allow for greater separation
based on the field strength if two ions
are of the same size
with a greater charge will move faster
so it allows
a greater degree or specificity of
separation
and for ions with the same charge the
smaller particle has less friction and
it will have a faster migration rate
so this is what allows this to have a
very high degree
of separation even if some properties
are similar
the lab equipment used for this compound
identification
process the only two covered here but
the goal is the same with the ability to
identify specific compounds being tested
each require specific protocols to be
filed in addition to proper setup
and maintenance of the material the
equipment
over a period of time so we have the
mass spec
or mass spectrometry and this is an
analytical method that
employs ionizations and mass analysis of
the compounds in order to determine the
mass
formula and the structure of the
compound being
analyzed we can see also this is another
highly specific process that allows
those compounds to be
more precisely identified that cannot be
done in the field
and then lastly we have infrared
spectrometry which
is analysis using infrared light
interacting with a molecule
so this can be analyzed in three ways by
measuring absorption
emission and also reflection the main
use of this technique
is in organic and inorganic chemistry
it's used by chemists to determine the
functional groups in molecules
so again another great laboratory based
test
to get at specifically identifying
the compounds in the substance that is
initially brought into the lab