okay here we're going to talk about the
topic of drug addiction and what we may
think of that as being synthetic drugs
or illegal drugs keep in mind this cup
of coffee has caffeine and this can also
be considered or classified as a drug
drugs in general we're looking at there
are neuromodulators which are chemicals
that prolong the effect of
neurotransmitters by either eating in
their release preventing their
reabsorption and for an example
depression may be caused by a shortage
of serotonin prozac inhibits that
reabsorption so here we are in kind of
the synapse here with prozac inhibiting
the reabsorption of that serotonin
molecule there again acting as a neural
modulator drug addiction in general
cells that are exposed to chemical
signals for a long time lose their
sensitivity so what does this mean the
sensitivity well they lose their ability
to respond to the stimulus with the
original intensity so while we can have
a normal kind of going on here where
we've got releasing we've got in that
synapse here that gap between the two
neurons we've got that interaction
occurring however here we see that nerve
cells are particularly prone to the loss
of this sensitivity and what does that
look at a molecular scale if we look at
the arrow here pointing to this kind of
receptor we can see those molecules are
free to move through this kind of
protein here
that proteins being blocked so this is a
change in the way the body is perceiving
or releasing an absorbing in this case
serotonin so this leaves more serotonin
to flow around in that synapse typically
cells will respond to high
neurotransmitter exposure by inserting
fewer protein receptors so we're having
this altered protein receptor amount due
which is altering ultimately altering
the amount of neurotransmitters left in
that synapse and we can see over time
how this addiction occurs usually not
just once curse over time because
there's this change or this shift in the
actual protein of receptors cocaine as
an example here addiction occurs with
chronic exposure to a drug that induces
nervous system to act in a physiological
way cocaine is a neuromodulator it
causes large amounts of
neurotransmitters to remain in the
synapse for a long period of time so
kind of what we saw the previous image
this is just an example of a drug that
does perform in that way dopamine
transmits pleasure messages to the body
and high levels for long periods and
causing nerve cells to lower the number
of receptors and this is why I typically
cocaine users need to use more and more
to get the same effect
sadly through just one use or definitely
if you're increasing the dose that
increases the odds of dying from cocaine
we can see it sadly this number of
deaths from cocaine comparing males to
females over a number of years at THC
the psychoactive drug found in cannabis
plants which makes it classified as
marijuana it mimics under another
neurotransmitter that we have in our
body causing effects to the body
those effects would be increased in
sensory intensity of perceived sensory
data what does that kind of mean it kind
of gives the sense of emotional
well-being in reduced concentration or
impaired judgment of both time and space
how it kind of works on a molecular
level here is normally we have our cells
that may produce in inhibitory
neurotransmitters they're represented
here by the little blue triangles they
prevent don't build they prevent
dopamine it's secretion however here
we're having this block of those
inhibitory neurotransmitters it's
inhibiting the inhibitors as a result
the dopamine is being released and binds
to the receptors here we're having this
kind of a loss of regulation well what
THC does is it mimics that same kind of
molecular shape and fits into that same
receptor causing the same effect however
in this case with the green we're having
eight naturally occurring in natural
balances occurring in this case we're
having a artificial occurrence which is
causing that impair judgment of time and
space and that feeling of emotional
well-being then we get to tobacco which
is involved
nicotine receptors they never ly serve
to bind a secede Oh chlorine the brain
adjusts tap along exposure of nicotine
by making fewer nicotine receptors and
altering the pattern of activation of
those nicotine receptors so having an a
change in the physiological response and
also a reduction in the total receptors
addiction occurs because the brain
experiences nicotine induced changes to
protein expression in the synaptic
connections there's no real easy way to
quit the only way to quit is to quit and
of course that's easier said than done
lastly looking at nicotine it's actually
it's a natural insecticide produced by
the tobacco plant so the tobacco plants
actually producing nicotine to help
prevent it from insect damage it's
synthetic forms of nicotine have been
produced
they're called new nicotine and they are
potential risk to reduce in bee
populations however their use across the
country is quite extensive so we're
having this particular insecticide being
spread over large areas so that's a
concern with anything where we
potentially could get resistance built
up to that or damage to our very
important be pollinators