welcome to this tobacco university video
going over drug
classification we're going to look at
different classes and schedules
for some example drugs now first off
it's important to remember that united
states code the usc
for controlled substances act provides a
list in rating scale called schedules
and we'll see some of those here
the drug potency potential for abuse
likelihood for physical dependency and
medical implications
are all factored into the scheduling
also this act establishes penalties
for offenses and we can kind of see the
website link
provided here when this video was
originally created
so the control substances act or the
schedules are scheduled one two three
four and five schedule one is considered
to be the
highest year the highest potential for
abuse no current accepted medical use
united states
lack of an acceptable level of safety
and use under medical supervision we see
some examples there
now when we look at the examples
probably the one that's under most
scrutiny
uh is marijuana as far as does it fit
all of these schedule one
characteristics we're going down we see
schedule two
a high potential for abuse schedule
three is less potential for abuse in a
schedule one or two
and so on and so on you see the
precipitous downward
scale all the way down to schedule five
where it's a low potential
for abuse there's also some examples
provided
as far as what currently is classified
in all of these different schedules
in addition to scheduling we also have
general classifications
so here are some general classifications
such as
depressants hallucinogens inhalants we
see marijuana also listed here narcotics
steroid stimulants and synthetic drugs
some of the effects typically associated
with them and at the very last column
here some examples
so you're welcome to take a look at this
not going to go or even go through all
this
but this just shows some classifications
of different drugs
and some of the effects and examples
for those drugs