on this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at some research
presented by the university of vermont
extension
looking at hemp cannabidiol drying trial
so hopefully you can follow along and
learn some information
here on the research presented and then
if you want to learn about it in more
detail
links will be provided in the video so
you can look at the full trial its full
details
if you so choose
all right let's get into the drying
temperature effect on cbd content
of cannabis based on the uvm data and
that's the university of vermont
extension here
so if you're looking for the actual
original publication this is the
exact link here welcome to take a look
at it i'll provide with a brief overview
in this video lecture so first off dryer
temperature
humidity and harvest moisture so here
we're looking at some of the data
presented and at harvest
the moisture of the flower buds was
statistically similar which
generally would make sense the average
actual temperature and relative humidity
for each treatment
indicated that the 105 fahrenheit
treatment dryer with the buds did not
reach 105 degrees fahrenheit
what does that mean if we look here at
the data actual temperature we could see
that they had it set for 105 degrees
fahrenheit
but only got it up to 86.4 was the
average actual temperature they did note
in the research they had some issues
with this particular
drying oven it was unclear why the dryer
was unable to maintain
a consistent temperature over the drying
period this is what happens in science
the dryer had an average temperature
that was only seven degrees higher than
the drying treatment at 80 degrees
fahrenheit there so something went wrong
with that particular dryer but does not
mean all the data here is null and void
there's actually some usable data here
when drying the bud and stems this is
bun and stems at 105 degrees fahrenheit
dryer did not reach its average
temperature until after seven
hours and fluctuated the most in
temperature
in the first three hours as it warmed up
although
after the first seven hours we made more
consistent temperature this is another
important
kind of data point information to
provide in the sense that it does take
some time to warm up and initially
it might be some more fluctuations here
that growers need to be aware of
however the 80 degree dryer did not have
this problem in temperatures
near 80 degrees fahrenheit right away so
if it's just something with these
warmer temperatures they noted uh the
changes there that's what's also
important science
to kind of document what happens even
though it may not go as intended to
document that
just so you have a better understanding
of the data when it's presented
then we also have the average relative
humidity presented
and the harvest moisture presented here
as well so hourly
bud only temperature in humidity and
they were looking at the buds only and
then the buds and the stems
so hourly temperature and relative
humidities for the buds only experiments
presented here
here we have the temperature in
fahrenheit and then we have the time
here
and we have the different colors um
shown here extending out we could see
that there's an overall decrease in the
ambient relative humidity
over the time ambient temperature and
the
80 degree fahrenheit drier humidity and
temperature so here's the humidity
here's the temperature very consistent
and then here's the temperature for 105
and the relative humidity here we can
definitely see
based on our data points that the 105
drier relative humidity
decreased to a much greater
level there as the temperature came down
so we got relative humidities here
temperatures here
see that relative humidity definitely
came down quicker at the 105 degrees
compared to the 80 degrees
is that necessarily better we'll see
later but that's at least
quick overview of what this data table
is showing then
they looked at the hourly bud and stem
temperature related to relative humidity
so the bud
and stem experiment average drier
temperature were approximate to the
desired temperatures
in the hourly temperatures and
humidities so again here we're seeing
temperature here very consistent at 80
temperature for 105 we'd expect it to be
somewhere right around here because it
did fluctuate a little bit
then the relative humidity here of the
80 degree temperature
decreased 105 definitely decreased much
quicker here and relative humidity
so when we're looking at the total
potential cbd here looking at the data
table
uh presented we have the treatment the
bud's only potential cbd
buds in stem potential and then trial
total potential cbd percentage
so in the buds only study uh keep in
mind this is about its only
column right here the ambient
temperature resulted in significantly
higher total potential cbd
than drying buds at 105 degrees
fahrenheit
so here we have a 7.71 percentage
compared to only a 5.88 percentage point
here the total potential cbd of the buds
dried at 80 degrees fahrenheit did not
significantly differ
from the higher and lower temperature
treatments and resulted in cbd
percentages between
the two extremes so here's the ambient
temperature and then here's
80 degrees fahrenheit it was a little
bit less but not
majorly less and even when they looked
at the stats when drying blood and stem
materials
look at this column here there was no
significant difference between the cbd
concentrations of 105
and 80 degrees fahrenheit so that's a
kind of important little
note there and this study should be
repeated because of the issues that they
had with the dryers maintaining
consistent temperatures
so again just keep that in mind um there
but we are noticing some initial data
that there could be differences here
notice with the different temperatures
so this kind of gets into the speed
versus quality
kind of concept or idea while the
use of higher temperatures results in
faster drying times we stop the graph
impact of drying temperatures on the
quality of their product should be taken
into consideration
in this trial drying at a higher
temperature above 80 degrees fahrenheit
resulted in significantly lower
total potential cbd concentrations so
it's important to remember that this is
only one year of data limited
replications and drying capacity
further research is needed and this
trial should be replicated with dryers
that are more accurate
but it gets into the concept of speed
versus quality the faster
you go the less quality you you might be
getting so again
speed versus quality something to keep
in mind so looking at the data here
ambient or 80 degrees fahrenheit would
be kind of the maximum
i wouldn't want to go much more than
that even though it might
quicken up the speeding the process of
the drying might speed up the drying
process
you don't want to sacrifice your quality
that you've been trying to grow and
perfect through the entire growing
season at the very end
just to make the drying times less this
is just some data here to support that
that you're looking at 80 degrees or
less really trying probably for that
more 60 degrees fahrenheit to be the
quality target
going much more than that yeah it'll dry
faster but at the risk to quality