in this debaco university video we're
going to go over drying systems for
cannabis looking at both the hanging
drying system that we see here
as well as a rack system to give you
some of the pros and cons of each
as well as show you some actual examples
of cannabis drying so you can decide
what drying system is the best fit for
your situation
[Music]
all right let's get into drying systems
regarding uh cannabis
now here we're seeing a lot of hang
drying remembers also rack or screen
drying as another option
and we'll see both of those mentioned
here as well as going out to greenhouse
to also compare them
so first off just in general what is the
reason for drying
when we're looking at kind of drying the
goal is to produce dry flour that has
improved taste and flavors when ignited
because we're not just selling kind of
an end product
ideally that will be kind of gone
through and burned in some way
so the drying process goal is to improve
the taste and flavors
of that cannabis end product when it's
going through the point of ignition
now the drying process just in general
when we're looking at kind of the
process as it relates to cannabis this
should be viewed not as a race it's not
kind of to dry first
and get there first the goal is to
produce a quality end product
it's more about kind of the destination
and kind of getting there
this might take a little bit longer or
might want to wait another day to ensure
a quality end product
now the area that you'll be drying in
should be very clean
and tightly climate controlled and
that's true if it's a very small
area or it's a very large area it should
be very clean top to bottom
and very controlled of both temperature
light air circulation and the
all-important humidity as well
so what's things that you should be
avoiding in the drying area
when we're looking at the drying area
high heat and intense light can degrade
the cannabinoids
so we're saying no light and that's
ideal but you don't have to have
absolutely no light just to have
very muted light and it's okay if you
turn that muted light on and go into
that room
doesn't have to be 100 solid complete
darkness but make sure the light is
minimal
low intensity and a very short duration
we also want to avoid a speed drying so
we don't want to take a hair dryer to it
and speed dry because that will cause
larger buds not to dry consistently
which will lead to an
inferior end product and the whole goal
here is to produce that quality
end product so what are the two options
or the two main options we have the rack
or screen drying system you can see that
here
its advantages is that it requires uh
minimal space so it's great for large
volume harvest meaning they can be
easily stacked on top of one another
the disadvantage is it does create flat
spots on the buds and does
usually require some pruning to be done
ahead of time because that reduced space
you have a reduced plant material so you
can see here
now comparing it to the other system we
can see right here
we call it the plant hanging system so
in this example there's minimal prep
of the plant material ahead of drying so
that's what makes it advantageous
however the disadvantage is it does take
up more space
because that plant material is a greater
volume of that simple plant material
and it can have increased odds of
contaminants developing such as mold for
example
simply because you have so much more
material they both can produce a quality
end product so just keep that in mind
that the
end product should not really be based
on the system of drying we have to be a
little bit more careful
with the hanging system simply because
they have more plant volume now if
you've learned about these systems
let's go into kind of a drying area
situation
let's look at where we're going to see
some plants hanging some plants
drying on a rack or screen method to
give you in kind of a real world kind of
example of both of these systems
so you can ensure that you're selecting
the one that is the best fit
for your given situation enjoy
so here we're looking at the
all-important drying process for
cannabis harvest and we can see the
large branches have been cut down and
hung upside down on a wire
the light relatively is minimal there's
a air circulation on the bottom behind
me there's also a
fan blowing to again help air moving
throughout the
under canopy here of the drying process
helping control humidity
allows this to dry down very evenly and
very consistently we don't want to have
like wet spots or areas of trapping
moisture because that could lead
potentially to disease
so we want to make sure we're having
this all be consistent and this is one
way we see here
that it can be achieved all right and
here we can see the drying process in
general
we see the fan blowing and we're seeing
kind of a little pathway which is
important for
people to be able to walk through but
we're also seeing the importance of the
ability for air to circulate we see a
little dehumidifier there
we are seeing some lights on which of
course is
important to be able to walk around but
again these are muted lights
this image here again is showing the
importance of that barrier under the
plants you do not want to have your
plants
directly touching the ground there now a
couple are getting some natural sunlight
and that's okay keep in mind that all
those fan leaves have been removed
the entire plants have been cut down and
there's that area of space below and we
also see the area
of space above because we want to have
even air circulation
around the entire plant material we
don't want to just have it at the bottom
just at the top you want to be mindful
of all those areas
as we're looking at the branches here we
can see many of those large fan leaves
have been removed which is great
it really aids in the drying down
process now on the ground there we're
also seeing some
tarping some plastic that helps again
trap any leaves that have fallen down
as well as maintain a humidity barrier
we've seen that here as well
looking kind of from the opposite end
looking down seeing a very consistent
harvest
seeing a lot of repetition very
important to allow
that efficient air circulation efficient
hanging efficient takedown process we
see some pink tags and some string
that can label them variety something of
interest so
making sure we have a method of labeling
and knowing when we harvested what we
harvested and what day
is all important documentation steps
that should be taken
we're saying here it's very early drying
process but we are seeing it is
initiated
so far looks like it's going pretty well
here so
monitoring is another important
component want to make sure that we're
setting everything up ahead
of time but also monitoring that and
making sure
at least everything is going in
generally
to plan so here we have different forms
of drying we can see a lot of the
dry product right here on screens all
kind of taken down
out of the field put here in a protected
greenhouse environment
yes there's some benches we're allowing
some air circulation below these are
actually also on
screens to again help that airflow
overall and allow that nice even
consistently
dry down of the product organized
not overly full in any one area so again
this just helps that drying process to
be very even
very efficient to allow ultimately for
the best product to be produced
now as we look going down this aisle
here of all the different cannabis plant
material drying
it is important that it is segregated it
is isolated
this can be from different lots this can
be different forms of grinding this can
be different
uh initial starting materials we do see
that
is they all are on screens and the
screens are on
benches and those benders are elevated
we are taking advantage of some of the
sun
here in this section of the greenhouse
to help again aid in the drying process
we'll notice that there are some tarps
in the background some shadier locations
where we're having the plants that are
actually
hung to dry but in this area we are
looking at the improvement
of utilizing the sun utilizing that air
circulation
to take full advantage of every
portion of the greenhouse environmental
conditions that we have
so here we're looking at a drying
process where we have all the kind of
hem plants here hung upside down while
for a lot of air circulation down here
uh and this is allowing for a very
efficient and very consistent
dry down of the buds and we can see this
goes on for quite a ways
this is about half acre of total plants
that have been harvested here and
initially dried down
and we could see it's being done here in
a very controlled manner
so that we're getting very consistent
harvest and very consistent yields off
everything
which is definitely important part of
the process
so here we're taking a look at the
drying process look at the actual dried
product
and we can see it's very consistent as
it's from the field
so we're going to have to deal with some
variability naturally with the field
but we're looking at the drying process
keeping that humidity keeping the light
relatively low
keeping the air circulation going
preventing moisture from building up
when they all kind of come together you
can get a nice consistent product that
looks like this
now looking our way down the greenhouse
we can see it the tabletop benches
are being used with some of the branches
here uh going through
and drying them down pruning a lot of
the leaves off removing that
putting them on the benches we see the
vast majority here the most efficient
method is hanging those branches
on the wire that's been strung on this
greenhouse on both sides we have kind of
light blocking tarps so we're not
getting
full intense light it's also helping
reduce the amount of heat that we get in
the greenhouse
those fans running behind me here they
can keep air moving
so that's also important to be sure that
we're not letting air get stagnant we
don't want moisture to develop and
that's very important
especially at the sunrise and sunset
times during this fall time of year
to bring that moisture from building up
within the structure because ultimately
that could lead to increased chance of
getting bud rot
molds developing and when you have this
much material it could spread very
quickly
if you allow it to initially get started
now here as we walk down the aisle we
can see
very clearly uh the organization of all
those plants hanging
above us we see the hanging methane
being utilized but we're also noticing
on the bench tops we're seeing kind of
like a rack system
also being utilized and it's important
kind of maximize the space that you have
and
kind of ran out of space to hang the
plants so why not use
the natural bench space looking here
these are a little further along that we
saw
in the early part of the video and we
can see again those fan leaves are
evenly removed allowing for those buds
even air circulation and really helps
that drying process
in general also notice that for the most
part while we are in a greenhouse we are
trying to minimize some of the light
and in the background there we can see
that there's definitely
some black plastic and tarps up we're
also noticing and probably hearing a
little bit
of fan moving so again air circulation
is important and that's a key factor
there
to be considerate especially when you're
in a greenhouse sometimes those vents
can open and close but we really want to
make sure
we're allowing air to always be moving
through those plants
you can see here just kind of the end
product of that when you are getting
that fan moving
it might be a little bit annoying to be
in there it definitely does help the
overall process
not heavily blowing on the plants but
again keeping that air moving
keeping that humidity from building up
in any one location
now lastly something we do want to
consider as we are removing buds
from the branches is the disposal of the
leftover plant material
cannabis plants do tend to produce kind
of stocks that are kind of woody in
nature so we want to be mindful of that
we want to be having a plan that
we're going to have to dispose of these
at the end of the harvest cycle
when we take the valuable buds off the
plants and get those dried down
hopefully this was helpful and you're
welcome to sketch any other videos here
on debaco university