okay here we're a look at logical
organization and you can see that
starting at the very basic or the level
of the organism umbilical population
lead to a community an ecosystem or
landscape in a global view here this is
just kind of general ecological
organization here we're going to in a
little bit more detail now so first of
all what is ecology
well evolution in ecology are two key
concepts keep in mind evolution are
changes that occur in an organism's
traits over time over an extended period
of time
ecology is how the organism lives in
their particular environment so again
keep in mind separation of these two to
break apart
ecology that's the focus of this video
lecture is that ecology eco stands for
house so house and the ology is the
study of so they have the study of an
organism's house the greatest diversity
of life on earth is a result of
evolution and evolution can be said is
the consequences of ecology over time so
they do have an impact in influence on
one another as a result ecology is the
study of how organisms interact with
their environment as an example we see
the be interacting with the flower here
now adaptions to climate many organs
have adapted to survive in their
specific climate see here with a
camouflage also the changing our fur
coats of color of the rabbits here white
during the winter months to blend in
with the background and ground here to
represent a little bit more of the
forested kind of soil leaf looking
material here six levels of ecologic
local organization this is kinda just a
general summary slide a good one to come
back to to be able to refer to and see
if you hit all the major points because
all these are covered in this particular
video lecture populations species
communities ecosystems biomes in the
biosphere will all be touched on here in
a moment
so starting the first populations well
what's a population populations are
individuals of the same species living
together the demographics are the
statistical study of populations which
will allow predictions to made about how
a population will change
so looking at past data past influences
we can make a prediction as an estimate
that's how it's going to turn out for a
prediction on how that population may
change over time
and sometimes it's can go up and down in
kind of a predicted pattern here here
we're looking at median household income
just as an example of how things can
fluctuate and change or tying this into
populations of species living together
so what's the species that they're
species living together well how do we
define a species
well species are all populations of a
particular kind of organism from a
species so what's this kind of mean
melissa's soon as there's common
characteristics within a similar species
genetically compatible interbreed under
natural conditions and sexual
reproduction can occur can that be
with exclusive asexual so we don't call
this with asexual organisms at how they
replicate or multiply this is
reproduction in the absence of may or of
a fusion of organisms so prokaryotes
amoeba and some animals plants can
reproduce with asexual means can that
it's exactly fits the definition for its
species here we'll thing at different
bird species here it needs to all have
common characteristics through
genetically compatible they can
interbreed in our natural conditions and
reproduce by the way of sexual
reproduction so this species species is
Latin for kind or appearance and Alanis
described species in terms of their
morphology you and morphology it's like
this shape or how they visually look
modern taxon is also considered genetic
makeup as a function in behavioral
differences when describing the species
a little bit more precise now I'll look
at the DNA aca-awesome commonalities
that may exist and that's how we can
kind of classify or define species
communities are populations of different
species living together so this is the
most system to define with precision a
community because community is a macro
system so it's a large system it's held
together by feeling and sediment at the
interface between society and
systems so we see the community could be
for example the school community it
could be the town community it could be
the state to be community it could be
the region community so that's why it's
difficult to define with a great deal of
precision
please though the consistent part is
populations of different species living
together so in the community the
populations are identified with one
another they may Accu pi common
territory engage in common activities
and have some form of organization that
provides differential functions which
allows the community to adapt to its
environment thereby meeting its needs of
its components so the meerkats can look
out
obviously a local community here
engaging in activities this interaction
between different species here now
within these communities components
include the persons groups or families
and organizations within its population
in the institutions it forms to meet its
needs so we see here where we see people
coming together community coming
together to build up bikes yeah see
community coming together here to
distribute food or water during a time
of crisis these are again are each
communities but they are defined
slightly differently now ecosystems
looking a little bit larger here because
there's a combination of communities and
associated non living factors so in
ecosystems and natural unit consisting
of all plants animals and microorganisms
also including the biotic factors in an
area functioning together with their
nonliving physical or abiotic factors in
the environment so this is defining an
ecosystem here we have a highway that's
passing through and we have an animal
crossing passage here to eliminate the
need for them to kind of go through the
road system so this again they have a
small version have an eco system because
we're taking into account biotic factors
the animals and a lad factors which can
be just a physical outline of the land
there in addition we have something
called biomes biomes are major
terrestrial areas of organisms that
occur over wide geographic areas so
a very large scale based location of
each viola biome is primarily designed
by the temperature in precipitation and
area may receive climbs can also be
defined by winds rapid temperature
changes fires floods etc this gives just
a little bit of an idea of
classification of some biomes here they
listed here but the key part here is
that it's major terrestrial areas
located within the geographic range of
the world and have you cannot link all
this together is the biosphere so this
is the largest scale that we're gonna
look at all this includes all the biomes
together with marine and freshwater
areas so the Earth's has four major
connected systems hydrosphere that was
the sphere the atmosphere and the
ecosphere all together creating the
biosphere just a portion of the earth
that's inhabited by life includes all
the biotic and also a nonliving commodes
or abiotic parts here so this kind of
ties everything together looking at the
very large scale go back to our first
slide we see that's the global view and
we worked our way all the way down and
kind of that organism level of the
population defining communities that are
interacting to form
ecosystems in the landscape forming our
entire ecological organization