okay here we can be looking the effects
of UV or ultraviolet radiation on plant
contents so why maybe from those UV
radiation of being something to be of
caution to and that is important it also
can be used to kind of reveal certain
things when we're looking at developing
money that's hard to counterfeit and it
can make certain liquids glow but it is
some things you need radiation is
something to be concerned about and
typically we'll see that associated with
sunglasses so UV light there's different
forms UVC UVB and UVA UVA is account
about 95 percent of the UV radiation
reaching the Earth's surface while UV
beza Chief's caused her skin reddening
and sunburn intensive damage the skins
more superficial epidermal layer so
that's the outer portion UVC is filtered
out by the ozone in the stratosphere so
these are in addition to visible light
as we see here there's uva UVB can see
the different wavelengths it's a good
occurring that you VA can penetrate
deeper into our skin than UVB which
tends to stay more in the epidermal
layer closer to our skin surface now
what's being shown here is that lettuce
is affected by UV light production so
growing the right type of green leaf
lettuce during the winter in a
greenhouse and exposing it to the right
type of ultraviolet light can boost
levels nutritionally of carotenoids
according to the Agricultural Research
Service so supplementing uva plus UVB
greatly increased the carotenoid and
chlorophyll concentrations in green leaf
lettuce varieties so here's one example
how adjusting the light can affect the
outcome of the plant this master's
thesis also looked at lettuce production
this thesis was published in the year
2016 they showed that the use of
supplemental light to improve the
quality of red lettuce is common
practice in today's greenhouse
production and the use of UV light
treatments leads to an increase in the
synthesis of health growing compounds
for phenolic acids in flavonoids there's
just another example of light affecting
the outcome now since we relate this to
cannabis here
the importance of you delight in
trichome development so in canvas
increasing UVB radiation resulted in
increased THC levels in the flowers it's
just referred to the study here ta
cheaters being a cannabinoid
maybe something like this could be also
be applied to CBD production trichomes
can block harmful UVB rays from reaching
the sensitive photosynthetic tissues of
the leaves as a result these trichomes
that are being produced increased
numbers I thought the function almost is
like a shading effect or a sunblock for
the plants some way to melanin protects
the skin from UVB damage in this case
plants are producing higher trichomes
which in return are producing higher
cannabinoids so then the plants that
were giving the artificial light to when
we may want to be considering lights
that produce the UV light part of the
spectrum to help increase the
cannabinoids that they can produce