here we go look at the effects of
osmosis on cells three important key
terms wanting to lay with our hypertonic
isotonic hypotonic and how these relate
and how these change the structure of
the cells and how some can lead to
potentially cell death and some
basically just not functioning properly
and what isotonic is here we'll look at
each of these in detail and how they
relate so starting with that same image
and defining our three key vocab terms
here
isotonic is the one in the middle this
is where solutions with the same solute
concentration as that was the cytosol
remember the cytosol is the interior
portions of the cell so here we see what
water moving in and water moving out
nice equal in equal out isotonic
hypertonic solutions having greater
solute concentrations than that of the
cytosol for water leaves the cell
causing this basic shrinkage to occur so
hypertonic the solution here having
greater site concentration than that of
the cytosol water leaving the cell
causing it to shrink so this is
basically causing this shriveled up here
and Stoker the opposite of that would be
hypotonic this is where solutions have
lesser solute concentration than that is
all water enters itself causing it to
swell and says here potentially the lice
causing them in this case the cells
slicing or it's exploding basically
breaking apart too much water's coming
into the cell causing it to swell up
that's why it looks a little more plump
than this one causing in this case it's
a lice or break apart so these are three
kind of situations we want to think
about how these cells are being affected
now those were animal cells are actually
red blood cells here we're looking at a
plant cell now plant cells have this
exterior cell wall so they have
something a little different plant cells
I mean turgid or firm this is generally
the healthiest in the hypotonic
environment where the uptake of water is
eventually balanced by the elastic wall
pushing back in the cell
so here turgid we have water coming in
this large vacuoles swelled up here a
lot of water containing it but that's
able to keep and maintain itself because
plant cells have a cell wall remember in
our hypotonic situations if we go back
to the red blood cells this was the
concept where he could 2/8 advice so
plant cells a little different they have
that so on they can hold that pressure
and islets keeps plants upright and
vertical isotonic they become flaccid
they can start to wilt a little bit and
yes we're having some water come in and
out and that's okay
who knows this little flaccid then here
an extreme case our hypertonic where a
lot of water is leaving this is
basically where the plant is really
blimp will thing down pretty heavily
where it can burn or cause severe damage
to it so hypertonic what do these
situations look like hypertonic osmotic
flow out of the cell so here's our
solute molecules here is ourselves here
in this case a great example this Iike
cucumber and you pickle it well that
pickling solution the brine solution
high amount of salt concentration in
that liquid environment causing our
wonderful locating line streamline
cucumber to become like a pickle to
shrivel up net what's occurring here
water molecules are leaving these cell
in this case they try to dilute the
solute or in this case a salt that's
located on the outside and that's what
causes the pickle to get that shriveled
look versus a cucumber hypotonic that
was the opposite of that
osmotic flowing into the cells so us
welding up in this case there's more
solute molecules inside the cell and
there are outside this could be if you
put something in pure water distilled
water free of ions this can cause cells
to swell up and if their red blood cells
they cannot ultimately lice or break
apart
isotonic as an equal movement of water
molecules both in and out itself this is
not the same as no movement so the site
molecules are the same on the inside and
the outside and water is coming in and
out at the same rate each molecule in
results in one
molecule out and sell there appears to
be no change so this one says no osmotic
flow this could be kind of misleading if
I couldn't down here no I'm gonna clone
most people think that's just not going
to move everything's going to stay where
it is well that's not necessarily the
case water can be coming in but for
every mouthful that comes in one comes
out pretty mild killer comes out one
comes in so this is where you get to
equal movement okay not no movement but
equal movement so it appears there's to
be no change
get hypertonic hypotonic and isotonic
shown those same images remember
hypertonic is like those salt solution
causing it to kind of shrink hypotonic
the cells swelling it
isotonic it's equal movement in and out
looking at our red blood cells this is
the proper shape they should have if
they swell too big they can lyse
and if they shrink and shrivel here
they're just not going to perform their
proper function this is how they look in
real world so we could see a little bit
harder to tell on initial quick look but
I certain sort without and that's how
they should look these are red blood
cells RBC's or abbreviation this is how
they should look we notice in comparison
how the properly formed red blood cells
look our hypotonic ones are definitely
larger definitely plump no real kind of
depression in the middle no biconcave
disk actually reducing the surface area
in this case they don't lyse they're
just being a surface here to volume
ratio hypertonic notice that they're
kind of getting this jagged appearance
this jagged appearance is because
they're shrinking they're shrinking down
and that's what's causing the jagged
appearance the collapse of the cell yeah
a lot of waters leading the cell causing
it to kind of shrink and shrivel up
there here's an example of what's unseen
out of the microscope where we have
water exiting the cell causing it to
shrink
water entering the cell causing it to
swell and this is how it should look
here
so again flipping back our hypotonic is
that swelling that be represented is
here here where it's all equal we flip
back that's how they should look at
isotonic
and shriveling up would be hypertonic
sample here so hypertonic hypotonic an
isotonic key terms to be able to know
and understand plasmolysis is when the
cell loses water in a hypertonic
solution so this isn't yet a plant cell
looking specifically at the vacuole here
that cool here hypotonic all nicely
swelled up when I was remanded to that I
sewed a hypertonic here that water is
leaving the cell at a greater rate and
we're noticing that vacuole is getting
smaller that's low presented here you're
taking up like 90% of the cell here it's
a lot less it can even get in the worse
situation what takes up even smaller
portion of the cell importantly in our
body systems the hydrostatic and
asthmatic pressures and our kidneys
hydrostatic pressure is water pressure
in its filtration that our kidneys go
through and do is passage of water and
solutes through membrane through
hydrostatic pressure pressure gradient
pushes containing fluid from higher
pressure area to lower pressure areas
just a brief overview here the
filtration process if the kidneys go
through is based a lot on this osmotic
pressure this is why it's there's a lot
of folds here a lot of membranes because
we want to excrete down certain waste
products we want to retain some water
and some of the things also so the
kidneys throughout all these little
areas here not going to notice the great
details here go through this osmotic
pressure this hydrostatic pressure
buildup water pressure that's occurring
allowing us to properly filter our blood
and other fluids to get excrete pure
waste products hope that was helpful