any growing operation often a necessary
evil as it's often said is the spraying
of the plants this can be organic
contact sprayers and the key part with
to make these as effective as possible
is good coverage so in this tobacco
University video we're going to go out
to the CBG gurus to see how they use
both an electronic pump and experimented
with a pressure washer to be able to
efficiently spray their plants in a Time
effective and good coverage method
something that might be of interest to
you that you might be looking at trying
out yourself so let's take a look at
[Music]
this before we get into the video of the
content I want to just go over the
mission of the CBG gurus because they
are built around the producing a premium
Quality Craft hempt products with that
are manufactured in stability and
alignment with nature they use wood
chips to kind of suppress their weeds
and build soil quality as well as Korean
natural farming methods uh during the
growing season so I invite you to look
at their website look some of their
contact information if you have interest
um that's what we're going to see a
little bit of today now two parts that
we're going to look at today are their
use of both an electronic pump uh for a
spraying the hemp plants which is a more
traditional style it's a portable 9g
sprayer so an image of the one that they
you'll see in the video it's battery
operated and the battery does offer
increased mobility in the field which is
great however the misting and total
volume uh is limited reducing the total
overall coverage uh but it can be
effective however they've also gone
through some experimentation as we'll
see with use of a pressure washer now
it's an interesting concept because
you're able to use a large 50-gallon
tank that's pumped out via a pressure
washer the key component though to make
this method actually work is the
handheld Mis attachment to allow uh
grower directed spray applications and
the three nozzle improves coverage and
also reduces the time I tried to provide
the English conversion as as well as the
actual website here of the catalog uh
located right down below here as well as
in the description so you can take a
look at the attachment yourself but we
can see both of these um actually in
action how they're utilized in the field
and just gives you a idea of what you
might want to try to implement with your
growing operation hope you enjoy okay so
here we can see the more traditional use
of spraying with the electric portable
sprayer with a battery operated this can
be effective you can see it does have
quite a bit of force but there is only
one nozzle that it can support and the
length of the hose goes down most of one
row um does make it easy to transport uh
in the field which is something that you
definitely want uh because you are
spraying on uneven terrain uh however
there are other methods and this one
uses a pressure washer which of course
has much more power you can see here the
pressure washer on the left but what
makes this really work is the attachment
on the nozzle on the right here we can
see the handheld basically onoff switch
and the actual um attachment here uh
very precise I don't know exactly what
it says but on the back label there is a
website you can see circled um there
that'll be in the bottom of the video
however the pressure washer is a lot of
power as you can see knock that little
statue right over um too much pressure
when we first tested it here popped out
the end um mising nozzle however after
some adjustments in lowering the
pressure on the pressure washer uh we
begin to get this dialed in and we can
see here a little bit later now we
definitely have more of a misting don't
have any over pressure with losing that
end nozzle there we have a great misting
um that is occurring and we can see that
misting is really the key part that we
want advantage of pressure washer is it
is hooked up to a 50 gon uh container
and we have a long um hose attached here
and I believe two hoses attached that
allows easy going up and down the field
um and allows basically the stock
50-gallon tank to remain stationary
giving the operator here only the
basically the wand and the cord to worry
about and we can clearly see in that
Setting Sun there the coverage that
we're able to get also able to get the
very precise um amount of Applied
product that allows us to spray the
underside of the leaves as well as the
upper side and that's really a great
thing to allow coverage uh because
you're only holding the wand uh
basically can go under the plants really
easily you can see here that they're
nicely trained through the um trellis
mounted horizontally and there's the
kind of the overspray as well now plants
here a little smaller so it's easy at
the top but you can see it those larger
plants there on the right also able to
get that very good even coverage
reducing the amount of product applied
and also applying it more effectively so
this is something you might want to take
a look at uh modifying a pressure washer
to be able to um allly and more easily
spray your plants just keep in mind you
might want to put rollers at the end
there to make it easier hope this was
helpful