so while the use of electronic
cigarettes has been on the rise found
some alarming facts and I want to share
with you regarding their usage so more
than 2-million middle and high school
students were current users of attract
cigarettes now it's just kind of an
alarming fact when clearly they're not
for sale to minors 11% of high school
and 4.3 percent of middle school
students are recurrent users of
e-cigarettes in 2006 based on the
information that I found and I've
included links at the bottom here so
remember the in the description you can
go to the slides pause it and direct
copy the URL into your chosen web
browser what's interesting now is
according to 2013 new 2014 survey eighty
one percent of current youths see
cigarette users cited availability of
appealing flavors as the primary reason
for their use so that's a little bit of
a concern when we're looking at how
these are being marketed and who they're
being potentially marketed to so let's
get to like the Surgeon General and the
American Lung Association their feelings
on these well the US Surgeon General
concluded that e-cigarettes can expose
users to several potentially harmful
chemicals more than just the nicotine we
might associate with the term cigarette
carboxyl groups of all volatile organic
compounds are just some of the other
harmful chemicals that you might be
exposed to if you're choosing to use
these the American Lung Association as a
result supports basically prohibiting
the use of e-cigarettes in work sites
and public places including e-cigarettes
under smoke-free laws with other tobacco
products the reason for this is they
remain concerned about their impact on
public health given a dramatic increase
in use especially among the youth these
cigarettes are our tobacco product in
the youth youth are using e-cigarettes
increasing and actually an alarming rate
the information I found again URL found
at the bottom here at the US Surgeon
General found a cigarettes
among high school students increased by
percent from just 2011 to 2015 it was
the most current date and I can find
with more teams now using e-cigarettes
and cigarettes now that reason is
potentials being glamorized more also
marketing of these cigarettes could be
more directed to youth because they're
offering like candy flavors like bubble
gum and gummy bears which are typically
appealing to a younger audience so this
is just something we're noticing a
dramatic increase of however there is
definitely some associate risk with this
so if you are considering this as a
cleaner or better alternative to
traditional cigarettes you may want to
think twice even though it is being
increased in the amount of use that
we're seeing across the nation the scary
part is it's being used at a much higher
rate amongst youth such as middle sadly
and even high school students