okay so when looking at setting up a
grow room well typically there's a lot
of electricity involved around lights
and fans and cooling and heating and
monitoring devices so you want to be
well-versed in the electricity basics
related to that supporting that grow
room so first off of our basics of
circuits will depend on the lights and
electrical equipment chosen they'll
impact the total capacity that that room
will need typically a 15 or 20 amp
electrical circuit will be necessary for
common household 120 volt systems keep
in mind if you're buying balancers
typically the 120 volt and also the 240
for buying a 240 system you want to make
sure that you have the appropriate
connections for that average household's
run on 120 you careful calculate your
power needs so no circuits should run
over 80% of the stated rating so let's
make it easy if it's a 10 amp circuit
80% of that would be 80 amps so a 20 amp
circuit would be running at no more than
60 answer whenever that a little bit of
a buffer factor there if it's a 20 amp
circuit you don't want to run all the
way to 20 amps there now know what your
electrical man draws in amps so it's a
system of measurement here look at the
labels lookit make sure your circuit
boxes can handle it if you're separating
everything out it's very easy to plug
things in but you've got to account for
what those draw for all the electrical
codes to know when it draws in amps add
these numbers up and determine the that
you're not overloading the circuit again
you keep adding something keep adding
one more thing one more thing one more
thing
very easy to overdraw any amps assume
everything's gonna be running at the
same time to create a worst-case
scenario sometimes you may say well my
lights are going to come off and then
this is going to come on then those are
going to go off and that's gonna
consider a worst case scenario just in
case everything does go on or is on you
don't want to run into issues they're
wanna be plugging into a GFI outlets
these are ground fault interrupter
certified outlets and these are
typically installed where humid high
humidity conditions where water
environment would be such as near a sink
this means each and its own built-in
breaker to cut power they're short and
they can be tested as little red that
here there is little buttons that you
can push to make sure they're functional
a little light here will indicate the
green light indicates it's on and
functional however you also
be able to note while these are
important should be able to have a
system to check these because they can
trip unexpectedly and so be sure to
check them so you don't suddenly lose
power to an outlet it should be this
typical three-pronged outlets component
so that you are also accounting for the
ground wire now typically to these
outlets who are plugging in extension
cords so running exchangers long
distance though is not as advised does
and also all extension cords are not
considered equal so we have a mess in
this little box here when purchasing
extension cords get the shortest that
you need to complete the job don't have
a bunch of coiled leftover extension
cords you also want to get the smallest
gauge or the thickest wire possible to
reduce resistance and chance of fire now
of course this is going to come out
increased cost but it is well worth it
so that gauge of wire this throws a lot
of people off the thicker the gauge and
as you can see here the thicker the
gauge the smaller the number so if
you're buying for example a comparing a
14 gauge wire to a 10 gauge wire well
that 10 gauge wire is going to be much
thicker than that 14 gauge a 21 get
really really thin here I'm 8 gauge to
be really thick so again it's kind of
sometimes it's counterintuitive or the
smaller the number the larger the gauge
and that will help reduce the chance of
fire reduce the heating and allow you to
be able to run longer distances if you
need to even though you want to try to
keep them to a minimum