okay here we look at electrons and
neutrons due to the subatomic particles
located in in atom so the energy levels
of electrons minister with the electrons
first energy it's the capacity to cause
change now energy as we have discussed
earlier energy and human life we have
our chemical energy here being converted
into ATP which is the body's energy
currency as part of our metabolism now
there is heat given off and chemical
waste giving off the energy of those
electrons so it's a lot of this type of
energy which is the capacity to cause
change the main molecule is ATP
adenosine triphosphate so there develops
an electrons well there's two main types
there's potential energy which is
probably how you're feeling about right
now it's stored energy that can be
released
Kelly referred to as chemical potential
energy which is the energy stored in the
bonds of molecules and I think of it's
like an energy at rest there then they
were a kinetic energy which is the
energy that's being currently used in a
reaction so those chemical bonds that
just kind of their they've kind of that
potential energy or that stored energy
then when a reaction is occurring way of
that kinetic energies that you see here
at the cat playing with the toy mouse
here that's the energy currently being
used in a reaction
Janene are the energy levels of the
electrons the electron of an atom differ
in their amounts of potential energy and
electron state if potential energy is
called the energy level or its electron
shell as we see here the very bottom
here is called the ground state as those
electrons that work their way out their
energy level increases these out here we
consider it more of an excited state and
electrons can jump to these different
electron shells through different energy
levels realize the ground state is the
most basic lowest energy form and
extended States as you work your way up
the amount of energy increases those
electrons have so arrangement of
electrons in an atom that first energy
level can all a maximum of two electrons
the second third angels can whole
contain
eight electrons so you see in the middle
here with hydrogen one lonely proton now
just with one proton I have to tell you
this this was hydrogen seeing one proton
indicates that it's hydrogen seeing two
protons indicates this is helium seeing
here we have 10 protons a little hard to
count there would be neon 3 might be a
little easier this is lithium we see
those energy levels you have these
electrons working the way up you'll
notice in all these cases the first
energy level can only hold a maximum of
2 electrons the second and third angels
can hold up to 8 we see that indicated
here when I try to keep this fairly
simple on the smaller atoms but the same
holds true as we could work our way up
so classification of the elements
families of elements share the same and
named electron configuration we see here
so we're looking at Group 1 and group 2
if we were to count all the electrons in
the outermost shell here we find that
there's only one outermost shell here
there's one outermost shell there's one
even all the way down here at francium
the outermost shell there's only that
one electron down group to those that
there's two electrons in each one of
these outer shells as a result they
share similar similar chemical
characteristics so this is why all the
elements in Group one have similar
chemical characteristics fill that same
one X outside or valence electron that
outside electrons when what's going to
do the vast majority of the reactions
that time the outermost area the
electrons kind of in the middle here get
stuffed in the ones on the outside doing
the reaction group one has one outer one
group two is to the own selections that
I mention move out of the way a little
bit a valence electrons here are the
ones on the outside these electrons in
the highest principle energy level and
they determine the chemical reactivity
so an important note to make their
elements in a group share the same
number of valence electrons as we see
here all these have eight valence
electrons seven and six five and four
and three and two and one
however if we look here a little more
closely well be easy to think all one
two three four five six seven and eight
there's an error in the air so I'm not
sure if you can spot that particular
error but if you go through and you look
at all of the protons that these
elements have yes all these have one
valence electron all these have two if
we look up here at element that is
located in this upper corner here does
not have eight valence electrons this is
helium this actually only has two
valence electrons so I'd say spot the
error the error is located right here
with helium having only two valence
electrons everything else in the noble
gas family will have eight now looking
at this kind of complexity of the
periodic table showing the electron
shells as we see here most they do get a
lot more electrons as we get down to the
rows 6 and 7 of the periodic table but
keep in mind all these have the same
number of valence electrons except you
can remember helium has two everything
else in noble gas family has eight
valence electrons which says remember
are the electrons located in the
outermost shell
now the octet rule atoms tend to gain
looser share electrons in order to
acquire a full set of eight valence or
outer shell electrons elements with full
valence shell are chemically inert
they're stable so we want to have eight
here's oxygen typically has one two
three four five six well it combines
with carbon here it's sharing these two
so therefore this count as part of
oxygen it will have eight those are
being shared they can't with carbon
tuned to count all the circles around
carbon will also see eight so think of
this octet rule there's an octagon and
octopus of our musical octet each atom
is trying to gain or lose or share
electrons in order to maintain that full
octet or that eight valence electrons in
its outer shell