okay here we're gonna look at an
overview of the endocrine system if you
look at the image located here on the
title side you can see a couple areas
glands that are very important to the
endocrine system because we're looking
at secretion of hormones in particular
see here in the upper area of particular
interest surrounding the brain thyroid
the thalamus to work our way down near
the pancreas and the adrenal glands
which are located on top of the kidneys
and ultimately the ovaries and the
testes so the endocrine system what does
this consist of well it's glands and
what are these glands do these glands
release hormones and they go directly
into the bloodstream
now hormones are hormones are chemicals
they're released is one part of the body
and travel through the bloodstream and
affect activities of cells in other
parts of the body so we're looking at
that connection between the hormones
being produced in small quantities in
one section one particular gland and
then it's going through the entire body
cousin in effect that could be from
cells that are very distantly located
from the original site or where those
hormones are produced now what does this
kind of look like well these releasing
the hormones which are chemical
messengers into the bloodstream signal
cells and these are signaling target
cells and they behave in certain ways so
when we say a target cell we need that
hormone to be able to bind to a receptor
to then cause a secondary messenger to
cause a reaction to occur this binding
stage is very important this is because
these hormones are produced in very
small quantities they circulate through
the entire body and only were they bind
will they cause that response to occur
this is a slow but widespread form of
communication so it's not very you know
super fast I mean this is circulating
throughout the body but it's providing
this communication of this hormone which
from one cell to a distant cell in the
body
double you might say it's kind of a slow
connection or slow kind of way of
regulating is we have a very fast system
called our nervous system so a lot of
people are comparing like endocrine and
nervous some people get these confused
are vastly different the nervous system
transmits electrical signals and
releases neurotransmitters to target
tissues these are very fast but short
lasting responses for our nervous system
the endocrine system which is our focus
here our ductless glands and they
secrete chemical signals directly into
the bloodstream
now chemicals travel to target tissues
these target cells have receptor
proteins these results in slow a long
lasting response
so again nervous system is quick kind of
movement of things endocrine system that
production of hormones is causing a
little bit of delay to the response but
will be a much longer lasting response
than the nervous system now comparing
MERIS and independent similars in
differences so some of our similarities
are they're both involved in maintaining
communal stasis they both secrete
chemicals the endocrine system those
transmitters are hormones that's how
it's getting the message across nervous
systems are actually neurotransmitters
occurring between neurons differences
here the nervous system responds much
faster than the endocrine system the
endocrine system lasts much longer when
compared to the nervous system nerve
impulses are transmitted vanarin
hormones are transported by the blood so
keep in mind that we're having this very
quick response and nervous system about
200 and over 250 miles per hour and
endocrine is relying on hormones which
are chemical messengers now regulation
of those chemical messengers
neurotransmitters again released by the
neurons important for the nervous system
hormones are released by the endocrine
glands and see just a couple is to here
so very different than our
neurotransmitters very short
communication here between neurons now
what does this endocrine signaling look
like we have a secreting cell the our
endocrine gland sending our kind of
hormone message and then it's bypassing
this out this is a non target cell has
the wrong receptor the wrong shape this
blue cell does have the proper shape and
that will receive the signal and cause a
response to occur this is like hormones
and binding is very important because
they're very specific
now messenger molecules cells must
communicate with one another to
coordinate cell processes within tissues
and maintain homeostasis well talk about
that little bit later but we need this
cell to cell communication and this is
carried out via messenger molecules and
they bind to different surface proteins
and as its gonna cause a response to
occur so do you need to understand look
at all the very specifics here no I want
you to get the journalist that we're
having this binding occurring with these
surface proteins causing a response to
occur in this case gene regulation
within the cell now this regulation
where hormones needed will do the
communication they are the actual
chemical messengers that's occurring in
one part of the body and traveling to
another part if you see here for example
growth hormones they're affecting
muscles the liver and bone grows so
we're seeing this one hormone causing a
response to occur more of a daily
routine they have regulation on large
scale such as regulating out blood
glucose levels but calcium levels the
salt in your body also related to
metabolism growth development maturation
and reproduction all of these involve
hormones and these feedback systems that
are occurring now endocrine hormones are
produced by ductless glands and secrete
into the bloodstream they may infect a
wide array of target cells to produce
multiple effects major glands that make
up the endocrine system on the
hypothalamus pituitary gland the thyroid
parathyroid adrenals ah so on and so
forth you can see a whole list here I'm
not going to make you memorize all the
individual hormones but realize each
hormone is produced in a very specific
gland located in very specific portion
of the body there's two major types of
hormones peptides which are small
proteins and steroids which are lipids
so important to note there's very
there's differences between those two
and how they react
some other hormones too are just too
close here erythropoietin is secreted by
the kidneys and this stimulates bone
marrow to produce red blood cells many
other organs as we just saw there
besides
endocrine glands also produce hormones
kidneys produce several hormones that
relate blood pressure which is essential
for kidney function
so there again they're helping maintain
that blood pressure and you can do that
to hormones the digestive system also
puts in several hormones that regulate
appetite so you can see how there's a
lot of complexities on on here he's very
important all these operate and function
properly so the body can maintain
homeostasis