okay so here I want to provide a brief
overview of the endosymbiotic theory and
how this kind of came about
if you look here this what is the
endosymbiotic theory well it's a
hypothesized origin for eukaryotic cells
how do we get cells that have kind of
membrane bound organelles well looking
here we have a prokaryotic cell and
there's a potential that cell membrane
in foldings could have occurred these in
foldings can create little pockets in
these ultimately could have led to the
development and specialization of
different organelles now two organelles
in particular for docking plant salesmen
for sure are very complex they're the
mitochondria and the chloroplasts we're
talking animal cells reducing at the
mitochondria now mitochondria
chloroplasts are very complex a very
unique structure so odds are that they
probably just didn't come from in
membrane foldings the theory behind how
they became incorporated into cell
looking first at the mitochondria with
this aerobic oxygen using proto
bacterium enters the eukaryotic cell it
could be either as a prey item or a
parasite and it manages to avoid
digestion or being broken down so that's
an important component there exactly how
it avoids that not really sure if
there's other theories regarding that
but it's taken into the cell and is not
broken down then it becomes kind of an
endosymbiotic and that's we get the term
endosymbiotic theory endo meaning inside
the cell somatic means both gaining a
benefit here so this poor bacterium that
is generating its own energy using
oxygen is incorporated into the cell so
the cell has this advantage of this
energy producing organelle proto
bacterium gains the advantage of being
protected within this cell so again
they're both receiving a benefit there
now chloroplast for docking plant cells
also very complex how did they kind of
get incorporated into into cells there
well as we'll see in a moment
chloroplasts have a lot of resemblance
to say in a bacterium so this is a
potential way that they could have been
taking in again not digested not broken
down and incorporated as part of the
cell now both the mitochondria in
chloroplasts
contained their own while small
percentage still their own DNA that
isn't found in the nucleus so this
further supports the idea or the theory
that they may have once been free living
because they do have their own unique
DNA so if we're looking at that kind of
comparison between our chloroplast and
our Co bacterium this just kind of shows
you some of the similarities that do
exist in their structures because see
the outer membranes present in both
intermembrane present both nuclei
present in both again that's kind of
that DNA component there thylakoids
ribosomes in both now there are some you
know unique components to each because
they are different at this point but the
high degree of similarities indicates
that they may have at one time than a
free-living and then some of them may
have been incorporated into cells for
the mutual benefit of again getting
protection the cell getting a way to
generate energy in this case capturing
the sunlight the light energy and
converting it into chemical energy