every cell needs to kind of produce
energy to be for an organism to be able
to survive so we're going to look at
some of those organelles
responsible for producing some of that
energy
in plants we have most notably the
chloroplast and then we have everyone's
favorite the mitochondria
so first off chloroplasts are the
contain chlorophyll those green pigments
that
allow to capture solar energy you can
see even with a light microscope you can
easily pick them out and see them as
they're very well defined in the cell
now chloroplast what's unique about them
is that they are they are
mobile they can actually change position
to maximize
their ability to capture sunlight so top
view here
in kind of sideways view in dark
environments those chloroplasts will
move kind of towards the top
so that they're able to try to maximize
as much light as possible
and if there's too much light they can
actually move to the side or kind of
work their way through
the um the cells a little bit more
diffused but when they want to maximize
the light
absorption they can actually move within
the cell
now these chloroplasts are originated as
endosomatic
cyanobacterium so they retain their own
independent genome and there's some
evidence to suggest
they may have once been free living and
are now through the endosymbatic theory
are now components particularly of plant
cells
so now these chloroplasts have a triple
membrane structure and outer and
inner membrane this again is part of the
reason why
the theory is that they may have been
one's free living because they already
have a membrane structure
this cyloquid forms disk-like structures
which are stacked in the form of grana
these kind of stacks allow for a very
efficient
surface area to volume ratio to allow
for exchange of materials
and then they're suspended within the
semi fluid of the stroma
so you can see here and also located
here now there's a lot of chemical
reactions as i mentioned
so we want to be able to have a lot of
surface area for them to occur
this is a zoomed in version here again
showing you kind of these like discs
that are on top of one another
allowing for that a lot of area for
these
chemical reactions to occur which are
very important because we want to be
efficient with our energy production
within the cells
now chloroplasts are probably most
familiar with process
of the photosynthetic process involved
with taking carbon dioxide
water with light energy and producing
sugars and oxygen as a byproduct
only plants algae and certain bacteria
are capable of going through this
process chlorophyll and other pigments
capture solar energy
and enzymes are ultimately used to
synthesize carbohydrates or sugars
now this site of photosynthesis their
carbohydrates
are being formed from carbon dioxide and
water cells making its own
food using this carbo using this carbon
dioxide here
you can see that kind of membrane here
and this exchange that's occurring
this photon energy this light energy is
driving the breaking down of water
producing oxygen these hydrogen ions
which are ultimately being used to
produce atp and nadph
both energy molecules and being used to
synthesize or create
carbohydrates now that structure here as
i mentioned the stroma the aqueous fluid
we see the thylakoid we see the grana
the thyroid being the individual
component the ground up being a stack of
those
thylakoids and the multiple membranes
here we also have the lumen which is the
um kind of semi-fluid area located
within
the thylakoid now we get onto the
mitochondria
it's originated also as an endosomic
eubacterium
since it has its own dna it has multiple
layers multiple membranes indicating may
have once been free of living
the mitochondria are smaller than a
chloroplast and they contain ribosomes
in their own dna
and they remain in independent genome
it's highly variable among
species so that's kind of interesting
fact about the mitochondria
it's involved in cellular respiration
produces most of the atp utilized by the
cell
a lot of people say it's you know it's
the powerhouse of the cell well it's
really
the site of cellular respiration or the
breaking down of sugar
to form energy so mitochondria is
surrounded by this double membranes and
outer and inner much as we saw with the
chloroplast
these folds again allow for a lot of
surface area to volume ratio
on the cristae surrounds the matrix the
matrix is the inner semi
fluid containing respiratory enzymes
these proteins
involved in this energy production
process and how they're generating that
energy is by breaking down carbohydrates
this energy production that occurs um is
fatty acid metabolism there's also the
krebs cycle or the citric acid cycle
and it's through the process of what's
called oxidative phosphorylation
you're having these kind of all these
components within these membranes
going through and isolating different
components allowing them to create
gradients to then
ultimately generate atp which is the
energy currency of the cell
lastly as i said that mitochondria is
the site of cellular respiration or
it's a site of atp synthesis
powerhouse just kind of cuts it a little
bit short for what it's actually able to
produce
it's a double membrane this is kind of
what they look like i'm looking at a
transmission electron microscope
just say there's folds in there there's
enzymes in there help the breakdown of
those carbohydrates
and ultimately producing atp which is
the energy currency of all cells and
vital for life
keep in mind that animal cells and plant
cells both have mitochondria
while plant cells and algae are the ones
that only have
the chloroplasts