here we're gonna look at the term
entropy and I kind of like this image
right here and as we learned about the
term this has a very low entropy this is
a very high entropy on this side here
low entropy is nice neat organized high
entropy we see that increase in disorder
net spreading L so entropy it's the
measure of the degree of randomness or
disorder or usable energy in a closed
system that's not available for useful
work so when we see something as low
entropy is a much more ordered system
see here a low entropy nice ordered
organized system here as you can see
here in the tall tower here we are have
a very low entropy and we are increasing
our entropy here with that increasing
amount of randomness that occurs high
entropy can have a high amount of
maintenance this disorganization this
disorder you see that low entropy
progressing to an area of high entropy
the second law of thermodynamics is that
referring to is a referring to entropy
increases so again low entropy nice and
organized high entropy very random you
can see that in this also the controlled
demolition of the Colosseum in New Haven
so we start with that low entropy
everything's nice neat and organized and
then the explosive go up go off and now
we have a very high degree of entropy we
have that kind of increasing in the
amount of randomness we start very nice
neat and organized and it was a very
random messy pile there so entropy
referring it to the food chain and
trophic levels the useful energy
available to the next level decreases so
as this mean so we have our sun's energy
here and that is involved as our primary
producers a hundred percent of the
energy here as we work from primary
producers to primary consumers up our
trophic levels roughly 10 percent of the
energy is transferred from one trophic
level to the next so we're simply moving
that decimal by 10 and this is
preventing large amounts of trophic
levels this is why our apex predators
are so few and far between
while our primary producers are very
prevalent the sun's energy and recycle
nutrients are the main sources of energy
here in our pyramid
now as we're reducing or the amount of
energy that's transferred where's it
energy going we have to still take
account for that well a lot of it's lost
energy as heat so when I say the word
lost we know where it goes it just
becomes unusable that's why we consider
it lost and also decomposers to any one
of these stages can break these trophic
levels down and add back in the recycled
nutrients to the bottom of the pyramid
that the primary producers can use and
then again it can fall into the cycle
here so hopefully this is a little bit
of an understanding what entropy is and
the degree of randomness or the degree
of disorder that may exist in your life
you could relate it to your room where
your room might have a high degree of
entropy where it's very messy when you
go through and organize it you'll have a
very low sense of entropy a high degree
of organization