so in this tobacco university video
going to explore entry-level ground
floor cannabis
positions so if you're interested in
kind of just getting started in the
cannabis industry
a lot of times you're kind of working at
the ground floor if you want to know
more what
that might involve continue watching
this video
[Music]
all right let's get into entry level
ground floor cannabis position
seeing here in the image we've got some
uh plants getting hung
ready to go through the drying process
all right so the job description
is involving uh we typically that entry
level grower position
you're gonna be looking at responsible
that growing that cultivation of
operations you want to ensure that all
plants are properly maintained and ready
for
processing want to follow current good
manufacturing practices
and you're going to report to the
manager of the growing department
now depending on the size of facility
you're looking at you could be
specializing in just the propagation
the veg the flowering maybe the drying
stage or if it's a smaller operation
you might be going through and
responsible for all portions of the
growing cycle of the plant
so important to check that out their
day-to-day activities just in general
always ensure the equipment is working
properly and maintain
a safe and clean working environment
that can conclude cleaning up the plants
pruning out
dead leaves and removing them from the
growing area
for harvesting you could be planting
transplanting water and feeding
defoliating staking
disposal of plant materials supposing of
substrates all those
are involved day to day depending on
what day it is during the year
for crop inspections you're looking at
pest identification record keeping
and track and record data on
environmental factors
temperatures min max minimum
temperatures maximum temperatures
humidity levels
things like that and the all-important
documentation
so qualities that a person must have if
you're thinking about kind of pursuing
this kind of
uh position ability to read and
comprehend documents such as standard
operating instructions
properly filing and executing
assignments capable of working well with
others
willingness to learn because hopefully
you could progress up
the growing facility there over time
ability to perform math calculations and
measurements important for fertilizers
ability to focus and pay attention to
detail because every grower is going to
have their own
suggestions or ways to do things they
communicate effectively
it must be a reliable and honest key
part area is showing up
you have to be there to again take care
of the plants be able to carry and lift
50 pounds must be able to spend long
hours on their feet
to go through in pruning removing
harvesting all that can be
very labor intensive and lastly just a
general connection here to the cannabis
industry
often you work closely with managers as
well as other employees
growers are the first step in the
manufacturing process and their
attention to detail and quality checks
allow for clean medical grade canvas
that we have in the industry today
anyone can become a grower it just takes
time and practice many companies will
hire
a wide variety of employees for the
entry level position it's an
easy way to work yourself up and into
the industry there so again
don't be afraid if you're taking that
entry level position you can learn a lot
and get exposed to a lot and then maybe
determine a subset within the cannabis
industry that is of greatest interest to
you