okay here we're looking enzyme activity
we see in our image here the amount of
energy here required is greater with no
kettles no enzyme and with an enzyme we
see that energy is reduced even though
we're starting with the same reactants
and ending with the same products the
amount of energy required is reduced so
we want to look at what at what can
impact our enzymes activity so some key
parts are the order of amino acids
that's why I show that picture of the
chairs here showing a very specific
order that can impact our enzyme action
the temperature the enzyme is in can
help and/or hinder our enzymes a pH
certain enzymes like prefer different pH
is to operate efficiently in then we
have our substrate concentrations and we
have our enzyme concentrations look at
these in a little bit more detail here
so starting with the order of amino
acids the wrong order equals the wrong
shape equals it not being functional so
you can see here a list of amino acids
listed by their three-letter codes here
and the order that these occur in is
very important because that's going to
determine the shape how these interact
and that is going to form either a
functional or non-functional protein so
getting everything in the right order is
very important so that the proper shape
can be had so that the enzyme can
produce the proper function temperature
temperature affects the rates of enzyme
activity there's an optimum temperature
the optimum temperature is the greatest
number of collisions between the enzyme
of the substrate for the human body our
body temps about 37 degrees Celsius this
is typically the optimum temperature of
our enzymes we'll notice here the rate
of reaction as that temperature gets
colder we see that the rate of reaction
decreases what some students forget is
that we have our optimum rate and as it
gets warmer then we've noticed a large
drop-off here
this is because our proteins are enzymes
in this case our denaturing they're
falling apart they're taking on a
different shape and they're not able to
perform the proper function so optimum
temperature is that temperature at which
we have the maximum rate of activity we
reduce the temperature we have less
collisions increase that temperature we
denaturing occurring causing these
proteins and enzymes to have the proper
shape perfect example d matron of
proteins gotten to unfold or lose its
shape is in the taste of the frying an
egg in this case what we're boiling the
egg their amino acids and proteins in
here when we boil the egg we're then
changing those shapes and they don't go
back when we cool them it's another
important note to make once we change
the shape of the enzymes they don't also
be cool then they go back once you fry
an egg it's kind of that same change of
shape and it was either cooler
temperatures at lower temperatures
molecules move slower secondly fewer
collisions between enzymes that's what
you see here the rate of reaction
increases as we increase that
temperature how is this certain point
here where we're seeing a decrease
that's causing denaturing to occur DNA
train is that proteins unfolding or
losing its shape and therefore losing
its function lucia indicated right here
as temperature increases we see that
increase that optimum rates the peak and
then all of a sudden we have this sharp
decrease as a temperature goes above
that optimum rate so it's not just a
perfect linear curve here there's an
optimum rate and it slows down due to
less collisions and above that
temperature we have denaturing occurring
now pH can also occur cause enzymes to
denature most of the enzymes in the
human body function between pH of 6 and
8 but depends where you're located in
the human body
pepsin for example in the stomach as a
peach around 3 and that's what works
best and in the intestines you have more
basic pH around 8
so it's enzymes you can perform better
at pH 8 we see an example here here this
enzyme has an optimum rate right around
7 you can see as we increase the acidity
or decrease the pH we see that rate of
reaction decreases the same is if we
increase that pH make it more basically
see the same decrease right here the
substrate concentration so the rate of
reaction increases until the point of
saturation so our substrate remember our
substrate in our products were
increasing our substrate therefore we're
increasing the rate of reaction to a
certain point here kind of plateaus or
Peaks out kind of will level off at this
rate here
most of the amount of enzyme
concentration so enzyme activity is not
always linear it's based on the amount
of substrate so here we have the time
and seconds the amount of product being
produced with a first phase here and the
amount of enzyme located here so the
amount of enzyme can also impact the
concentration enzyme can also impact the
rate that products are produced enzyme
shape is imperative each enzyme has a
very specific substrate that it binds to
as a result you need many different
types of enzymes to be able to survive
there's many different locks many
different doors need many different keys
kind of the same concept here where all
our enzymes have very specific shapes
that bind to very specific substrates
lastly here to change that shape we have
something called competitive inhibition
the body needs a way to stop enzymes
from working at times so here we have
our site we have our substrate binding
to the enzyme and it's binding just here
just fine and it's able to go through
and perform its function no problem
but with this inhibition site so if the
body wants to stop this enzyme from
working it can take this molecule when
it binds to this inhibition site we
notice the active site here changes
shape as a result in this case the
substrate may bind but the enzyme can't
perform its function so this would be a
way to inhibit an enzyme without
breaking it down necessarily this
inhibitor molecule binds to the site
here and changes can change the shape of
the active site or it can cause this to
bind but not be able to be broken this
is just a way that the normal reaction
will occur here just fine and this is a
way that the body can inhibit an enzyme
without necessarily temperature causing
denature or changing the pH at the
environment maybe because we don't
always want enzymes always working and
breaking things down per se this is how
the body is able to help maintain
homeostasis it can help regulate certain
bodily functions