okay here we'll look at enzymes which
are very specific types of proteins so
we see here on the title slide art
enzyme located the dark gray molecule
here
and we have our substrate being broken
down into two end products
remember enzymes can break things apart
swell is assemble them and hopefully
this would make a little more sense at
the end of this video lecture so in
general what are enzymes all enzymes are
helper protein molecules so all enzymes
are proteins but not all proteins are
enzymes here we see a disaccharide being
broken apart with enzymes into two
monosaccharides so chemical reactions
for life enzymes are involved in the
building of malthus or the synthesis
here we have two independent molecules
taking an energy to form this bond this
synthesized molecule and the officer
that would be break down it's very
important we have enzymes as part of our
digestive system
tell us release some energy here
throughout the digestive process
activation energy is the minimum amount
of energy that must be present for a
chemical reaction to occur so here we
have reactants producing our energy love
our end products this is minimum
activation air this is the minimum of
energy we need to obtain in order to
produce our end products so this
activation energy can be greatly reduced
in the presence of enzymes now Cal the
converters relate to cars here also
internal combustion engines have
catalysts which accelerates chemical
reactions and there's a catalytic
converter the internal combustion
engines this helps speed up the reaction
that occurs to reduce some of the
emissions that are produced
now mechanisms for enzyme action aliy
enzyme must bind to the substrate
practice for metal lower activation
energy and the product will then be
released so enzymes important proteins
for living things and enzymes are
protein that changes the rate of the
chemical reaction they can speed up
chemical reactions allowing biological
functions to occur at a much quicker
rate at reduced energy allowing you to
be able to survive
this is a great summary slide here for
chemical reactions in living partisans
require enzymes to do work the enzymes
speed up reactions are catalyzed them so
let's take this a little more detail the
red line here shows the reactants and
the amount of energy required without
enzymes this is the activation energy
here without an enzyme it's producing
the end products now in the presence of
enzymes we see that the amount of
activation energy is greatly reduced in
this case not only is the energy reduced
but the time to produce the end products
is also reduced so in this example we
have less amount of energy required and
a quicker time to produce the end
products however we look at the
beginning in the end we start in the
same place and we end up in the same
place however her biological purposes
sometimes there could be too much energy
required and if we didn't had enzymes
and if we did not have enzymes we would
not be able to perform the necessary
functions for life so here again enzymes
reducing the activation energy in this
case also reducing the amount of time
this is the overall energy release
during the reaction we see that's
basically the same with or without the
enzymes now some key vocabulary will
region audit enzymes and these very
specific types of proteins are substrate
which are the molecule the enzyme works
on the end product which is what the
enzyme helps to produce at the end the
reaction in this active site which is a
very specific shape which allows a very
specific substrate to bind to that so
that's the active site here it'll be
different for every enzyme one enzyme
cannot bind to a bunch of different
substrates and only bind to the same
type of substrate so kind of just view
that general progression of the
catalytic cycle Weaver active site with
our enzyme here we have our sucrose
which is consists of glucose and
fructose flying together this is a
disaccharide two carbohydrates two
monosaccharides two sugars bonded
together this enzyme has a very specific
shape for sucrose and it's forming this
enzyme substrate complex as mining is
occurring
then the substrate enzyme places
stresses on the sucrose unnecessary on
the glucose fructose bond of the sucrose
molecule and that ultimately will break
the bond and we're seeing that breaking
of the bond and that products being
released in this form of glucose and
fructose and here's the enzyme now open
and able to bind to another sucrose
molecule to go through this process
again again kind of shows you just that
general same progression here again with
the enzyme a lot less energy required
and without the enzyme enzymes are
proteins keeping that in mind all
enzymes are proteins but not all
proteins are enzymes and then typically
end with the suffix ASE or ace and it
can help you identify what substrate
it'll break down so for example lactase
breaks down lactose maltose
breaks and maltose and so on and so
forth a malaise breaks down starches in
mice as a type of starch you see all the
others lipase written down lipids
protease breaking down proteins kind of
using indications if you're looking at
something that you're not quite sure
this may help you identify as a
potential enzyme it may also give you
some hint as what substrate that breaks
down here's an image from the beginning
on the title slide so each enzyme is a
specific help like a very specific
reaction each and then it's the right
shape for the job and this is why we
need our proteins have the proper shape
to perform the proper function this
specific enzyme binds the specific
substrate is able to break this down
into its individual products can I use
the content of a lock and a key class
isn't very important for the proper
shape to perform the proper function so
the shape of protein allows the enzyme
substrates to fit as a regular very
specific enzyme for each specific
reaction that occurs also important
remember that these enzymes are not
consumed or changed by the reaction
they're only used temporarily you can
greet reused again and again for the
same reaction with other molecules as a
result your body needs very little
enzymes to help its
many reactions that occurs so they're
able to bind break down
or synthesized and repeat the process
again and again and again the dieters
need to go through and make more enzymes
necessarily there's enzyme this after
site is a very small area of the enzyme
so this is our giant enzyme this is the
actual binding site and our catalytic
site here reduces the chemical
activation energy and this can let it
allow these enzymes to kind of move and
break things apart or synthesize them
together it'll come back in to perform
that function again lastly changes in
proteins environment can cause the
protein to low-cal denature denaturing
is losing its three-dimensional shape so
here we have our functional protein we
add heat we deem nature that this
changes the shape and therefore this
protein for this enzyme can no longer
perform proper function so shape
determines function if we change the
shape that protein can very often lose
its function in this possibly calling
this protein would denature