when we're looking at a growing
environment we're looking at modifying
the conditions many of these conditions
I have here I've kind of the six most
popular ones a lot of times we use
equipment to do this and this equipment
can malfunctions we need to be mindful
of that so you don't have these
technical difficulties because the
plants are not going to wait idly by so
the equipment in any grow operation
there is a need to include equipment be
sure to know what equipment is rated for
and do not exceed the recommendations as
is concern the life of the product and
this could be for example water pumps or
heaters they usually have stated amounts
or areas that they cover and you want to
try to hit that recommended amount or
low low if you exceed that that's where
you're shorting the light is shorting
the life of that also be aware of
maintenance that may be required with
any piece of equipment as often this can
be very easy or minimal but it doesn't
mean it can be missed or forgotten about
so for example just checking the oil in
your car can be a very quick and easy
test but something that if forgotten
about could lead to failure of the
engine there now for one thing we're
trying to moderate typically no-go area
is heating so generally wears some form
of energy source you need to make sure
you have a consistent source of this
energy and this could be wood this could
be coal sweet propane's could be
electricity even natural gas regular gas
there's a whole bunch of different
options yeah make sure that you plan
ahead it's your core your heating source
especially as you get into colder winter
conditions where you're likely to go
through the required heat source much
quicker we want to be running out or
ordering it when everyone else needs it
prices will go up and it will be harder
to get AAPIs of that way of cooling this
can often be very costly for operations
it is possible to cool an outdoor grow
space with shade netting kinda like
putting sunglasses over the plants but
you planning this will reduce the
overall light that reaches the plant so
he mindful of how much you're shooting
the plants fans do not cool the plant
they only mix the air and keep it moving
which can help increase transpiration to
aid in the natural cooling process of
the plant true cooling required air
exchange as an air conditioner unit
split-level cooling units there's a lot
of different options but they typically
consume a lot of electricity
to keep that in mind after lights old
bulbs wolves reduced their efficiency
slowly over time as a result growers
will typically not notice it poorly
producing gulp simply by looking at it
it'll still appear to be very bright
this is where par metres come in are
highly recommended as well as
documentation of the purchase date an
estimated number of hours of usage you
can write the purchase date right on the
bulb itself or keep that as part of your
records so you kind of know about what
you should be changing that out on the
calendar based on the hours you plan I'm
using that Lowell reflectors can't
forget it everything's of the bulbs
can't forget about the reflectors here's
two different options reflectors can
also reduce their efficiency over time
bulbs need to be changed more frequently
but changing reflectors should be
considered about every two to four years
best way to know if the or estimate your
reflector efficiency is to test with a
par meter each time you add a new bulb
if you get two feet away let that bowl
warm up test the power at the plant
level and every time you add a new bulb
test it out and see based on
documentation records that see if it's
the same they'll tell you the amount of
light being reflected and if it becomes
a below a certain amount you may want to
consider changing out that reflector you
have the photo period determines the
stage of growth the clip will be in and
if there's a problem with the amount of
light or really want to think about as
hours of continuous darkness this can
create plants that are not in the proper
stage that the grower expects purchasing
quality timers and also check them to
ensure their accuracy during the entire
growth cycle some girls will prefer
these analog style ones because they can
physically see if it gets off digital
ones you kind of got to be there to be
able to tell there's no real physical
means you can go through and take a look
at so again they both work just fine
some girls do prefer the analog for that
reason but have some way of checking to
make sure your plants are under the
proper photo period community is
important because depending on the
growth stage the plant will determine
the proper percentage you want to
maintain when plants are younger and
smaller one have a higher community as
they get older it's hard to produce the
buds we want to reduce that humidity so
you can having control over this I'm
doing containers I'm having a way to
regulate the committee are all important
things to consider
and also monitor water pumps often pumps
are necessary component but growers will
commonly undersized the pumps causing an
increase in wear and tear reducing their
overall life you want to oversize pumps
to be sure in continuing to monitor them
since it will typically burn out without
little warning I also set up a schedule
to ensure regular cleanings of filters
so if you are running a complex
operation here and you have some filters
those filters may need to be changed at
certain times or just go through and
monitor them depending on the quality of
water that you have but it's a sediment
filter or chlorine filter fans are great
for air circulation but they can die
without warning so you also want to be
mindful of how old they are what their
expected life maybe watch the blades and
cages to ensure that they're cleaned as
needed to maintain the peak efficiencies
typically accumulate a lot of dust and
the fan blades and that can cause them
to kind of overheat and work harder than
they need to which can vastly reduce
their expected life