when looking at setting up a hydroponic
system there will be some equipment that
will be needed
now the specifics of the equipment that
you need will depend on your exact
system chosen but there are some things
that are true just about for all systems
so first off the minimum equipment like
and while there can be variability it
would be a water monitor of some kind
that will allow you to read the
temperature the EC or ppm and pH as well
also you need a quality water source or
to be able to make a quality water
source and precise measuring equipment
so that water monitor out blue labs
bluelab Guardian is particular here it's
important to always know the current
conditions of the water pH is important
but so is the EC and temperature and
that's why I like this kind of
all-in-one it allows for continual
checking and monitoring of it's a good
habit to get into to always have this
kind of reading that always making sure
the numbers are where you expect them to
be or within the range you expect them
to be here the ppm is a little high but
temperature is looks good and pH also
looks good
there's also wireless systems that can
allow you to nightly check on conditions
remotely so you even have to be in the
room but can also sometimes give you
alerts if a certain parameter has gone
over or under to give you that
indication without you constantly having
to check it also quality water source
it's important to know how your native
water test meaning what do you need to
do to modify that it's important also to
recheck whatever source you're using
over time to get an idea of a range so
I'm just test it once and assume it's
always like that throughout the entire
year determine if you need to invest in
a filtration system it's best to meet
the native water conditions for example
if you have high salts or high water and
ro or reverse osmosis system might be
advised you have a lot of particulate
present sediment filter you have
chlorine coming out of tap water a
carbon filter may be your best option or
a combination of these your measure
equipment with hydroponics it's very
important to be exact with the nutrients
you're adding keep in mind looking at
these graduated cylinders there will be
this little bit of this kind of bend to
the water it's called the meniscus you
always want to be reading the value at
the bottom so while this water does come
up a little bit here in here this would
be a 40 unit measurement here
so we want to use the bottom of that
what's called the meniscus having
quality measure equipment is important
you know try to get different gradations
here these are graduated cylinders they
are very accurate beakers are not very
accurate
you always make sure you're cleaning
these before and after you use that
regarding of regardless of what
nutrients you are adding don't estimate
no value and be sure you're adding that
amount and check to confirm with your
water monitor if you sure those pH and
then as PPM's are hovering around where
you need to be and double check to make
sure you Dan over or under add your
nutrients