okay here oh look at the plant hormone
ethylene but you don't realize that this
one you may have experience with before
even if didn't realize it was this
particular hormone that was doing it so
to start off with ethylene plays a role
in fruit ripening so here we have an
apples acid and soured Starkiller
chlorophyll and pectins hard and large
molecules when we had ethylene it can
activate a bunch of enzymes who knows
all these and in the ACE indicating that
their enzymes and we can develop a ripe
apple now which is neutral pH has a lot
of sugar instead of starch less
chlorophyll less peckmon so it's offer
and increased fragrance notes with our
banana here it's going from a green
banana all the way to a ripe banana to
an overly ripe banana this is showing an
increase in ethylene that is causing
this ripening to occur so ethylene what
is it it's a smallest hormone it
typically is this as a gas it's
important for seed germination fruit
ripening and abscission of leaves that
means leaves get basically fall off
we're noticing here our fruit ripening
the stage of a fruit and our ethylene
concentrations here those in the green
or unripe stage are ethylene production
is quite low then others have a large
spike as we get closer to ripening and
at peak ripeness your notes and the high
amount of ethylene produced now that's a
slow decrease over time here but we
notice that those where the fruit is
ripe the ethylene is much higher than it
is when it is unripe so looking at the
functions of ethylene well I mentioned
that a decision person it has a rapid
diffusion so ethylene can work in the
leaf here the obsessions hindered the
shedding phase where the leaf is dropped
off deathly can actually block it to
this kind of line here means block
auxins from from activating nuts with a
lot of hormones or interactions between
them i'm gonna try to focus on this with
these specific hormones do or what
they're kind of known for and ethylene
because it's a gas can diffuse very
rapidly
also affects adjacent individuals so we
come up with the same which you may have
heard of one that apple spoils the bunch
and this
because one bad apple is gonna produce
high amounts of ethylene that ethylene
is going to affect the adjacent
individuals so this one bad apple is
going to cause the apples adjacent to
ripen which those are gonna cause ones
basement another ripening and it's gonna
spread throughout the entire barrel or
area here we go back here to senescence
in abscission that's where the leaves
senesce is where they're being broken
down and obsessions where they're
actually falling off the plant and
that's ethylene is involved in that
process in in the end the one bad apple
spoils the bunch of nuts because of
ethylene one bad apples gonna ripen all
the other apples now this could be used
to our advantage if you've ever had a
hard peach or unripe bananas that you
want to speed up the ripening may have
heard you put them in a brown paper bag
and let them sit for a day or two
that'll speed up the ripening process
that brown paper bag is trapping in the
ethylene causing that fruit to ripen a
little bit faster so the brown paper
bags something you might have put fruit
in miraculously they come out and
they're softer especially peaches and
nectarines well that's because of the
ethylene production that's being kept in
a closed confined area speeding up the
ripening process lastly with ethylene
there's something called a triple
responds this triple responds indicated
here we have zero ethylene concentration
of parts per million more slowly
increasing them keep in mind all home
was working very small quantities so
here the triple responds well I think
inhibits stem elongation who knows hairs
were increasing our concentration the
elongation of the stem is being reduced
the stem is being thickened compared
this stem diameter to this stem name of
the highest ethylene concentration and
lastly a third part of the triple
responds horizontal growth of the stem
as a concentration of ethylene increases
we see that here was shaved upright
growth with no ethylene as we're
increasing the ethylene we're noticing
that stem is slowly starting to bend to
the side there it's also thickening and
we're noticing some there
the leaves are being different
maturation rates they're also so
hormones despite their very small size
and typically very small concentrations
can have a large influence on plant
behavior