okay this is gonna be a very quick
overview of eukaryotic cells looking
here's an example of just a model one
this is an animal cell and looking at
some of the components and what
basically allows you to look at this and
define it as a eukaryotic cell we're not
going to go over any of the individual
organelles
that'll be saved for another video so
first off you care excels the domain
Eukarya what's it include if you looked
at my video on ProCare as soon as we
talked about archaea and bacteria here
looking at basically the rest the
protists the fungi the plants and the
animals here
these are eukaryotic cells so what's
eukaryotic cell well they contain memory
bound nucleus if specialized organelles
a plasma membrane and are actually in
comparison much larger than prokaryotic
cells some cells example plant cells
have a cell wall not switch this is
indicating here so the key part here is
these memory bound organelles and it's
what makes them distinctly different
than our very simple more primitive
prokaryotic cells these organelles for
example are basically little
compartments and they perform very
specific functions the isolate reactions
from one another so it allows them to be
membrane down this is a nice
representative cell there's 14
organelles basically identified in this
other videos we'll go through these but
if you're able to kind of recognize some
of these I quit number nine is clearly
the mitochondria notice the folds in
their e1 and to write nucleus is the
larger structure nucleolus is the
smaller structure in there and so on and
so forth so again being able to see the
fact that this cell has organelles puts
it in the category of eukaryote and in
understanding what all of these do we'll
be safe for another video two classes of
organelles our endomembrane system these
are organelles that communicate with one
another via channels these are
completely endoplasmic reticulum the
Golgi apparatus and there's the other
type of organelles the energy week
related organelles the might occur in
the chloroplasts these are both
independent and self-sufficient they
kind of generate their own
energy no slot folds in both of these
high surface area to volume ratio on the
mitochondria present in all cells and
remember our chloroplasts only present
in plant cells because they go through
the process of closed synthesis a nice
comparison between prokaryotes and
eukaryotes cells good way to kind of go
down the list and see if you can be able
to recognize or identify certain
characteristics of one which is the
other being able to compare and contrast
in two makes for an excellent quiz or
test question so going through and
looking at the type of nucleus remember
you carrots have that true nucleus and
double membrane proteins just have a
nuclear region they look really true
define nucleus dealing a circular and
prokaryotes linear and eukaryotes and so
on and so forth so you look again pause
the video and compare the two and look
back at the pro Kerik video if you'd
like to review that one and be able to
compare both of these different types
because you're probably gonna see it
somewhere in the future