here on this debaco university video
we're going to be covering the eurasian
hemp or
proper identification and control as it
relates to cannabis
so here we can see pictures of the same
plant here when cut away
clearly there is an insect in there this
is identified as the eurasian
hemp borer and we're going to go through
how to properly identify it in a plant
and also how to go about controlling it
so first off just a general description
the asian hemp oil can have negative
impacts on cannabis plants
document is documented as an economic
importance for fiber production
economic threshold is 10 larvae per
plant due to reduction in plant growth
and seed production and seeds the
problem is that it borrows into the stem
so here is a cutaway of the stem we
could see definitely a
necrotic region here blackened region
that's where probably entered is eating
away at the stem
the base of a bud here but it is
internal
so how do we go about identifying uh the
eurasian hemp or
and we could see here just some of the
adult
eurasian hemp or moths we also see the
pupa evident
here so when we're going through and
identifying or proper identification of
the bore
it has a distinctive characteristics
there's a pinkish
whitish pale brown a larvae with several
uh barely visible pale
bristles at the body segments the asian
temple are small 78 millimeters compared
to the corn earring which is much larger
so you don't want to confuse the two
uh earlier larva and stars are difficult
to distinguish from the background as
they're whitish and cream colored as we
saw on that first image
may have two to three generations in the
southern united states so be aware of
that
the head is a yellowish to brown
coloration and can be dark to
black it does have light detecting very
simple eyes
the late larval instar in the fall is
the overwintering stage and can have an
orange to reddish coloration kind of as
we see down here
this stage passes the winter in well
sheltered places such as folded leaves
or
tunnels tunneled into stems the telling
may cause some stunting and distortion
of the stems and stalks
the adults merge during the spring after
mating and they start to lay eggs
in the absence of hemp they can feed on
hops and knotweed and probably other
weeds as well
adults are small moths as we see right
here displaying white stripes
in the front edges and four chevron-like
stripes
near the center when they'll expand it
now the adult this kind of shows that
kind of a little bit more zoomed in
version of the adult
they are commonly spread to new
locations via infested hemp seeds or
debris
the cultivar selection may be important
wild hemp in vermont seems to have
innate resistance to the pest compared
to that wild hemp in the midwest united
states
that's kind of an interesting discovery
there at least initially
now what to look for on the actual
plants is the larva
of the infested moth borrows into the
stem of the hemp plants making tunnels
so while it looks like we have some
wilting going on here and some browning
it's really that
internal portion that is of concern they
can also feed on the leaves and later in
the season attack
seeds as well as flowers so if you see
this die back
go through and investigate the stem you
might have to do a little cutaway and
you might find
one of these hemp boards so to go about
managing
the hemp or well the first step should
be cleaning pruning and disposing of
infested plants
remember this insect lives in the stems
this is of increased importance if
cannabis will be grown in the same
location
the following year removal of wild weeds
is also recommended to eliminate
alternate hosts
insecticide application effectiveness is
reduced to the fact that the immature
stages live inside the stems
very difficult to control them there
systemic products are often not
registered or recommended
and that's what it would take to get to
the actual location
where this templar is located so this
gives you some good information there
hopefully you don't see it but if you do
you're able to properly identify and
start to implement control measures