okay to go along with this unit on the
immune system I figured I should mention
two diseases that are particularly good
at evading the immune system and
describe just a little bit about how
they're able to go about avoiding
all of the systems we have in place to
hunt down and seek out and prevent and
destroy pathogens that enter our body
the first ones pride the most obvious
and when you're probably most familiar
with HIV human immunodeficiency virus
what this basically doesn't have too
great links here so you're welcome to
look at the description and click the
links directly there
they mimic antigen presenting cells by
activating the macrophage and helper
t-cells cd4 receptors so instead of an
antigen it's actually injects its own
RNA and three enzymes HIV is actually
what we call a retrovirus
it is taking RNA it's transforming it
into DNA incorporating it within the
macrophages T helper cells in the DNA as
a result because the HIV virus this DNA
is involved in the host cells T helper
cells it's able to hide within the
immune system and basically render the T
helper cells as they replicate basically
rendering them helpless inside and not
able to perform their function so T
helper cells replicate destroys the
cells and leaves the immune system
unable to not response up to any foreign
antigens let's forget the concept of
AIDS a variety of otherwise commonplace
infections prove fatal
so if you're infected with HIV it the
virus itself here is not what actually
kills you because it's essentially
nothing out or preventing T helper cells
from performing their proper function
you're more likely to die from cancer or
even the common cold because you lack a
functional immune system
another great theater of the immune
system is tuberculosis so specifically
Mycobacterium tuberculosis this resists
the cell destroying enzymes and
replicates in the macrophages of the
lungs in particular so when the immune
system finally does
is fine the bacterium is protected by a
thick waxy wall here has come examples
on what it looks like humans cells
surround the bacterium long enough
creating this trabeculae but does not
kill it and it's a key part there the
bacteria becomes dormant until something
acts to weaken the immune system so it
kind of can stay there and kind of hang
out for a while when the immune system
becomes compromised that's the time that
it will start to replicate again causing
a new outbreak this is why typically
people need to break your losses
screenings to be able to tell whether
they're carrying this particular
pathogen which could easily be hidden at
times but show it cells during times of
stress so another quick short video here
a minute 41 seconds you're welcome to
take a look at regarding the CDC's
tuberculosis treatment and transmission
here so it was helpful and just giving
in to examples of diseases that exist
that are able to evade the immune system