okay in this tobacco university video
we're going to be looking at the details
regarding evidence collection
how some specifics how they pertain to
some individual pieces of evidence
you might be looking at collecting keep
in mind you first want to define
the crime scene because crime scenes are
never consistent each is unique and
presents different challenges
you need to determine the area that will
be searched and ensure this is protected
from people entering and exiting so that
there's no alteration
whether intentional or unintentional of
the evidence that you're going to be
collecting
looking at performing the evidence
collection process
keep in mind this needs to be systematic
and detail oriented
you want to start with preliminary kind
of crime scene survey and walk through
they want to progress to determining the
evidence collected and search method
that you'll be utilizing
because since av crime scene is unique
you want to make sure you're utilizing
the best one to best fit the evidence
you intend on collecting
for the crime scene at hand now the goal
in all crime scene investigations and
evidence collection
is to help ensure that the evidence
you're collecting is of high integrity
the goal is to keep this evidence in its
original condition as it's found at the
crime scene whenever possible evidence
should be submitted to the laboratory
intact examples such as blood
hair fiber soil particles and other
types of trace evidence should not
normally be removed from garments
weapons or other articles
um that bear them you want to move the
whole article that contains that
into an ms collection bag or container
and give that to the lab
this entire object should be sent to the
laboratory for processing
there in the lab as you can see down
here everything can be kind of isolated
and contained to ensure or reduce the
odds of any potential
cross-contamination that would occur
now in order to keep this consistent you
want to make sure you're labeling
everything so all
containers must be marked and sealed
seen before moving
the item so this kind of gets to be a
little bit tedious task but is a very
important one
many items will have primary and
secondary containers you can see here
the primary container that's wrapped in
a secondary container
here may be placed in a plastic bottle
which then is placed in a paper bag
so there could be multiple kind of
areas where you're encasing this
evidence but keep in mind all needs to
be
labeled it's a tedious but very
necessary
process the reason why i say it's
tedious is labels have certain
requirements they could
require to put the case number the
offense the location of the offense the
date of the offense description of where
the evidence including any model or
serial numbers
collector's initials so all this kind of
needs to be documented for every piece
of evidence that's collected
this is part of kind of that chain of
custody you're establishing that initial
evidence
and then you're keeping track of also
where that is going
or where that may be shifted to now the
equipment for evidence
collection can be quite varied looking
at gloves and forceps and tweezers being
necessary especially looking at some of
that smaller trace evidence
scalpels and swabs paper bags for sure
for good storage containers plastic bags
often not advised in general but can be
used for some objects or inclusion of
others
cardboard boxes for larger items
wrapping paper thermometers a plastic
bucket for large objects to prevent them
from getting damaged
so as you can see the amount of
equipment needed is quite varied because
each is designed
to maximize different pieces of evidence
to eliminate the chance
of them being altered to a great deal
now this
physical evidence is typically we think
of initially as evidence
with any evidence the goals to prevent
any alterations from the time it
collected to once received in the actual
lab and that physical evidence that
transporting it here into the
plastic cup here we're taking a
documenting photographs
and then lifting prints maybe collecting
what we see on the ground and then
putting into paper bags as an example
when we're handling this physical
evidence in general we want to make sure
that we're photographing it to begin
with
we want to handle in a way that
maintains the integrity of the sample
which is often a way it's not
normal for an object for example you
don't want to grab a firearm by the grip
when you go to pick it up you want to
grab it
because that's typically where the
fingerprints may be you want to grab it
in a way that might be a little awkward
but will preserve the integrity where
someone normally would hold that
particular piece of evidence
when we're packing that evidence there
we want to use separate containers
for different items collected at
different locations this is intended to
reduce the chance of damage or
cross-contamination
we could see those paper bags being used
we see metal cans we see this cardboard
for syringes or sharps or knives being
placed in foam
inside a round plastic container here
and sealed being zip tied to the bottom
of this cardboard box
all ways that we can ensure proper
packing of physical evidence
now the standard packaging requirements
we're looking at for general items are
placed in appropriately sized containers
this is why
investigators will carry so many
different sizes make sure it's
appropriate size for the evidence
they're collecting
knives if a folding knife if found open
do not
fold it closed it should be placed in
separate separate sharps tubes
a folding knife and found closed it
should be secured with tape so that the
blade doesn't open
and then it should be placed in a
plastic sharps tube this is not only to
preserve
the evidence itself but also to protect
you as the investigator from getting any
sort of harm
from the objects you're collecting now
some specific requirements so for
example here for any
narcotics that might be collected at the
scene there's a whole host
of kind of processes to go through keep
in mind packet
package all found or kayaks are
dangerous substances and should be in
paper l
paper isolated envelopes keep drug
paraphernalia in separate packaging
you want to weigh in document each type
of drug in its entirety including the
packaging
you want to conduct a presumptive test
to give an idea what it may be
and seal the evidence tape with your
initials in your date
once packaged you weigh them again in
the complete packaging and write the
gross weight on the outside of the
package
again so this is important to keep that
documentation step going those way and
going as well
for firearms packaging we want to take
pictures before
moving the firearm so that's a key part
right there make note the position of
the bolt and slide and chamber and
hammer
where the safety's placed position of
the cylinder and any cartridges that are
found
for handling be sure to secure the
weapon by eliminating part of the gun
from moving
and you can see that evident here in
these cardboard boxes with zip ties
caution is this may not involve
unloading of the firearm
when it packages the fire you can also
package it potentially in plastic
but make sure any ammunition is packaged
separately that is
found so again certain requirements here
for packaging up
firearms we're looking at our trace
evidence our hair our fiber and our
glass and other
examples of trace evidence typically
plastic bottles are used
with pressure lids because they're great
options for this
paper bags are a good choice for larger
objects we want to avoid the mailing
envelopes that's why we kind of like
those little
sealable kind of plastic containers
there
different sizes again to match the piece
of evidence
that we're specifically collecting the
proper techniques for liquids so keep in
mind what evidence must be air dried
before it's put in a container because
it might be altered when placed in that
container
when suspected biological evidence is
found on clothing or other
absorbent surfaces transport to the
laboratory an appropriate container
moves the entire substance
possible whatever should not be folded
over on itself use
paper wrapping to prevent contamination
during the transfer process
items should be air dried thoroughly in
a drying locker and packaged in a
container suitable for
dried evidence this means avoid airtight
containers to the increased chance of
mold growth over a period of time
this evidence may not get looked at
right away this if the suspected
biological evidence is liquid form on a
fixed surface that cannot be transported
for example like a concrete floor
the substance should be recovered using
a dried material collection
technique that's the only way it should
be removed from the actual crime scene
that dried material kind of moving it
through make sure you're always using a
gloved hands
slightly motion a swab with distilled
water the swab should be dampened out
overly wet
thoroughly rub the stain using a single
motion swab for
a small stain and multiple swabs for a
larger scene
i air dry the swabs and then place those
swabs in separate labeled packaging that
may be placed inside a paper envelope
collective substances control a sample
as well from an unstained area using the
same techniques
and be sure to label it so as you can
see again this
is certain techniques that are needed
depending on what material you're
collecting
there are certain techniques that must
be followed and be sure that you're
labeling
everything so that all this evidence can
not only be
utilized in the future but can have that
proper documentation step so it can
uphold itself in court