so here we look at evolution getting it
there from here kind of help in
explaining origin of certain structures
in organisms and certain species so
starting with evolution in general there
is looking at this we're seeing that
there's evidence of macro evolution
what macro evolution is is the
evolutionary change on a grand scale
large scale this encompasses the origin
of new species and major episodes of
extinction
so macro think just like this is large
scale changes micro evolution are
evolutionary changes as it would may
guess at a small scale so know
encompasses genetic changes that will
occur within populations over time these
traders are result of changes in gene
frequencies so we see here our gene
frequencies for certain colors have
changed in these butterfly wings here we
have the squirrel River grey squirrel or
black squirrel and our by now way to the
squirrel here this would be micro
evolutions it's simply a change in color
they're all still squirrels are all
still butterfly's wings here we're
seeing a micro evolution change this
could really impact whether or not an
individual can survive or not but still
it's considered a micro evolution a
small change versus a macro which is a
large-scale change so putting it
together Mac refers to changes in
tourism's over time that are so that are
so important that the neuro RISM would
be considered a whole new species that's
the best way to think of the macro
evolution microevolution and
macro-evolution both happened in the
same way and for the same reasons but
micro is more that kind of change in
coloration and macro is the potential
extinction or creation of a new species
there and that's our comparison between
the two
getting there from here so I'll mark
here many and many others prior to
Darwin and Wallace so that's different
if nothing prior to that theories
developed by those two thought
biological evolution occurred by what's
called in acquired characteristics it's
a treat that an organism develops
through interactions with the
environment in those past
ah spring body in behavior changes
acquired during their lives so I gave
some examples here and this is ends up
not being the case but for example the
manatee with the scars in the back this
happens usually with boats at one that
went into them sadly acquired
characteristics mean if all the manatees
had these scrape marks eventually they
would pass on these screen marks to
their offspring or individuals
if someone continually got pierced ears
eventually their offspring we would have
pierced ears naturally in the black
spots on the leaves here done to the
ostrogothic black spots and leaves this
is the concept of acquired
characteristics now again this is not
what happens but this is what mark
thought and this is was his theory so in
contrast John and Wallace they proposed
variation is an inherent acara critics
of all biological populations so it's
not created by an experience it's
readily observed in all populations
again just look around the variants that
we have but the example here of um some
shells we see some different patterns
from different colorations it's the idea
that the body has a certain number and
amount of genes they get passed on to
the egg for the embryo to then develop
from our punnett squares and our kind of
odds of getting certain alleles and
combinations we see here again
number alleles for height it was very
short is very tall here's the mean the
average these acquired characteristics
do not hold true so I'm back here not
acquiring these characteristics right we
are variation based on genetics so
that's not created by experience that's
created by the genetics of the
individual not the experience that the
individual may or may not have so mark
again compared to Darwin the mark was
idea of the giraffes is for his primary
example so he came up with the idea that
by reaching higher for vegetation
giraffes simply stretch their necks and
as a result this results in them
acquiring longer necks in their
offspring Darwin believed that giraffes
were born longer necks and are better
able to survive and
for have more offspring who inherit
longer necks so again it's nice
comparison between these two scientists
at the time its holds true even today
the scientists that debate one another
so we need to support our ideas with
evidence and this is how we develop and
refine different theories so hallmarks
environmental roles is too much to
change in Darwin the environments role
as a selector the organisms role and
Lemax was active and Donnell it was
passive it's the genes that you get and
these didn't change and it's basically
regardless it's a slum gravan will
change regardless of what scientist you
look at the key part is here Darwin
believed in the inherent of genetics
mark Lydon acquired traits and inherent
it's definitely with the DNA the way
that this does occur evidence for
standard view of Darwin was that
evolutionary change occurred extremely
slowly and these changes accumulate such
that over thousands or millions of years
major changes could occur this term is
called gradualism and here's our horse
that I explained in the overview of
evolution we see how it's changed both
in size and structure but it's occurred
over a long period of time give the
examples of over millions of years we
can get these major changes that occur
they occur slowly and over time but over
these millions of years we get these
large changes that can occur let's refer
to the pace of evolution so punctuated
equilibrium hypothesis this is a blue
shape change occurs in bursts separated
by long periods of little or no
evolutionary change so we see here
gradualism where we're slowly getting a
lighter and lighter and lighter color
here punctuated equilibrium is where
things definitely diverge and change all
of a sudden we get a white one and that
white basically doesn't change for this
time period and we get the kind of the
more orange and red fish color you tan
color boom that changes that state is
pretty consistent for a long period of
time this is referred as punctuated
equilibrium gradualism refers to just
slowly that changed over time here
there's there's definitely these break
off points and while it's a white one
here it stays a white one here there's
not constant changing that's occurring
whose abrupt changes that occur in the
time scale so examples of both gradual
punctuated equilibrium to exist so
speciation clearly occurs in different
ways this would be the same example here
while starting with the green butterfly
and progressively these two colors with
gradualism and here's how it look with
punctuated equilibrium have the idea
that speciation is necessary and linked
to phenotypic change has not been
supported so we're seeing that
speciation can occur without phenotypic
change and phenotypic change can occur
within a species in the absence of
speciation so we're looking at that
morphological change we're not looking
in any of these cases at the genetics
we're just looking at the phenotypic
changes rate of replication different
organisms do with all the different
rates bacteria evolve much faster than
eukaryotes because they have a simpler
base pair unit in their genome so they
can occur much faster versus mammals and
fib using flowering plants in much
larger against base pairs many more base
pairs so it takes a lot longer for these
to change enough genes to cause a shift
in that organism in the rate of
evolution that punctuated equilibrium is
that branching that occurs and
gradualism is that steady change over
time the genome size again the base
pairs is more of a visual the mutation
rate and the genome size we see that the
larger the genome size them longer it
takes so viruses can change very quickly
and relatively speaking compared to
eukaryotes this is what makes viruses a
little bit harder to kind of combat
control because they can change from
year to year eukaryotes can also change
but it takes them millions of years a
lot slower rate of evolution still
occurs again it could be graduation or
the punctuated but the rate that the
change occurs is dependent on the
mutation rate which changes based on the
base pair or the number of base pairs
that individual organism has for DNA
sequences