okay Hugh metallian a little bit of one
of the larger groups of dinosaurs and
the evolution of dinosaurs and how that
kind of relates and provide a local
connection for those that live in
southern New England so evolution of
dinosaurs see we differ our different
time periods and our progression and
branch points of different types of
dinosaurs suddenly we see him around
here on 65 million years ago it's kind
of like a distinctive stop they all kind
of reach an end point and modern day is
up here and you can see the branch point
that made it to the end and how many
different types of species and subsets
were ended around that 65 million years
ago so evolution of - oh here's a
Triassic period it's the oldest known
fossils we have small carnivorous
dinosaurs dominate this time period now
when I say small I'm talking about three
hundred thirty to four and forty
estimated pounds here they're successful
these were successful because their legs
were directly under their body provides
good support being where agile and
beings fast runners we're well adapted
to dry conditions and mass extinction of
other infants reduced competition so
we're looking at what makes an organism
survive well this organism to its
environment very well when we're talking
about the Triassic period in particular
talking about that 208 plus million
years ago then it goes Jurassic and
Cretaceous the period does all part of
the Mesozoic era and then we get closer
into modern-day dinosaurs became extinct
at the end of the Cretaceous period
again around that plus or minus 65
million years ago now Pangaea and the
dinosaurs remember the world looked very
different around 200 million years ago
try our climate the mass extinctions and
have curd diversity to fill mitches left
by these extinct species the Mesozoic
eras considered the age of reptiles 235
million years ago dinosaurs dominated
the earth
pam g has separated climates and changed
dinosaurs became extinct while new
species flourished so we have this kind
of initially this is kind of how it
looked it since all our continents kind
of colored in what Pangaea is that one
single landmass
that eventually all broke apart and keep
in mind even today the continents are
still moving providing a local
connection on dancer State Park located
in rocky hill Connecticut they
accidentally found 2,000 dinosaur tracks
there's uncovered during the excavation
for a new building in 1966 literally one
of the operators of the equipment
bulldozer sat down to have lunch and
looked down saw what he thought was
dinosaur footprints and that led to
other people looking and eventually the
discovery of these 2,000 tractors in a
rock layer more than 500 of the tracks
are now enclosed within the exhibit
centers geodesic dome which is open to
the public and remaining 1500 are still
buried for preservation and they look
quite good they're very well preserved
and this is one of the model dinosaurs
that you could see in the dinosaur State
Park it's important to a sir state park
in Rocky Hill on the side note the
footprints are named separately from the
dinosaur
so since conditions that preserve
footprints do not preserve bones
typically like a mudslide as great
preserving bones not right for
footprints the footprint is given its
own unique name compared to the likely
dinosaur that made them so the actual
footprints in Connecticut are called you
bronty's and this is a positive
footprints of the dinosaur actually
stepped and that's a kind of a downward
depression the negative print is a
raised region this is the sediment net
filled in so keep in mind or to get
accurate footprints we need the dinosaur
to step in mud with a thin layer of mica
or some other substance to come in that
can separate and we need sediment to
come in typically this is like a rising
and falling tide and that allows these
two sections to separate if you get the
footprint but not that thin layer of
mica to be able to separate it the key
walking on the beach more sand fills in
and you never knew the two step their
positives where the dinosaur stepped
negative is the seven that fills in the
dinosaur that we believe made those is
called Dilophosaurus nearest bones those
were found were in Arizona
far cry from Connecticut but it matches
the same approximate height and weight
and lived around the same time here
if you seen Jurassic Park they'll
officers look something like this
and it's kind of Hollywood taking their
own liberties with developing a quote
they may think is a cool-looking
dinosaur but we keep in mind that
Hollywood and that is nowhere near the
accuracy of what we believed I love this
source locally