okay here me to describe the basics of
experimental design and when we come
across a problem when design and
experiment is the general steps you
should follow so first step is a
generate a hypothesis start by simply
asking a question and then complete some
background research and then generate
the hypothesis so we're talking about
generating that hypothesis you know to
start right with that you want to ask a
question first and then complete some
background research you can see that
we're getting here we're gonna test the
hypothesis during new data do you agree
or not agree and then work from there
but that first step is kind of identify
a problem gather some data and then
generate that hypothesis it's got to
come from somewhere
now once we develop that we want to look
at an independent and dependent variable
so here we're starting with the
independent variable this is a variable
often termed denoted as X whose
variation does not depend on that of
another
well scientist changes or what changes
on its own so a way to think about this
is the independent variable is for
example the fertilizer building at
growing the plant the independent
variable could be the amount of
fertilizer added so that would be an
example of independent variable contrast
to that we look at dependent variable
well it's a variable off node by Y whose
value depends on that of another what is
being studied or measured
so if our independent variable is the
fertilizer our dependent variable would
be the height or how big the plant is
growing so again going back for a second
independent variable what the scientist
is changing for example the amount of
fertilizer dependent variable would be
the amount that the plant is growing so
again lot of students kind of confuse
those two that should be a pretty clear
way to think about them at least one
example then that experiment they what
is an experimental scientific procedure
to undertaking to make a discovery test
hypothesis or demonstrate unknown fact
so it's kind of a broad definition there
but it's kind of performing those tests
and that could be you know in sterile
lab here or it could be looking at can
you generate power from a carrot now as
a control group in good experiments so
when we think about control groups as a
set
that does not receive a treatment by
their researchers so in this case you
can with the plant example were looking
at adding fertilizer the control group
would be the set of plants that does not
receive any fertilizer the goal of this
is to provide a benchmark to measure how
other variables perform kind of getting
into that separate group and you may see
in drug studies a placebo or sugar pill
when it doesn't have the chemical
substance in there again after that
benchmark to then act for comparison
their constants are different than
control groups constants are portions of
the study or experiment that does not
change so for example pi is the same
number regardless so a constant in our
plant growing example could be the size
of the container we don't wanna have
some plants growing in small pots and
some growing in large areas or outdoors
and indoors when I've Constance when I
have the media that they're growing and
one of the container growing in the
environmental conditions as constant as
possible across all plants allowing the
potential for fertilizer variables to be
shown then we have different trials that
we may go through and do this is a
number of times that protocol is
followed a lot of times experiments not
just done once and that's it trials are
given may grow plants in a greenhouse we
could grow them for you know the month
in the summer months ago and then repeat
that in the winter months human
conditions the same Navon times these
experiments are repeated which refer to
as different trials so you may see the
average of trials average of experiments
you can see here some small tubes again
different trials repeating that again
Clifton analyze the results while
collecting data is an easy format
initially and we need to change when
it's published for others to see so
analysis can take on many different
forms which determine on the questions
asked or the purpose of the research
either they should be determined before
the research is concluded so you don't
wanna say be determined the questions
ask the purpose of research at the end
kinda want to have that at the beginning
and kind of that's driving the entire
process there
lastly the conclusion summarize how your
results support or contradict your
original hypothesis include key facts
from your background research to help
explain the results as needed so that
conclusion is kind of take
information taking what you've seen
taking some things she may have taken
notes on and kind of developing that
conclusion summarizing those results so
that someone when reading your study you
can kind of see what you're able to find
and then potentially build on that in
the future