this video here on debacle university is
going to focus
on explosion chemistry so looking at
that combustion
that occurs and results in this
explosion what are some different
examples of this
so starting with just chemistry of an
explosion in general
well essentially a combustion reaction
is very similar to that of a
fire the major difference though is the
speed of the reaction
damage is caused by rapidly expanding
gases in
a confined area so again there is still
a quote fire present but this combustion
means that there is definitely a speed
associated with this reaction as well
now the explosion is a sudden release of
chemical or mechanical energy caused by
an oxidation or decomposition reaction
that produces heat and rapid expansion
of gases here we may see it as like
a fourth of july fireworks for example
very controlled explosion and here we
see definitely a large fireball
indicating over a large area here now
there needs to be a reagent so the
reagent is a substance used to produce a
chemical
reaction to direct measure or produce
other substances there's kind of that
initially
starting substances we have reagents
also in various other
aspects of chemistry here we're looking
to produce that chemical reaction and
reagents can be quite
varied we're looking at a high
explosives so high explosives are
chemicals that oxidize extremely rapidly
producing
heat light and also a shock wave if you
look down here below me
you can clearly see the evidence of that
shock wave here
of the explosions occurring on this
battleship
these will explode even if not combined
so
keep in mind high explosives don't have
to necessarily be combined to produce
their end result again we capture that
nice image here you can definitely see
evidence of that shock wave that is
present
then we have our low explosives so keep
in mind low explosives are chemicals
that oxidize rapidly producing heat
light and a pressure wave look at kind
of that pressure wave these will explode
only when they are compressed or
confined
in an area there so slight differences
there from the
high explosives but again explosive
still
very dangerous and things to be
considered
when we're doing an investigation