if you've looked at hydrocarbons to work
on extracting cannabis
one be cautious but two hopefully this
video here on tobacco university
will provide you a little bit more
detail with this extraction process
[Music]
all right let's look at extracting
cannabis with hydrocarbons
so the general description of the
extraction
method well it is a closed-loop system
and plant material is placed
in the extraction vessel and then cold
hydrocarbons such as butane or propane
is washed through the plant material
you kind of see that here we have a kind
of a column example
the waxes fats and lipids from the
cannabis bind to the hydrocarbon and the
plant material is then
removed the resulting mixture is then
cold boiled in a vacuum
and the butane evaporates as butane and
propane have very low boiling points
then the resulting extract is collected
so we kind of again
see here we have the solvents chill down
the low temperatures
some washes over cam is packed into a
column okay
the cannabis and terpenes separate from
that plant
material and they create kind of a crude
oil we have the collection tank where
the solvent crude oil mixture enters
and then heat is applied to evaporate
the solvent and then we kind of see the
crude oil being collected
and then a compressor pulls the
evaporated solvent pulls out of the tank
condenser tank
condensing cools solvent vapors
back into a liquid form and the solvent
can be turned back and can have this
closed-loop system
so in theory it seems pretty pretty good
pretty efficient
and it can be but again we're dealing
with hydrocarbons and butane
uh be cautious with those so what's the
resulting end product well that
resulting
end product of hydrocarbons come from a
variety of forms textures consistencies
based on the protocol that's actually
used we're all
compressed by the broad term butane hash
oil
examples in end products are shatter
batter and crumble
cannabinoid concentrations average
between the 80 to 90 percent
range so one of the advantages of this
system
was that it does preserve the terpene
and cannabinoid content very efficiently
compared to other methods there are a
wide range of extract types that can be
achieved through hydrocarbon extraction
and it can be done with trim and flower
it also has relatively low equipment in
run cost
as we kind of see here a simplified
version of that system
however with any system there are
disadvantages and one of those
disadvantages we'll put in kind of all
caps here
it can be extremely dangerous butane pro
and propane are highly flammable and
extreme caution must be used when
extracting with hydrocarbons
also unwanted compounds could make it
through the extraction process
it would need to be later refined so
keep that in mind as well
so let's talk a little bit about
hydrocarbon extraction if you are
kind of looking at it definitely make
sure that you are cautious
when utilizing this make sure you
understand your equipment very well
so you don't create a very dangerous
situation