welcome to this tobacco university video
here i want to go over easy clone for
the cannabis cloning process
setting up the physical system if you
want to know how to actually take the
clones i have other videos
on that but let's go over the setup of
the easyclone system
for cannabis cloning
[Music]
all right let's make sure all the
mechanics will be working so when you
take your clones
they'll be going into a good environment
well first off we want to be
mindful that the reason why i chose the
easy clone is it's the industry standard
there's many options but this is
considered just to be one of the
standards and hopefully you'll have
roots that will look like this or even
better
there's many other designs that copy the
easyclone
basic system which is again a sign it's
probably pretty effective
it is very efficient in a simple system
and that's kind of the reason why
there's so many copies
so you don't have to specifically use
this easy clone
actual system that i'm going to show
here a lot of the basics will apply to
other systems
but i chose that one here just as a
representative sample and hopefully you
find it helpful
and increase the odds of success with
your own plants
okay so here we're looking at the easy
clone system it's a very efficient
aeroponic cloner
what we're looking at here at the very
top is all the nice little foam discs
here
these will be utilized to hold the
plants so when we're looking at taking
our clones and harvesting our clones if
they were this
pen for example we would simply go
through take a clone about that long
and then insert it into the foam disk
that then allows this to be held
and that will simply go into the area
here we'll have our little clones here
now occurs on the underside well on the
underside this is where
all of the water pump is and all the
water will be
so on the inside here we'll notice
we have this water pump now this water
pump simply takes in water
and then sprays it out of all of these
little jets here
what does that create well that creates
a very high humidity heavy
mist environment right here why is that
important
well if we look at kind of the underside
here you can see where i still have the
pen
this is where our roots are going to be
initially formed want to keep that area
dark which we can see here
and also high moisture to reduce the
stress on the plants
so our plants will all be kind of here
or clones with no roots
initially this will then create a very
favorable environment for them
to root and this simple water pump just
constantly runs on it 24 hours a day
and that will just kind of keep that
area well misted so that offers a great
advantage
to be able to kind of offer a
favorable area for that rooting to occur
you also notice
on the tank here there is a
on the underside here there is an area
to easily drain it
that is great to easily drain it when
you want to keep in mind that if you
are initially filling this you want to
make sure that's closed and set
and that no water is going to drain out
when you go through and fill it
so you can see fairly easy simple system
this is the official easy clone
name brand if you will there's many
different
kind of copycats there are kind of
different types of competitors out there
this is kind of where it all originated
and this really offers a nice very
efficient
system and let's see setting it up in a
small grow tent
so here we're looking at the 2x2 grotin
that's going to
house our 64 easy clown what we're
noticing right here
is a deluxe 315 watt cmh
ceramic metal halide light that's going
to provide the even
light source here for all of the plants
i've got a couple systems off
right now we'll see those kind of
implemented as they go through and turn
them all
get the ball working together but right
now i've got the light testing that out
and down here is ultimately where the
easy clone is going to go
keep in mind just because they're clones
air circulation is still important and
here we're in an office so we also want
to make sure that we have a carbon
filter
to reduce any potential odors also going
to set up
the water monitoring system to our easy
clone but let's go ahead and just simply
install the basic structure of the easy
clone so kind of getting it right off
the
main desk table there simply going to go
through and
it's a tight fit but it does just fit
perfectly right there so you can see
again two by two
really maximizing the overall space that
we have
now i want to go through make sure we're
filling it full of water and i'll show
you that process
so one quick note when we're setting
this up you want to make sure
if you look very closely at the easy
clone here
you'll notice that there's a series of
numbers
that work their way from one
all the way to the number eight on this
side
and then there's a series of letters as
well h
through a that's up there and numbers
replicate up there
the numbers replicate up there and the
letters replicate coming down here
that's just important for identification
which you should be keeping track of
anyway but knowing what clone
what strain what variety is in what area
is important
so again it's just helpful if you start
off by organizing it in such a way
and orienting it so that the entering
point
matches up with everything now if you
look ahead here as i'm getting
everything together
you'll notice i have the monitor
in there and again this is just with
regular tap water so i've gone through
and just taken
right out of the water faucet
with our blue labs
monitor here you can see reading 130
parts per million 74 degrees fahrenheit
and a ph
of 7.0 to 7.1 i'm going to go through
and add the
necessarily the necessary nutrient
solution
and let's see where this ends up before
we start modifying the ph at all
so it's looking getting our nutrient
solution all ready for our clones
i choose to use a clonex clone solution
and it recommends about 5 to 10
milliliters per liter
so use that as a general starting point
always start on the low end and start
adding
what i kind of do is start at the low
end and i use my
blue labs monitor here to be able to
dial everything in and make sure
the solution that the plants will be
exposed to is within the tolerances that
i want
so again this is a great kind of initial
solution to start with
works great with the easy clone and can
kind of go right through and
just takes a little time to get
everything all adjusted
and when we're adding our nutrient
solution it's very important to keep in
mind
of where your monitors are so as an
extreme case here
where i poured the nutrient solution
happens to be exactly where the monitors
were
so you could see right now growers might
be a little bit of in a panic
with a high concentration of parts per
million a very low ph
but keep in mind you want to let that
pump run you want to give it a couple
times before you start making
quick adjustments let it settle out add
a little bit more add a little bit more
until you get it dialed in
now again as another note you want to be
mindful that while everything looks like
it's nice and sealed here
when you lift these out you might be
getting some mist that sprays out
so that's why it's important always to
start or have these on hand
to maintain a nice sealed environment
here because that pump is actively going
and it's doing exactly what we want it
to do
doing exactly what it wanted to do in
the sense that is spraying water some a
little bit more violently than others
but down as i look down in there in that
environment that's exactly what we want
to see you want to see that nice
heavy heavy mist so there might be some
dead spots here and there
but for the most part the high humidity
that this does create is
beneficial for rooting just remember
you want all of your nutrients dialed in
and you also want to be mindful
of maximizing the amount of water
and maximizing the amount of light
keeping air circulation keeping all the
conditions you want consistent
again we're watching our nutrients kind
of come up and get a little bit more
dialed in there we're adding a couple a
little bit more being incremental not
making sure we spike anything too much
pump seems to be working great just be
mindful that you might want to be
careful of some areas you can spray a
lot of water
um so you want to make sure those are
all nicely sealed up before you get to
your clones
and that will just help maintain the
water in the environment and efficient
use of that water
because it's constantly recirculating in
there
and as part of these clone we get
everything dialed in what am i shooting
for
well i think a parts milling around 7 20
temperature around 74 and ph around 6.2
these are good initial targets to have
there good way that will definitely
produce some quality clones
so again once everything is dialed in
make sure everything's running well i
got the fans running
the carbon filter set to go and i've got
all
of the area here all ready
for clones