so in this debaco university video we'll
be covering
fabric pots and grow bags for cannabis
production
[Music]
all right let's start looking at some of
these fabric pots and grow bags for
cannabis production so first off the
advantage of using
a fabric pot is that it allows for
aeration to the root zone
they come in small to potentially very
large sizes up to 400 gallon size
they're very user friendly the material
allows for natural root pruning to avoid
kind of that circling effect that you
might get with a solid
container and then they also allow water
to drain
very easily all these are great
advantages and part of the reason why
they've become so popular
the material that they're made of might
vary slightly from company to company
but here i provided a little example
here what's called gorillapods they're
pretty
commonly used they are used basically a
breathable fabric that helps support
while still allowing movement to the
root system they're typically made from
mostly polypropylene fiber with an
anti-uv
application to reduce degradation
especially in outdoor settings
because fabric pots are not only used
just in indoor settings
they can be used also in outdoor
settings there's a lot more
environmental stresses so you want to
make sure if you are going in an outdoor
situation that you are finding a pot
that might be a little extra for
but definitely has the advantages of
those anti-uv applications made
now fabric pack you'll notice that they
come in a variety of colors
and while there are a variety of color
options tan simply has gained popularity
especially in
outdoor settings because it can keep the
root zone cool
in the heat of summer something that's
going to not necessarily absorb a lot of
heat
we saw the white one earlier but won't
show the a dirt from moving it around
quite a bit
so again there's a variety of colors the
really advantage particularly for the
outdoor
network do you want that anti-uv
stabilizer but you want something that's
going to keep that root zone
relatively cool now fire pots and water
we're going through and kind of like
looking at reusing them
parapets do not really collect water so
this can help prevent over watering of
plants allows them to drain through very
easily
and also many fiber pots are washable
and can be
reused so it's another potential
advantage we see here we're using a
solid container
and then we're having the fabric pot
here with some
material at the bottom that will allow
it to drain very well and this is again
a way
particularly for new growers to help
prevent them from over watering their
plants
and if you're going through and wanting
to reuse that make sure you're giving it
a good scrub a good wash
of removing as much of the substrate as
possible so they can be reused
with reduced chance of contamination
from one crop to the other