okay here we're investigate some of the
factors that shape climate so there's
many things that play into a particular
regions climate where I look at some of
those factors and how they influence it
so the key factors at shape in area's
climate and here I have some an outline
of the geographic or the world and some
of the typical climates we might be
familiar with or associate with
different areas and the key factors that
shape these are temperature water or
moisture content the sunlight soil and
wind now something might be weird we
think oats the earth resulted in the
sunlight but keep in mind of the
different amount of sunlight that may
occur and extremes it the pole regions
how during the summer the northern
hemisphere way up near the Arctic Ocean
Arctic Circle area they may get close to
23 24 almost 24 hours of continuous
sunlight in the winter they may get the
flip of that of almost complete day of
darkness so that can be what I referred
to as sunlight so take the first one
here temperature influences natural
plant life you may have heard of the
USDA Plant Hardiness zone map this is
referring to kind of the average
temperature in these various regions
might be a little hard to see here but
as you can see in general thing at the
colors these areas tend to be colder and
planted to be able to be harder to more
harsh or cold conditions than the colors
here tend to be more mild
they'll notice it's not a perfect kind
of based on degrees of latitude see this
kind of western coast area very similar
to the southern southeastern regions of
the United States this can be located or
based on proximity to water particular
oceans that has more mild in certain
areas or mountainous space and elevation
here where it's a lot colder a lot
further selves so land masses can also
shape climate there's as I mentioned
there's these coastal areas that tend to
have smaller changes in temperature and
mountains can have a large effect on
climate because it can cause
precipitation so we have the western and
kind of eastern slope well the western
slope kind of a look in here
western slope being here or Sierra
Nevadas western slope is going to be
much more lush a lot more water it's
gonna occur they're out more
precipitation is going to occur because
that water is basically getting kind of
squeezed out then in the eastern slope
or kind of the backside of in this case
the mountain range it can be a lot more
arid a lot drier is that moisture get
squeezed out on the western slope and
that leaves it less to be on the eastern
slope as that moisture kind of comes
down the other side of the mountain
creating a very dry particular type of
climate on that side we can kind of see
that here we call terrain shadow we're
looking at prevailing winds on the
westward side kind of compressing and
condensing that water causing a lot of
rain events you can see very lush green
this here here about a satellite image
and then on that other side there the
dry air advances and there's something
called that rain shadow it's very arid
or dry we see that clearly evident here
with a lot less lush green plant growth
and we could see now we look back that
that western slope and easier so how
that western slope has a lot more those
trees a lot more vegetative growth in
the eastern so being a lot drier and
maybe this kind of sideways image of the
mountain kind of shows that western
slope here being squeezing all that
convincing all that water moisture out
and then that eastern slope being a lot
drier that rain shadow evident so we're
talking about water can see the water
here different types of rainfall or
looking at typically the Gulf of Mexico
region here can get a lot more rainfall
and overall the eastern half or kind of
that Mississippi River East tends to get
more rain than Mississippi River West
particular so again it can kind of
impact in areas climate also this kind
of shows a nice little progression here
of the different months and the typical
inches of rain or milliliters per day of
rain on average in the where that tends
to occur over the different months of
the year and we can see
really in this kind of band right here a
lot of rainfall overall this portion of
Africa the northern part of Africa
remains very dry this is there's a lot
of deserts located here aa system to be
much drier region and the closer to the
equator area here there's darker blues
indicating a greater amount of rainfall
on average per day over the courses of
the month that we see here than over the
year
now sunlight as I said latitude is a
great influence on this looking at the
amount of sunlight that different
regions get again we would think that'd
be a nice kind of easy influence here
where equator gets the most and the
poles get the least there is some slight
variance amongst that but latitude does
have the greatest influence odds are the
closer you are to the equator the more
direct over the course of the year
sunlight will receive also have soil
type so those global soil regions and we
see these many different soil orders
these all have independent properties
and qualities some better for grown
crafts and better for supporting plant
life others not as supportive of plant
life and we can see that they are quite
variance across the globe here we see
some consistency and in northern regions
these dezerter regions here and to kind
of looked back at the water we see that
also has an influence on the type of
soil that's present in the different
regions of the globe lastly we have wind
so land basin offshore at annual average
wind speed at about 80 meters and could
see areas that may be windier turns
areas it tend to be calmer this can also
impact the various climate also being
impact on weather companies could invest
for wind turbines as alternate forms of
energy but wind can also impact in
area's climate typically near the coast
it can be windier then more regions or
proximity to mountainous regions can
also impact the average wind speed in a
particular area
you