so here in this debaco university video
we're going to be looking at factors to
consider
when estimating the time of death and
we're going to look at some of the
digestive systems
some blood pooling to look at so these
are different factors
while not a complete list some key
factors to consider when estimating the
time of death
so first off the digestive contents we
want to keep in mind
these can help determine the time of
death by determining how long the person
was until
they ate until they died so seconds it
only takes seconds for chewed food to
pass through the esophagus down to the
stomach
four to six hours for the stomach to
empty its contents into the small
intestine
about 12 hours for the food to leave the
small intestine 24 hours until
undigested food is released from the
large intestine and this digestive
process usually takes a bit more time
than a day
but it can be affected by sickness
liquid intake
fear and also any drugs the person may
have consumed so you want to keep in
mind of these potential variables
to the times stated here when we're
trying to look at the digestive contents
of an individual
now looking at the eyes is another
indicator that can be used because the
eyes of the victim can also hold answers
to the time of death
there's a thin cloudy film that will
develop over the eye within about two to
three hours after death has occurred
if the eyes are closed though this will
take about 24 hours for this film to
appear
so keep that in mind is how the person
was found originally can influence again
these times
that are stated here the eyeballs become
softer as a result of less fluid
pressure behind the eye
and the degree to which this has
occurred can be used as a measure of the
time since death as well
keep in mind i have a couple little
chart here kind of looking at
uh open versus closed in the onset just
to give an approximation for trying to
pinpoint within as degrees accuracy we
can to estimate that time of death
we also have skin coloration to take
into consideration so the color the
corpse will help determine the time of
death from about
48 hours onwards so not great
determining under two days
but beyond two days this has a stronger
correlation
from approximately 40 hours after death
bacteria begin to breed in the skin
giving the skin
a noticeably green tone the tinge will
start in the lower stomach
area and spread outwards affecting the
hands and feet
last so they can also give an idea of
where that progression was found
or discovered on the individual
approximately four to seven days after
death the skin will
acquire this marble-like appearance and
this veins become
closer to the surface thus becoming more
easily visible
so again skin coloration another factor
to try to estimate that time of death
we also have blood pooling as we can see
here the pulling of blood
can be a vital clue in determining the
time of death and
is known as hypostasis this occurs when
blood ceases flowing selling the lowest
parts of the body and in turn causes the
skin to become pink
and red in color blood will pool at the
lowest parts of
the body usually starting between six to
eight hours after death has occurred
analyzing location of pulling can help
indicate the position of the body
also if we find that region and we kind
of apply some pressure
depending whether the coloration changes
or not or how quick it returns can also
help indicate
an estimate for time of death here in
the upper image
see the blood pulling in the back here
as this
person is left in what's called the
supine position there on their back
and that blood pulling indicates that
that is the position
they were in when they died so all these
are contributing factors to help
pinpoint
when the time of death had originally
occurred