yeah I'm gonna go over some farm
equipment off general farm toys not
always are they things that are powered
and big tractors they can a simple
wheelbarrow or a shovel if you want to
know who your true friends are show my
shovel so going over just general
equipment what we may need on the farm
so the first step is appreciate what you
have to me easier said than done but the
basics of what you need in part depends
on what you already have so whether it's
a small rider mower a small tractor or a
larger tractor even just a walk-behind
tiller appreciate what you have because
what you're going to need what you think
you might need it's gonna depend on what
quipment you already had what your setup
is and how large or small your operation
may be so needs and wants what do you do
need it or do you want it we all look
good indeed the shows that nice shiny
new tractor but that could be is that
more of a need or is that really want
here's the old symbol there for Apple we
all want maybe a new computer but we all
need the actual food in substance
ideally being copy is right between the
needs and the wants and it could be very
hard to decipher in some cases but
sometimes take a step back and really
look at the situation so items worth
consideration so of the farms I visited
invent ooh and even my own little
operation here what's worth constancy
consideration what should you really
look at potentially getting and these
three things kind of keep coming up in
second inning a Miss blower and drip
irrigation with an injector and it's
kind of shows that netting on Miss
blower and drip irrigation with an
injector doesn't show the injector here
well why are these things important so a
sort the insect netting well ince
igniting is gonna be the way for the
future from what it seems like
instead pressures constantly increasing
it's the only item for insects that has
a hundred percent efficiency again
assuming it's installed properly we want
to make sure that we're protecting our
crap and especially with those trying to
be organic and not lying to or having
very limited applications of products
that they can apply a physical barrier
is the way to go
even for some chemical guys the spring
of its exercise does work on occasion
but nothing beats insect netting for
that true physical barrier now again
there are some things that come with it
there's set up there's the making sure
it's installed properly but it does
offer 100% effectiveness if it is
properly installed so there's different
mesh sizes so all insect anything is not
the same ought to include certain
insects again the larger the insect the
bigger the mesh size you can get away
with finer mesh should be advised to
protect against aphids or other small
insects here's some infant even down the
like little strips some cases larger
mesh is typically less expensive not
always but typically less expensive it
can be used for like squash bugs on
cucurbits that transmit yellow vine
decline become a major issue in our area
collard potato bill beetle get bigger
insects bigger mesh typically less cause
if it's very small tip require smaller
mesh sides and typically more expensive
in Sec netting so infinity more than
there's a crop cover highly recommend to
be installed on all season extenders
such as high tunnels do not make a hinge
door as it may left open so your high
tunnel structures if you have roll-up
sides they're great for air flow which
you may want to be in lining that with
insect netting to prevent insects from
getting established there early in the
season with you should but then starting
in that April or even March timeframe
you want to prevent your insects from
getting built up there the reason why I
say don't put a hinge door is if you
walk in you might close it but if
someone else walks in they may leave it
open leaving it open can allow some
insects to escape in and they've trapped
in a nice perfect environment I'm having
doors may have like
screens have like magnets that keep
coming through and they be attached that
can also be great and you walk through
and you snap them right back together
something to just have a pipe down so
you have picked the pipe up to walk in
and drop it right down immediately so
you're kind of eliminating the chance of
insects kind of sneak
in but still allowed you access physical
bear this isn't a new idea it seems like
everyone's like oh sick nanny
it's been used bird netting from grapes
to keep birds out of grape vineyards
same concept getting different mesh size
of course but same basic concept that
physical barrier providing that
separation between the crop and the test
the miss blow is another one this blower
can allow for efficient nutrient
applications Bruce is very small
droplets a fine mist
it's basically a backpack leaf blower
with a water tank the goal is to get the
droplets very small a very high surface
area which can allow them to be spread
out more efficiently on the crop this
blur saves time quick coverage to
provide better coverage over traditional
hand pump sprayers and it can get the
top in the bottom of the leaves very
quickly also means you don't feed right
there at the crop it can spread pretty
far distance and still be able to get
efficient coverage this blower allows
you to less product it's a cost savings
mine's actually paid for itself they are
expensive but the thei product that I've
used a lot less of I've been able to see
it cost that way not to mention the time
and labor stay tensed I've had so by
simply pulling the truck mix the area
going through and spraying I'm using
less product doing it in less time and
to me now it's completely paid for
itself still works just fine miss
blowers can help avoid the cult the
lobster arm here are fiddler crab here
where you're constantly one hands always
all season pumping the pump sprayer the
miss blower is gas-powered makes it
really easy and efficient to go through
and start it up and walk down the field
these are two examples steel makes two
models here I'll the downfall those they
can be heavy but there's two different
size options so the four gallon is here
it weighs 28 pounds empty and water
again about 8 pounds of gallon you can
do the math there adds up really quickly
but they have a small 2 gallon one it's
only 17 pounds again empty but you only
fit two gallons in it so it's it's less
weight in that regards this is basically
steels we lack or motor and says they're
true least
I've used them both I can say that they
both perform and they both do the same
function with the four gallon one is a
much bigger motor you basically run into
a net idle this one you have to use the
throttle a little bit but it's more than
capable so if you're someone it's a
little bit something lighter on their
back this would be a great option to
look at the other thing I should I think
most farmers should seriously consider
is drip irrigation in an injector so
drip tapes allow efficient watering low
of operation percentage in the injector
indicated here last for precise nutrient
application which allows you to put
stuff in the pail here and it's injected
right through to the crop they do
require some filters may be some
pressure gauges some extra plumbing but
it's well worth it in season do please
come in different thicknesses
if you sterilized your rows the thicker
can be more cost-effective because you
can use it multiple years there's the
six mil it's basically in one season use
used under plastic 8 mil common leaves
for vegetable crops again about one
season use but a little rougher and
tougher 10 mil come using heavy rock
areas or when turning something like a
strawberry plant and the 15 mil allows
multiple years of use I will say I've
used the 15 I'm using some on my sixth
year and it's working out just fine you
give to take care of it and pulled out
of the fields for the winter is a little
bit of a labour in that sense but using
it year after year makes it so much
easier then have enough you make all the
irrigation lines drip tapes their flow
lights and emitter spacings are
different this can determine the amount
of feet of tape you could run at once it
takes a little math calculations I'm not
going to worth a ton of math but
basically you can adjust the tapes or
flow rate to match the gallons per
minute your equipment good supply we've
got a lot of water you can double a lot
of water from irrigate large field or
you might have a slower kind of flow and
you just have to irrigate less at one
time just takes a little math
calculations give you some examples here
I'm not going to bore with all the
details but the key part is here if
you're assuming we have a consistent
seven gallons per minute which is on the
low end the amount of water you want to
add
it's 400 gallons your total world feet
is 1500 feet well in this case if you
got the low flow you can run 3000 feet
of drip tape at once if you get to
higher flow you can only run 1500 drip
tapes at once this one you'd have to run
twice as long two hours because it flows
less this and you can run for less time
so again depends on the pump in the area
a lot of companies are very willing to
help you out
and while the math may look scary
initially once it kind of dive into the
numbers you can always pause the video
and look at it in more detail it's
really not that bad the injector says
dosatrons is for him name it allows for
precise amount of liquid to be
fertilized the irrigation at a time
these are ones might here off they're
running and they kind of click click
click click click click click click
sound as they're going through the
injecting the fertilizer as the water
flows by you can see here valves here
this one's not running or operational
the valves are closed off so you don't
always have to run it through here but
it gives you that option injectors they
can be used when needed they can move to
different zones they make little carts
and it can provide a quick fix if you're
in a situation where you knows
crops going a little deficient in
something you could we load these over
here hook it up to the irrigation line
and go through and fertilize the crop
just what it needs a Mazzy injector is
less expensive alternative to the
dosatron type injectors there's no one
in carts they work with the entry effect
if you're familiar with carburetors if
you're have an old tractor or an older
car they have their issues but their
jury is basically what's going out the
carburetor in the case of mashing
injector here you can see it's set up
very similar to the other one there's a
timer and a fertile and a filter I
should say in the fertilizer injector
these do tend to lose some pressure
because they're working on the venturi
effect which is passing liquid through a
smaller area causing it to move faster
changing pressures allowed to soak up
the fertilizer here and you do lose some
pressure overall so just again it's a
big leap in mind for your system however
just because you can inject fertilizer
doesn't mean you should always be doing
it focus on a few key elements to liquid
feed your soil should do the mean
feeding okay this is a fertilizers dream
the grower the farmer who buys the
entire car every different type of
nutrient because they got this fancy new
injector and they're spending all this
money injecting fertilizers because they
can focus on a few your soil should
really be prepped and you shouldn't be
going through and having to fertilize
with a ton of stuff nitrogen is a key
one sometimes potassium too so wish
lists for farm equipment different for
each individual unique farm you know
everyone has different wish lists some
some can give smaller items larger items
but everyone I know has a wish list the
tried and true all does that say
outdated anti tractor still around for a
reason or overbuilt
they're very heavy this is a new to me
john deere em that I bought 1949 you
spot it is kind of fixed it up a little
bit ran through runs just fine two
cylinders Johnny popper it does the job
just fine no issues so just because it's
old doesn't mean it's outdated so don't
always think he need the brand-new
latest and greatest computer technology
this is just a very very simple system
it works just fine there's also some
tools out there that one does it all
kind of the Swiss Army knife approach
the BCS Detroit built flex is kind of a
new one on the market here they lacked
specialization they can do it all if an
engine goes down though everything will
stop and you can only do one task at a
time so just because you know one power
base can go through and be a blower be a
snow blower be a mower be an air
compressor Clin to one of those at a
time so just important to keep that in
mind if this does fail you think all
your attachments simply don't work so
again just another reason for concern
but the advantages they have one thing
to keep and maintain so that does make
it a lot easier that typically you're
not mowing the lawn and snow blowing at
the same time so you're only using those
one at a time you take care of that
piece of equipment and it can last you a
long time specialized equipment can
allow for quick transitions be efficient
use a plastic mulch layer potato digger
cultivator specialized equipment you
know when you get into certain things
you may if you're spending all
that time doing that you may want to
congestive I in that case going through
and researching and buying that once
piece of specialized equipment that you
may only use one or two times a year but
if it makes it better overall for you
then it's worthwhile hey equipments a
prime example yeah all these different
lower attending the rake baler all these
different specialized pieces of
equipment are all needed to produce
those nice little square or those large
round bales needed for animal feed I
also want to make comparisons don't get
locked into one thing a lot of farmers
think oh it's a farm I need a tractor
well in some pieces a skid steer might
be better here's some just weighing some
of the pros and cons look at both sides
you can see here proce detractors good
for row crops long and high designed
designed mainly for farming not easily
maneuverable in tight spaces though
limiting on their lifting power that's
something of concern skid steer very
maneuverable high lift height good
weight capacity multiple attachment
options but they're very low ground
clearance and only front end attachments
no kind of three point hitch on the back
or something
so again pros and cons everything way
both sides talked with others see what
they're using preventive maintenance is
another important aspect there's a whole
different kind of lecture and
presentation on maintenance but this is
often I find overlooked I know it gets
busy in season checking the oil is
important checking tires for weathering
and grease fittings you can't stress
that one enough knowing where they are
knowing what grease it's filled with
having a grease gun knowing where that's
located does that preventive maintenance
quick kind of coolant check tire
pressure check can really save you a lot
of time being down in season when you
really need a piece of equipment so just
good to check oil make sure it's in the
low to full ranges at burning oil is at
cleaner oil you don't have a tire go
down and grease fittings you want to
burn it out fittings quick little
maintenance can really save you a lot of
time and lastly for equipment I don't
want to be about hand tools I want to
think that every farm needs to have a
giant tractor
do not underestimate
made the need for simple hand tools and
the variety of hand tools a sigh I can't
I'm amazed at how many people don't have
one or no even what one is or if never
even used one we had a weed whacker go
down at one of the jobs I had previously
they had a size sitting on the barn door
forever and how no one's ever touched it
and I grabbed it and cleaned up the area
we need to it takes a little getting
used to I'd be careful with them it's a
long blade but they can be very
efficient you're loppers you're pruning
shears your different types of shovels
everyone's got their favorite shell
whole different lengths so don't
underestimate the need and the
efficiency that hand tools can offer in
certain instances always have plenty on
board keep them hanged up so you don't
lose them or forget them in a field you
don't want to leave one in the field and
run it over with something and pop a
tire or have other issues but hand tools
for especially smaller operations have a
wide variety keep them organized and
they can make your job a lot easier