in this debacle University video we're
going to look at fascination with
fasciation on a cannabis mother and
clone plant we're going to hear from
Connor out from the greenhouse to show
us one of the plants that is going
through and cloning as you can see in
the picture here to see if we can
perpetuate this fasciation trait
[Music]
all right well first off I should Define
this in fasciation if you're not aware
is really Define its development of
elongated flattened in stems on a plant
we can clearly see that here compared to
the normal this can be also expressed in
the flowers from the apical part of the
of the plant we can see this one in
comparison to the normal one dandelions
can also have this so we can see the
normal dandelions in the background with
this fasciation one here in the
foreground
now is this good or bad particularly
related to cannabis well typically it's
not considered to be advantageous other
than a unique ornamental characteristics
however in cannabis this change in
flower morphology can lead to some
interest and we can see all these plants
exhibit a fasciation now the question is
you know is this good or is this bad
definitely is looking very unique
so what are some potential causes for
this to get it kind of like the root
cause is what this might occur well this
is typically the result of a genetic
mutation of the meristematic region of
the plant remember meristematic region
is the area of high cell division this
is evident by the elongated and
flattened cells this is kind of what the
top of the plant looks like right here
as seen in the example here it's the
apical meristem showing the change in
this morphology and it's really not
shown on the side branches and you'll
see that in a moment with Connor out in
the greenhouse since this occurrence is
typically isolated it could be pruned
out after grower decided but in this
case the grower has attempted to clone
it for the future to see if this trait
will continue
now does fasciation equal a super bud
you know we're seeing this change in
morphology in that apical meristem well
is that going to make a super Bud well
typically uh the apical Bud the top bud
can initially look very impressive but
often the actual development is quite
poor so what it may look like it might
be a super dense Bud sometimes though
there is a lack of density due to Rarity
there is the reason for the cloning is
to Simply increase the sample size to
see if this is if this initial
observation repeats itself however even
if it could structured superbud was to
develop you have to keep in mind that
the odds of botritis would likely be
much greater so extra attention would
have to be taken for this plant to
ensure you're not losing this unique
quality to a botrytis or a bud rot mold
so let's go out to Cotter and see what
he has to show us with the fasciation
plant we've seen in the greenhouse
hello everyone once again we are back
here in the greenhouse
um we're here looking at our fascinated
plants again our mutations
um here we have
one of our original fasciated plants you
can see it started down way down here it
started getting wide started thinning
out
and if you follow along up
you can see
it only keeps getting wider
it's around two and a half inches almost
getting to three and it actually up here
started to curl in on itself almost like
a piece of celery
there's a crease that goes down the
middle
and that eventually follows all the way
up to this new apical meristem growth
and this
this plant specifically
has some of the most unique growth
because there's no fasciation on any of
the side branches coming out look at the
difference between the thickness of that
main stem
and this Branch it's it's absurd
and once again if you look up to the top
near the apical Marathon you can see how
bushy it's really getting
compared to a normal standard growth
I'm a little nervous as it as it starts
to Bud that we might be running into
some
humidity moisture issues with this large
mass of growth but I'm going to watch it
carefully and make sure to thin out any
leaves that I need to
but it is just a beautiful work of
nature
and if you want a little
comparison for size that is a quarter
sitting
in the middle of the stem it just looks
crazy
yeah I look forward to what what this
plant comes to um I'm hoping for a
fairly unique kind of wide flower nice
big bud but once again I do have to
worry about those moisture issues as it
does
Bush up some more
welcome back guys we're here looking at
um our fasciated plants again
these mutations along the stem were so
unique that I decided that I wanted to
try to continue on the Legacy
and well I did
um here we have two clones
these are baox strain a high CBD variety
and they were taken
from this fascinated Branch right here
and if you look at these clones they
have
continued to fasciate they have these
long wide stems that are really strong
and dense
you see how thick it really is
when you get those angles
both clones are exhibiting this feature
this one almost already like a half an
inch wide when in reality it should only
be millimeters thick at this point
and I'm really trying to keep these
going and possibly get a whole Bay of
fascinated plants if possible
I love this mutation and I can't wait to
see what it does once it fully flowers