okay here we're ELCA feedback loops and
how they relate to the body so while
this initial example here looks at kind
of like an engineering standpoint I kind
of like the suggestion of the infinity
sign because riccati is constant going
back and forth trying to maintain
homeostasis and that's exactly what's
kind of going on here with feedback
loops there's a way to kind of raise
something it can be away also to low or
something we're gonna look at two
specific types of feedback loops here so
showing with the first one we call a
negative feedback loop this has a
response that is reverse of the change
that's detected so an example be
thermoregulation in blood sugar
regulation look here at low body
temperature so we have our normal body
temperature the body temperature
decreases well what's gonna cause
through a negative feedback loop it's
advised going to shiver and it's gonna
cause an increase in the body
temperature now that body temperature
increases too much well then we're gonna
have the negative which is basically the
opposite effect we have cooling
mechanisms such as sweating that occurs
that helped us reduce our body
temperature so looking at negative
feedback if something's decreasing then
we're gonna cause the loops gonna cause
an increase to occur and just vice-versa
an increase occurs we're gonna have a
decrease house looks a little bit more
complicated sense is their release of
adrenal cords which is to a by the
release of hormones from the
hypothalamus the pituitary gland
this is signals inhibited when the
political quarter ends levels become
elevated by causing negative signals on
the 2-tier and in hypothalamus so we
have our homeostasis we have our nice
happy body conditions we have an
imbalance that occurs here so within the
body there's the hypothalamus perceives
low blood concentrations so that's
causing an imbalance what that's gonna
relate to is a hormone to be released
this hormone release is going to cause a
cascading effect to help increase these
blood levels these blood is going to be
released in the various glands which
will hopefully cause a correction to
occur and that correction be evident by
the levels increasing in the blood these
increased levels so when the hep
elmo's perceives normal concentrations
it will stop releasing them so here
initially we had to release the negative
feedback system is now causing the
stopping or release of that resulting in
homeostasis to occur so if you've in
mind negative feedback is when if
something is going to stimulate
something then it also be way to kind of
suppress or reduce that from occurring
now the opposite of negative feedback as
you might have guessed would be a
positive feedback loop in this involves
the response that reinforces our
amplifies the change detected childbirth
is one example in blood clotting
we're only specifically here these two
examples show child-birthing so here's
the nerve impulse from the service of
treatment to the brain of the Biebs head
pushing against the cervix the brain
will then stimulate the pituitary gland
to release a hormone that hormones
carried into the blood stream to the
uterus and the students the contraction
of the uterus tour these cervix that
will then cause the baby's head to hit
against the cervix again causing this
kind of go around and around see that
same thing here were positive he I
keeping mine we're amplifying the signal
so stretch receptors are activated in
the uterus as the baby's growth takes up
larger space in the uterus this will
then signal the brain to release a
hormone oxytocin this then will cause
the uterine muscles to contract
contractions will get stronger until the
baby is delivered we have this positive
feedback which is kind of building our
amplification of this signal okay so
hopefully that gives you a little bit of
a background between negative feedback
loops and positive feedback loops