watering your plants is often a
necessity
as well as adding fertilizer so
fertilizer applicators are going to be
gone over
in this tobacco university video to
improve your efficiency with cannabis
production
[Music]
all right let's go over fertilizer
applicators for efficient cannabis
production
so what are some of the options well
there's many options these are going to
be a few that will be covered
going to provide you with the pros and
cons of each as well as when you select
one
hopefully search this channel and you'll
be able to find a more detailed video on
that particular type
all of these though are intended to be
able to deliver nutrients to plants via
irrigation water
this is an efficient method since plants
will need to be irrigated anyway
irrigation with fertilizer can help
prevent deficiencies
we see venturis injectors piston pumps
pressurized tanks as well as a diluted
irrigation tank as all viable options
so first off looking at the venturi
injector well the advantages is low cost
it is water powered simple to use
calibrates while it's operating and
there's basically
no moving parts those are great
advantages to the venturing injector
however some of the disadvantages are
that pressure drop is created in the
system
so if you already have a low pressure
system this may not be the best option
and the calibration depends on the
chemical level in the tank and can
fluctuate
as your tank level changes then it gets
to piston pumps now piston pumps are
very precise they have linear
calibration
they can tolerate very high pressures
and the calibration is
independent of the pressure that they're
being exposed to so they offer a great
level of consistency these are probably
the most popular used in larger scale as
well as smaller scale operations
the disadvantages is that they do tend
to cost more compared to everything else
mentioned here
they may need to stop to adjust for
calibration
and the internal parts do wear out over
time and may need replacing
however when they are operational their
high precision
and ability to really dial in a nutrient
feeding program is why they are so
popular
then we get into pressurized tank mixing
and this is kind of the
middle cost range they're fairly easy to
operate the total chemical volume is
accurately controlled so those are all
great benefits
however the disadvantage is the pressure
differential is required and there's
variable chemical concentration provided
to the plants
they also cannot be calibrated for
consistent injection rate
so you're kind of having a little bit of
variability there
which might cause sometimes plants to
get over fertilized and some plants to
potentially become
under fertilized and then the last one
the most simple is looking at a
diluted irrigation tank so we're looking
at a diluted irrigation tank there's
really no need for equipment beyond
a water pump in a tank so that's why
this is
can be used provides growers to know
when fertilizer is added and what
concentration because if you're
adding x amount of fertilizer to the
tank and you're earring with that tank
water
then you know exactly what the plants
are getting it does
require a large tank equal the size of
the irrigation volume and sometimes as
we see in the picture here
multiple irrigation tanks it also does
not allow for concentrated mixes to be
used
you have to go through dilute and make
sure it's evenly distributed there
before you go on and irrigate so these
are some options here we're looking at
fertilizer
and adding it to the plants if you find
one that you really like
search this channel and hopefully you'll
find a more detailed video
to get you dialed in even further