okay I'm gonna go over some fertilizer
requirements for squash now whether
you're organic or buying commercial
fertilizer that's important always to
get a soil test for your fields and use
that as a gauge for initial amendments
however there's two fertilizer classes
you should have on hand if you are
growing squash the first one would be
early in the season that's up until
flowering and be a nitrogen source it
could be a calcium nitrate so a great
initial source especially the soils are
cool urea which needs to be incorporated
into the soil because if it's not it
will volunteer into the atmosphere or
blood meal for organic restrictions I
can also be used but I have a hard time
justifying Lee about a dollar fifty per
pound they're charging for blood meal
when these other nitrogen sources will
work just fine also
other than nitrogen you should get a
potassium for fruit fill not be post
flowering sulfate potassium zero zero
fifty is a low salt potassium fertilizer
there's also potassium nitrate if
they're still need for some residual
nitrogen that's a good source but rarely
do you need to be adding both nitrogen
and potassium especially late in the
season so again you take a soil test to
get the exact amounts that you may need
these are two good classifications of
fertilizer to have on hand if you're
growing squash