all right in this debaco university
video i'm gonna go over fertilizers to
use with coco coir for indoor cannabis
plant production
if you're choosing to grow in cocoa
choir you should be aware of certain
fertilizers to use
and in this video i'm gonna cover just
that
[Music]
so let's get into some of the specific
fertilizers to use if you're deciding to
grow your cannabis
in coco coir so first off cocoa has some
special
requirements and that's why you'll see
as we saw on the beginning slide
some companies specifically make
nutrient lines for those growing purely
in cocoa
when growing in cocoa choir there are
some special methods of fertilizing that
growers should be
keeping in mind while some companies
manufacture coco
car specific fertilizers growers need to
keep in mind a few key
items that you don't necessarily need to
go out and buy
that specific fertilizer others can work
but you need to be aware of
some unique requirements if you're
choosing to grow in coco acquire
so first off with coco coir in typically
growers
will be doing frequent feedings so
having a system that allows for easy
and consistent delivery of nutrients is
highly recommended
because cocoa core has some great
properties from a morphology or plant
structure standpoint
if you need to be irrigating quite a bit
usually daily it's usually good to mix
in some fertilizer with those frequent
irrigation events as well you don't want
to neglect the basic
macro nutrients you don't want to get
caught up in all the little details
you need to be aware that plants still
need to be fed the macronutrients the
nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium the npk
mentioned here
these could not be forgotten about to
avoid common nutrient deficiencies
so many times people who grow in coco
coir get caught up in the
purely the micronutrients or some of the
secondary nutrients
do not forget about the macronutrients
as well
and they'll be listed in any fertilizer
container or label
when growing cocoa choir put the
question here got calmag
if you're growing cocoa coir you need to
make sure you also have sufficient
calmag fertilizer on hand
many companies offer a calm bag product
but based on
personally collected tissue test results
the botanic cares
calmag plus gets my recommendation
though there are many
other options out there but i have used
the calmac i do have tissue tests that
confirm it will increase
plant levels of nutrients so that's the
one i choose to use
specifically and not sponsored by them
by any means
iron is also needed with coca-cola some
growth suggests that iron deficiency can
also occur with greater frequency with a
coca-cola substrate
while this may be possible calcium
magnesium deficiencies are usually more
common
also botanicare's calmac plus also has
iron in it so that's another
plus to be using that product in the
sense that it should cure any potential
deficiencies you would get by growing in
coco coir
well with any fertilizer so this is true
if you're growing coco coir
or anything when mixing any fertilizers
they should be initially mixed in a
clear jar
to see if any unexpected reactions are
what's called precipitation occurs
calcium-based fertilizers seem to be
more likely to react so if you are going
to be mixing other fertilizers please
follow the manufacturer's
suggestions and also perform a test
before you make an application to your
plants
to avoid any potential negative impacts
that could cause phytotoxicity or leaf
burn or anything like that
i want to do a little jar mix mix it up
ahead of time let it sit
make sure it stays mixed make sure you
don't get any participate that falls out
you can always check the ph
always good to see if it coagulates over
time with any fertilizer you're going to
be mixing
perform a jar test to make sure that if
you find any negative interaction make
sure they occur in the jar
and not on your plants