okay when girls are looking at applying
fertilizers they typically want to do it
an efficient way a lot of times this can
lead to growers wanting to mix
fertilizers it's important to keep in
mind fertilizers do interact with one
another they can be a positive
interaction as we see with these gears
or it can be a negative interaction if
we want everything working together
so this interactions mixing different
providers a lot of births - it is it and
save time and it's a great advantage
however there's also the possibility of
some unwanted interactions it's
beneficial to only tank mix certain
nutrients to reduce the chance of
negative interactions so our example
here for looking to produce color we mix
all three together we're going to get in
some case white or we're not producing a
one of the three colors here so you keep
in mind those interactions can be
beneficial but they can also be negative
so keep the amount of fertilizers you're
mixing together minimal because you'll
reduce the chance of having unwanted
results now certain flowers cannot be
take pics but spacing out applications
in spoon-feeding plants is more
advantageous to the grow psycho anyway
however you a lot of times if you read
labels they'll say perform a jar test if
there are questions well what a jar test
is is where you mix the chemicals ahead
of time in a clear jar and visually
inspect them to see if there's a
separation or other forms of interaction
if you mix everything together and let
it settle for a little bit it comes up
nice and consistent this would be a very
positive result however if you mix
everything and get this separation these
are in evidence a visual sign that these
fertilizers may have a negative
interaction and you don't want to apply
these to your plant also if you mix them
together you wanna let them settle and
see if any precipitate forms it's a
solid as a result mixing two liquids
that would be another negative when
you're performing the jar test you don't
want to simply splash everything in the
jar take a quick look and move on I'm
gonna give it some time to have an
interaction to see if a precipitate will
form sometimes it's gonna take several
minutes or I usually let them sit for
about half an hour go back and inspect
them and if it all looks nice and
consistent then you have a very good
odds of having low odds of negative
interactions even as you're going
through and applying the various
products well that gives you some idea
of what to look for and what to
consider when mixing fertilizers to have
positive interactions in benefits of
saving time