okay if you're gonna take a brief look
at some fertilizer labels keep in mind
that while sometimes they are labeled
fertilizer just here no lights there's
no other information you can see the NPK
nitrogen phosphorus potassium listed
here this is zero zero fifteen getting
50 percent is potassium flip some bags
over this is humic acid along give you
some other information such as chemical
composition analysis and suggested
applications now specifically at
fertilizer labels they don't really lie
to you but they often don't tell the
entire story so it's important to know
what they're actually telling you it's
important to keep in mind that
fertilizers are regular at the state
level and various state lemon laws are
similar but sometimes not identical
so again just if you're looking at
comparing different fertilizers
comparing across state lines that can
sometimes present an issue but not often
the case those stated values though
fertilizer labels state the guaranteed
minimum which means there could be more
in there than what stated on the label I
think it's important note to remember
it's a guaranteed minimum it's the
minimum amount that's in there so if
they say 5 percent nitrogen it's
guaranteed them saying basically there's
at least 5% now companies do not want to
under quote by a large margin as far as
what they're selling so if it says 5
percent nitrogen you know they're not
going to have potentially fifteen
percent nitrogen this iguana usually
state that but it's a guaranteed minimum
and I think that's important you know to
make to make as far as when you're
looking at comparing fertilizers those
nutrient forms also that are listed
nutrients are listed as a molecule or
not a single element so we see here with
ferrous sulfate heptahydrate feso4 and
seven water molecules there's 20% iron
in here information Fe but again it's
ferrous that's iron sulfate is the main
molecule that's presented here now this
is because roots absorb most of the
nutrients as inorganic ions or molecules
and not single elements these roots
always say oh they're up taking nitrogen
for example it's not just pure nitrogen
in this case with our iron example
they're not up taking just pure iron
pure Fe
they're taking in maybe in this case
have ferrous sulfate so that's why
they're stated in molecules and
only pure elemental form