okay it's going to be a quick overview
of fertilizer requirements for tomatoes
now keep in mind it could be organic
fertilizer like manure or it could be
bagged commercial fertilizer that you
are using key part is to start with a
soil test and to amend your soil so at
least you have your general conditions
near that optimum level along with a pH
around six oh two six eight now for
field production looking at early season
usually adding nitrogen is typically
required especially if you see your
plants kind of going a little limey
green and it can be supplied through
calcium nitrate urea or blood male keep
in mind that urea is almost four times
as strong as blood meal so if you're
going from blood meal to you really are
not going to be using the same volume
keep in mind that these percentages of
nitrogen are that first number midseason
we're typically going to switch over to
usually a calcium based fertilizer this
is one from botanic here that's a
quality calcium source I tissue test to
prove that its ability to increase
calcium levels in plants if you're under
organic certification there's biomen
calcium which is Omri certified late in
the season looking at sulphate of
potassium zero zero fifty which was a
low salt is typically preferred over
potassium chloride which is zero zero 62
so a higher percentage of potassium but
also higher salts potassium nitrate has
typically not advised because at times
of the year you usually don't wanna be
adding nitrogen though if your plants
are deficient in that it is worth
considering that as a nitrogen and also
potassium source under plastic under
italic conditions same thing early
season nitrogen same as previous slide
midseason calcium but usually the later
in the season we want to do a potassium
and calcium kind of rotation may depend
on the exact conditions but in years of
hot weather where irrigation is
frequency is very high it can lead to
flushing of nutrients from the soil in
these operations as a result you may
want to have more of a rotation since
unlike field situations you may push
some of your early season nutrients out
of the root zone so there are just some
general ideas to keep in mind for
fertilizer requirements and it kind of
kept it very basic very simple
you no need to go overboard despite what
fertilizer companies may tell you