welcome back to another video here on
debaco
university today we're going to be
looking at fiber
analysis and as we see in the rope
picture here
this is a large piece of fiber but
there's also some smaller fibers in here
so we're going to look how you would
analyze those and how would we
look at those in more detail so
first off when we're looking at fibers
there's two main categories there's
natural fibers
which are made from animal or
plant-based fibers and you might be
familiar with like cotton silk and wool
we see the cotton plant located right
here then we have synthetic fibers which
are man-made or artificial
they're produced entirely from chemicals
typically in extrusion
process examples of these are polyester
rayon
or acrylic polyester is the single most
used textile
overtaking cotton so we've actually
started using more
synthetic fibers than natural fibers now
we're looking at fibers want to be
taking into consideration the coloration
of those fibers
so here's an example of kind of viewing
them on a large scale and then we're
also under a microscope
and this is an acetate fiber we see that
kind of blue color
if it didn't have any dye in it it can
be like a gray kind of
color to it if the dye wasn't present so
this definitely shows that with a light
microscope
you can also determine individual fiber
color
then we get into fiber diameter so we're
looking at these particularly the
diameter of the fiber
just like a circle the diameter is kind
of through the center
and from one end to the other it's a
straight line that passes through the
center
and ends at the endpoints of that circle
so
same as diameter in a math class since
here can be variable because only
provide a general
range keep in mind as a person ages
their hair
typically becomes thicker and stronger
and the thicker hair is found closer to
the root section of the hair
and kind of like thins out or almost
tapers as it gets to the end
within some degree and the diameter of
human hair
is typically a range of about 17 to 181
millionths of a meter or typically we
start looking at
microns and here's an average here here
of 70
microns in diameter lastly we have
a fabric pill which is the pilling is a
term used for loose strands
or balls of fiber that form on a piece
of fabric typically if you have older
fabric you kind of get this
pilling that develops and pills form due
to rubbing and abrasion during normal
wear and use and this can indicate if
you find a piece of
fabric that does have a lot of this
pilling indication that it might be
worn or has a lot of abrasion over a
period of time