if you're thinking about turning a field
into a tomato field I'm gonna go over
some of the basic field preparations you
should be considering for that
particular field to make it an effective
crop for you so starting with the
grapple of tomatoes they're native to
South America so they prefer warm
weather and a long growing season this
is why they're not direct seeded in New
England and they need to be started
early and translated into the field you
can also go into season extenders
extenders because these can be helpful
to allow the crop to reach its full
potential so growing site evaluation
well we were looking at a field your
drain looking for a site that has full
Sun is well-drained and does not have a
lot of rocks now put an asterisk here
for them not a lot of rocks because the
plants actually don't mine the rocks but
the person cutting the stakes for
support for those tomatoes will or
especially if you're using row covers a
less rocky field would be advantageous
now preparing that field for tomatoes we
want a well-drained field so they're not
sitting in a lot of water pH around six
oh two six eight slightly acidic in
general nutrient profiles we're looking
for them to be optimum soil nutrients
with special attention for potassium and
maybe calcium now looking at the two
images of the soil here I can't tell you
which one is better just looking at them
a lot of people would say well this one
looks darker so is probably a better
soil this is not necessarily a bad soil
this is why it's important to take a
soil test to be able to determine what
nutrients are in the soil and what level
they're at we're shooting for optimum
and not excessive
now field preparation for our Tomatoes
there are heavy feeders so starting with
good levels is advised while considering
in seasons supplementation at times and
typically they're grown in rows for
efficient placement of irrigation and
plant supports so while this is a
greenhouses situation here it should be
very similar to a field where they're
nice and neat and organized blind for
efficient treatment of the tomatoes
management of them and able to spot
anything that potentially could go wrong