okay here I'm gonna cover the basics for
field preparation first wash planting
now you could do the traditional disking
method here until in of the entire field
or some people are going to it's called
a no-till operation they're spraying an
herbicide down the center path here what
we'll be planting the individual squash
seeds now allowing a green kind of cover
crop to exist in between the rows so two
different ways to approach preparation
from field to squash now in general
squash are native to the Americas
considered the new world and it's part
like perform well in the New England
climate so we tend to perform them quite
well and get good harvest with not
necessarily a ton of its special inputs
so when we're looking for a grow site to
evaluate we want a good field conditions
we define as those that have full Sun
well-drained in a near neutral pH now
because I tend to do well in this area
and they tend that to have the greatest
return on investment in comparison to
say like a tomato these crops are
commonly planted in what's called the
next-best plot we've been at the best
most ideal field but the next best field
now when we're preparing our fields for
squash they don't have to be first on
the list they can be later on the list
because squash perform warm field soil
preparations are coming to later in on
the list or later in the season in
comparison to other fields Dennis Lee is
Memorial Day sometimes eaten slightly
later getting into June at least early
June because they like that warm soil so
when planted they kind of jump up and
get going so they may not be the first
prey prepared they should be in your
rotation and wait until that soil gets
warm if you plant them too early they
will not perform well