okay I'm gonna go over field
preparations kind of like this is saying
here without a plan you can never be
lost so I know there's a lot of
variability depending on the size of
your field or equipment that you might
have so I'm going to be kind of in
general terms here so once you start
deciding to get your field together well
I always say you're already behind
there's something you can be doing each
season if you haven't started yet
following typically we're moving on the
crops the planting cover crops taking
soil tests the winter you can actually
lime in the winter frost heating can
help incorporate and compile records
inside where it's nice and warm and
develop a plan for next season in the
spring it's a crazy time I want to kill
the cover crop you want to plant the
main crop you want weed control your
irrigation set up a lots going on in the
spring some are also very busy
monitoring for disease be trying to be
proactive checking in systems harvesting
crops ideally there's always something
going on in the fields even that we have
those four distinctive seasons even if
you're not necessarily thing for winter
markets there's always something to do
on the farm so the field you should know
when to stay away and this is
particularly important in the springtime
if it's wet stay away you don't want to
get the tractor stuck you know on
destroy the soil a lot of bad things can
happen here you're damaging the soil in
ways that you may not be able to get the
texture back to the way it was before so
when in doubt stay away trying to find a
drier field try to do something else and
no he gets antsy in the springtime but
try to avoid this particular situation
here some basics timing the cover crop
kill what the main crop is important
here you can see your main crop in a
cover crop killed that timing as you'll
see again is also important to get
everything the maximum efficiency on le
the cover crop to help protect the soil
but also for a preparing the field to
get your main crop in there's you can
get ideally a yield and make some money
from that crop that you did plant it all
comes back to having the plan that's
where the winter is so important plan is
just an idea
to progress you forward so that mean you
have to follow the exact same order of
the plan but having that plan gives a
lot of growers come
and this helps you out in the long range
of things gives you just that checkpoint
where am I in my head my behind
odds are you're probably always gonna
think you're behind but are you getting
stuff done and I'm going through and
trying to avoid some of the errors that
you may have had in the past that your
plan kind of outlined be flexible with
the conditions some Springs start very
early some start late some are rainy
some are dry but have a way to try and
avoid forgetting something
so there's certain key things that you
definitely need to do try to have those
in the forefront on a white board
something it's a walk by each day things
can always change but if you forgot
something last year you forgot to hook
up irrigation lines or prep something
make sure you don't make that mistake
twice
consumer comes to be important to be
able to prioritize things hard to have a
plan to do this but ask yourself is this
the best use of my time or just
convenient at the moment have a little
dead space and just kind of want to go
and do this but this is the best use of
my time this kind of set me up for later
in the season if I do it now we'll have
to do it later anyway you know if I'm
gonna go through and the weeds are just
kind of starting in the field and go
through and I want to tell them well I
might have to go back next week and till
the MINIX I'm not gonna plant until two
weeks so prioritize don't do things
twice trying to do it once do it well
and move on and does it does this need
to get done now will there be seedlings
ready to be planted in an unprepped row
for the next week are you prepping a row
that you're have to reap rep because you
know your seedlings your transplants may
not be ready since that prioritizing
this is where it comes a little
experience knowing what you have known
what's coming up trying to plant it into
the weather you're just trying to use
your time as efficiently as possible and
timing is everything if it's possible
working teams focus on one task at a
time
get it done personally I feel kind of
the best way to approach something is if
you're tilling and laying plastic for
example something very common a lot of
farms do do teal till the one two three
and four fields today and then tomorrow
you just like plastic and fields one two
three and four already you till field
one and then my plastic and field one
until field two in the plastic and field
two
now this depends on a lot of things but
typically it's an ideal time to tell oh
you go through distill them all just hit
them all once and then come back
tomorrow switches the tractor over and
puts a plastic layer and go through and
do all the fields
now there's separated by a great
distance it might be more advantageous
to till one than lay plastic on one
ideally you'd have two different
tractors for this purpose and want to
keep switching equipment and again this
is where that timing comes into being
everything teams are a great thing if
you can kind of coordinate and work on
and all dedicate yourselves to a task
but you kind of want to stay focused on
one thing here by tilling all the fields
in the same day you're just focused on
one thing
and then put the tiller away and clean
the tiller up you can rinse it down and
grease the fittings would be good then
go back grab your plastic layer grab
that tractor and make sure you have
enough plastic set up all the all the
rolls and just go through each lay
plastic on your perfectly tilled fields
from the day before so again be flexible
keep in mind timings everything I know
you always think that you're behind keep
working at it have a plan and hopefully
things go smoother here to here