go here I'm gonna go over different
types of filtering methods even though
the basic idea might be the same
there's different methods to approach
and that will depend on the protocol or
the materials you're looking at
filtering but here we have a feed here
we have a barrier and then we have the
filtrate so we're seeing that these
larger molecules are being stopped these
falah ones are allowed to pass through
looking at filtration in general
separation technique used to isolate
solids from liquids or gases using a
selective medium might be most Ameritech
with coffee and filter paper associated
with isolating coffee grounds filtration
terms the suspension is the initial
mixture or solution and the fluid that
passes through the filter is called the
filtrate and that's what's kind of
getting through the pores here and
that's ultimately what you're collecting
and they container down below here
common forms of filtration will include
brewing coffee your kidneys form a
filtration process very important vacuum
cleaners are filtering out and aquarium
filters are all again examples of areas
that you might be familiar with
filtration the filtration methods
there's different methods exist to best
match the given as the situation example
is the solid suspended or dissolved in
the fluid that may influence what type
of method you choose to use in which
would be the best to allow the greatest
extraction at separation in general
frustration uses gravity to filter the
mixture solids remain in the filter
while liquid will pass through and might
be further doing some sort of labs like
this we're putting the bunch of you know
liquid and solid suspension and then
you're lying overtime to gravity pull it
through and collecting that liquid below
but there's other forms
so there's vacuum filtration now
Buechner flask and a hose are used to
create a vacuum here to pull the fluid
through the filter typically with the
aid of gravity so this is and said if we
were waiting forever for gravity kind of
pull this through with this set up with
this being sealed here and pulling kind
of a vacuum to some extent you're then
hoping this process along and you saw
gravity you're still working with
gravity but you're kind of speeding that
up and this is great
for substances that may take a very long
time to filter if you are just used
gravity then we go into hot or cold
filtration so different temperatures
will be utilized if you want to
encourage that would be cold filtration
or minimize and be consultation crystal
formation so if you're looking at you
know heating something up here that's
going to minimize the formation of
crystals if you're going to be using a
cold way here's an ice bath that's going
to encourage the formation of crystals
through the filtration process then we
get out of different types of filter
paper this is where qualitative filter
paper is used in applications that are
routine separation to occur or determine
identifying of those materials and
there's quantitative used where the
precipitate is to be covered typically
with vacuum filtration and to identify
specific materials
how are the quantitative filter paper is
more precise is more expensive so if you
don't need that high level of detail
typically you'll be using a qualitative
filter paper there and they're labeled
right on the box qualitative or
quantitative again quantitative used for
specific purposes qualitative a little
more broad-based and less expensive