here on this tobacco university video
we're going to go over the femme pruning
technique for cannabis
[Music]
all right let's go over the fin
technique which stands for f
i missed printing method for cannabis
production here
so the goal of this technique is to
create multiple tops we can kind of see
that pictured here quite well
this multiple tops is great if you're
looking at cloning for example
it's typically done when you're cutting
or topping a plant but not really making
a clean cut
because true topping would eliminate
this kind of center portion here
and only allow for kind of like two main
branch points to kind of come out
uh here we're looking at multiple
branching points
as if the grower feels like they look
back and china did topping but kind of
like
missed that clean cut is kind of kind of
what the name implies
you can also see here multiple kind of
points growing out and this is why it
can be good for cloning
however this is technique is not
recommended for autoflowers
so again we're seeing some other
examples here the reason why it's not
recommended for autoflowers
is because it will delay plant growth
this result in lost plant matter
production days which will mean for
autoflowers it will likely not reach
its full potential so this technique is
used on autoflowers the advantages will
likely be mitigated
by the required increase of plant
numbers required to make up the
difference
so again you could do with autoflowers
but not recommended simply because of
the delay in time that's going to occur
now that top section that kind of
portion here
this is what it looks like just to kind
of give you an idea of what you're kind
of
removing when selecting a top to prune
growers should be looking for a tip that
has four
full nodes and it's developing a fifth
look specifically at the small early
kind of branch points in the leaf
clusters it's kind of looking right down
here
typically five to six nodes up on the
plant will allow for maximum efficiency
when utilizing this technique the plant
stem tip
remaining will grow back slowly into
multiple new branch points
oftentimes there can be some
discoloration do the physical damage of
the area
but again something you really should
not be that concerned with
the timing of this so when we're looking
at you know when we go through and
implement this technique there may be no
exact time
but the general rule is start two to
three nodes up the plant you don't want
to do it much earlier
than that this can result in a box like
plant of about two and a half feet wide
and tall just to give you a general idea
and it might depend on your
strain your variety you might be growing
and also the conditions how quick you're
flipping them over into flowering
but this kind of gives you an idea of
kind of what you're looking for
uh when topping and kind of this filming
technique because it is a
modified version of toppin
now what if we bend and then thin some
growers actually take the plants bend
them because we can see here at 90
degrees
and then thin their plants to maximize
the plant space
while minimizing the overall plant
height this technique can
also produce many growing points that
can allow for efficient production of
plate material
particularly for cloning purposes
because we're taking the bending portion
growing this portion out
and then filming other portions here
again to get more branch points thin
is part of a complete pruning method so
film can be used in conjunction with
other printing methods so i think just
because you're filming
that's it that's all you can do you can
utilize it or
correlate it with other techniques often
used with the screen of green because
you're trying to get those multiple
branch points going
mother plants for cloning and also again
as i said a modified version of topping
and this kind of shows a good example of
taking the same plant here if you were
going to thin the plant you'd cut it
right here
a level if you were topping the plant
though you'd cut it lower here
closer to where those that actual
branching
leaf petiole nodes kind of come into
intersection there
so again thinning we're going to cut it
up here topping we'd cut it lower than
that
last thing we're looking at the plant
hormone shifts associated with the thin
technique
the cut results in many new growing tips
and this kind of looks like a zoomed in
version here
again if we were topping we'd be cutting
right here but feminine were up here and
that's allowing these multiple little
branch points to kind of grow out
which is great for having these new
meristems new areas that could be used
particularly for cloning
or if you're looking at that screen of
green method where you kind of need a
lot of these little branch points to
kind of go through and work your way
through the screen
this is another way that it could be
implemented hopefully this gave you some
good information about the fin technique
for cannabis cloning