welcome to this debaco university
student series video we're going to look
at final plant preparations for the easy
cloner to encourage success
now there are a couple key things you
need to do this video will walk you
through those steps but hopefully you've
got everything taken care of as far as
mechanics go harvested your plants and
now this will help you increase the odds
of rooting success for your plants
[Music]
so now we're going to take the clones
that we just cut from the field
pick one out from the water
and we got to prepare it to go into the
cloner so as you can see this one's a
little tall for our operation we don't
want the top getting burnt so we're
going to cut it down to a better size to
fit our
cloner
so i'm going to choose to cut it from
the next node up which is right about
here
just discard the bottom
next i'm going to get the foam collar
ready to go about
an inch up the branch from the bottom of
the branch
be sure to be careful when putting it in
we don't want to break the branch
then you're going to take your claw next
rooting solution
and dip the bottom in
this will allow for the roots to callus
quicker
now it can be moved into its new home
and start growing again
for this plant specifically we kind of
have a lot going on down at the bottom
so i'm going to choose to take
one of these branches off
now based on the damage that this one
has it has some
looks like bug damage looks like a bug
went in and ate that a little bit
i'm just gonna take that leaf off
so as if you're taking a clone just try
to get as close to the branch as
possible
and snip
now that we have a little bit more area
to work with
we could take
the foam collar
and try to give it as much space on the
bottom
as possible so i'm going to go all the
way up here
next i'm going to take our clonex
rooting solution
and dip the bottom in
this allows for the rooting on the
bottom to begin callousing quicker than
it would without it
so now i'm going to place
the clone
into its new house
now you may be wondering how this is
efficient considering that it's bending
over this way
but luckily
after it's spent some time in the cloner
due to tropism it's going to start
looking back up towards the light so
it's
leaning is not something that we have to
worry about
so as you can see we've reached the
final step of setting up our cloner
we've put every single one of our clones
that we've found outside into the cloner
adjusted them accordingly by cutting
them a little bit adding clonex to the
ends
now you can see that they're looking a
little sad a little droopy but it's not
to worry it's just because they were
just moved from an outside environment
to a sterile inside environment it's
kind of a big change for them especially
since they're no longer on the mother
plant they're pretty much left to fend
for themselves so
if you see over the next night morning
even the next day that they're seeing
seeming a little droopy that's
completely normal just give them a
little bit of time make sure the
nutrients and conductivity are where
they're supposed to be and you should be
all set
you