don't you hate me get a fingerprint on
the screen well hopefully this video
will make you appreciate or at least
take a little bit look harder at what's
on the screen before you go through and
you'll wipe it off so this is gonna
focus on fingerprints but same applies a
palm prints and foot prints the dermal
papilla I lie atop the dermal ridges and
that's what we're looking at when we
look at a natural fingerprint they're
elevated overlying the epidermis into
dermal ridges
they are swept films because of sweat
pores and they're actually genetically
determined so we're going to be looking
at a couple of the key different types
there's three main classifications
arches loops and whorls we'll be able to
identify these in greater detail just
for those thinking about getting a
tattoo so if we're talking about skin
the dermis is the receptive site for the
pigment of tattoos so a little bit lower
or deeper down or focusing a little bit
more on how this dermal layer impacts
the shape or the ridges that occur on
the surface so starting with
fingerprints awesome the basics no two
people have been found with the exact
same fingerprint pattern the fingerprint
pattern will remain unchanged for the
life of the individual however the print
itself may change due to permanent scars
or skin diseases or damaged conceal a
little bit of a pie graph 55% typically
have loops 23 whirls 12% arches and 10%
composites we're going to investigate
each one of these in a little bit more
detail just to go back if you're
interested in learning more about
fingerprints I included a couple of
resources down here and some slideshows
to take a look at so continuing on the
three major fingerprint classes are
arches loops and whorls each group is
divided into smaller groups as seen in
the list below
so within arches we have what's called a
plain arch a tented arch loops we have
something called a radial and all our
loop and whirls we have different types
I want to show you some examples of
these and so you can be identified what
your own fingerprints are so starting
with the most basic one of the arches
this is the Saint Louis Gateway Arch
good thing of that arches are the
simplest type of inner plants and
they're formed by ridges I'm either side
of the print and exit the other see here
a plain arch just kind of a little bit
rise here ridges enter one side and
at the other side tinted archers similar
to plate arch but has a spike in the
center a little bit more pronounced here
so both of these are arches is because
inter plane arches these would be tented
arches loops is where it gets a little
more confusing loops must have one Delta
and one or more it is at and dirt will
leave the same side these patterns are
named for the position relate to the
radius in the ulnar bones the bone the
loop is opening is facing towards so the
bone the loop opening is facing towards
is the bone it's the name so let's see
some examples here so we have our left
hand we have our right hand it's
important to remember that wherever your
thumb is this portion here this phone is
the radius on the other side here is the
ulna and same goes for left and right
hand you can see here's the thumb and
here's the radius the thicker bone and
the ulna is the thinner bone here so
when we have a print here a loop made
was it the loops the openings are
pointing this way well this was made
with a left hand and if we're on this
hand and the roots are pointing this way
be pointing towards the radius this
would be a radial loop but if this same
print was made with the left hand okay
to be pointing this way and be pointing
actually to the ulna the ulnar loop
would be the proper term for this and
same thing goes here unless this was
made at the left hand we pointing to the
the ulnar loop it was made with the
right hand it would be pointing to the
radio loop the Delta that's mentioned
are these small regions here from a
little Delta little triangle we can see
that evident right here so with loops
it's very important to realize or
identify if it was made with the left
hand or if it was made with the right
hand
continuing on to worlds so worlds have
have at least one ridge that makes or
tends to make a complete circuit they
also have at least two deltas the print
has more than two deltas it's likely
accidental so we see here we see in our
world plane were only of a center pocket
whirl so what we're doing is we're
drawing a line here between the two
Delta's in the plane and central pocket
whirls if some of the curved route is
touched the line did you see here
considered a plane world if none of them
touch the center line
we would call a central pocket world
again it's just getting into little more
deeper into the classification of worlds
there's both a plane in a central pocket
worlds part two are actually composite
so we have something called a double
loop world here's our Delta here's
another Delta a double loop worlds are
comprised of two loops combined into one
print so it's called a double loop
mentioned the composite if the picture
here of a dog and kind of a bird kind of
a merger of two that's what we see kind
of here with an accidental world
sometimes you contain two or more
patterns and not included including the
plane arch or does not clearly fall
under any of the other categories it's
kind of somewhat considered with the
miscellaneous category accidental world
this composites had a combination of a
few different things so identify each
finger print pattern now you'll notice
with each finger print ABCDE I also
include what hand it was made from
that's very important if we're looking
at identifying if we look back we want
to make sure if we identify something as
a loop we're going to find the left or
the right hand as an owner or a radial
loop based on what direction the
openings are pointed if it's going back
to the very beginning said arch it
doesn't matter left or right hand loops
it does make a difference in worlds it
does not make a difference so it'd be a
chance to just take a look at this you
can pause the video at this point and
see if you can defy these various finger
prints okay hopefully you've paused the
video when I reveal the answers to you
hope you've gone through and being able
to write down some of these and here are
the answers to the various finger prints
here hopefully this is helpful
identifying finger prints here on the
slides that I have and also makes you
look at your fingers at you're very
familiar with working with a little bit
better and develop a better
understanding of your own body