all right here in this video on debacle
university we're looking at
fire investigation go over some of the
basics
and also some of the goals of
investigating what may have happened
when we have a fire that occurred
so first off that invests those
investigation basics well workflow
should start
from minimally damaged areas and
progress to ones with greater
damage those kind of fringe areas and
working closer to where the potential
source may have been
investigators should use typical forms
of forensic
documentation and collect evidence as
they're going through in doing this
in this documentation can include notes
and photographs
the evidence collected typically is
evidence of potential accelerant
samples fire items and other evidence
that may not be directly
fire related but can help in that
investigation process
the goal of this investigation is to try
to determine the point of origin
the heat source or sources and also a
possible
reason so that point of origin well
that's basically where did the fire
originate from burn patterns are used to
help answer this question
in addition to the area of the most
damage is commonly where the fire
started because it simply had the
longest burn time
the point of origin can be used to help
determine the cause of the fire as well
this is why this is one of the goals of
the investigation process
they also have char patterns so char
patterns are created by very hot fires
that burn very quickly that move fast
along a path
this can result in sharp lines between
burned and not burned
material door char patterns can help
determine
what side of the door the fire was on
and floor chart patterns can help
determine if an accilent was used in its
path
we see the example here of a char
pattern from about one liter of gasoline
on the area that that can create
just to give a general idea of what a
char pattern would look like
there's something called v patterns and
as the fire burns up as we see it
actively burning on this image here on
the side of the building
it burns in a vertical v-shaped pattern
so a fire that starts at an
outlet against a wall leaves a char
pattern that points to the or point of
origin
now a narrow v-shaped patterns typically
indicate a very hot fire that could have
an accelerant added to it
a wide v-shaped pattern so just a slow
burning fire
and if there's kind of a u-shape to it
this indicates a
pool of origin not really a point of
origin such as a puddle
of gasoline you kind of get that area
where it's kind of progressing
not that distinctive v-shape
now when we're looking at an area of
post-burning we could
notice the potential for heat shadows
and what a heat shadow
is is it simply occurs when an object
shields another which can help determine
the point of origin
a room a desk could shield a wall here
we see an
evidence of where a person may have been
laying we see evidence of their legs
torso their arm and their head region
and kind of the heat shadow that is left
behind
uh due to the result of the body
physically blocking
some of that fire from progressing to
certain areas
looking at glass if there's glass in a
particular
situation this is great for the fire
investigation process
as we see here a light bulb this can
help indicate the fire's direction as
they tend to melt towards the heat
source
so in this case of the heeple the light
bulb up here where the heat source is
basically came from this region over
here this indicates the bulb was pulled
showing that the heat came from the
right of this image
windows can also be another source as
they can help determine how the fire
burned
there's presence of like a really dark
layer on the glass this could
indicate a slow smoldering fire
and clear glass with an abnormal pattern
of cracking could apply a very hot fire
it could be possibly due to the use or
inclusion
of an accelerant in that process we also
have something called the chimney effect
and if you've got regular fireplace in a
chimney it
operates along those same terms so that
chimney effect is simply when the fire
ignites at a point and
superheated gas is raised upward in a
giant fireball so a typical chimney
you're mostly going to have
the smoke and the gases kind of extend
out the flute of the chimney
here we're having a fireball effect a
fireball will continue to burn straight
up and burn a hole in the ceiling
potentially if it's present in the area
which can help determine again the
origin of the fire which can be directly
underneath
this area so it kind of potentially
allows for a pinpoint of an area
so that chimney effect can occur more
than just so and only just a chimney
but it can help determine again that
important point of origin
keep in mind if you're looking at an
actively burning fire if someone was
able to capture a picture of the fire
the color that you see can help provide
some clues for example the smoke color
this indicates potentially the type of
material
burning if you're looking to make a
signal fire you want to use like
typically your conifers that are fresh
and green they'll produce a lot of smoke
to that fire where most of the time
you're looking if you're burning in a
wood stove you want to let your
wood cure for a period of time for
example your oaks and your maples this
will create a much cleaner
almost no smoke coloration also the
flame color indicates the fire
temperatures we see here with the little
candle flame
the blue zone being about 800 degrees
celsius here
and then we could see upwards at the top
here much hotter
potentially 1200 degrees celsius to 1400
degrees celsius
in this upper portion so again looking
at that kind of coloration
that we see of the flame color can help
provide a general indication of how
hot that fire is burning then we also
have
fire patterns and this image shows an
ignitable liquid pore pattern
so it's a pore pattern if you look at
the image here like a spilled
container of milk it's simply indicating
that
area where the accelerant may be where
the ignitable liquid
may be located we can kind of see this
evidence of our
hard edge we see our unburned areas
so taking this apart you know really
looking at
potentially not just oh is it burned in
an unburned area looking at the
medium burn the heavy burn the hard edge
this can tell an investigator
a lot about what it would occurred as
the fire was going on