okay here i'm going to go over different
types of firearm ammunition and while
these all may look very different
there are some similarities and some
consistencies and i'll go over those
specific terms
so you can be able to talk whatever part
of the ammunition you're talking about
you can be accurate so first off
ammunition
can be abbreviated ammo as the material
fired
scattered dropped or denoted from any
weapon you can see
a bunch of ammunition here as it is here
notice that there are some different
ones
these rounds here with the little red at
the very end those are called trace
arounds i'll go over those in another
video
the purpose of ammunition is to project
a force against a selected target
and have an effect usually not always
lethal so i don't think it's always
lethal
but a lot of times in this case with the
images projected here yes you're looking
at probably being lethal
the most iconic example of ammunition is
the firearm cartridge which includes all
the components required to deliver the
weapon
effectively in a single package so we
have a bullet we have a shell
casing so these are independent terms
and these are
different so a lot of times they get
mixed up the ones located here on the
screen these are all
bullets these are all the shell casings
so if you're going through a crime scene
and you find something like this and
people say they found
found bullets no technically you found
shell casings
the bullets would be located here so
again just be aware of the terms that
you're using
shell casings versus a bullet now the
cartridge here
in this image uh consists of a bullet
which would be number one
then the case which is located right
here and that holds all the parts
together
inside the case would be the propellant
which is for example gunpowder
and then we have the rim which is the
very end portion here and that provides
the extractor
the firearm a place to grip the casing
and remove it once
fired and at the very bottom kind of
center here
underneath here we would have the primer
which ignites the propellant
now the bullet specifically is
typically referred to as the end point
here so we're looking at a
bullet we're really looking at kind of
that end point
the actual bullet portion is limited
only to what we call
the projectile um so a lot of times we
call this the bullet that's inaccurate
this is
only only bullet remember it's that only
limited to that projectile portion
then we have the case so that holds
again all the parts of the cartridge
together
the cartridge without a projectile is
called a blank
now in the different types of cartridges
and kind of
can they're not always all together
there
are served different purposes so for
example
if we have a cartridge here that's
completely inert meaning it contains no
active primer
and also no propellant that's called a
dummy so that would be something
used just to kind of represent the same
size
but it contains no primer no propellant
it's just a dummy
when it's failed to ignite or shoot off
the projectile is called a dud
meaning there's something wrong with all
those components they didn't work
together it's a dud it didn't fire off
then when it ignited but failed to
sufficiently push the projectile out of
the barrel it's called a squib
that could be for a variety of reasons
it could be a lack of propellant could
be
an inaccurate primer uh but these are
some terms
given if you had a crime scene you find
kind of
something that you know failed to ignite
or pull through the barrel if you find
it within the barrel
that could be called a squib just for
example
now the rims you mentioned that lower
portion down
down at the very base that provides the
extractor the firearm a place to grip
the casting and remove it from the
chamber
you can see different rims here with
different calibers but that they all
serve the same
purpose now center fire and rimfire so
these are two different types
we see center fire here and a rimfire
located right here
centrify cartridges as the name implies
is essentially located primer held
within the recess
of the case head often have about 6 65
psi max pressure the rimfire
priming is popular solution because
before
center fire priming was perfected so
they only have a maximum change of
chamber pressure about forty thousand
psi uh they don't have to be quite as
precise
uh they're a little less powerful a
little less punch but to get that center
fire really a lot
uh components had to come together so
before this was perfected the rimfire
rimfires are still used today but really
for the accuracy you can see definitely
that
center fire has that primer located
right in the center
that probably been talking about primer
when hit and the firearms
the hammer the primer will hit that it
will cause it to rapidly burn
that burning gas from the primer will
ignite the propellant so it's kind of
that first stage
and then the propellant goes this is an
explosion of ice propellant casting a
large explosion and that
large explosion will ultimately propel
the bullet down the chamber
and out the barrel that propellant
specifically
these propellant gases push the bullet
base
causing it to move the path of least
resistance which is down the
bore of the barrel modern propellants
are often
smokeless powders composed of
nitrocellulose
some contain nitrous cells some contain
nitroglycerin there's a whole bunch of
different types
but those are these the two major ones
they all fall into the same category of
propelling and that's what's actually
going to cause the force to force the
bullet out the bore
of the barrel they have different
calibers
so caliber is a specific nominal
integral
diameter of the gun barrel so the
diameter of
the barrels would think about caliber we
see a bunch listed or shown
here we have 22.22 caliber
all the way up to the 50 caliber here so
for example when we say
22 caliber the firearm has a barrel
diameter of roughly
0.22 inches if of the board you can see
it's a much
thinner or smaller diameter than the 50
cal
that is can be measured in kind of
inches or they can also be measured in
millimeters
very common one you may hear is nine
millimeter pistol so that's a barrel
as a barrel of nine millimeters and i
have a couple just shown here for
comparison
and last we have the shotgun shell so
shotgun shell
is a self-contained cartridge often
loaded with either
multiple metallic shot uh in this case
they're very small generally spherical
projectiles
or a single large slug and that can just
depend on one kind of
large slug one solid kind of piece of
metal or a bunch of little bbs
the shell consists of paper or plastic
tube mounted in the base and primer
holding that
and the shots typically contain a small
chamber inside the shell
casing and we could see that here
typically shotguns are used for
example bird hunting where you want to
have kind of a little bit of a spread
um to be able to hit the bird with some
of the pellets or it could be a slug if
you're kind of deer hunting
because you're kind of having that
target being very specific
so just some basics of firearm
ammunition