in this tobacco university video we're
investigating fire debris sample
collecting
so if you were to enter an area that a
fire had recently occurred how would you
go about collecting
samples well first off we want to be
looking at well what areas would we want
to sample
and we want to look at the areas that
are likely to contain traces
of ignitable liquid because this can
help provide
some valuable information about what may
have started or continued that fire from
going
areas you want to look for are like low
regions and burn areas depressions
insulated areas within a pattern poor
substances in contact with the pattern
examples of this could be like articles
of clothing paper products or
potentially
wood in that debris sample
also looking at seams or cracks it could
be in floors or next to walls
uh also important areas to be
investigating for potentially
good samples lightly burned edges of the
pattern are good because they're not too
far
charred and they're not untouched they
kind of give you that fringe area and
can tell you a lot
about the fire there now the fire to be
the evidence
you might be looking for collecting
paper in trash itself if you're looking
at the you know the trash can there
typically does not really yield much
evidence we want to be looking for if
there was a use of an accelerant to aid
in a rapid start
was a chemical device used for example
we see the picture above me here the
flares
were they the potential start of the
fire
are there any signs that an electronic
device that could purposely
delay the initiation of a fire used
indicating that someone may have been
able to set the stage and then leave
and then have the fire occur when they
were safely out of the area
also unburned portions of chemical
electronic devices
may be left behind this can help again
provide some more
evidence leading to telling the story of
what happened with this
uh fire when we're collecting
fire debris so this is important that
along with the sample from point of
origin
a control sample should also be
collected this is material from a
different room or location it acts as
that good source of comparison
there's carpet fibers for example
synthetics maybe petroleum based
so again we should take some charred
remains and also
them from another room especially if
they're unburned to act as that
comparison
now transporting our fire debris well we
want to transfer the collected samples
into a tightly sealed container
typically it's a glass jar or a metal
can
kind of want to have that isolated want
to make sure we're labeling it
ideally putting some evidence tape over
that so we're not having anyone tamper
with it
and also indicating with an image and a
number where we collected that sample
from because it could be very important
later
in the investigation process now the
role of
accelerance so keep in mind that these
aid in the
initial ignition and potential spread
pattern of a
fire usually in debris
make finding it a challenge because they
tend to be dirty or
contaminated a lot of times for existing
example with gasoline
operates very quickly but we could
potentially look for if there's evidence
of a poor
pattern for example but these
accelerants can
really help determine that initial
ignition point or potentially influence
the pattern that that fire progresses
now this accelerate sample processing so
when we're looking at you know hopefully
identifying if an accelerant was used if
we do determine that to be the case
when i send that to lab in a clean
vapor-tight container
typically paint cans are used but not
plastic containers
you could also use a glass jar as well
we want them to be vapor tight so we
don't want that excellent to basically
evaporate
in its time from being recovered from
the scene to entering the lab
one of three techniques are typically
used heated headspace gas chromatography
absorption strip and solvent wash could
help determine
what accelerant was collected
now keep in mind and remember that
during a fire or explosion investigation
you don't want to forget about
collecting other forensic evidence such
as
shoe prints in the area dna tool marks
blood fingerprints and a whole host of
others
so just because there's clear evidence
of a fire being present
by all means collect the evidence
related to the potential fire
but also don't forget or don't
cross-contaminate
any other typical evidence that would be
collected
at any forensics crime scene