good here I'm going to go over this
brief overview of the five themes that
unify biology kind of make it a whole
encompassing unit
well first one is evolution June Fink
it's these change in a species over time
terms we're going to work with when we
get into the topic of evolution will be
genetic drift natural our official
selection and founder effects well
there's just a quick overview here is
before selection we have all these
circles are different colors sorry for
colorblind we notice here after
selection the red and the dark red or
the favored for this particular
environment or stress that occurred and
our final population for those that can
see color are composed of red and dark
red and the yellows and tans and oranges
were selected again also here have a
migrating population and we have a
couple generations that occur do planner
effects we see the purple ones here were
the most advantageous so one of the five
themes that unify biology is evolution
the second theme the flow of energy all
or all living organisms require energy
the Sun is the source of energy for most
ecosystems except for some organs that
live way down in the deep ocean vast
majority though otherwise the Sun is the
main source of energy plants capture
energy via photosynthesis and they can
act as an energy source for other
organisms you see here the sun's energy
at the very bottom that's producing for
our primary producers that's their main
source of energy then the primary
consumers and secondary consumers third
level consumers apex predators a lot of
energy is being lost to heat again we
can't create or destroy energy but a lot
is being lost to heat then these are
being broken down by decomposers those
nutrients are being recycled and the
kind of circle goes around notice 100
percent then 10 percents is how much
we're losing to heat this is why there's
so few apex predators and so many
primary producers third theme that
unifies biologies interaction
interaction between organs is critical
for evolution there's social behavior
that occurs when organs of the same
species live in direct contact so you
see here with the meerkats these are
highly social animals
it's community dynamics that occurs when
organs of different species live in
direct contact with one another and this
could be an example here we have the
butterfly in the flower two very
different species put interacting in a
community like way the fourth theme that
unifies biology's structure determines
function should be very important to go
over macromolecules specifically
proteins but biological structures are
well-suited to their function this is
very true at every level organization
the example I get here is the sequence
of amino acids leads to a specific
structure that can lead to a very
specific function the example here would
be enzymes that are have a very
specialized active site that only bind
to one particular substrate so their
structure determines their function
lastly the last thing that unifies
biologies homeostasis all of the organs
act to maintain a relatively stable
internal environment in maintaining
homeostasis requires energy a lot of
singling back and forth between cells
need to have positive feedback and
negative feedback systems here as a way
to lower things or erase things to
maintain these relatively stable
internal conditions so just to quickly
review all five you can see them listed
right here and provide them in
individual size and broke them down with
images that hopefully make it more
memorable so you're able to make
connections with the five themes that
unify biology