on this debaco university video we're
going to look at another student series
video we're going to look at flat or
ribbon vining mutations in cannabis
plants we're going to go out to the
greenhouse bay look at the variability
you can get from using seeds even though
they're from the same variety some of
the mutations that can develop and
connor's going to walk us through just
what we're seeing out in the greenhouse
[Music]
well what we're seeing here is a few of
our mutations that we have on this bay
uh this whole bay was from one cultivar
one seed
it is our baox strain it is a high cbd
variety
here in front of me you can see a
healthy
normal looking plant very uniform
christmas tree like shape
you know no branches out of the ordinary
nice skinny strong
center branch
stock
um then you take a look to my right and
you can see
a stock almost three to four times the
thickness of our normal healthy plant
and
it's very tall compared to our
healthy plant
um another
distinctive characteristic is this big
split in the middle and i did not top
this in any form
with scissors or anything it was all on
its own
we think it's a mutation of some sort of
the main stem almost like a conjoined
twin
and if you look over here on the left
you see this monstrosity
very bushy tops
a stem that is almost three to four
times as wide as a normal
healthy stem
you see these big tufts of new growth on
the main
stem
and what you can see is that
this left
leftmost stem has actually started to
curl and grow upside down at a 180
degree angle
the new growth is pointing downwards
and growing downwards as well
and another notable characteristic is
how
skinny
the stalk is on its side
on one angle it's very wide and at the
other it almost looks normal
and yeah that's some of our fun
interesting cool mutations that we're
seeing in our greenhouse currently