in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over some more
of the specifics when you're looking at
flipping your plants or transitioning
them
from the vegetative to the flowering
cycles
[Music]
all right let's go over flipping indoor
cannabis plants from the vegetative to
flowering cycles
so first off the change when we're
looking at making that change
uh growers growing photoperiod dependent
or even autoflower plants need to
realize their plants need to go through
a shift
from reducing leaves to flowers now in
autoflowers of course that will happen
naturally
photoperiod dependent you have the
opportunity to decide when that change
occurs
so because with photoperiod dependent
strains growers have more control over
when this actually happens
there needs to be a consideration for
how to best prepare the plant
to maximize your growing efficiency also
if you're using
light sources that have strong red
wavelengths such as high pressure sodium
this will increase intensities for
plants to stretch
so just be mindful if you're in a
ceiling or height limited growing
situation
now the photoperiod itself well for
photoperiod dependent cultivars a simple
switch from an 18 plus
hours of continuous light to 12 hours of
continuous light
will shift the plant at any age to focus
on flower production
and development autoflowers are based on
the
days old and the day that the plants
will shift from vegetative to flying
will depend on the exact strain
grown so keep in mind with those
photoperiod dependent you have the
option
you could do it really really small i
could do it in the really tall doesn't
really
matter to the plant once it's exposed to
that 12 hours it's going to go through
and produce
those development of those flowers as
growers need to be mindful of
how our plants look so we can maximize
the efficiency
now light limitations with the
photoperiod dependent photoperiod
dependent strains will only
allow growers to provide it with 12
hours of light should be the maximum
light intensity
in supplementing with carbon dioxide so
their plants use
highlight intensity since the duration
will no longer be the 12 hours per day
why is that light intensity important
well the goal is to try to maintain a
high
dli which stands for daily light
integral
so because you're reducing the duration
of lights you're limited by how much
increasing the intensity is advised now
to allow plants to utilize that higher
intensity
sampling with carbon dioxide enrichment
for indoor locations
it will allow plants to utilize a
greater percentage
or intensity of light
now when we're looking at photoperiod
independence such as autoflowers what do
we do with
those if we're choosing to grow those
plants however the advantage of
autoflowers being photoperiod
independent is that they can handle
longer durations of light to help
maximize light which is important
considerations for growers
since the days of plant production are
limited what does that mean
since it doesn't matter kind of what you
expose them to for light
running them running lights longer for
autoflowers can help
increase productivity because you're
giving them a better chance
to go through and produce those
necessary sugars and cannabinoids
however while the cost of running lights
and potential cooling
should also be factored in because
running plants for 20 hours at high
intensity with carbon dioxide can help
maximize the harvest from these plants
because this will maximize the dli the
daily light integral that those plants
receive
if you are increasing the intensity keep
in mind there's only so much plants can
use under ambient carbon dioxide levels
so enriching that environment
will increase the intensity that they
can utilize
now as i mentioned ceiling height is an
important consideration so if your grow
space is ceiling height limited this can
impact
when the flip is made for photoperiod
dependence
and or the pruning style you use for
autoflowers remember that just because
plants are
in flower development mode doesn't mean
that they will stop
growing in vertical height they still
will continue to grow in height
while not as much as is in the
vegetative stage if you are growing a
sativa dominant strain this will stretch
more than an indica dominant in
morphology regardless of the increase in
height
can be around 50 percent so just keep
that in mind just because they stop
they're going to continue to grow this
is important when considering the
distance plant should be kept from
lights you're using
overall this height limitation tends to
be more of an issue for smaller grow
tents
than actual grow rooms but just because
the ceiling is high doesn't mean
you have to also consider where the
lights are hanging as well
now plant age so with autoflowers plant
age determines the transition point
for photoperiod dependent growers may
decide to
make the change in the photo period
based on the plant's age again to
maximize productivity and efficiency of
their grow operation
the best age is dependent on many
factors such as pruning style
if physical space of the growing air and
physical space of the growing area
however general starting point is to
float plants into flower when they have
reached about half
their total height you want them to
reach just as a heads up
now looking at up potting plants so this
is another important part of the process
many growers take the time around
flipping their plants to change their
containers or up pop their plants
this is typically a good idea however be
sure not to plan everything on the same
day might be great for the grower
not so great for the plants idea the
plants should be up potted and then
growers should wait about three days
before altering the photo period to
induce flowering
simply to reduce the stress that's going
on the plant
after the potting process that's going
to be a stress on the plant and if you
flip it the same day that could be too
much and could stunt the plant
potentially so what you're planning for
this stretch this kind of gives you just
a little bit of a kind of an image here
uh as an example in this case the pla
the tent height is
7 feet or 84 inches we see right here
the top
of the tent to the bottom of the lights
is 21 inches
so we're looking basically right here
with 16 inch spacing between the plants
and lights required
to give a total of 63 inches of grow
space remaining
and that is located basically right here
so the container is
13 inches tall resulting in total of 50
inches
of equipment height space being taken up
so just because you have this total
height of the grow tent
you also have to consider the distance
your
lights are hanging from the top the
distance the soil line is
up from the bottom so this limits 34
inches of plant height in the growing
space
so when plants reach 50 percent of
possible growing space in this case
17 inches the flowering photo period
should be initiated at least as a good
starting point
so here we're thinking oh 7 feet 84
inches plenty of growing space
well really when it comes to actual
plant space you only have about 34
inches
so again take all these factors into
consideration so you don't get caught
with your plants running into the lights
or having to do something
that's not going to be very plant
conducive take into consideration the
actual growing height initiate that
flowering halfway through
and that should offer you a very good
starting point for your plants to
determine
when you should flip them from the
vegetative photo period to the flowering
one