so here we're looking at the flood and
drain system of hydroponics also can be
called the ebb and flow basic setup is
an area here where the plants are with a
water reservoir below the pump that will
pump the water up causing this trade
area to flood and then after a period of
time that water will drain that down
this is really set on a timer and this
will be repeated as needed depending on
the size of the plants so the
floundering system basics in more detail
on the hydroponic lecture this is the
same system is not unique to cloning so
you may have heard something like this
used for clones but it can also be used
a lot of times for the actual production
of the plants it can be scaled to match
operation size whether it's a small grow
tent or a very large operation this
system can be used in both situations as
well as a medium-sized operations the
systems include a table so we see here
where the plants are being supported a
pump right here water reservoir is not
pictured would go where the pump would
be sitting in that reservoir but I
removed that for the image and in the
growing media as we see here when the
plants are actively growing the basic
operation involves flooding part of the
root zone a landlord will wick up the
media before it drains away keep in mind
the flood only takes a short period of
time to saturate the media before it
drains away we're not holding that water
there for a very long period of time
typically 5 to 10 minutes at the most
this allows for adequate moisture by
still allowing the roots to breathe
because if we lift that water there for
too long the roots would essentially
drowned and not be able to respire now
we're using smaller operations or if
we're using this and clone operations it
can utilize humidity domes makes an easy
way to evenly water a large quantity of
clones efficiently and as I said it can
also be used for a large scale
production but because we are pumping
that water in from the bottom we can use
humidity domes if they are needed for
the growing environment that those
plants are being placed in the drawbacks
are that it's dependent on electrical
pumps and timers Ostrom set up there's
keeping the tray clean there's
installing the trailers getting the
right table all these come into the
flood and drain operation pH needs to be
monitored or many clones can be stunted
or killed this
can go for the full-size plants there
that we can also stunt or kill even
full-size plants it'll be much quicker
for clones due to their very weak root
systems now the oven flow or the flood
and drains is what it actually looks
like easy to use and very reliable
utilizes a growing table or bench in
this growing bed it recirculates a
nutrient solution to reduce loss of that
the solution floods the growing table
with 1 to 3 inches of nutrient solution
which is allowed to drain down the crop
and then refill the reservoir so what
happens here is this lower area here's
where the water will be pumped into
actively a pump and this simply will
allow a drain now this can be adjusted
based on height it can put another
spacer in here to make it even taller if
we would like what this means is that if
the pump for some reason was to
continually to run so if the timer was
to fail this would prevent the pump
pumping out all the water burning up the
pump and flooding the entire room here
this would automatically drain back down
now naturally when the pump turns off
what is great is that the water will
backflow back down the hose here and
refill the reservoir keep in mind that
you want to keep the size of the tubing
for the pump to be smaller than the size
of the tubing for the drain this way is
impossible for the pump to over
compensate for the amount of nutrient
solution that can drain back in as a
result this will maintain a very
consistent maximum height and then your
timer will adjust the amount of time
that water is spent here now this is I
said scalable the commutes from one
plant can use for you know a million
plus plants it's often used for
propagation and clones but can also be
used for large plants as well what makes
this so great is it is very easy to
automate and this is part of the reason
why it can be used at such a large scale
it's commonly used with rock wall as as
this offers the ability to flush the
system and pushes air out on the flood
so what happens as water comes in it
pushes the air out it has the water
drains away it can pull in fresh air
increasing the oxygen content within
those fibers in the root zone as water
drains away from that media that air is
being pulled in this increases the
potential for oxygen concentration to
help the roots breathe which is
advantageous for them it's increasing
the popularity we're using rock
or with the flood and drain grodan is a
very popular system to be used with
hydroponics as a result they have a
great lineup of products that allow
clones to be easily propagating them and
then stepped up to these larger blocks
and then you can go to even larger
blocks for a large-scale production so
the Rodian or rock wall is being
utilized in combination with ebb and
flow on a very large scale but it can
also be scaled down to smaller
operations now there is a volume so this
typically system requires high volumes
of water but losses can be reduced with
sealable reservoirs keep in mind when we
are sitting at reservoir we don't want
to keep it completely airtight we just
want a lid over that to help reduce the
amount that may be lost to evaporation
because that can mean one way if we lose
that water at a very increased rate what
will happen is the nutrient solution may
become more concentrated in that
reservoir if it's not monitored so yeah
just a couple things to keep in mind
that evan flow is a very popular method
very efficient method and when that be
should be considered for any grow
operation