in this debaco university video i'm
going to cover flood and drain or some
people call it the ebb and flow
irrigation method and related to
cannabis production
whether you call it flood and drain or
you call it ebb and flow
let's get into this method of irrigation
so first off the basics of this general
method of irrigation
is that plants are typically grown in
inner
substrate that is within a container
located in a growing tray
where nutrient-containing water is
pumped from the reservoir to the growing
tray
you kind of see that evident right here
in this very simple homeowners type
setup this essentially will flood the
tray allowing the substrate and roots to
absorb some of the nutrient solution
before the water slowly drains back into
the reservoir
this process also aids in the aeration
of the root zone
another benefit of this system now why
do growers like this system in general
well it's easy to automate and it's also
easy to set up
and really requires minimal parts and
equipment
the system is also scalable meaning it
can be used for if you're only growing
one plant
if you're growing hundreds if you're
growing thousands or more than that
of plants it can be applied to that
situation as we see in the images
presented here
now there's no perfect system so there
are some drawbacks to the system
the disadvantage of the system as of
any other hydroponic systems in general
is that if something goes wrong
even for a short period of time the
entire crop
could be a loss simply because they're
all dependent on that exact same water
source
this requires growers to carefully
monitor
the process is essential this includes
nutrient concentrations as well as
ph values typical nutrient solutions are
changed every 7 to
10 days or so and the system should be
cleaned between
grow cycles or at any point that's
noticing that
it's justified or warranted looking at
the plants
looking at the trays and also the
reservoirs now what equipment
do you need if you're thinking about
employing this type of system
well a reservoir ideally with a lid a
growing tray to support the plants
and hold the flooding cycle tubing with
required fittings to attach everything
a water pump that's sized appropriately
for the size of the tray
a timer and plants that are potted in an
inert growing
substrate that will allow for absorption
of that nutrient solution
so a lot of times they're sold as kits
which is great this gives you just one
example
of a basic kind of components looking at
the flood and drain system
now what about the frequency and
duration some of the specifics
well how to best run your setup will
depend on a few factors
some of those factors include the age or
size of your plants
these substrate the plants are growing
in in general growing environment and
conditions temperature and humidity
so keep in mind the size and age the
older plants
larger plants are going to typically
require more water
the substrate the plants are growing and
how receptive is that substrate to water
is it holding water for an extended
period of time things to be in
consideration
and also the general growing environment
is it humid are you able to monitor
those conditions hopefully you're
monitoring those and able to keep those
in a good range
but if not if you have increased amounts
of temperature your frequency of
irrigation might be
a little bit higher however for a
starting point frequency should be two
irrigation events per day during a light
cycle
in a duration a 30 minute flood cycle
would be a good starting point
now this might be a little heavy so you
can always go a little bit lighter it's
just one way to kind of get a feel for
the system
30 minutes allows you a good time to
check to make sure everything's working
and you can kind of work it back down
from there as you see fit
as you monitor your plants so that you
dial in the frequency and duration
that best matches your conditions