so on this tobacco university video i'm
going to go over the flying or bloom
phase
of the cannabis growth cycle and show
you a little bit of some images
so you get an idea of the duration of
flowering phase
related to cannabis
[Music]
all right let's go over the flowering or
bloom phase of cannabis growth cycle
so first off the flowering stage length
well the flowering stage is the final
growth
stage of the cannabis plant and is when
the buds are produced and maturing
this is typically in weeks eight to
eleven of the growth cycle
most drains flower in eight to nine
weeks of the growth phase to give an
idea some can take even longer
particularly those that are sativa
dominant strains everyone wonders like
when is their
in flower what week and flower are they
in this kind of offers
a good visual guide as far as the
flowering phase which is
initially week one two weeks in the
flower three
four five six seven and eight and we can
see how that progression does
change as far as weeks into flower
now this may depend a little bit on the
variety you might be growing but at
least this provides a general kind of
overview of the stage of flower your
plants might be in
particular determine when those early
weeks are occurring
now flowering stage for outdoor and
indoor production well
outdoor plants will initiate flowering
naturally when the plant receives 12
hours of light or less each day
which occurs in summer transition into
fall
indoor growers can trigger the flowering
cycle by reducing the photo period to 12
hours a day
so they have a little bit more control
and better timing of when that exactly
occurs
now the flowering kind of subphases kind
of like the stages of fetal development
here
flowering initiation is at one to three
weeks and that's the plants continue to
grow in physical size
pre-female flowers produce the pistols
which are the thin little white cat like
whisker hairs
then we get into the mid-flowering phase
which is approximately weeks four to
five
and the plant vegetatively will kind of
stop or at least slow and growing as the
plant focuses more on the bud
development
then we get into late flowering or
ripening which is basically week
six and beyond and this is trichome
density will
be noticeably increased color of the
pistils will also change
so this gives you again another
indication of are you in initiation of
flowering mid flowering or late
flowering phase of your plants
now grower tips during the flowering
phase so do not prune the plants during
this phase
plants should be trellised to support
heavy bud production
and you can see here excessive outdoor
production trellis thing doesn't have to
be super fancy you're just looking at a
way of plant support
growers will typically feed bloom
fertilizer to plants that have high
concentrations of phosphorus
but consider the substrate and be
careful how much you add
to avoid negative environmental effects
and limited
positive effects to the plant there yes
phosphorus
is needed but i find a lot of growers
are over applying it to the plants
at the end of the flowering phase we
have the flower buds will be
visually developed quickly towards the
end of the flowering phase
and we'll go about how to kind of go
through and look at all the wonderful
little trichomes
densities getting a magnifying loop
would be great to inspect these
so you could go through and determine
the peak ripeness
of your particular flowers but a lot of
it has to do with the setting up those
plants during the vegetative phase
recognizing the stages of development in
the flowering phase so you can ideally
have
a good harvest dry and cure phase as
well