thank you for a look at flowering growth
cycle of cannabis and we could see in
the picture here that initial kind of
female flower is starting to be produced
at the apical meristem of this branch
there we're gonna let see just a little
bit more about this growth cycle that
the plant goes through so flowering
first is induced by an even 12 hours of
light you twelve hours of dark the key
remembers those twelve hours of
continuous darkness after the change
plants will show visible response in
under two weeks so once you kind of go
from those 1618 plus hours of light to
twelve hours of light and dark after
this change that's we're gonna start to
see that within about two weeks time
there's flowers development this mimics
the fall season where Knights begin to
get longer which is typically when
plants want to begin to prepare flowers
to carry on for the next generation now
as a plant prepares for fall time New
England we have the leaves that turn
different colors indicated by that
shortening days for canvas the
vegetative part or phase the plant will
begin to slow it will still grow maize
stems may still stretch and leaves may
still grow but they may produce less
blades and typically that it hit of
course will be slowed for sure this is
when plants are needing less nitrogen in
their fertilizer program which is where
bloom fertilizers come in bloom furrows
are typically higher in phosphorous
which can be come integrated to
encourage flower production into your
nutrient reservoir during the flowering
stage is when most of the cannabinoid
interpreting production will occur so
keep that in mind this is considered
flower rooms are often considered the
money room even though it is important
to set your plants up well in it through
the vegetative stage
remember your chosen cultivars of
cannabis ruderalis will flower
automatically in about three or four ish
weeks of growth regardless of the photo
period there's some late blooming sativa
varieties that may need special care so
again just knowing your cultivar that
you've chosen to grow and all the pros
and cons associated with that ahead of
time will be best for your operation