if you're growing chemist plants
outdoors you may have heard
of indoor growers flushing their plants
again only applies to them
however this can also apply to outdoor
growing
of cannabis and this debaco university
video will provide you with some
specifics on how to flush
outdoor grown cannabis plants
[Music]
all right let's look at flushing outdoor
grown cannabis plants
well first off realize that there is no
standardized method
no studies have been published to date
that examine the exact process of
flushing
cannabis plants however this does not
mean that is not common practice
as the idea to produce high quality bud
and also minimize
inputs is in the play meaning that we're
looking at
how can we maximize our production and
minimize
our inputs to have the best efficiency
as possible with our final end product
now the goal of any flushing protocol
indoors or outdoors is to
reduce nutrient concentrations in the
root zone so the plant metabolizes what
is already present in the plant tissue
so it's really easy to think about in an
indoor growing situation we have a lot
of water added to a container
and the water is being over added sort
of speaking allowing it to drain
out of the container away from the root
zone taking nutrients with it
a little harder to do in an outdoor
setup but i'll go over some specifics
for you
now the water properties that you want
to be flushing with ideally the water
should be around room temperature 70 75
and have a slightly acidic ph value of
6.0 to 6.3
because this will aid in the ability to
ensure nutrients are soluble
and easily removed via the water this
maximizes the efficiency of removing
those nutrients
dissolving those nutrients and getting
them away from the root zone
so this can be great to have a little ph
tester this is a little bit more of a
higher end
testosterone also gives it temperature
and everything but good to have some
idea
of what your water properties that
you'll be irrigating with
so the first nutrient to go when you're
doing this process will be
nitrogen because it's the most water
soluble of the nutrients
so watch for a potential deficiency of
this nutrient first
in the plant you'll know you're having
nitrogen
deficiency and it's because it's
characterized by the lowering
lower leaves becoming yellow while the
upper portions of the leaves will remain
green at least for a period of time if
you run this for too long especially the
whole plant will go yellow
if you start to see this kind of
yellowing of the lower leaves you might
be flushing too early in the plant
growth cycle or too aggressively so keep
that in mind it's a great kind of way to
check
and balance your system there now timing
is important
as we can see here with this image the
goal is to time the reduction in
nutrients with the harvesting of the
the buds of the end product when the
plant runs out of nutrients this should
be very close to harvesting so there's
no plant stunting or a chance at yield
reduction
note this is best done if you're going
to be harvesting the entire plant
and not doing a selective bud harvest as
this may result in the second harvest
being negatively impacted by the
reduction in plant available
nutrients now growing uh conditions do
play a role in this so you've got to
take this into consideration
are the plants grown in field soil or
the plants growing outside
in containers for field soil what's the
soil texture composition for example
it's a percent sand silt and clay
that's going to play a role if you're
going in containers what are the size of
the containers
and what substrate is also found in
those containers it'll also
impact your protocol to file for the
flushing process
now we're looking at field soils they
say they present sand silt and clay
we go to our kind of triangle here
to kind of determine are we in a clay
soil a silt loam a clay loam
sandy loam that all plays into it in
general though
as a percentage of clays increase so
does the length of time
of the flushing period this can be as
much as 15 to 20 days because clay tends
to hold onto
nutrients much for a much longer period
of time
so as you work your way up here and your
percentage clay increases
so will your duration of time that
should be flushing
sandy loams down in this region are
typically recommended to flush for 10 to
15 days
as always this can depend on how
aggressive the plants are being fed
leading up to harvest as well also
realize
that flushing is not truly possible as
the roots will likely be quite extensive
but the period of time where only waters
being added can help reduce the cost
and impact the final yield and not
impact the finally that i should say if
done
properly so this is great a great way to
kind of reduce your cost
you will not be able to fully flush your
plants as a container grower can
can do but this is a great way to reduce
your overall cost
reduce your chance of environmental
contamination while not
impacting in any negative way your final
yield
so if you're growing outdoors in
containers which some growers do the
container size
is something to take into consideration
large containers will typically make
flushing more difficult
simply because of total volume of
material and increased likelihood
of holding on to nutrients typically
large containers you can favor in that
10 to 12 days
smaller containers make for easy over
saturation so the duration of flush time
can be reduced at five to seven days
and then we have the substrate
composition if the substrate holds
nutrients the flush time should be
longer than if it's more easily drained
for example sandy soils that drain very
easily compared to clay soils
and that's why you see such a large span
of 5 to 15
days here complete saturation and
flushing may not be feasible
but not adding nutrients this is
reducing cost and not
ideally impacting the final product if
done properly
so your basic flushing protocol just in
general here
would be while this can be a challenge
when uh the water is leading the
determined when the water is leaving the
root zone it cannot be
measured as a very large container or
field soil saturations so general
estimates
need to be applied generally the
starting point to initial irrigate with
two and a half to three times the volume
of water as a normal irrigation event
would occur
followed by normal volumes of plain
water for the duration of the time
suggested in each situation
some growers like to do this kind of
heavy flush period to really force that
water
plant water through to really force some
of those nutrients out of the root zone
not necessarily required but you can
have one irrigation event maybe when you
initially start to
start the flushing process that is a
little bit longer duration than you
normally would
to initiate this flushing protocol
hopefully this helps you an outdoor
growing situation to reduce some of your
inputs
without reducing your yields to help
maximize
your efficiency