welcome to this video here on tobacco
university looking at a fly
life cycle how it may relate to forensic
science
so the reason why we'd be interested in
insects particularly in relation to
forensics
is that they have a certain succession
or progression that they go through
so the progression of insects life
follows a pattern on cadavers
and development rates of flies are
relatively predictable
so the length of the life cycle varies
between different fly species and is
dependent on
temperature so that can help us kind of
backtrack or determine
how long that corpse has been there or
potentially the temperature
based on the insects that are present
typically flies lay eggs usually within
the first 24 hours
and then the predatory rove beetles or
parasites that feed on maggots will have
to wait until the
blowfly arrives and lay their eggs so
we're gonna focus a little bit on the
blowfly in particular here
beetles that specialize on bone will
have to wait until the bone is exposed
so based on the insect species that
we're noticing or observing
that can help us kind of get a general
idea of the time
frame between very important when we're
looking at trying to determine
when the initial point of death occurred
now blowfi
metamorphosis so we kind of focus on
this just for a little bit
the blowflies are attracted to dead
bodies and often arrive within minutes
of the death of an animal
there are distinctive egg larval and
pupil adult stages which help estimate
the time of
death and this is where a good
entomologist a good person identifying
not only the insects
but the stage of development they're in
can help also provide a direct
correlation to
time so stage one looking at the eggs
all adult flies lay eggs on the
carcasses especially in the wound areas
or around openings in the body such as
nose eyes and ears
so to kind of be that very first stage
to be looking for early on
in the fly life cycle progressing on
then we have the larval stage is where
the eggs hatch into larvae or typically
referred to as maggots in the first 12
to approximately 24
hours continuing from there the larvae
continue to grow and they'll molt which
means they shed their exoskeleton
as they pass through the various n-star
stages an
star is a phase between two periods of
molting in the development of
an insect larvae or other invertible
organism
the first instar if you capture them and
preserve them you're looking at
you can determine that by being about
five millimeters long and that occurs
after about 1.8 days
the second end star they'll progress to
about 10 millimeters long and
occur after about two and a half days
and the third and star will be about 14
to 16 millimeters long
this will occur after four to five days
now the pupa stage has stage number four
here the larva about 17 millimeters and
they develop into pupil after burrowing
into
surrounding soil so this is where we're
not only looking at the corpse but the
soil around that
can also play a very important factor
the adult stage that we're probably most
familiar with for the fly emerge from
the pupa cases and this occurs after
about six to eight
days and again probably most easily or
most common
for recognizing now looking at the
blowfly
in particular it has six parts the egg
the three larval stages the pupa and the
adult stage
and this kind of gives you an idea of
not in the progression but how long it
takes to go from one
area to another keep in mind this is at
70 degrees fahrenheit
each station of blowfire's life cycle
takes this known amount of time to
complete
and as they said temperature or
documenting that temperature having an
idea with that temperature
may have been in the area can impact the
time exactly
so important to take note of that as
well now this
metamorphosis process that can occur
well in flies and beetles and many other
insects have a complete metamorphosis
which consists of four stages
that egg larval and pupil to adult stage
so in these both metamorphosis stages
the insects begin to cycle as an egg and
complete the metamorphosis
and the insect passes through four
distinct phases which produce an adult
that does not resemble necessarily the
larval stage this is important to keep
note of this is why a good entomologist
is needed because it may look quite
different
squeeze these different transitions that
occur from that nymph to the adult by
molting the excess skeleton
whenever it becomes too tight in its
original casing there
so lastly just where you want to look
for these insects again if you're not an
extra entomologist just kind of an idea
of where to kind of look for
after the adults meet the females
usually lay eggs into the corpses that's
usually near natural body openings or
wounds
feeding activity is usually seen in the
head region first which is the mouth
nostrils eyes or ears this is followed
by the
expiratory and reproductive openings as
well the trunk of the body is invaded
much later in the process so that can
just give you a general idea
of when you're looking for those insects
where you may find them
just to give you a general idea of the
progression keep in mind of the type of
insect you're looking at
as well as the temperature in the area
because all that will have an
influence and be able to try to pinpoint
with the greatest degree of accuracy
the original time of death