okay here looking at foliar feeding man
this just as the name implies and mouse
feeding the leaves are feeding the
foliage of your plant we're going to go
over a little bit about some of the
basics of this process so first off
involves the simple act of applying
fertilizer on the actual leaf surface
often diluted application rates of 1 to
100 or greater are often suggested
anything higher concentration that when
you're applying it to the leaves on
depending again what product you're
using but you increase the odds of
burning the leaves you want to be
mindful in applying things to the leaves
that the odds of burning can increase
there's ways we can go about reducing
that and one is through dilution rate
that means the equipment you're using so
the finer the water droplet the better
the coverage the plants will get in the
more efficient application of the
product hand pump sprayers are very
entry-level they're easy to get they're
very cost effective but they tend to
produce larger water droplets if you're
looking at misters or foggers are often
recommended because of that fine
water droplet that they're creating
increasing the interaction of that
particular product and the leaf surface
which allows it to be taken up much more
efficiently now looking at the time of
day that you apply is also an important
consideration you want to watch out for
periods of high heat and light
intensities as these can increase the
odds of burning the leaves no matter
what product you're using typically
early early morning or late evening for
outdoor growers is recommended to reduce
the burning but also increase the
efficiency due the higher percentage of
leaf stomata being open Symone are
basically pores in the leaf and if
they're open you can get that particular
product that you're applying into the
leaf a lot more efficiently I mentioned
this is for outdoor growers early
morning we're looking at for indoor
growers yeah
soon before maybe lights come on or
definitely at least not during peak
lighting maybe just kind of before they
come on or just after they go off maybe
other options for some indoor growers to
maximize foliar feeding and minimize
damage also for foliar feeding new
spreaders and stickers what a spreader
is is it reduces the surface tension to
allow for the applied products reduce
flat droplets increased amount of leaf
surface interaction literally this is a
normal water droplet it spreads that
to create that nice interaction you
could see here here's our entire product
we're only having this level of
interaction here having ideally the same
volume of water but a lot greater
interaction could see the extreme
example here we're having again that
minimum interaction that spreaders will
help spread that out this is because
leaves how the waxy surface to them
which is hydrophobic which is repelling
the water so spreader helps kind of
negate some of the negatives the polar
compounds of water and helps spread them
out to increase that interaction there's
also something called stickers and these
reduce the chance of water splash from
washing off the plant leaf surface it
literally will help them adhere or stick
to the leaf surface so if you have a
spreader sticker combination then only
you're getting the higher contact of our
spreader
but the sticker is actually making it
adhere to the leaves a little bit more
efficiently the benefits of these better
stickers again help increase the contact
between the liquid and the leaf surface
makes the products more effective so
this can be a great way to maximize that
use of the product and ensure that that
leaf is getting a very even coverage
throughout however the drawbacks is some
products are not recommended to be mixed
with spreader stickers so know what
product you're using and know if there
is any potential negative interactions
with adding that such product you also
sweater stickers can make some products
work what's called to well it increases
the odds of burning so sometimes if
you're using a spreader sticker I'm
going to cut back on the dilution I want
to increase that dilution rate a little
bit more and cut back on maybe go with a
very small amount or smaller amount as
you work your way up to reduce the
chance of spray damaging or grower you
know induced plant leaf burning through
the use of all of your feeding which can
be effective at increasing especially if
there's deficiencies but we want to be
mindful of some of the concerns that are
also associated with it and typically
this is a little bit more of a quicker
fix want to be managing the vast
majority of our nutrients through the
growing media that we're choosing to use