so here we're looking at footprint
enhancement we see a great example of
that here
we have sequential chemical enhancement
of footwear impressions
in blood on white polyester using
luminol
neohydrin and acid black one so this
kind of gives you an idea of how we can
enhance or change that kind of
footprint to be able to show certain
characteristics
so however when we're looking at
enhancement in general
one word of caution is i want to be
careful with any enhancement methods
that we might be implementing
why because these may damage the
original prints which can lead to
destruction of evidence
and possible disqualification from being
used in court
here we have an original photograph here
we have an enhanced one
at a certain point of where's the line
of over enhancing something
so again just word of caution only use
this if you need to
don't use this as a default method so
post initial photography methods
so if footprint is made in blood color
changing reagents can help
visualize the prints these can be
physical methods such as latent powder
lifting impressions or impressions
on paper a lot of these are found in
easy to carry kits
to a crime scene we also have dusting
for footprints so just like we would
dust for fingerprints the same can be
applied to footprints
and you can use the same powder even
fingerprint powder can be
visualized prints using the same basic
procedures as you would for fingerprints
lifted with adhesive or gelatin and
photograph then to be included
as evidence so something that may
initially be really hard to see you can
kind of see it sort of kind of
with that with that adding of
fingerprint powder it becomes
much clearer we also have something
called electrostatic
lifting which is an aggressive technique
to recover
impressions typically used on hard
surfaces such as tile or wood
there's basically a charge used to lift
dry materials from a surface
to a black film this lift will provide
more contrast and is non-destructive
and then it can be photographed and
entered as evidence
placards or markers are used to document
locations of impressions
if possible remove and transport those
impressions
those electrostatic just lifting devices
operate by charging a plastic film
placed over a dust pan
which creates electrostatic adhesions
into a film surface
showing the print now casting of prints
this is kind of
simple requires a little bit of a kind
of carrying of this bulk material
but it can pick up really it can pick up
detail very well
material is very durable this casting
and it can be cast
after its photographs you should always
take photographs first then make a cast
and if you want to take photographs
after
typically this casting material is kind
of a basis of
some sort of dental stone because it
allows a
really strong structure to be made but
allows also the
retaining of certain details and
products can be sprayed with colorized
wax to aid in highlighting
those prints now impression enhancements
so poor impressions can sometimes are
made
and may have to be enhanced by the
following means so initially it might be
really hard to see the details
so you can offer some of these
enhancements particularly for
the purpose of photography
oblique ultraviolet infrared or other
special methods can be used
here we see kind of a snow print simply
using a coloration
to create a greater contrast can really
help provide
an exposure to some of those details
that can be more easily
photographed now chemical enhancement
methods
looking at chemical enhancement reagents
such as crystal violet luminol
dehydration may also be used we saw this
on the title slide
the difference you can get with these
certain chemical enhancement
methods then we also have digital
enhancement
software such as like photoshop can be
used to enhance
impressions but remember there is a fine
line between overdoing the enhancement
here we see women in the woods we see
kind of left and right we see that kind
of enhancement of color
here we see probably a photoshop that's
gone a little too
far so again keep in mind that digital
enhancement methods
should only be used if absolutely
necessary and kind of as a last resort
because it could eliminate them from
being included as evidenced in a court
setting