now here i'm going to go over footwear
evidence comparisons and
a pretty good example to show you which
you may
you may not catch during the duration of
this video so you're welcome to pause
the video or go in the description
download the slides for yourself and try
to look at some of the points that i
bring up because
a lot of this takes just a lot of going
back and forth a lot of time spent to
develop that kind of detailed eye so
what can footwear impressions tell you
well they can actually tell you a lot
they can identify the footwear eliminate
certain footwear
participant they identify participants
in the suspect in the crime they can
kind of offer locations of impressions
how those might play into what may have
occurred
rebuttal or confirm confirm alibis link
suspects determine shoe size
to try to determine number of people
present track kind of see where the
direction of travel was
so they can actually tell you quite a
bit that's why they're an important
piece of evidence so footwear evidence
kind of these impressions will have kind
of found a great
example here we're looking at a print
looking at some of the details and kind
of pointing out some of the key
components to this
particular shoe now it's very important
to kind of orient yourself
have an idea of the size so that when
you have the actual sample you're able
to go through
and kind of glean all of these wonderful
details and again you're looking at kind
of the manufacturer
to just the general size to obviously
looking at just the general tread as
well
so how may that play into certain
aspects when you're making these
comparisons
we also have kind of class
characteristics to look at that's what
you should be looking at first
now keep in mind class characteristics
in general uh there's numerous class
characteristics that's only going to
kind of give you that general
kind of size tread design things you can
obviously see
they're still important they're very
important for potentially of eliminating
certain shoe types we see kind of a
whole bunch listed here
i'll even move myself kind of out of the
image here so you can kind of
be able to determine and see that kind
of comparison between the two
again these class characteristics can be
simple as manufacturer tread design
and things like that which you wanted to
be able to get to potentially if you
think that you have
things that match on a class
characteristic end you want to get to
the wear characteristics
and this can be getting into more
individual evidence the question shoe
print shows where characteristics that
are similar to that of the known
shoe very little wear on lateral edges
in the
forefoot section of the shoe print of
the shoe so you're looking at you know
you're having a lot of wear
up here and not so much down here so
it's getting into wear characteristics
getting into that more individual
characteristics and again as i mentioned
those class characteristics here are
some very specific
ones kind of identified here remember
class characteristics
are distinctive a particular model of
shoe identification of class
characteristics and the footwear
impressions
allow examiners to determine the
manufacturer model sizing of
shoe wear and also the impressions some
class
class characteristics present in shoe
above and i've
kind of provided you with some kind of
comparisons
here that you say however when we get
more specific we get into those
individual
characteristics so we're talking about
individual characteristics
we're now looking at characteristics
that are very distinctive to that
particular show
these consist of random damage on the
outsole
they could cause there's a little piece
of gum attached there's a
crack in one of the areas of the shoe
and this is really matching it up to
something that isn't found on all shoes
photograph above there's about 12
individual characteristics here we can
kind of see highlighted
in that comparison of the actual shoe to
the impression
provided this is why a detailed
impression is so important
here's kind of that last detailed
impression comparison with some kind of
arrows
indicating to allow you to kind of see
kind of where those arrows are pointing
and can kind of pick that piece of
evidence out and can you kind of
identify
those individual characteristics if you
want to kind of do some comparisons you
can go grab one of your own shoes and
see if you can identify
any individual characteristics for your
own shoe
with this helpful video