okay here I'm going to provide a brief
introduction to forensic science so the
nature of forensic science well let's
start with just defining the terms here
that are included so for example
forensics is scientific test used in
connection with the detection of a crime
and that can as you can see up here I
can be involving certain laboratory
techniques we're gonna go over more
details in other videos this can involve
eyewitness testimony and dealing with
other aspects of that so it's in all
centered or rounded the detection of a
crime the other part of that science is
an intellectual and practical activity
encompassing the systematic study of the
structure and behavior of physical and
natural world through the observations
in experiment so a pretty long
definition for a single word there well
what that science is is kind of that
application so while forensics is
detection of a crime using the science
components this is how we take this
practical and systematic approach to
analysis or analyzing I should say a
crime scene and how we go about pulling
out the information identifying
information and developing potential
tests to encode for and provide data in
detail observations that may be made so
putting it together science as it
relates to the law so there is that lab
based component but then there's also
the law because a lot of times forensic
science people aren't going in front of
courts and forgeries in court settings
and they have to be able to argue and
provide evidence that they found through
their work it uses a crime scene
processing protocol and says how can we
go through and how to break down what's
going on with crime scene to be able to
gain information without altering what
might be going on there so it could be
presented in a official base in front of
a jury and a court setting so that's
kind of just a very basics of
introduction to forensic science other
videos in this channel will go through a
lot more detail