so welcome to this video here at debaco
university
looking at forensics entomology so how
do
insects relate to forensics and in their
involvement within
crime scenes even though they're
probably not the ones committing the
crime
so entomology in general what is that
referring to well the
entomology is the study of insects in
relationship to humans environment
and other organisms entomologists make
great contributors to such
diverse fields such as agriculture
looking at crop loss or potential pests
chemistry biology human and animal
health
molecular sciences criminology and the
focus today
is forensic so insects have a lot of
contributions and a lot of potential
areas of study
within multiple areas within science so
why study insects well insect species
arrive at a corpse in waves like
clockwork so when we're looking at a
crime scene
why are we looking at insects well they
have a very
distinctive and repeatable habit this
because of this it provides a good
estimation of the time
that has passed since the individual has
perished so this is a great reason why
entomology or
insects are such a major focus within
forensics
now this forensics entomology flies in
maggots also provide an approximate time
of death which is very useful in cases
where the body
has been long dead we're not necessarily
fresh on the scene
it's happened over a period of time and
discovered later entomology can play a
great role in that
because only certain insects will feed
and light eggs on a dead corpse
and the forensics entomologists can
study these insects their larval cycles
and they're after and can determine
whether the body has been dead for just
one day
or up to three or four weeks potentially
so again great resource
for information there now antomonas aid
in
this process in this process of studying
of the
persons who have passed away by
identifying the insects in the various
stages of their life cycle so not only
knowing what insects are there
but are they the egg stage the larval
stage or present as adults
by collecting and preserving insects as
evidence this can ensure proper
preservation procedures and ensure that
those insects are
kind of frozen in time there this can
help determine the estimate of
postmortem interval or pmi
time between death and the discovery of
the body which can help provide
an approximation for where further
investigation should be
focused on factors such as insect
evidence the weather that's the
conditions that have occurred the
location and condition the body are all
useful as well
entomologists can also testify in court
to explain insect related evidence found
in the crime scene
and as a result they can aid by
providing expert testimony
now insect species and time so when
we're looking at the species and the
actual time that's passed by
we can calculate the heat slash thermal
energy
which is accumulated in degree hours
required for each stage
of for example here the green bottle
flies life cycle just one insect that
can be used
possibly the greatest potential source
of error is using the arthropods
successional patterns lies in the
collection of the actual specimens
this is why entomologists will typically
be used and focused in on this area to
ensure accuracy
most only done correctly to accurate
sample the insects so we want to make
sure we're getting a good sample
but also we're getting the correct
sampling of those
insects in the various life cycles that
we may notice
so insects typically that we'll be
focusing on would be like flies or
beetles
species may also provide clues and some
feed on fresh corpses while others
prefer ones that have been dead for a
couple of weeks
so again proper identification can
really help a forensic scientist try to
pinpoint
the time of death which can help further
investigation
and allocation of resources