okay so here I'm gonna go over forensic
photography methods and things you might
want to be considering and this is some
things that make it advantageous if you
get a camera that allows you to adjust
some features it's gonna really allow
you to maximize the shot consider you
can't move the object or change a lot of
things by just in the camera you can
capture the information of the image
that you need so starting first general
methods looking at all photographs must
contain three elements the subject scale
and a reference object and we have a
prime example the footprint here was
nice scale cuz I got the subject got a
reference object included a website here
at the bottom that at the time of
videotaping this video here this was
active and it allows you to print out
something just like this to allow you to
include this in any images that you may
take or want to practice with it's a
great way to kind of have color
correction have size have scale of
contrast really allows a set distance so
really allows you to add a lot of these
elements to the photograph such new your
take so what should our crime-scene
photograph should contain what well as
we can kind of see in the images here
they should always be in focus so in the
case it's kind of easy when they're in a
controlled environment but we don't want
to move them so we need to make sure
that they are in focus they also need to
be kind of the main object within the
photograph again it's been photographs
or taking notes particularly talking
about the object contain a scale or
ruler so as we can see in these images
while they are listed is 45 they all
contain that nice scale allowing us to
know the exact size of that object and
also it number tags it which is great
for organization purposes that skill or
ruler having a little right angle here
also helps be a fair and accurate
representation of what is seen so while
we have that as our main object what's
around it or where it may occur be or be
placed or be left also important any
change in color may miss identify an
object or investigators and pusle jurors
so this is why we want to have our
photographs be as accurate to true light
as possible so which one of these is the
best representation so we have a couple
options here we have photograph
one photograph to a photograph - is the
correct representation so a lot of
people look at photograph one see that's
a little bit brighter
well you're losing some of the detail
photograph one is too much light means
that the photograph her failed to catch
the proper light to describe the object
by just in the flash photograph or
should have just camera flash to capture
the object in the detail as well you
might want this level of detail and
scale is if I took this out here and
just kind of took a picture of the
turtle you would know if that's an adult
large turtle or small turtle by putting
some hands showing how small it is
that gives us that perspective or that
correct representation so be mindful
here's two objects the exact same but
that's slight difference of cutting down
the light really takes into account a
lot more of the detail now when taking
the photographs now with the digital age
we are taking a lot of photographs which
is great but we also need to keep a
photographic log this should be done as
you're taking the pictures responding
officer must also maintain this log of
any photographic evidence that it's
taken should contain the date the time
of the of the photograph the subject
matter in any additional notes it should
be done in order and also who took those
pictures very important there's two
people taking pictures these lots must
be maintained within a case file or
incident report as they are part of the
examination record and discoverable
material at trial it's important as much
as people don't like to this to be
updating this log as you're taking the
pictures you may stumble across
something in a different direction
whenever you're making sure that you're
kind of always making that subject in
those comments as your date in the
pictures those three components of
photography there's ISO shutter speed
and aperture and it's just kind of a
great way of kind of creating a quick
little comparison aperture or small
aperture will get a further depth of
field larger after it tends to focus
more closer shutter speed the faster the
shutter speed you can stop a moving
object the slower the shutter speed will
blur an object if it is moving
typically on crime scenes the objects
aren't moving all that fast ISO low
sensitivity and high sense that even get
a little bit more greening potentially
depending on other factors that may be
be using with our cameras so ISO just to
start here International Organization
for Standardization
really
the human sensitivity to light back in
the days of film there was they were
stolen different is OS but this creates
a great contrast ii-era photograph one
photograph to shutter speeds the same
focus is the same but the ISO is
different here's ISO of a hundred you
can barely make that object out here
1600 it's very clear in dark
environments that ISO makes light sensor
of the camera more sensitive so
increasing the ISO will allow this in a
dark environment to show quite well I
saw there's a high possibility to make
careful nose which is kind of blurriness
which can cause that visual distortion
too much dependence on ISO can distort
the image so knowing your camera knowing
how to adjust certain things is great if
you're left with only adjusting ISO
though as least as possible so you don't
get noise and distortion for your images
shutter speed shutter speed is the
length of time when the film or the
digital sensor inside the camera is
exposed to light so here we have a slow
shutter speed to get that kind of
smoothing of the water that kind of
cascade effect which are tuned is shot
with different shutter speeds when when
25th the second one 400 these two
photographs taken are the same situation
except the shutter speed is changed this
slow shutter speed makes image more
clear and bright because the low shutter
speed takes in more light than the
higher shutter speed however high
shutter speed is often necessary for
moving objects but in this case we see
kind of can make out one fingerprint
sort of pended here here we can make up
that one for sure but also several
others also the ruler is much clearer
visible here allowed us to get a better
idea of the size of that object so
here's an example of adjusting shutter
speed and how it can vastly impact the
image aperture or focus so aperture
means the extent with the sharpness of
an image is shown with the lens here we
can see list of candle or a line of
candles one two three four all pretty
well in focus here the first one is a
little blurry the second one looks great
third one's a little blurry and the
fourth one definitely starting
definitely the background so photograph
one all objects are very clearly visible
with a high aperture to the image shows
an object with the right focus but the
rest of the evidence are all blurred
because of low aperture this would be
important if this is the one you're
looking at focusing on for some reason
but this tells a little bit better story
of where these objects are and what is
also located behind them
so it's important if you have a pitcher
and focus in mind which might be limited
based on the light and other factors
lastly the flash we're looking at flash
of the cameras white balance of the
photo flash and it's set to mimic
daylight to ensure proper color balance
of this subject matter
be mindful though of reflections
particularly of glass objects or shiny
objects that can occur due to the flash
here we have the flashes indirect you
can take the flash point upwards in the
ceiling here it's directly on the image
if you could see how it really distorts
it this adds enough light so you can see
in detail but doesn't distort anything
then they have any reflections because
this can demonstrate its flash it's
either removed from the camera body
creating the angle or bounced off the
ceiling or some other object because you
want it to be well lit but you do not
want it to distort or kind of cause that
blurriness to occur due to the flash so
there's just some important key items to
keep in mind when we're looking at
studying our photography skills and
making sure that we're capturing quality
images that really depict what was seen
at the crime scene