okay for watching this video you're
watching for one of two reasons first
could be a stumbled upon this video
first or two you came across my other
fourth line method video and wanted a
little bit of an easier version this is
gonna explain the same method and go
through the very similar process so you
can gain some experience with it want
you to be comfortable with the fork line
method to get away from the punnett
squares this is a more reliable method
and it's easier and quicker so we're
going to try habit cross using the fork
line method now this same can be applied
to more or less complex equations the
key part is you need to understand what
a monohybrid crosses and also the foil
method from math class look at the first
outer and inner last to distribute
things in that use a Punnett square
problem is a politic plant and the
genotype big a big a big B Big B Big C
little C is crossed with another plant
of genotype which is homozygous dominant
for a heterozygous for be in
heterozygous for see what are the
expected genotype frequencies of the
offspring or seeds produced from this
resulting cross now since both parents
are homozygous down for the a allele the
process shown isn't quite as efficient
as it could be but this isn't in it to
though to help those that might be
struggling to understand this method
odds are you probably haven't seen this
in middle school or anywhere else this
might be your first exposure to that and
that's okay
I want you to be sure that you can
understand it if you were to do a
Punnett square it looks something like
this which is gets very complex and very
hard to keep track of things and
increases the odds for an error we want
to try to avoid that this fork line
method is a lot cleaner and a lot easier
to understand once you get over the
initial hurdle of seeing that something
different in the punnett squares you
might be used to so step one identifying
the triad would cross into three
monohybrid crosses one for the a alleles
one for the B alleles one for the seal
is never use the foil method and not
punnett squares and generate this
looking at plants or looking at
generating the genotype for seeds so
same with the first one because both
parents in this case are almost I guess
dominant
100% of the time that's going to be the
resulting of the offspring they're
called true breeding in that sense for
that allele least for the because we
have a homozygous dominant heterozygous
half the time
we'll have Big B Big B and the other
half the time will be heterozygous Big B
little B see it's a little more bit more
complex here what both being
heterozygous 1/4 of be homozygous
dominant the other quarter will be
almost I guess recessive and half the
time that will be heterozygous so how do
we put all these genotype frequencies
together well first off we have to
identify the possible combinations of
genotypes this requires the pairing of
genotypes from all the monohybrid
crosses previously completed you're
talking about plants will get pollen
grains so hundred percent in time it's
always gonna give a homozygous dominant
for a half will be homozygous dominant
for B half will be heterozygous for B
and then for C remember a quarter of the
time it'll be homozygous dominant
quarter time homozygous recessive and
half the time heterozygous so start the
fork line method well since one hundred
percent in time the big a big I you just
write that one down
now we want to distribute that to our
Belial we know that half the time it'll
be homozygous dominant for me the other
half heterozygous now II to get a little
bit more complex with the C alleles and
we notice that here we're including all
three of those possibilities for all
three of the options now to get to the
seed genotype we simply multiply these
percentages or these fractions right
across notice by doing that it's easy
because the first ones will always 1 1
times 1/2 times 1/4 would be in eighth
one times 1/2 times 1/2 would be 1/4 1
times 1/2 times 1/4 can will be in E not
only are we carrying those numbers my
color coded those accordingly
we're also carrying around those alleles
so you could see that one is that big a
big a indicated here the 1/2 is that
almost I guess down it from B and the
core is the homozygous dominant for C so
this is how we develop our seed
genotypes with this fork line method and
you can see once you get comfortable
with this how quick and easy can
actually be into
a lot more reliable than upon its square
so the simplified version here we take
these fractions and turn them into
percents 1/8 times 100 to give you 12
and a half percent and you do that for
the rest here now getting back to the
questions what are the expected genotype
frequencies of the offspring or seeds
produced well that would be indicated
right here you notice you have all of
these percentages with these genotypes
perfectly aligned and all set to go if
you were to add these up you would also
get a hundred percent which is a way to
check to make sure you calculated or
accounted for all the stated genotypes
now if you want to test your skills you
can go my other fork line method example
we look at this cross I'll be sure to
put a link in the descriptions you can
look at this the key difference here is
the a alleles one parent is heterozygous
the other one is almost I guess
recessive you can see how that changes
things you know what else you better
understand get more comfortable at this
worked mine