okay I know can be hard to teach an old
dog new tricks but in this case I want
you to get away from the punnett squares
you're so familiar and probably
comfortable with and start to learn this
fork line method see punnett squares are
represented here but this fork line
method is a very efficient way and a
great way to handle larger crosses
because in this case we're gonna use the
example of a tri hybrid cross now I know
you thought the fun started stopped with
dihybrid crosses but it only just began
there we're now into tri hybrid crosses
in this fork line method will make it a
lot easier once you fully understand it
so try a bit cross example we're gonna
use this fork line method and it builds
on withwith dihybrid crosses remember
the foil method where we're distributing
our gametes here
so our first outside-in said in last and
that's how we're going to distribute the
gametes you need to be also familiar
with a monohybrid cross because we're
gonna build upon that with our tribrid
cross so if you want to do a try have it
cross with a punnett square it looks
like this complex mess here one try to
avoid that so our problem is a politic
plant as a genotype big a little a Big B
Big B Big C little C is crossed with
another planted genotype which is
homozygous recessive for a heterozygous
for B and heterozygous for C so the
question is what's the expected genotype
frequencies of the offspring or seeds
produced and hidden take a try hybrid
cross because there's three different
traits looking at here and again if you
do a Punnett square look like this very
complex mess here and your odds for
error are very hot and we want to try to
avoid that so step one here's our cross
one won't know what what seeds can be
produced we need to simplify the Tri
hybrid cross into three monohybrid
crosses hopefully not too bad the first
one is gonna involve the a allele second
for the B third for the C remember
punnett squares could also be used for
the monohybrid crosses but we're gonna
focus on the foil method it's a little
bit easier to follow we're looking at
producing the plant across in two plants
together so step two the expected
genotype frequencies now I colorized
them here
so if you're colorblind I'm sorry but
for a is going to represent green peas
are going to be in blue and C's will be
in red here so look at just the AIDS we
were just across those together we have
our heterozygous with our homozygous
recessive and a resulting Austrian to be
1/2 would be heterozygous half would be
almost I guess recessive not too bad
right - the same thing for the B's so if
you're looking at the B's now it's over
it's over here now we've got our almost
I guess dominant they're heterozygous we
cross these together in a monohybrid
cross way we would have half being the
homozygous dominant in half the indoors
itis C's get a little more complicated
with both heterozygous so if we look at
the C's now we cross two of our
heterozygous C's we have 1/4 being
homozygous dominant half being
heterozygous and 1/4 being almost I
guess recessive okay so now we do with
this let's go the next step the possible
do you know type combinations now
requires the pairing of genotypes from
all the monohybrid crosses previously
completed so I just took those symbol
boxes here or and progress those to the
next step these are the possible gametes
that could be in the egg or in this case
the pollen grain because we're looking
at crossing two plants together so let's
start the first one here we start with
are resulting from the a alleles half
would be heterozygous half would be
homozygous recessive now we've got to
include the B's so we bring in the B's
now half would be Big B Big B 1/2 would
be Big B little B same thing here
also needs to apply to the homozygous
recessive ones half would be homozygous
dominant half be heterozygous kind of
fawn along so far can flip back or pause
me at any time here now we're gonna go
and progress to the C's so here we're
including the C's now remember those had
three different ones and it was 1/4 or
1/2 1/4 and 1/4 being almost I guess
dominant half being heterozygous and 1/4
being almost I guess recessive now what
we need to do in order to get the C
genotype this reason wise is called the
for Klein method it's a for Klein we're
gonna go through
we're gonna just gonna work these right
across so 1/2 1/2 and 1/4 so 1/2 1/2 and
1/4 you'll notice 1/2 times 1/2 team2
quarters at 16th and we also carry this
genotype so here's our heterozygous for
a rose and right here homozygous
dominant here and almost I guess down in
4c here notice I did that with the same
thing as we carry our way through 1/2
1/2 and 1/2 1/2 1/2 1/2 min 1/8 and we
carry also those alleles with us here
also carry those through and we notice
we developed this nice seed genotype for
this tri hybrid cross it's very complex
but if you break it apart into the
individual steps you can follow back and
see where everything comes from
as a result getting back to the question
knowledge used to remember it what are
the expected genotype frequencies of the
offspring or seeds produced this would
be the expected genotypes now these are
fractions we can easily convert these to
percents 1/16 divide that one 5 by 16
times 100 if we add all of these
possible seed genotypes up we notice we
get a hundred percent which is what we
should get it's a way to check yourself
when you're looking at the end so go
through add up all the percentage if you
get to 100 percent you know you have all
the possible genotype combinations
hopefully this was a relatively easy way
to understand the fourth line method if
not I do have another video that is a
little bit more simplified it follows
the same steps and you're welcome to
check that out I'll put a link in the
description along with the citations for
all the pictures and information that I
used