welcome to this debaco university video
we're going to be looking at forming
female flowers on male
cannabis plants so how is this possible
i'm going to take you through some of
the steps i'll point you to our research
paper
and this can be very important for the
breeding process
so first off the research article here
you can research it on here this is a
copy of that
original research you can find some more
details here i want to provide a summary
here
for you but this is the source and where
some of the images and information were
gathered
so first off looking at self-fertilizing
so while self-fertilizing a plant can
help retain certain genetic traits
this can be quite a challenge with
dioecious plants
such as cannabis that produces
distinctive male and distinctive
female plants since each plant only
produces one type of flower this creates
an inherent problem
with self-fertilizing a lot easier with
some other plants
some growers may just decide to clone
the plant but if this does not allow for
the production of seeds which may be
desired
so we have to find a way to kind of be
able to self-fertilize
and this research does allow this as an
option
so first off we determine the male plant
primordia
so what does that kind of mean what's
that referring to and that's kind of
like the early
flower indication so that primordia
determine that section that's early
flower development and when that
initial formation does occur male
promoter can be identified by their
curved claw
shaped which was followed by the
deformation of round pointed
flower buds at the time of primordial
formation
the primordial were formed between the
stipule and the pale under the chute
tip as far as where to look as time goes
on leaves become smaller
decreased and more flowers were formed
so it's important note to make
this kind of gives you some visual
indication here of the female
and male plants kind of how they look at
that very early stage very similar and
how they become
differentiated now the plant treatments
here
in this trial for 7 to 14 days
after the primary formation the male
plants were treated with 500
milligrams per liter of ethron
to induce female flower formation
dilution rates are provided at the end
and how you go about
calculating those uh so just important
consideration there
male plants at the time of ephron
treatment so
here in figure a male plants at the time
of the ethanol treatment after male
primordial formation
we kind of can see that located right
down here at that stage of development
image b shows that seven days later what
the progression is
and then we see 14 days later again the
leaf and the male flowers
becoming much more distinctive two weeks
after
now female flowers on male plants you
know how does this go about what kind of
negatives do we see here well female
flowers and male plants have five
stigmas in contrast to the dual stigma
of
female plants that's an important note
there male planted
seeds were lighter and smaller than
those from female plants
we see that here here's the male plant
seeds there's those from the
corresponding female plants they are
smaller
and they are in lighter in coloration
and although germinates are
lower in these smaller seeds compared to
normal seeds from female plants as that
source of comparison
the seeds from the male germinated did
still germinate and grow into seedlings
so even though the percentage of
germination might be less
they still can produce plants and that's
very important again for that breeding
process
and here we see female flowers on a
female plant that's the normal to kind
of expect or control
here we see the male and female flowers
induced by the
etharon treatment on the male plants and
last we see male flowers at a male plant
which would be normal or control
so again this would be a normal female
plant a normal male plant
and then here we see the treatment and
how we get that slight you know
difference between the two because we're
inducing those female flowers to form
on a male plant now there's fm
treatments to conclusions here
well we're looking at the treatment to
male plant set
soon after the primordial formation will
be a good strategy and breeding program
to breed
inbred lines of hemp by self-fertilizing
it allows that plant to then produce
pollen
that otherwise we would need a separate
plant for so it's allowing that kind of
closed
loop within the genetic lines so a lot
of growers will hunt the whole okay
how do i go about calculating how to go
about treating this well here i'm going
to describe the process
so here we're calculating that 500
milligrams per liter
of the ethron here part one i'm going to
take you through a couple parts this is
an example product here
so note that the goal is 500 milligrams
per liter
which is a 0.05 percent solution
in this example here this product listed
is
21.7 percent um ethron
it's the same as saying uh 217
000 milligrams per liter so you want to
use this equation if you've done any
science particularly chemistry
you might be familiar with this equation
c1
v1 equals c2 v2 the c1 is the
concentration of the stock solution
v1 is the volume to be removed or
l-quaded out from the concentrated stock
solution
c2 is the final concentration of the
diluted solution
and v2 is the final volume of the
this is the volume that results after
v1 from the stock solution has been
diluted with
whatever you're diluting it with here
it's water to achieve the total diluted
volume of v2
an alternate and commonly used notation
for this equation is
m1 v1 equals m2 v2 where m is used in
place of c
so you might be familiar with it
presented that way let's run through an
example
so keep in mind that goal still is the
same 500 milligrams per liter because
that is what was used in the study
we have the same starting material here
that's 21.7 percent
so here i went through and show you the
calculations i'm using the c1 v1
equals c2 v2 and this would be c1 times
v1 equals c2 times v2
fill in our knowns we're creating a 500
milligram per liter
solution and we're just for the purposes
here i said we're going to make a total
liter one liter and we have the
concentration here of our product is
21.7 percent
and that would equal 217 000 milligrams
per liter
we simply go through we multiply these
two numbers here
uh we go through we uh would then divide
by here
and we get v1 would equal 0.002304
liters that would be the kind of
concentration or volume i should say
that we're using
of this particular concentration of
solution
so how does that look and taking it the
next step the final step here the part
three
note that that liter amount is the same
as
using our conversion factors two point
three zero four
milliliters take l and divide it by a
thousand milliliters take the liters
divided by a thousand get milliliters
so you want alcohol exactly 2.304
milliliters
of the stock solution and dilute it with
water so there's a final volume
of one liter typically what you'll do is
you're i'll quote that 2.304 milliliters
and then fill it up to a one
liter mark this will yield a one liter
of dilute solution with a final solute
concentration
of 500 milligrams per liter note the
following returns to the total solution
volume which is the combination volume
of the stock solution
and the volume of the water used for
dilution that's why typically you might
add some water and the 2.3 and fill it
up to exactly one liter
because that's your final solution there
see if you want to try this out yourself
this is an example
product here if you find another product
as a different percentage
you can simply follow these same steps
with a different percentage
and calculate the exact amount that you
need to aliquot
to create your one liter solution of
that would be still
500 milligrams per liter hopefully this
was helpful gives you a little bit of a
scientific background here
when we're looking at breeding cannabis
plants