okay as the title implies we're look at
the four theories that unify biology so
theory uncertainty in relation to
science the theory is a set of
hypotheses that have been tested many
times in that redirected this means it
indicates a high degree of certainty
however there's no absolute truth in
science
everything is open to more testing and
reinterpretation acceptance of a theory
is always provisional that to the
general public we use the word theory is
often used to mean what a scientist
would call a hypothesis a lack of
knowledge or a guess however two
scientists theory represents that of
which they are most certain explanations
support a wealth of evidence and
experimental data so when we use the
word theory the general public has kind
of a slate if the interpretation of it
then a scientist would so we want to be
careful when we look at some of these
theories such as cell theory and so on
and so forth that the general public
typically defines a theory a little bit
more like a scientist called a publicist
sometimes got a lack of knowledge or a
guess
the scientists though it's their most
certain explanations like 99% certainly
that's how it happens because of the
high degree of certainty related to all
the tests that have been done in no
rejections to those tests here's another
link to YouTube video if you want to
observe what's the difference between a
scientific law and a theory there so
limitations of science Sciences is
limited to organisms and processes that
can be observed and measured
there's also practical limits scientists
can prove options understanding say this
cannot be relied upon to solve all
problems for example what constitutes
acceptable risk cannot be answered by
science to get to that and we do sort of
experiments or evaluating certain things
so it's acceptable risk well sorry I
really can't answer that so getting to
the four theories the first one we're
gonna touch on here is gened theory the
information that determines what prison
is like is encoded in its genes genes
are located along DNA molecules
deoxyribonucleic acid
the entire set of DNA instructions that
specifies a cell is termed its genome so
while we pre-much accept this as fact
this actually is a explained through the
gene theory here again something that
sangd is there 99% choice is how it
works even though it's a theory again
not how the general public would define
theory the second theory is cell theory
all living organisms are composed of
cells cells are the basic units of life
all cells come from other cells so you
see here a cell's fighting I'm going
through all cells in this picture here
so initially we say all cells come from
other cells make sense right and see
cells dividing brings about the question
I was like where did the first cell come
from well for right now we're not gonna
get into that we're looking at the
general idea of cell theory moving on
the theory of heredity genes represent
traits of an organism and are inherited
as discrete units the chromosomal theory
of inheritance genes are physically
located on chromosomes we've done
punnett squares or looked at traits that
are inherited what's dominant what's
recessive this is all supported by the
theory of heredity it allows us to go
through and create these punnett squares
to determine the percentage or the
predicted percentage of offspring that
will be one certain genotype versus
another lastly the fourth theory that
unifies biology in this class the theory
of evolution all of the organs are
related to one another in the common
tree of life diversity of the living
world is a result of natural selection
we see that here with the different bird
beaks Darwin came up with all these
different birds at eat different food
items that weren't all competing may
have all stemmed from one common
ancestor they each developed certain
degrees of speciality so you didn't
catch all four of those theories here
they all are in one particular slide
here gene theory cell theory theory of
heredity and evolution and how they can
all tie it together in unified biology
in this class because this is a biology
class