ever wondered how frost impacts cannabis
plants
well in this debaco university video
we're going to go over
some of the cold tolerance related to
cannabis as well as i'll take you
outside
to a field after a cold early fall
night to see how cannabis plants in this
various area
were impacted by the cold temperatures
that occurred over that night
all right let's go through the frost
threat for cannabis plants
well first off how does cold
temperatures impact the plant
this is a question it gets asked a lot
in general a true frost is when
temperatures get below 32 degrees
fahrenheit or zero degrees celsius
but temperatures approaching these
values can cause damage
cannabinoids are not directly impacted
but the plant is
so cold temperatures can stunt the plant
and cause stresses which can limit
production so keep that in mind so are
you having a cold night are you having
cold nights with that s on the end one
cold night may
be enough to stunt the plant but
multiple nights of cold temperatures
not even below freezing was can cause
plants to completely shut down
this can be very hard to get the plants
to restart even if it gets warm for a
period of time
and we're not looking at the daytime
temperatures it's really those nighttime
temperatures 33 32 31 30 degrees
fahrenheit
this could be causing some issues there
for any outdoor cannabis
plants so sometimes this leads to what's
called a forest harvest
when cold temperatures set in this can
be a sign to the grower
that they need to harvest what they can
when they can
getting some harvest is better than
getting no harvest
because if we're going to lose the
plants too cold even though the plants
may not be 100
ready well it doesn't look good going
into the future so
take what you can get when you can get
it now let's go outside
take a look at some plants that
experienced a pretty chilly night
and see how they reacted so people will
often ask is cannabis frost tolerant
and some people will say yes some people
will say no
and while it may be frost tolerant it's
not very frost talent we see that
perfect example here where this
area outdoors did get hit with a frost
and we're seeing this cannabis plant the
effects
from that frost so did it kill the plant
no
but if we look very closely we because
it did induce a lot of stress we're
seeing a lot of coloration
changes kind of we're not getting that
growth anymore
we kind of really stop stunted a lot of
the growth factor stunted a lot of the
plant
so while it didn't kill it it definitely
set it back and it's
kind of damaged that structure in the
sense that if possible you want to do
your best to avoid frost
on your cannabis plants or if you get a
frost soon after
try to get through and harvest them
because you're not going to get much
after
and it's only going to cause a chance
that other bad things could happen
you could lose the entire plant so
here's an area that got hit with some
recent frost this is an outdoor grow as
you can obviously tell and you're
noticing plants respond in different
ways to the frost
some get definitely this more yellow
coloration to the leaves
some get more of that purple coloration
as anthocyanins to develop
but overall if you just look down this
little row here
we can see that no matter how the plants
respond to the frost
either way was not very good it's not
going to boast well
for future improvement on harvest
so cannabis plants definitely can
tolerate some frost
but not really something you want to
expose them to as we can see here
where at least these cultivars
definitely have
kind of reached their peak and should be
harvested soon
now that we're not going to get too much
more progression on their growth
there's only a chance that other
negative factors could occur
more frost other damage so it'd be best
to get these out of the field
now here we're talking about frost
damage and how that affects plants
differently this is another plant
outside
a little closer to a tree line as you
can see right behind me so not
necessarily hit quite as hard with the
frost as some
others maybe that are in fully exposed
areas but we can still see
definitely a little bit of a stress
there a little bit of a hit to the
overall
kind of plant performance there not what
it could have been
but this was a little further along so
hopefully
not as great a percentage reduction but
still not reaching the maximum that
could have been
that's just a factor of growing outside
some of the challenges associated with
that
where you don't have control over all
these different conditions
now the advantage is we have a lot less
up front cost so you kind of got to
balance that out
as far as maybe not getting the maximum
amount of yield here being grown
outside but also not having the all the
inputs necessarily
that would be associated with an indoor
grow