here we're gonna be learning a little
bit more about fungus gnats me see it
zoomed in picture of one here Jesus is
about three millimeters long just to
give you an idea of the size of these
fungus gnats so often discovered in
plants or Moop that jostle effect you
can kind of see them moving about at
that point how the larvae is about two
to four millimeters long and half
translucent bodies and blackheads you
see the image here they also have a poor
ability to fly even though they do have
some wings portably the fly meaning they
can't fly very long distances where to
look which is key for the identification
for these is inspecting the roots for
dark spots we can see the evidence of
one right here and two here and one guy
over in this area and a bunch kind of
located here they're commonly found in
the growing media since they infest
infest plant roots close to the soil
surface so they don't dig down very far
they are close to that surface area and
that's important we're looking to try to
find these and identify if you do have
these in your container or near your
plants the coal here to prevent them is
to keep the surface as dry as you can
help reduce the pressure on the plant
now this can be after you plant you
could top dress with like perlite sand
or rice hulls these are all ways to kind
of keep that surface very dry which can
really reduce and prevent the fungus
gnats from getting established you can
increase with numbers when plants are
stressed by nutrients or excessive
irrigation so by over watering or kind
of over stressing the plants can meet
other ways you can encourage fungus
gnats trigger that excessive irrigation
keeping that soil surface wet will only
hurt your plants by both suffocating the
roots but also potentially increasing
these on this gnats population bogus
gnats can also live on green algae that
may be growing in media or containers so
important to keep that clean for a
variety of reasons avoid excessive water
in the media in the environment as this
only encourages a fungus gnat
development how to control them well
there's predatory mites it can be an
option some feed on both the eggs in the
larvae which is a great one to select
adults do not feed on the plant and
females can live to 200 eggs and the
seven to ten days BTR Bacillus
thuringiensis can be applied to the
media surface and it's effective against
the larva as we can see here this is a
leaf sample here these are peanut leaves
which is shows you the example of the
effectiveness of bt this is a normal
peanut leaf this is when it's been
treated bt and you can see the much
reduced feeding activity and the ones
truth bt who knows that if not you can
see the mouth parts here for the fungus
gnats indicating there can be pretty
aggressive feeders and really be very
destructive to your plants