okay I'm going to go over a few Syrian
wealth and what we see on the title
slide here is an image of what true
serum looks like under the microscope
and this would be a pretty high degree
of infection and hopefully many of the
plants you grow no pathologist will see
this in any samples you bring them now
the identification of who Syria it's a
soil based on that second texture roots
it can happen to various degrees of
severity so it's not just on
one-size-fits-all looking here at very
severe cases they're very mild cases so
again this can have this variance makes
it a little hard to identify times where
to look where the plant will will as a
result of the root rot leaves will
quickly turn from a yellow to a brown
and also have a curl to them when this
is known as it advised to cut into the
stem inspector vascular tissue for
browning upon inspection of the roots
there may be a red orange coloration
notice once the media is removed so we
can see two plants here's is showing
that vascular system you can see the
upper portions don't look quite as bad
but especially down towards that soil
line we see that more tannish yellowish
temperature i tannish orange coloration
that's occurring it can progress to kind
of this green coloration and look almost
normal to top but again that vascular
system is infected here with Dew Syria
how to prevent it will avoid reusing
media's this can increase the odds of
accumulating Fusarium in infecting
subsequent plantings this is especially
true for outdoor operations that do not
rotate plants in the soil that's grown
in as part of a quality crop rotation
using Kerry vetches we see image in this
image here to aid an organic matter in
nitrogen fixation it's a great cover
crop as this can also nettle an often
those benefits but also potentially
reduce Fusarium well been shown in areas
of outdoor operations that grow
watermelon this hairy vetch great
organic matter of supplement great
nitrogen but in also Fusarium reduction
in outdoor soil for control so once
notice the area should be planned to be
rotated to reduce the chance of building
up a serum in the soil just because you
see a kind of mild infection one year
don't think that's going to go away the
next way it's only going to get worse
so this is be a clean plan so you're
starting to see infections early on you
don't want to plant repeatedly
applications in there to get to more
severe cases down here if you do see
this reducing nitrogen in season you do
not over water and can help slow the
progression as fund the states only
offer a reduction in spreading and are
not a cure to measure so it's important
as a grower to recognize this early do
what you can to get by with the closing
out of that season and to know you need
to rotate out for the volunteer two or
even three or greater if that is
possible to help reduce the chance of
getting to cerium well in future
plantings