okay here I'm gonna explain what fuzzy
logic is now fuzzy logic if you're
looking at carbon dioxide controllers
often it's listed your fuzzy logic mode
physiologic active and what does that
exactly mean now if you're finding
controllers that do have this an option
those tend to be the better controllers
and you'll understand why that is a
little bit behind the technology of
fuzzy logic
well first off standard controllers so a
standard co2 controller are either on or
off based on preset co2 levels so it's
kind of like flipping a light switch on
or off these do not allow enough time
for carbon oxide to mix with the air
standard logic co2 controllers are used
for co2 generators but are not efficient
to be used with bottle based systems so
this on and off the lights are on or off
with fuzzy logic though consider it to
be a light on a dimmer switch we're
having this variability or this banding
that can occur so this controller would
suppose a lot if they allow for that
precise control again he's heard of our
light example here we can those
precisely dialed in what that light
intensity should be it makes predictions
based on past events to create an
environment that hovers around the
target co2 level without large degrees
of variation that includes large degrees
of overshooting or a large degrees under
shooting the other thing important
remember that fuzzy logic cannot be used
with su 2 generators only for bottle-fed
systems so when you're looking at a
controller might say here says true
fuzzy logic that can be something
preferable to look at and consider when
purchasing the controller for your own
operation so fuzzy logic relate to
temperature because that has many
applications essentially it can allow
for variable conditions that can be a
mix of different situations rather than
simply being on or off see the example
here with temperature instead of just
having hot or cold options there can be
a mix to get this warm to generate a
warm water
combination here so again fuzzy logic
instead of being on or off hot or cold
it allows that kind of that mixing to
occur here to have that kind of warm
temperature possibility the fuzzy logic
concept can be compared also to a good
driver so good drive approaches a red
light will apply the brakes
slow down before getting to the
intersection physiologic uses the same
idea to bring the co2 levels up to the
desired setting without going over the
set if we're looking at a standard
controller and the driver example here
the brakes would either be fully on or
fully off be kind of one option or the
other that fuzzy logic allows for that
greater gradual kind of control over the
situation here versus is on or off
that's it helps make them more efficient
these micro processors so within this
unit is a microprocessor processor that
can apply calculations to the injection
schedule to maintain co2 levels
efficiently standard logic controllers
will not make these calculations and
they'll continue to inject more and more
co2 until the room reaches the setpoint
and then turn them off but at that point
the air wasn't mixed properly that
caused an overshoot and then it can drop
down to a certain level and keep
injecting keep injecting that can cause
some issues having this microprocessor
this applying calculations ensures that
while they might be more expensive
initially it can help ensure that the
co2 that is being added to the the grow
room is added an efficient manner based
on calculations of the conditions over
time and this is why they're advised to
be used for growers to find a controller
if you're adding co2 from a bottle to
get the ones that have the fuzzy logic
mode as an option