here we're gonna focus on the gas
exchange that occurs in plants so well
there's a bunch of other things going on
here or specifically looking at the
carbon dioxide in the oxygen in this
case realize that those are used as part
of different reactions that are going on
within the plant there's water and
there's all these other kind of
molecules that are being either produced
or consumed but here we're focusing
simply on the exchange of carbon dioxide
and oxygen in plants so plants need to
breathe just like we do however unlike
us plants need to consume carbon dioxide
and they exhale oxygen they're taking in
carbon dioxide from the air and they're
releasing oxygen Wiis through our
breathing we do the opposite we're
consuming oxygen in producing carbon
dioxide now the importance of the carbon
cycle so we look up here seeing a little
bit of our kind of carbon dioxide within
a forest system but the same is true for
all plants the carbon dioxide
abbreviated co2 is taken in from the air
that's the clear here that is the carbon
dioxide taken from the air and is
assembled into sugar through the process
of photosynthesis which you see
occurring here we're taking in these
sun's light energy burning of plants you
see down here with these couple reds pop
up here and here well release carbon
oxide back into the atmosphere so the
yellow here is the sunlight the red
appears here here and here is fire or
respiration that's occurring this is the
carbon dioxide molecules the clear ones
green is just carbon which is stored in
the chunk of trees or plants and blue is
water again those are all coming
together right here for this
photosynthetic process now plants
regulate Carmex in water via the stomata
stomata are pores they're not holes in
leaves that allow the plant to take in
carbon dioxide which might say the
reports in that holes is there able to
be regulated it's just an opening and
closing right here so what they look
like on the leaf surface if you look
straight you kind of scan that leaf
surface with a microscope this is what
you may say it's a greater concentration
on the undersides of leaves in most
plants except not in lily pads because
of the water there so typically on the
underside of leaves its reopen the
stomata this is important because when
we're foliar spraying our plants and
looking to get nutrients and other
products inside the leaf these stomata
is one way where we can kind of
easily get something into the interior
portions of the leaf so plants also
regulate connects it in water via these
stomata however when the stomata are
open they let co2 in which is great but
at the same time they're also losing
water so they're in a continual balance
here taking in carbon dioxide and losing
that precious water they absorb through
the roots our plants are in this battle
of trying to regulate stomata to take in
carbon dioxide so they can boost the
sugars that they need but not lose too
much water and that's why I have the
seesaw here to kind of show that balance
of taking in one thing but losing
another lastly here of roots the roots
of the plant we can't figure out those
in gas exchange they respire just like
us so as a result they're consuming
oxygen and releasing carbon dioxide it's
important that roots have oxygen present
along with sufficient water and
nutrients this is why it is possible to
drown plants and by adding too much
water so as we just talked about these
roots taking in oxygen and also sugars
they will be releasing carbon oxide and
water in the stomata and the plant is
trying to take in corrected from the air
through the process of photosynthesis so
keep in mind we have to look at the what
the leaves are doing in the chloroplasts
and also what the roots are doing
because they're kind of both complete
this continual cycle here of gas
exchange in plants