okay here I'll get the gastrointestinal
often abbreviated GI tract also known as
the digestive tract and when we're
talking about the GI tract or the gastro
intestinal tract looking at basically a
tube and that tube has a lot of layers
to it you'd see a lot of veins and
arteries and a lot of layers to it so
we're gonna look at some of what occurs
in this digestive tract so start with
the basic overview of the GI tract I
could see our necessary organs and
basically what each is contributing to
the process of digestion begins in the
mouth works its way down through the
entire GI tract ultimately exiting out
the anus at the very end now some very
important steps that do occur here
you're welcome to pause this video and
take a look at some of the summaries of
the particular points of the digestive
tract continuing on we have actions of
the GI tract so what's in general
occurring we just saw they are what's
occurring at very specific locations but
in general what's occurring well first
off we have the ingestion process this
is occurs when materials entering the
mouth here we see the horse eating the
grass this is the ingestion part you
have to have it first enter that GI
tract then there's a mechanical
processing this is the crushing tearing
we see here with the giraffe and is
basically making materials a little
smaller and easier to move throughout
the the GI tract then we move on to the
actual digestion process this is the
breakdown of food into small organic
components for absorption keep in mind I
Jessen is not the same of absorption
we're just having this initial kind of
breaking apart and this typically occurs
in the stomach and also the intestines
moving on we have a secretions which are
release of water acids buffers enzymes
themselves in the epithelium of the GI
tract in glandular organs what does that
mean well in order for this process of
digestion to occur enormous breakdown to
occur enzymes have to be release to be
secreted at certain points based on the
pH of different points of our GI tract
that will determine what enzymes are
released where then we have absorption
this is movement of organic substances
electrolytes
water across the digestive epithelium
because if the nutrients only stayed in
our digestive system and didn't get to
our actual blood system and into our
body that would be the point so we need
to have that very important absorption
phase and lastly remove a little waste
we have the execution phase and that's
where we're just removing bodily fluids
now as general summary of kind of our
digestive system it is a tube within a
tube you're basically one long tube with
openings at both ends let me say sorry
because that's basically all it is is
there's a distinctive path that it takes
you could see there's different things
that happen to it of course along that
path but simply it enters one point
mechanical and chemical processes occur
throughout and it exits out the other
end so your tube within a tube the
histology structure of the GI tract you
can see here a little bit more detail a
zoom in of the different layers involved
and how there's this intense network of
our RVs and our veins and our different
types of tissues allowing food to easily
pass through and also for not only the
digestive process to occur but also that
very important absorption process that
digestion its water absorption also as
we see the same image again here cells
cannot actively absorb or secrete water
all movement of water across the lining
of the digestive tech involves down or
up osmotic gradients remember as Moses
is simply that movement of water and
that is why the body is so important
regulating different ion concentrations
to determine whether water will move
into or away from certain areas and we
can see here some of the secretions that
are occurring in the estimated volume of
that water with the digestive endocrine
system there's hormones
cholecystokinin play important roles in
the digestive process you can see all of
these many different hormones and
released at different points because
there's also different pH in different
breakdowns occurring at different parts
of the digestive system hormones will
play vital roles and several bodily
functions and processes as do certain
and
lastly we have the microbial communities
in physiological gradients along the
mammalian GI tract you could see here in
the stomach to tottenham jejunum ileum
and colon rectum what our microbe load
is this is in scientific notation some
of the actual bacteria that are living
in different regions and also the oxygen
concentration and pH so keep in mind out
of the stomach the pH is very low or a
minimum and as we work our way through
the pH will actually increase or raise
ultimately the neutral I'm actually
slightly basic I'll bile acids will
decrease as we work our way through so
on and so forth
so it just gives you that idea well
there's just one long tube there are
very certain specific and certain
processes occurring at different regions
to maximize the digestive and also the
absorption process for the building