here i want to attempt to simplify some
of the complexities
associated with gel electrophoresis and
explain them to you
this is the basic equipment and setup
and this is a typical end result that
you'll see
but how do we go from here to here well
stay tuned
well we have dna fragments migrate
through a gel
so we are going through a gel and this
gel is going to allow portions or pieces
of dna to be able to move
through it now the gel electrophoresis
is a procedure that separates out these
molecules
based on the rate of movement through
the gel and is influenced by an
electrical field
keep in mind that dna does have a
negative charge to its backbone
allowing this positive negative charge
to be able to move the fragments
gel electrophoresis is a widely used
technique
for analysis of nucleic acids as well as
proteins let me give you just a general
breakdown that these
bp stands for base pairs so a thousand
base pairs versus only 100
the smaller the base pairs the smaller
the molecular size
the greater the distance that they it
can move or travel
and that's going to be a consistency
with the gel electrophoresis process
so this gel electrophoresis will require
an agarose
gel well agarose gel with electro
freezes between the use in preparation
for dna analysis
if you look at it under a skinning
electron microscope kind of looks like
this
think of it as like a net or a bunch of
little pores through here
it's a polymerase agarose it's porous
allowing for the movement of dna
this is why the larger fragments kind of
get caught up in this net
the smaller fragments are able to move
through it much easier
now it's a linear primal extracted from
seaweed specifically
and while you may think it's got a
seaweed color it actually ends up being
this white
kind of thin a small and fine powder
dna is negatively charged as i mentioned
so when placed in the electrical field
dna will migrate towards the positive
pole
or the called the anode and agarose gel
is used to slow the movement of dna and
is separated by its size
with the smaller fragments moving
further than the larger one so here
we're looking at how fast will the dna
migrate well depends on the size of the
dna
small dna will move faster than large
dna and electrophase it separates dna
corona size so here are the wells
this is where we initially place the dna
and we fill those up
with our dna which contains small and
large fragments
we turn the power on keep in mind the
positive of on the far end of the gel
and the negative over here
dna with its negative charge will get
pulled towards the positive end and
depending on size will separate
here we see an example of the small bits
of dna in smaller sections
smaller base pairs of dna traveling
further than the larger base pairs
within aggression linear dna migrates
inversely proportional to the log base
10 of their molecular weight
what does that simply mean smaller
fragments move further than larger ones
so if you want to make an agarose gel
they said the aggress is this white
powder
it's prepared by combining agarose
powder and a buffer solution
and it's going to have to be heated up
to the point of boiling so you also need
a flask for boiling
the electrophoresis equipment
specifically is going to
require a casting tray so you want to
seal the edges of the casting tray
put in the combs you see here that's
going to be placed in on a level surface
and none of the combs should be touching
the surface of the casting tray
what these combs are going to do is
create little wells that you're going to
put the
dna in now to give you just an idea
these are very small
so what makes this such an efficient
operation is it can occur on a tabletop
doesn't need a large area
to occur it's a power supply it's a gel
tank a casting tray
some power and some combs here now when
you mix the agarose
with the buffer we need to boil it so
when we're looking at our agarose and
our buffer solution we want to combine
the agarose powder in buffer solution
use the flask that is several times
larger than the volume of the buffer
because we'll be heating it
aggress is inside at room temperature so
when you first add it you're going to
get this kind of like immediate
separation
then the aggro solution is boiled until
it's clear you want to gently swirl the
solution periodically when heating
to allow all the grains of agarose to
dissolve well in it
be careful when boiling the aggro
solution may become superheated and may
boil violently
if been heated for too long for example
in a microwave oven
so you want to be very careful with that
boiling process keep it controlled
then once boiled you want to get some
mitts that actually have some insulation
to them because you're going to be
pouring this
very hot liquid i want the aggression to
cool slightly but not too much otherwise
it will solidify in the flask
when i say cool it's about 60 degrees
celsius and then carefully pour the
melted aggro solution into the casting
tray
to avoid air bubbles each of the gel
combs should be submerged
in the melted agarose solution as we see
here when cooled the
agarose polymerizes forming a flexible
gel should appear lighter in color
when completely cooled and this will
take about half an hour to 45
minutes to occur then you want to
carefully remove the tape on the sides
and the combs and you have a prepared
gel
then you're going to place the gel in
the electrophoresis chamber
now the advantage of this you can make
the gel the day before a couple days
before and hold on to it
before you're able to run it this is one
advantage that maybe you go through a
day of gel making
and you go through a day of kind of
running through the analysis portion
you want to add this to the chamber and
you might add enough
buffer to cover the gel to a depth of at
least one millimeter
make sure the well is filled with the
buffer solution
and keep in mind that dna is going to
migrate this way because here's our
positive anode
and here's our negative cathode and you
can see our buffer solution in
a series of wells sample preparation in
gel loading
you want a six time loading buffer it
can have this really dark kind of blue
color
you can use glycerol for weight that you
can use uh
bromophile blue for color and you can
mix those two
you want to mix the samples of dna with
the six eggs sample loading buffer
with tracking dye this allows the
samples to be seen when loading into the
gel makes it a lot easier
and increases the density of the samples
causing them to sink into the gel wells
the last thing you want to do is go
through and load those gel wells and
have everything kind of flow
and go into the buffer solution you want
to stay in that well region
so because you want to push it or pull
it through that
gel to allow that separation to occur
then with good pipetting skills you want
to carefully place the pipette over the
well
gently expel the sample the sample
should sink into the well be careful not
to puncture the gel with the pipette tip
so it requires a very
steady hand then we're actually running
the gel
i'm going to place the cover over the
electricity's chamber collect the
electrical leads connect the electrical
leads to the power supply
be sure the leads are attached correctly
with the positive and negatives being in
the right area
because dna will migrate towards the red
or the anode and the positive in this
case
when the powder when the power is turned
on bubbles should form in the electrodes
the electropieces chamber indicating
that you do have a flow of electrical
current
and just be mindful that that is
electrical hazards so
you want to be mindful when that power
is on
warning the gel when it's in progress
after the current is applied make sure
the gel is running in the correct
direction
double triple check this otherwise you
might lose your entire experiment
bromenthile blue will run in the same
direction as a dna and it gives you an
idea of here's the wells
you can see that it is moving towards
the anode it is moving through the gel
there
so this is hooked up correctly dna
ladder is also recommended to be added
an inclusion of a dna
ladder which is basically just sections
of known sizes
it's called the ladder because it kind
of looks like this nice little rungs of
a ladder
it makes it easy to determine the sizes
of unknown dna fragments
so this is a known defined inclusion
of different base pairs allows you to
compare that to your own sample
note blonde blue migrates to
approximately the rate at about 300 base
pairs of dna molecule
so if you see a little darker band in
that area it could simply be the
bromentile blue
when you're staining the gel gonna place
it down a staining tray containing warm
diluted stain
allow the gel to stain for about 20 to
30 minutes follow the protocol
suggested to remove excess stain allow
the gel to destain in water for a little
bit
replace the water several times for an
efficient d stain so you're getting
a well-defined band region you have many
options when you're looking at gel
staining
ethidium bromide is one that's probably
used quite extensively
because it does bind very efficiently to
the dna and it fluoresces under uv light
however be mindful and caution is that
glove should be worn at all times when
hailing this
because it is a powerful mutagen it will
bind to the dna in the gel
and also the dna in your hands and your
own body so it can be
toxic it can potentially be a carcinogen
so again be mindful when handling
burlington blue always always wear
gloves as a result there's some safer
alternatives like methyl blue or bio-rad
makes when rewards
make some uh the advantages that these
are inexpensive they're
a lot less toxic they don't require uv
light source
no hazardous waste disposal but they're
not used in some cases because they can
be less sensitive
more dna is needed on the gel and longer
staining and destaining times
so again the safer alternatives do have
some advantages but ethidium bromide
when used on those kind of trace samples
just be mindful as a handler of that
material
here's a gel with athenian bromide stain
we see it here
placed on a uv light trans luminor the
environment requires ultraviolet light
to be visualized so right now with the
uv light off you really can't see
anything
but this would be the surface it would
be prepared on
then we turn the uv light on you can see
here should be wearing protective
glasses if you are viewing it
you can start to see some banding
developed here and you can take a good
image
and then be able to use that for
comparisons
visualizing dna with that athenian
bromine is what a kind of picture would
look like
here are the wells here the ladders and
here's the pcr product it's plumless
chain product
samples 1 4 6 and 7 were positive
for 500 base pair dna fragments and we
could see that this
right here so again gives you this kind
of that idea of being able to separate
dna
determine if a certain fragment or base
pair length is present
here's the visualizing the dna with the
quick view stain
here we see the same wells you see in
the ladder we see the same pcr product
we see here 1 6 7 10 and 12 are positive
for 500 base pair of fragments
this is not a thin bromide in this case
there was sufficient amounts of dna the
sensitivity wasn't necessarily required
so we could use one of those safer
alternative staining products
and here you can see compared to the
gold standard of ethydium bromide
you'd see a very similar result