okay here we look at the process of gel
electrophoresis this takes the DNA
fragments that are multiplied through
the process of PCR and I have another
video on that and separating them
through literally a gel-like substance
and this is separating out those DNA
fragments based on their relative size
to one another so where this may be used
we can typically see this being used
potentially for paternity tests forensic
science things like that or how they
determined who the father is this
process could be used for this purpose
what the basic setup looks like in the
lab is a gel and a power source because
we're using electricity to separate out
the DNA we need a power source so here's
the power source DNA actually has a
negative charge on its backbone this
allows us to have a positive charge
located here and that will actually pull
the DNA down through the gel we notice
here the larger fragments kind of stay
closer to where we initially put the
well here for our DNA and then the
smaller fragments are actually traveling
further through the gel material and
getting closer to that positive charge
the gel electrophoresis again looking at
our molecular size which BP stands for
base pairs and we could see here the
distance migrated the greater the
distance migrated the smaller the
molecular size and we see that evident
here here's our marker which is just an
area where we have known fragments of
DNA and we're seeing it separated out
here keeping in mind those smaller base
pairs only 100 base pairs are going
further than those at 902 or a thousand
DNA is cut with restriction enzymes so I
have a video also on restriction enzymes
that you may want to take a look at it's
cutting the DNA at very specific
sequences this has many applications
such as forensics paternity testing
medical diagnosis evolutionary
relationships and many more so comparing
the cut-up DNA how are the fragments
compared how the fragment separated
they're actually
based on their size and their base pair
of lengths is this specific how are
looking at size run through a gel
substance and you can see here is
literally gel like and it looks like
initially when we look the straight
lines it looks like they all ran into
the same spot well actually that is just
the dye and that was what called the gel
front that is just showing you basically
the furthest that the dye has moved
through that gel these are just an idea
where the fragments are moving but there
will be little lines here and we have
ways of marking them in indicating where
those bands may be located so I
mentioned that DNA had a negative charge
and it does that negative charge comes
from the oxygen which is on our
phosphorous backbone here so nothing to
do with the nucleotide bases nothing to
do with the sugar backbone and
particularly the oxygens on the
phosphate backbone that's what's causing
the negative charge we notice here this
is a gel run on its side and we have our
positive charge here and our negative
charge down here so when we add our
solution of different DNA fragments we
add them to the well and we can see that
we can see that here and then the larger
ones are not able to run as far they're
bigger and they kind of get caught up in
this gel then smaller ones are able to
run further or closer to this positive
charge so the smaller they are the
further down the gels are going to run
and it's syndicate swimming through gel
the bigger ones are going to have a
harder time and they're not going to
move quite as far how this looks how we
compare these fragments well I mentioned
this DNA ladder the smaller piece is
moving further larger pieces we've been
slower and lag behind the DNA ladders
look is loaded into one of the gels what
that ladder is is there's an image of it
here it has known DNA base pair links so
we know what bands it's going to produce
this allows us to compare our unknown or
even our known segment segments to
figure out how many base pairs long they
are the same process here they fill the
well up the ladder this relevance will
enter the end
and the larger ones will run more
towards the beginning here this is
evident here we have a thousand base
pairs here's 500 base pairs and here's
100 base pairs when we're loading that
actual gel they're actually depressions
in there we're learning that mixture of
DNA be sure to load these slowly so no
sample is lost it's a very small area
you want to make sure that we fill that
with our sample and shows it kind of on
this side here should filling up that
sample on the side I'm careful not to
lose any and see another well right here
otherwise that's going to cause a
reduction in the amount of sample that
couldn't run through that gel the basic
process it can be vertical or horizontal
those gels taking our sample here's
contains our DNA we take our micro
pipettor we're adding it to the wells we
add a charge to it and then that's
simply over time allowing it to separate
out that's important do not run it too
long as far as time goes because
literally all of your samples will run
out of the gel you want to run it so
they all separate but so they don't
leave the gel you want to keep them in
the gel so you're able to compare them
running into all the DNA's cut with
restriction enzymes so that's what's
giving the different fragments or
different sizes to stay in the DNA with
atheneum bromide it binds the DNA and
it's fluorescent under UV light
and so causes it to glow the Athenian
bromide remember it binds with DNA and
cause mutations so that's why you always
want to be wearing gloves it was working
with Athena bromide but what makes it
really neat is that it causes DNA to
glow under UV light and it causes these
nice little bright bars or lines this is
indicating these size and the relative
position of those DNA fragments again
the smaller ones will move further down
this small smaller ones will move
further the larger ones will stay closer
to the actual well I'm using a lab take
extreme caution diffusing this because
it is it does mutate your DNA we can
take a picture this was very special
cameras and be able to tell us a little
bit about the DNA and if we're comparing
samples we can develop a DNA fingerprint
which is another video