all right welcome to this debaco
university video we'll be covering
general design features for cannabis
production room
[Music]
let's get into some of the design
features regarding a cannabis production
room
so generally environment factors to
consider just remember that a large room
does not need anything different than a
small room
but some environmental aspects can be
harder to achieve as the grow space gets
larger basic items to consider which
will be covered here
are lights temperature water air
circulation
plant density as well as ceiling height
so let's get into some of the specifics
here starting with
lights so you want to know what your
electrical circuit can handle
and this may determine the total plants
you can grow or what you need to upgrade
to what kind of level you need to
upgrade to
now the type and wattage of lights you
plan on using will impact the total
coverage
area per light in addition you want to
take into consideration other factors
such as hvac systems fans
and other things that may need power but
lights tends to require the most
wattage so definitely something to
consider there in addition to our lights
we also have the temperature to regulate
so
heating and or cooling at larger space
can be a challenge
remember the regulation of temperature
needs to take into consideration all
plant supporting equipment
they just talked about here the lights
we could also be looking at
fans and anything else that you might
have running
in the production area grow space
then there is water so will you be using
stored water or using it directly out of
a source
if you're using stored water can the
floor support the weight of a water tank
you plan on using
remember one gallon of water weighs
about 8.33 pounds
so a 250 gallon water tank will weigh 2
082 and a half
pounds does your water source supply the
volume and pressure you need
and to answer that question you need to
know what chosen irrigation system or
fertilization system you're using
to make sure that is the case also the
very important air circulation so as a
single room increases in square feet
moving air can be a continual challenge
fans on the walls are common solution
but more air movement may be
necessary so this could mean overhead
fans and our fans
within the grow space might be needed so
you can see here there's some on the
walls
but there's also some down here on the
floor
we also get to plant talking about plant
density so
total plants per square foot is
partially dependent on the pruning
methane
but in general a full-size plant you
want to plan for having one plant per
five square feet or two plants for every
square meter just to give you a general
idea
of how many your plant density should be
and lastly ceiling height so it's
important factor to consider the height
of the ceiling can impact the amount of
air circulation
and spacing of plants and lights higher
ceilings offer more flexibility for the
growing space
but also make it more costly to enrich
with carbon dioxide
so again taking into considering these
pros and cons
with your grow space and definitely have
a plan
for each of these particular
environmental factors mentioned here