alright here I'm going to go over some
of the details regarding gene
architecture
what's gene what's it comprised of how
is it organized
what are components to a gene to help
cells function so let's get into it here
so first off the obvious question is
just you know what is a gene how do we
define a gene well
a gene is kind of the work of some
scientists that basically determined
that genes reside in chromosomes so
chromosomes contain proteins known as
histones in DNA so within the chromosome
here little X you have that condensed
form of DNA so here's again here's our
DNA and these little green circles are
histones so the question was what is the
hereditary material is it the protein or
is it the DNA here so when we're looking
specifically at those histones that
protein structure that helps organize
the DNA those systems are actually very
important so while the other chromosome
we have our chromatin we have our DNA
and then we have those histones well
think of this if we have this very long
piece of string it's very easy for it to
get tangled there for histones our
little protein structures that allow
that DNA to kind of like wrap around to
help keep it organized we see a kind of
wrapping around here it's kind of calls
like balls on a chain kind of all kind
of a way to nicely condense the DNA
instead of just taking a large piece of
string there's kind of cream and all
together to kind of all rats nests there
this is a very organized way to be able
to keep that DNA together organized and
condensed for the process of cell
division this one's actually have other
purposes here but here we're just
looking at the fact that they organize
in DNA now within those systems this
gives you another kind of image or
picture of how it looks here's our
chromosome here's our within our nucleus
here's our DNA and then here's our
histones these little blue spheres here
now when it says silent and active the
sound is kind of like taking all those
fears and kind of condensing them and
keeping them tightly packed very hard
for other mechanisms to get in there
kind of Express those genes here the
active form we see it more spaced out
greater space that's allowing for these
genes to be active or turned on so these
histones help that organization of that
DNA into potentially an active or a
silent or inactive form and we're
looking at the architecture of a gene in
general you know how do they kind of
look well we have that DNA which is very
important and we're speaking here in
eukaryotes genes are basically
fragmented and they're composed of two
components exons and introns I don't
know why they named them this way but
the exons are sequences that code for
amino acids in the introns don't have
any coding regions so if you look at our
DNA here and then we're going to RNA in
our mRNA ultimately want to take that
full-length DNA composed of exons and
introns now only the exons are kept and
we see that in our final messenger RNA
here so exons a lot of people think oh
they exit now exons are kept together
they are the coding regions it is the
introns that don't the introns are
spliced out so we could see here's our
total DNA sequence here's our RNA and
our messenger RNA will only be composed
of those exons part of the reason is
this if there's a mutation or
a nucleotide base that's an error
hopefully it falls in one of the intron
areas it's spliced out and doesn't have
to worry this way the cells that have to
make necessarily every single nucleotide
pairing and match up be absolutely
critical otherwise one little flip would
cause a major mutation here there are
some basically non-coding regions as
architecture of the gene again speaking
for eukaryotic cells they transcribe the
entire gene producing a primary RNA
transcript this transcript is ends
heavily processed to produce mature
messenger RNA transcript the mRNA leaves
a nucleus for the cytoplasm so what does
this mean our primary RNA transcript has
the exons in the introns there's an RNA
processing that occurs and that will
basically splice out those introns and
only the exons will be left into that
final messenger
our announcer then sent out to the cell
there's a five prime cap in a poly a
tail also added after it's spliced as
well so if we're looking here we want to
notice the locations of everything so we
have up here the gene contains both
exons and introns that's the full DNA
now the RNA is processed to remove the
introns that final process located over
here is the messenger RNA that messenger
RNA will only contain the exons and this
mature messenger RNA M stands for
messenger so mature messenger RNA mature
mRNA travels to the cytoplasm what's
responsible for the synthesizing of
important proteins for the body now what
does this look like while alternating
splicing here we have this kind of
combination produces three different
proteins at the same section of DNA
notice the alteration of the order of
the exons so the exons are the coding
regions well in this case we have five
exons here we have the RNA with the five
exons and also the introns
single-stranded versus double-stranded
we have alternate splicing what does
this mean well love these five exons in
this first protein protein a we have
them in exon order one two three four
five makes sense is how its presented
however alternate splicing was if we
take those same exons and we mix the
order up in this case we have only exons
one two four and five we're missing
number three that's going to create a
different protein here we have one two
three and five we took number four out
and you can see a different protein this
is the way that I'm cells or DNA can
conserve the amount of new DNA sequences
just simply mixing the order up will
change the proteins and vastly change
the function now processing you carry
mRNA through RNA splicing was this occur
well different combinations of exons can
generate different polypeptides via
alternate splicing we just saw that in a
previous slide there where we have our
pre messenger RNA and through different
splicing and different combinations of
those exons if an order all those exons
will create different end products in
this case polypeptides known as
genes that the promoter region in a DNA
sequence it's the region of DNA that
initiates the transcription of a gene
the promoter is kind of like the on or
off switch to a light it's located
towards a five-prime end and it will
initiate or allow that kind of coding
region to then be basically expressed or
transit into our RNA sequence here now
the architecture of a gene so kind of
title here well it's a segment of DNA
located on the chromosome that contains
instructions for protein production so
just looking at chromosome from parent
one and parent two well there'll be a
certain locus a certain region for
height for example in this case we're
looking at peas looking at Gregor Mendel
if you're looking at pea pods whether
it'll be wrinkled or smooth in that
locus be the locus or the section of
gene for the architecture within these
general pea pod whether it be a smooth
pea pod or a wrinkled to pupa and again
this if we look at the big chromosome
here we look at that in a more detail
level will see those histones ultimately
to that DNA level of introns and exons
composing of the gene now lastly here
just controlling the gene getting
whether it's get turned on or it's gets
turned off well the genes are typically
controlled at the level of transcription
sis so the cells not going to waste
energy and procreates proteins are
either blocked to allow RNA polymerase
to access the promoter or they're
repressed so repressors will block the
promoter region that kind of on-and-off
switch like someone puts a cover over
the on/off switch won't be able to turn
that light on activators that make the
porter more accessible maybe it's kind
of like a nightlight over the light
switch to make it easier to find in the
dark most genes are turned off except
when needed the cells have a lot of
genes and the whole point is not to have
them all on at the same time so we can
see here just some examples
looking at our prokaryotes if where they
have different food sources so low
glucose and lactose is available well in
this case we're having that activator go
right through and make these genes the
case here where high glucose and lactose
is unavailable we're going to repress
those particular genes
and we see the same thing here we're
lactose is unavailable we're lactose is
available we're having some level of
expression this is a get the lock operon
in prokaryotes so looking at activating
these lac genes if lactose is not
available there's no point in running
that or having the cell go through the
process of expressing those genes
therefore that promoter region will be
repressed and those genes will be
essentially turned off so hopefully this
gives you a nice little background here
of gene architecture to give you a
little insight into the complexities
going on within cells