so you may have heard the term in gene
therapy in the news well here we're
going to learn a little bit about that
process and how it's been used so first
off what is gene therapy in general well
gene therapy introduces healthy genes
into cells that lack them so as first
used successfully in the year 1992 girls
were cured of a rare blood disorder
caused by a defective gene and the girls
remained healthy even well beyond that
so what this is in the most basic form
is kind of repairing genes or fixing a
broken gene it's finding in identifying
a region or a gene that is defective
identifying that area and replacing it
with a healthy gene and allowing that
cell then to replicate causing that now
normal or healthy gene to proliferate in
the cells however this has other cases
in implications one example would be
cloning of animals so here's just an
example of Dolly the sheep
how is Dolly the sheep clone produced
well it's through this kind of concept
of gene therapy now the successful
embryos about 30 and 277 tries so again
a great percentage were transplanted
into a surrogate mother sheep well this
process looked like so well even though
only one in 270 tries was successful in
July 5th 1996 Dolly was born
how would that process go about well you
take that donor cell from a sheep and we
extract extract
the nucleus is extracted from that so
this in this case only the nucleus is
being used we have this egg cell taken
from an adult female sheep and that
nucleus of the egg cell is removed so
essentially essentially from this sheep
we have the egg cell components in
machinery and from the sheep we only
have the nucleus through an electrical
shock process that nucleus is
transferred into that fused egg cell
that egg cell then is induced to divide
normally that single fused egg cell will
then produce an embryo that embryo will
be placed into a foster mother and that
foster mother will ultimately have the
cloned sheep as a offspring so the
embryo develops normally and that baby
lamb is produced in this case it was
Dolly
since Delhi scientists have successfully
cloned sheep mice cattle goats and pigs
hell of our problems and complications
still a lie arise leading to premature
death not really sure why that's the
case but dolly died in 2002 having lived
only half a normal sheeps life so while
the process does make sense that were
just taking the nucleus from one in the
egg cell from another you're still a
potential for shortened life
expectancies now UConn has gone through
with large animals and in 1999 in the
first of the first first cloned calf
from an adult farm animal on and non
reproductive cells the United States
that name was Amy and Amy has given
birth to one hundred and three pound
calf in 2002 now if we look here this is
kind of the mother if you will these are
the clones you could see that they also
have a very similar kind of white
triangle on the top of their head there
and they're all the clones and I forget
all their names but it it was a B C D
and E they had the name acute letter
ABCD and ian's was at UConn so stem cell
basics how this is all as possible well
it's through the process of stem cells
so stem cells have a very unique
characteristic to them they're what we
call pluripotent and that means they're
capable of forming an entire organism
one cell can form basically all the
components of an organism as development
proceeds cells lose their pluripotency
so they become committed to one type of
tissue and these are called adult stem
cells because they still have the
genetics to produce anything but they
themselves kind of become specialized it
only produce one particular type of cell
so since you arise from just one cell
that had to have the ability to perform
and produce all these different tissue
types however as you get older heart
muscle cells tend to produce more heart
muscle cells and neurons for the short
at least first two years they can
produce more neurons intestinal cells
produce more intestinal cells they
become more specialized they start to
lose that pluripotent miss that that
originally had when were very very young
now we're looking at stem cells there's
some benefits and some drawbacks
so benefits and black stem cells could
be used to restore tissues lost
damaged due to accident or disease
experiments have already been tried and
successful in mice damaged spinal nerves
as I mentioned nerve cells don't divide
for very long to your life so damaged
spinal nerves can be partially repaired
it can help someone recover from a
spinal cord injury might be paralyzed in
parts so some of the benefits to stem
cells some of the problems I was finding
a source especially for those embryonic
stem cells harvesting them from
discarded embryos Rises ethical issues
are appealing unborn babies and then
there's also the possibility of an
immune system rejecting them so
implanted stem cells will likely be
rejected by the immune system of the
individual so it's important to realize
some of the benefits but also be mindful
of some of the issues or problems when
you're making a decision going forward
these are things that science has to do
is constantly balances the pros with the
cons