here in this debaco university video
i'll be going over some general
fertilizer considerations
that apply to really any fertilizer you
might be adding to your plants
all right let's go over some general for
lesser considerations for cannabis
production
so first off we want to consider the
general fertilizer ratio and the
dilution
so as a general guide two to one to two
which is the n
phosphorus uh potential sorry the
nitrogen phosphorous potassium ratio is
often considered to be the standard for
cannabis
and that could be a two one two or a
twenty ten twenty or a whole other host
of potential
nutrients there could be a ten 5 10 as
well regarding concentrations
manufacturers recommendations should
provide a good starting point
and use those as kind of maximums you
can go a little bit lower than that and
then
see how your plants respond and your
work your way up to that
this i don't want to go much higher than
the general recommendations
by the manufacturer because it could
lead to other issues with your plants
then the fertilizer concentration check
once you go through and do the math and
dilute it out
in general an ec or parts per million
meter can be used to check the
concentrations of nutrient solution
it's good to kind of have the secondary
device electronic
connectivity or you see or parts per
million ppm meters measure the salts in
the water
for example tap water could have a 0.4
or about 200 parts per million ratio the
nutrient solution example should be 1.3
or around 650 parts per million again
just to give you an idea of how
concentrated
your actual nutrient solution is because
if it's too concentrated that could
cause
issues to the plants could cause some
unnecessary stress of the plants
depending on the stage of growth for
example if you're talking early on
clones or seedlings
we want to be really mindful of that
continually monitoring that so don't
risk damaging
that entire crop and then using the
meter so when we're going through and
using
whatever chosen manufacturer meter we
use the goal is to measure the water
being given to the plants
and is also what is coming out of the
container or substrate
this will help growers dial in their
feeding concentrations so they can
maximize plant production while limiting
nutrients
lost or wasted meaning if you know x
amount is going into the plants in any
of your container
and you measure what's kind of coming
out at the bottom you can have an idea
of
what you may or may not be over
fertilizing with if you've got a lot
coming in
a lot coming out well you might want to
reduce the amount that goes in
to try to allow plants a chance to
uptake those nutrients to be utilized
instead of being
flushed through and wasted that's a
great way using that meteor of both your
irrigation water as well as your pour
through water
to get an idea to better dial in your
particularly growing situation to
maximize plant efficiency
while minimizing losses that could
contaminate the environment
and incur unneeded expenses