okay here I'll cut the genetic
engineering summary and then after the
summary we'll go through a couple stages
in experimentation so starting with the
general summary we're looking at the
engineered animals can also apply to
plants it's the same basic process of
changing or modifying different genes in
an organism so start off with a gene
cloning let me go through just the
highlights here so step one is a small
circular DNA molecule called plasmids me
remember that from our previous videos
I'll remove from bacterial cells these
plasma serves serve as vectors which are
molecules that carry genes of interest
and that unit of interest could be just
something we want to multiply something
we're interested in developing let me go
through a lack C gene would be an
example antibiotic resistance genes or
also could be added here we see
restriction sites if you remember from
our restriction enzymes those are areas
where it might be specific couple sites
again those plasmids are those small
circular regions of DNA found in
prokaryotic cells in this case bacterial
DNA containing the gene of interest is
also taken from its original cell so
this cell here contains our gene of
interest whatever didn't want to
multiply we're taking it out of this
nucleus so this would be a eukaryotic
cell and we are going to put it into our
plasmid so step three is restriction
enzyme recognizes is specific
restriction site and it's a short
sequence about four to eight bases long
and this is a specific region here
restriction site where that DNA is going
to be cut if you remember from our
restriction enzyme video here we're
going to cut the DNA we're going to
cause these things called sticky ends
these sticky ends our bases that don't
have pairs and they want to pair up they
want to join and that's part of the
sticky ends part for it breaks apart the
DNA these restriction enzymes leaving
overhanging regions called sticky ends
these restrictions enzymes cut open the
circular plasmids and the same enzyme
cuts our gene of interest so it's
important and the same enzyme is used
because we
these to rejoin to one another so I want
them to cut the very same specific
sequence moving on from step four
and we left right here in step four we
has that five these sticky ends of the
restriction fragments attached to one
another via base pairing in a binds with
T defines let's see that's the same
thing that happens the gene of interest
gets included into some of the plasmids
forming recombinant plasmids so it's
important here some of the plasmids we
like to think that every single plasmid
takes and that this particular gene of
interest but that's not always the case
so they form weak hydrogen bonds the
gene of interest gets included on other
plasmids close right back up remaining
unchanged so we could see an example
here the red indicates the gene of
interest some plasmids basic it's
separated with the restriction enzymes
and get rejoined and they did not take
into deed of interest
DNA ligase links our bonds together
makes bombs permanent by attaching
nucleotides to each other with those
phosphodiester bonds you may remember
from methylation these phosphodiester
bonds are joining that ligation and
they're forming now a larger plasmid but
still at circular form of DNA the
plasmids are mixed with bacterias some
of them take up the plasmids in the
process called transformation that
should also sound familiar can hopefully
see a lot of these terms are coming back
into this one big summary of genetic
engineering
so our unchanged plasmids here don't
have the little red and our recurrent
plasmids do and some of those both
unchanged any comment are taken up by
our vector results
moving on from step 7 step 8
the plasmids here with our lack c gene
turn the bacterial blue in the recurrent
plasmids the inserted gene interrupts
the lacks a gene and the bacteria remain
their original color
Macario do not take up any plasmids also
remain uncolored this is used for a way
to identify what bacteria may have taken
up our gene of interest
antibiotics can also be added because
the plasmid contains genes of antibiotic
resistance so other than just inserting
our gene of interest for whatever that
may be it could be produced insulin or
something we also introduced antibiotic
resistance genes what these allow us to
do or
when would you make engineering
something is to select for those cells
that took up our gene of interest those
cells that took up our gene of interest
also get this antibiotic resistance gene
so that when we add antibiotics you can
see those that did not take up our
plasmid end up dying only those cells
that have the antibiotic resistance
genes will end up surviving those genes
those bacteria that have those genes for
antibiotic resistance also have our gene
of interest and that's an important step
here step 10
the bacteria are then sorted by color
isolating the bacteria took up the
plasmid cane gene of interest in the
uncolored bacteria are then allowed to
be produced so we simply have selected
as we can see here these bacteria these
blue bacteria in this case or something
against they are not taken up so we
could use antibiotic or we can use
coloration sometimes the key part here
is we want to generate genetic
engineering we want to isolate the
bacteria that have our gene of interest
and this is a process which we go
through and do that there's four stages
to through genetic engineering
experiment this is a large view here if
you see here this is the generally all
the steps that I just went through in
more detail we all saw these stages
milking an experiment so stage 1 some
terms we might become familiar with
cleaving DNA large number of fragments
are produced is separated by
electrophoresis there'll be a separate
video on this but in the quick summary
what we're doing we're taking our long
DNA and we are putting it into wells
we're separating out or chopping that da
up into different sections then we're
separating it based on size larger
fragments stay up closer to where we
originally put the whole slug of DNA and
the smaller fragments are able to travel
further more on that we do
electrophoresis it's good it's pulled by
current that's where the terminal
electrode comes in stage 2 producing a
become a DNA Ginny's vectors important
term here site of cleavage cleavage here
is referring to separating our DNA and
these are done by restriction enzymes
vectors are plasmids or sometimes
viruses that carry foreign DNA into the
host cell these
dr. DNA is cut with the same enzyme as
the source DNA thus allowing the two to
join not only do we need to cut the host
plasmid to form the sticky ends we also
need to cut the DNA to take out the gene
of interest we want to add in we want
them both cut the same restriction
enzyme so that they bind together and
form this nightma this nice need to bond
here cloning host cells are using
bacteria as the bacterial cell
reproduces it forms a clone containing
the fragment bearing vector again all
we're doing is using bacteria cuz they
multiply so rapidly
for example ecole I can multiply every
20 minutes and we're basically
multiplying that gene of interest very
quickly turning a lot of plasmids and
cloning those during a lot of the genes
we have a screening process so the
primary screen of clone library
eliminates clones without the vectors
those that don't have the gene of
interest are clones with vectors that
don't contain DNA in certain cases here
we have the example of our DNA fragment
in our vector since to become a vector
that we want not all cells would take up
this particular plasmid so we'll just
take up the vector without the gene of
interest and that's how we have a
screening process could be antibiotic
resistance it could also be based on
color in that to your talents are going
on agar could see here nice tea streak
that screening again as I mentioned the
antibiotic resistance ampicillin czar
very common antibiotic that's used
we take our cells we put them on those
that have an ozone those that have our
gene of interest also have that
antibiotic gene and able to break down
ampicillin be able to survive while type
or general cells are not able to do that
so we ensure the cells that are left are
the ones that have our gene of interest
because they also have antibiotic
resistance
it's a selecting agent beta collected
ace is another way this is looking at
color so the white colonies have the
plasmids with the foreign insert blue
cows have plasmids without the insert so
we would be selecting for the white
colonies here and basically what's
happening here is we're interrupting the
normal sequence of the genes causing the
cell to lose its color
that white color are the cells that we
want this again shows our sticky ends
forming from our plasma in there just
cut with a restriction enzyme ampicillin
resistance gene and then we can see the
genome with the in this case the
plasmids with the gene of interest
located here and we need a screening
process because as you can see here not
every bacterial cell took up the vector
with the gene that we don't want it so
just a quick summary from while watch
the this you to other YouTube video this
is just a way we're taking our plasmid
we're cutting it open with our
restriction enzymes and we're putting in
our gene of interest but we also need a
way to select for or insure the bacteria
that we have have our gene of interest
we can do that through antibiotic
resistance or also coloration hopefully
this is there just hopefully overview
for genetic engineering