welcome to this tobacco university video
where we're looking at general cannabis
breeding overview
just kind of looking at a general
overview of something
that can be quite complex so hopefully
this will provide a little description
that i develop some basic understanding
so first off the basic review overview i
should say of heredity
other videos are provided on this
channel to better understand the basic
breeding process because i said it can
get quite confusing
we can look at punnett squares and
medium genetics we'll touch on that just
a little bit here
realize this is a very complex topic and
i just hope to give you a basic
overview here on this video so first off
we have to understand the basics of for
example
genes and there's dominant and there's
recessive genes so understanding
the difference between those two is
important individuals receive one
version of a gene called an
allele from each parent if the alleles
are different
the dominant allele will be expressed
while the
effect of the other allele called
recessive is masked
so a dominant gene will be expressed and
can
mask or override the effect of a
different variant of the same gene
on the other copy of the chromosome
recessive genes
an individual must inherit two copies of
the
mutated allele in order to express that
trait
now keep in mind this does not mean that
genes are bad or negative recessive
genes some some are but not necessarily
all of them sometimes recessive and
dominant
genes here have really no major effect
where we can see the example here of
having a
attached earlobe versus kind of a
distinctive earlobe here
this is an example of recessive trait
and a dominant trait doesn't mean that
the recessive can hear any worse than
the dominant this is an example of a
phenotype
or what it would physically look like
compared to the
genotype the genetics here and we can
trace that through different lineages
now you get into things called sometimes
true breeding intrubing is a kind of
reading where the parents would produce
offspring that would carry the same
phenotype again phenotype is how the
organism looks
this means that the parents are
homozygous for every trait
this example we're reading purple with
purple getting purple reading purple
with purple getting purple
so on and so forth they're true breeding
they come true from type
we see the same thing here with the
white flowers as well
where we're noticing that the self
pollination we're getting more and more
of the same these would be examples of
true
breeding lines keep in mind
there's two sex chromosomes we identify
a female as having two x's and a male is
having an
x and a y this is how we get the female
flowers as we can see here
and then the male flowers you can see
closer to me here this is again boy and
girl
same example now the y is drawn smaller
at least in humans because the y
chromosome does contain
less genes than the larger x
now simplified punnett square this may
take you back to kind of
uh biology class where you're looking at
crossing
two genotypes together and this punnett
square is just a quick way to organize
things
it's a great way to kind of quickly go
through things where see the big g would
be dominant over the little g
we have a heterozygous this is called
where we have a dominant and recessive
allele with a dominant recessive allele
we breed them together
25 or one out of four would be the
homozygous
dominant fifty percent would be
heterozygous
we have one dominant and one recessive
allele and then 25 percent
would be homozygous recessive now
phenotypically or how they would look
75 percent of these would be green if
the capital g represents green color
and 25 percent be yellow because they
need to have both inherit
both of those genes there again just a
simplified quick run through of
punnett squares we you might hear things
called like the f1 and the f2 generation
because some traits may skip a
generation so here we have the parental
generation
the f1 and the f2 in this example the
parental generation we have a tall plant
and a short plant we can see their
genotype here
when these are bred together all the
resulting offspring are tall
but they're all heterozygous and they
all contain that mast
or that hidden recessive allele however
when we breed these together we see
those
short varieties come back again they
skipped that generation there
so it's important to keep that breeding
lineage going through
and we can see that here again with the
kind of cannabis strain two chemist
streams bringing those together
where we're tracking everything these
are female from these seeds make a back
cross
talk a second about back crossing but
keeping a
lineage and a kind of a family tree is
important for tracking traits
now that back crossing that i briefly
mentioned uh previously
back crossing is crossing of a hybrid
with one of its parents
or an individually genetically similar
to its parent
in order to achieve offspring with a
generic
identity which is closer to that of the
parent it's kind of like
going backwards literally within the
cross so here we have our parental
strain we have our f1 strain
well we have that back cross going back
through and reverting it to one of the
parental there
and that's helping limit the kind of
variability that you get
so here we have two parents this is kind
of a good way to kind of visually
consider it parents a and parents
are breed them together we get offspring
b we're going to breed offspring b with
that free current parent
parent r again b with r we get c and
then
c we breed that with r again and we're
kind of back crossing the sense we're
going
back to those genetics we're constantly
bringing those back into the line
to try to create some genetic
variability but also kind of keep an
idea of some of those traits recurring
back in the population
now gregor mendel was a monk that
studied
pea plants these are kind of an example
of kind of dihybrid crosses they're
called
so again this is a simplified example
the phenotypes are provided in this
simplified example it's kind of a great
visual that we can see tall plants and
green plants
looking here many traits do not follow
mendelian inherent so it's important to
keep that in mind
so this helps show the variability that
can occur from a basic cross involving
only two traits now when i say they
don't inherit
all mendelian so for example here we
either have green
or we have kind of that purple color
well there's a chance we could get
green with purple spots or purple with
green spots so
there is a lot of complexities and while
you look at this to go well this is
pretty complex
this is actually a simplified version of
having either a trait being expressed or
not expressed
following those mendelian inheritance
these are tall plants or they're short
plants they're either green
or they're purple so this is why keeping
a track record
of your breeding projects having a good
idea going in
and reviewing this video as well as
other videos that are on this channel as
well as
others can be important to know what
you're getting into so you have a good
understanding of the breeding process
so that you can be effective with the
time that you spend
and have an idea of what to look for
what to select against
to create a hopeful successful breeding
project