so welcome to this tobacco university
video we'll be investigating genetic
testing of cannabis to determine
genotype and this is kind of the picture
here looking at gregor mendel back
looking at just the morphology of the
plant
now when we're studying plant to next we
tend to use more genetic testing let me
go over some of the techniques here and
present the research study
so first off using the pcr is a very
common genetic tool so you hear this
term tossed around quite a bit what is
pcr
well it stands for polymath chain
reaction this is a scientific process
that allows for small
theoretically one sequence of dna to be
replicated to many copies
because a lot of times you're only
dealing with a very small
amount of dna well this is a way to kind
of generate
multiple copies to help identify if the
sequence is present in the original
sample
this is used quite a bit because it's a
very precise process
and therefore can be really great at
being able to pinpoint very specific
genetic sequences that in the scientific
investigator might be looking for
now there's genetic testing options
there's many different types you can
look at whether a plant is male or
female
you can get the genotype the full
sequencing or ip production which is
intellectual property protection as well
and all of these relate to the cannabis
industry directly
now the research study that i'm going to
be presenting some of the data from it
can be found right here
give the reference right here a link
there and kind of the picture of the
first page if you want to look at it in
more detail yourself
now first off gender detection screening
of cannabis so this is
dna sex or gender testing benefits of
utilizing
this method and this is the goal of this
is to be able to save time by
discovering if a plant is
a male months before it can be
traditional traditionally detected or
phenotypically detected based on the
visual
assessment of the flowers it produces by
being able to detect this early this can
save resources by identifying plants
early fewer plants need to be grown
which reduces the input such as water
labor nutrients and lighting and a whole
host of other things
that are needed to maximize the space to
grow plants in
upfront costs for the testing can be
justified by the reduction cost of
reduced plant care
at least in some instances so looking at
the overview of
samples here so again going to that
study that i showed earlier
four well-known varieties of industrial
hemp and six experimental varieties
of medicinal cannabis were included in
the experiment and they're kind of
listed here to give you some information
sample marking variety or genotype the
material and the source or provider of
that
plant material so there's three
different primers pairs used for sex
determination we can see them listed
right here and the key part is while
these are all
primers can be used they do not all have
the same reliability
this is referring to the actual primer
sequences the actual sequence of the dna
the amplification product and then the
marker's name provided here in the first
column
now this is the visualization of the pcr
products we're looking at
for sex determination of canvas
varieties and this is at the marker
stated right there
on the c2 a marker and this shows you
kind of the
different varieties there and the
different bandings and if you see the
same banning
that's indicating that that same dna
fragment exists there if you see
different bandings
that's going to indicate that there's
different lengths of those
dna fragments we see on the left here we
see the marker the ladder is as it's
called
with this representing 1 500 base pairs
this representing 100. if you ever
looked at a gel from pcr
products the larger or longer sequences
will be closer to where the wells where
the first dna was put
and then these smaller bands can travel
further through that gel and you see the
data presented here from the research
study mentioned earlier
and we kind of look at this the
conclusions of the studies that's the
actual data let's kind of get to the
conclusions looking at the markers that
they were kind of
investigating this scar one one nine
marker appeared to be the most reliable
for male plant detection in cannabis
the other two showed limited or even
controversial results at times
this study confirmed that sex
determination of cannabis plant is a
complex
process you can see as we see and look
in the data here the genotype scoring
and different varieties here different
markers this would represent a
plant with female phenotype here's a
plant with male
phenotype this is a monostage plant
green color indicating
sample with genotype scoring in
accordance with phenotype the red
colored samples
with incorrect genotype indication so
this again shows that the scar
119 marker for the most part has all
that green across the row indicating it
was the most reliable
out of the ones studied and presented
here
now the cannabis genotyping just in
general when we're looking at that
genotyping
it's essential that the plant's
blueprint which includes the entire
spectrum of possibilities
for a particular cannabis plant same can
also be said for the human genome so
while this is very focused to the
cannabis industry
a lot of this also applies to other
organisms knowing precisely what defined
characteristics are in the plant will
help
guide decision making when it comes to
breeding that can be very important
particularly if you're looking at
breeding or introducing
a unique trait or strain
now that sequencing that i had mentioned
earlier what is sequencing what's
actually the kind of
sequence or the order of all of the
nucleotides within the dna
this can be used to determine the
stability and uniqueness of a cannabis
plant while also determining relatives
origin
and ancestral lineage once the genetic
code is known
this can allow for new and unique
strains
having record of genetic sequences can
allow for protection against false
patent claims
and other legal controversy so it's good
to kind of have that as like the
blueprint or sequence of the genetic
plants that you might be growing or
producing
lastly when we're looking at kind of
genetics
sequencing for ip production
intellectual property production
the greater amount of nucleotide bases
sequence the greater power of
differentiation can be occur
there are two classifications of
sequencing there's the targeting and
then there's a whole genome sequencing
so targeted of more than 3.5 million
bases
across thousands of high value targets
including 29 cannabinoid and terpene
synthesis genes
as well as several genes for seed
production and sex determination
that's where they're looking at very
kind of particular sequences that have
been identified within the whole genome
of the cannabis plant
compare that to the whole genome
sequencing this provides a data file
that contains the strain's full genetic
sequence
which can be used to identify important
genetic markers and determine
novelty so since chemistry um is highly
polymorphic
single primer sets can often have
reduced overall identification abilities
why is this important for ip production
we want to protect
what you might be developing and the
resources you might be putting into
something
we see here with the sandals here being
examples
of ones that you may read as mcdonald's
and nike initially but this is an
example would be ip
infringement where we're looking at kind
of copying something not exactly
if you look very closely you'll see
there's some code misspellings there
but close enough to determine that it's
infringing on the intellectual property
agreement
same basic thing can happen here with
the genetics where even if there's only
like a little slight misspelling
it's determined to be close enough that
can be advantageous for growers
particularly breeders of cannabis to
protect the plant material that they've
put so much time and effort into
creating