so in this video we're gonna relate
genetic engineering to plants typically
grown in a lab controlled conditions you
see growth chambers here little sterile
conditions in these little jars and
we're gonna relate this how we're able
to change genes relate to plants have
another one on medicine we looked at
vaccines you're looking at food we may
eat so transgenic plants such as corn
cotton soybeans and many others there's
pros and cons different ways we can
genetically modified plants one example
here and it provide the the source where
we're looking at Roundup Ready soybean
yield so Roundup Ready means these Swee
beans are resistant to the herbicide
roundup that you might be familiar with
here's the control and here's the
treated so yield and bushels per acre
Sierra control again yield is referring
to how many soybeans are getting off the
field here's the treated you noticing it
dramatic increase so improved yield on
Roundup Ready soybeans so four point
three bushel average increase per acre
average of 14 treatment locations across
different states and into Canada a
corporator of this roundup which is the
active ingredient glyphosate is the
what's roundup is basically what that is
and by having soybeans that aren't
affected by roundup glyphosate being the
herbicide farmers are able to go through
and sprayed the field control the weeds
and not kill their crop and that's
what's causing the increase in yield
here seen in 2009 so conventional
compared to Janice modified well
conventional corn you can upfront bill
Inc down here no real benefits detected
versus genetically modified corn
requires 6 percent less pesticides to
produce enough calories to feed 88
million people per year higher yield
seven point six percent in this study
increased farmer income overall across
all farmers from 1996 to 2007 estimated
over forty four billion dollars so you
could see here there's some advantages
and pressures to switch over to
genetically modified corn
but there are potential risks which
outside your abbreviated GM promise of
genetic engineering is very much evident
however its generates some considerable
controversy and protests our genetic
inheritance within genes there's been
rallies that say no GMOs very much
against modified whether you're for or
against a corn production and yield per
acre has dramatically increased we need
to feed the world here so that's one of
the pressures to to this increasing of
yield and GM crops are one way that's
showing to continue this increase Oscar
Golden Rice example is another form of
genetically modified it's a variety of
rice that was genetically engineered to
produce beta carotene which is a
precursor to vitamin A here's the world
where there's a shortage of vitamin A in
the diet this genetically modified rice
and has this kind of golden like color
to it is a great plant because its
whites reduce over the world as a main
food crop so instead of growing this
traditional rice by simply growing this
golden rice behaves in the same way
individuals are able to get this
precursor to vitamin A and its beta
carotene can really save a lot of people
a lot of lives without really causing
any change to simply starting with
different seeds I've to comment rate so
for genetically modified at least used
on the large scale here across the
United States
our herbicide resistance is one and it's
often refrigerant Roundup Ready amount
of ready corn soybeans alfalfa and oil
cotton it simply means that roundup when
applied to most plants causes anodizing
herbicide
however these genetically modified
plants have this protein that's able to
basically break down and not suffer the
effects of roundup
so gently modifies the ants are
resistant to this weed killer what this
allows occur is the plant that has that
particular gene to survive and all of
the regular crops and weeds and any
other plants in the vicinity of that
chosen crop dies allowing the main crop
to be able to survive so
and farmers enough to plow the fields it
sistex a lot of input lot IDs a lot of
energy a lot of time dustbowl
illumination back in the turn of century
this is actual images of topsoil that
got picked up by the wind and carry
these large clouds of dust it occurred
because farmers plowed their few fields
the appositive fields to reduce the weed
pressure well with herbicide resistance
they don't have to worry about that
as a result improving yields and
resulting in cleaner fields because of
the lack of weeds without going through
the plowing and have a risk of losing
very valuable topsoil on some
disadvantage though herbicide resistance
like anything you use any chemical over
a period of time plants animals are
going to develop resistance to that it's
not gonna be as effective and because
only certain crops are resistant to that
herbicide the concept of mono cropping
occurs you can only grow or only that
one particular crop with that one
particular gene is gonna survive as a
result you're gonna have a bunch of
essentially potentially clones or at
least ones that are very genetically
similar grown you can't grow carrots and
peas and soybeans in the same field
could only grow genetically modified
ones that are resistant to the herbicide
the idea of super weeds myself are on
this side super weeds where we're
applying these herbicides and the whole
resistance develops so we have another
herbicide different chemistry
well it resistant so that would apply
another one apply another one these
super weeds may become resistant
eventually to all the herbicides that we
currently have so that's another concern
potential disadvantage that could occur
another modification that's being added
to plants is insect resistance BT beauty
and satyrs it's called Bacillus
thuringiensis what this does is it
breaks down and kills caterpillars
it's a protein produced by solar
bacteria and harmful to pests such as
caterpillars but not humans it's been
introduced into tomato plants and many
others corns another example here we see
feeding that's occurring on a plant that
did not have the gene here's our Jena
the modified one and we see very minimal
feeding that has occurred
for their traits for a percent of
resistance as one as I mentioned insect
resistance is another and putting them
both together in the same plant it's
another one that's getting popularity
herbicide tolerance you see increasing
dramatically insect resistance also but
now we're seeing the rise of the
combination of the two putting two
traits into one plant these concerns for
risks with these GM crops are GM foods
safe for the environment well other
organisms be harmed unintentionally will
pass become resistant to these
pesticides what the introduced genes are
passed from the GM crop to wild or weedy
relatives these are all concerns with
these crops one of the other issues is
that we have this ever increasing world
population so we need to produce more
food if we have a way of modifying crops
to be able to meet that demand that will
allow the population to increase but
there's also potential for other risks
that may be occurring with that
starvation with the other flip side of
that coin so insect resistance again at
bacillus thuringiensis at Pt advantages
to this are that don't have to fight
insecticides of the crop no one wants to
buy a corn it's got the tip basically
eaten out by an insect reduces trips in
the field farmers don't have to drive
over all these fields and these are very
large fields in some cases early insects
can be easily controlled that first
flush of insects can be controlled
because the crop already has a built-in
insecticide with it however the cons are
i pianets integrated pest management
that isn't managing the pests
effectively year to year here we're just
putting the pesticide in the field in
the plant that's really kind of going
against the whole IPM practice
insecticide resistance we can get
insects that could be resistant and
non-target insects could also be
affected here's resistance of different
chemistry of insecticides we see the
resistance increasing much as we saw
with the herbicide resistant now here we
have ideally if the entire field was
applied and grown as with those insect
resistant genes when it's the increase
of developing or selecting for
individuals
resistant becomes very high what farmers
should be doing his alkane part of the
field that simply does not have GM crops
what that does that keeps some insects
alive that are susceptible to that
particular herbicide or that particular
in this case insecticide that allows us
to be mixed in the population and
increases the odds that they'll be
susceptible genes in the environment
through our punnett square crosses
reducing the overall pressure the hard
part is if farmers grow a large scale or
killing a blue mass the vast majority
off we can be selecting for this
increase in insecticide resistance at a
faster rate non-target insects corn
borers killed those are the ones that go
into the very tips of the corn but the
pollen that washes into streams may kill
the non target caddisfly the cash fly
looks like it's present in freshwater
streams eaten by a lot of trout and fish
and aquatic organisms this could be a
potential non target insect from the
pollen from the BT corn that's targeted
at corn borer could be getting into
streams and could be potentially harming
the catus fight population a non target
insect potential risks are GM food safe
to eat it's a common question well
herbicide blocks the synthesis of
aromatic amino acids which is okay
because humans don't make any aromatic
amino acids so glyphosate is not harmful
to humans however gene modification is
that render the plant resistant if I
could say may introduce novel proteins
these may again may have the chance to
cause allergies and humans just put some
examples here of some of the aromatic
amino acids their full name their
three-letter abbreviation and also their
single letter abbreviation tryptophan
are probably most familiar with
especially around Thanksgiving TRP or WR
the abbreviations for them should GM
foods be labeled every serious
scientific investigation has included
that GM foods are safe there's no real
health risks so the question is well why
label something that's that harmful
however people basically have the right
to know and we are seeing
Creason labeling more laws are being
passed at the state level so we are
seeing an increase in Leyland of GM
crops GMO acreage genetic modified
organism acreage worldwide we see
overall vastly increasing on justjust
from 1996 to 2009 even from 2009 we're
seeing a continuation of this if you're
not familiar with the completely
Monsanto they are leading and pioneering
this Roundup resistance they developed
and make roundup and they are working on
increasing genetic modified food give
you their websites you can take a look
what they're advocating is that by
getting everyone involved informed we
can prepare to grow enough food for a
growing world that's one that's
predicted to be 9 billion people by 2050
so they're playing the side where need
to produce more food which is true and
they see genetically modified corn and
other crops as a way to supplement that
again people have this stigma against
the genetically modified crops there's
no scientific studies show there's any
major negative effects but the real
question is we just simply don't know we
don't have enough years of data and if
we start growing all genetically
modified crops and there's a problem
that develops down the road and that's
all we're growing that can lead to
potential issues also but we have to
keep in mind we have this delicate
balance of this ever-increasing world
population the main question is how are
we going to feed all these individuals