welcome to this debaco university
lecture video
today i'm going to be going over
genotype chemotype and phenotype as
relates to the breeding of
cannabis and to go over these three main
types and also provide you with some of
their advantages
and disadvantages of utilizing each so
first off breeding can be based on
three main categories here phenotype is
basically how the plants
look chemotype is the chemical profiles
that it produces
and genotype are the actual genetics so
again all these are different strategies
for breeding so first off we look at
phenotype and this is how the plant
grows
this is a result of how the genetics
interact with the environment
so if a plant has the genetics to grow
10 feet tall but it's constantly under
water or salt stress
the plant may only grow to be three feet
tall as a result the phenotype would be
three feet even though the genetics are
different in the sense that the genetics
could produce ten feet tall plants
because the environment it may only
reach three feet tall
so what's the advantages to using a
phenotype selection for which is often
used by growers
well it's often used because there's no
specialized equipment needed
growers can judge plants purely on the
performance for their given environment
if they keep the environment consistent
that can allow
different grow to grow comparisons
attentive growers can select one
individual out of many
so that is another advantage if
something is a genetic
standout in its look then that could be
those genetics could be preserved and
may be cloned and may be carried out
going further and bred in future
lineages
however the disadvantages of using
phenotype selection is that
resulting plants even if it's a clone
may not be the same
it's based only on the morphological
characteristics
this can also require an attentive
grower typically growing many plants
if it grows only growing a small number
of plants that can be more difficult
to go through the process of phenotype
selection
so then that brings us to chemotype
which is referring to the chemicals
produced by the plant
we have type 1 which is a high thc a
production plant
they have type 2 which is a balanced
ratio of cbd2 thc
and then type 3 is a high cbd production
plant now there's others that go further
and look at type 4 being cbg dominant
and type 5 being zero cannabis
cannabinoids
uh reduced number there in the sense
that those are looking more at
potentially
just producing terpenes and that the
cannabinoids
now the advantages to using this
chemotype breeding
is that you can know the classification
of the cannabinoid production
in that plant ideally it shows the
plants not producing the needed
compounds
to not be grown so that's a way to
select those and can speed up the
selection process
or especially early on in a breeding
program as far as kind of eliminating
those that are going to be a waste of
time
for the grower's desired traits but the
disadvantages with using
chemotype is that typically this
requires a specialized equipment
high resolution mass spec is a
kind of high-end piece of equipment that
might needed to really assess the
chemical profile
plants may change classification based
on generations of the breeding process
if a growers are selecting for one thing
or another it's based on what the plant
actually produces which can be
influenced by many environmental factors
so just another downfall to consider for
using chemotype breeding
then that leads us to genotype breeding
well
traits such as photoperiod dependence
and cannabinoids produced
can be strongly influenced by the
genotype of the plant so this is why
using the genes can be a very important
and powerful tool
the advantages to using genotype
breeding is that it's
very specific to the actual genetic code
it allows for quick and efficient
screening for targeted sequences
and can be performed at any stage of the
plant growth cycle
meaning the genetics of that plant the
seedling stage as well at the end
ideally will be just about the same
so therefore you're going to be able to
speed up the breeding process instead of
growing a plant all the way to term
you could grow a bunch of seedlings
screen them for their genetics and then
select out those
that don't have the particular sequences
deemed desirable by the grower
how are there also some disadvantages
and the disadvantage of using
genotype for breeding is that it can
require specialized equipment can also
be expensive
some coffee some companies are offering
genetic testing for a fee
other companies are going through doing
in-house with a lot of upfront cost
you also with genotype reading you need
to know what you're specifically looking
for
so you may be able to find the whole
genetic sequence or find certain
targeted sequences but
you need a way of detecting or knowing
what particular sequences you're
actually
looking for so with that this is just a
comparison here
how will you base your breeding strategy
on phenotype chemotype or genotype
each had its own pros and cons and you
can find videos on this
channel about each of these in more
detail so if you want to explore any of
them
further continue to search on this
channel and i'm sure you will find
some more information to allow you to
have the best breeding strategy going
forward