okay here we're gonna be looking at
genotype versus phenotype and how
understanding this difference will
relate to this term called Fino hunting
which is often used in the cannabis
industry so genotype is the genetics of
the organism it's referring to the
actual DNA sequence the actual
double-stranded DNA sequence now to say
what it looks like in its phenotype
genotype or the actual genetics of that
organism phenotype is the observable
characteristics of that organism and it
can be the result of interactions with
the genotype and the surrounding
environment so phenotype is how it
physically looks genotype is referred to
the actual genetics so we get to this
term female hunting well it's it's short
for phenotype hunting this is referred
to as searching for a particular plant
that is demonstrating a desirable trait
out of a large population so there's a
large population here high degree of
genetics high degree of looks and we go
through a process of selecting for
certain phenotypes certain
characteristics that we see in a
particular plant and want to breed that
particular trait further and replicate
that Sophie no hunting or cloning or
tissue culture could also be used unless
we have the chosen individual this will
ensure that multiple plants exhibit that
desired trait so once we feel oh honey
we find that one that we're really
interested in we then will clone that
particular one just like a copy machine
here we see two duplicates in some cases
it's material can be used for breeding
to help increase the odds of
transferring one trait remaining with
another so in certain types some people
will phenotype certain males looking at
breeding there are times that phenotype
hunting is for females particular plant
morphology or a particular or Roma's
produced or something unique or
different however one word of caution
with phenol hunting is looks can be
deceiving
since you're selecting traits based on
phenotypes this may result potentially
for a high degree of variability so even
though two things may look the same
looks can be deceiving as we see here we
only need to have a page that kind of
course perspectives there because two
traits may or look
like or we may see something that looks
like what we want that can be sometimes
deceiving let me go through and
propagate it or breed it further so an
example of this when you fee know if
anything goes wrong there was a time
when breeder who were looking for to
improve bonsai plant diversity and the
search was on to find a new bonsai plant
in a new small dwarf plant for container
gardening for example many people
thought they hit the jackpot when they
went to the beach because there were
many trees there bonsais size despite
being very old so they able to determine
they had a bunch of these older trees
species that were very small and be very
conducive to a container garden they
don't want a tree that's going to grow
full size so a lot of breeders took
these plants and thought they kind of
hit the jackpot there with finding
varieties that were for whatever reason
old but still very small
the downfall was when these plants were
brought into greenhouses to kind of
propagate they began to show normal
plant behavior so what was actually
happening is all at the beach where
saltwater and a lot of stress winds poor
soils
this was actually stunting the trees
giving them a bonsai phenotype even
though they had the genotype to grow to
full size trees and they were brought in
a greenhouse for propagation they were
given a better environment and they
started growing more normally so again
this is just a word of caution you know
hunting can go wrong because you're
basing it on the simple hello plant
looks and not based necessarily off the
genes the genotype and phenotype can
sometimes differ