okay here I'm gonna go through the
process of properly germinating a
cannabis seed so hopefully you can take
a seed and turn it into a nice healthy
looking seedling like the one pictured
here so what does germination let's
first define that it's a development of
a plant from a dormant seed this is not
the same as emergence which is when the
sprout actually breaks the soil so seeds
can germinate but not emerge and this is
important note here these are
germinating seeds is that when you're
looking at the germination percentage
that's usually provided by companies
it's only the percentage that actually
produced in this case a small root it
does not mean that this they emerged
from this soil so germination rate will
always be higher than emergence rate so
how deep to plant this is important so
that you have the increased odds of
emergence because you don't want to
plant the receives too deep because the
seeds will run out of energy reserves
before it can emerge and start utilizing
light energy to further photosynthetic
process typically when a plants seeds
only about 1/8 to 1/4 inch 3 mils to six
bills deep rule of thumb is to plant the
seed twice as deep as the width so 1/8
inch seeds we printed about quarter
inches deep here see in this image
hearing and judicial and planting in
soil this would be much too deep for
canvass seeds because they'll run out of
energy before they can emerge out of the
soil so what's the germination process
requiring what acquires a see that has
oli genetics and it should be a quality
seed on top of the genetics you need
seeds that have this kind of dark
coloration and are full these typically
come from a known source it's helpful
for increase the odds of quality now
what defines a quality seed well you can
see very consistent conditions here but
the presence of stored nutrients so even
these full seeds here have a limited
amount of energy stored in their
endosperm that's what gives the seeds
the energy to emerge out of the soil
before they shed that seed coat and are
able to capture light energy if planted
at the proper depth energy would be
deserves will allow the emergence out of
this soil and again quality seed nice
consistent conditions we see here the
seeds only need water heat and air to
germinate which sounds really easy but
having the right amount and ratio of
those is important
for water soaking seeds can speed up
water infiltration but this is not
required when water does enter the seeds
it will cause hormones for example tuber
Ellen's to activate and produce this
radical radical pops this is the first
sign of determination has started for
temperature more temperatures not better
the goals to maintain about 78 to 82
degrees Fahrenheit
to increase the odds of successful
germination if temperatures reach to 90
degrees in greater this can kill the
seeds and prevent germination from
occurring system essentially roast the
seeds in denature vital proteins
preventing this radical formation of the
seeds air seeds need to breathe they
especially need oxygen so over soak and
then we'll literally suffocate them so
you examle example to scuba diver here
seeds need to breathe they need to have
that kind of air exchange that's
occurring if you just soak them in water
and kind of drown them that can be able
to exchange important oxygen for the
process of respiration advice if you are
going to see it so providing time for
seeds and so can work can help increase
germination rates purified distilled ro
which is reverse osmosis or a quality
tap water can all be used there's no one
preferred source some growers may even
put some seaweed or kelp to help the
process along but again this is not
necessary Sookie needs no more than 12
to 18 hours is recommended do this if
you soak in the bath for too long your
fingers will get pruney we don't want to
drown the seeds and over saturate the
water inside them
you may notice if you do soak your seeds
some may sink over time which indicates
a fully developed sea denser heavier
those that float typically are hollow
and have poor in this burn development
the result is typically reduced
germination rates scarification is
weakening the seed coat which increases
water infiltration to improve
termination rates by carefully sanding
the outer surface of the seed coke and a
lot easier water penetration they're
essentially taking away that solid
texture and just a little sandpaper
allowing water to get inside the seed a
little bit more efficiently however if
you do over sand them you can damage the
delicate embryo inside and that Satan
could cause a delay in water
infiltration which could reduce or
increase germination time with scarves
scarf eight seeds a soaking time can
often be reduced or may not
be needed in some cases you can direct
CDs as a preferred method moisture
initiates the germination process so if
you're planting that image saturating
the media ahead of time that should
provide adequate moisture levels to
initiate the germination process over
saturating the media will suffocate the
seeds there's no need for additional
hormones or even kelp to aid in this
process distilled water is advised for
consistency and lack of additives the
key part here is having everything
prepared ahead of time you can see even
the corner of the middle and the side
cells here are all even moisture
throughout that's important to allow
even a germination process and not
having wet over the wet or dry spots
some growers have heard this paper towel
method this is a discouraged method for
Candida seeds it's a process that
involves starting seeds in moisten paper
towel prior to adding to media this
allows you to see the radical produced
in transplants easy to know have
germinated so of course think is the
advantage and while that is true
this process is discouraged because
increase of odds of dirt damaged to that
very newly formed radical this method is
best suited for plants that have large
seeds reduce large roots chemists does
not fall into that category
environmental factors some believe that
you can increase the percentage of
female plants by adjusting nutrients in
light none of these have supporting
science and genders turn my genes
some say increasing nitrogen immediately
lower K levels or in the first weeks
will make plants turn female that the
case ensuring plants receive more blue
than red light for about 14 and 16 hours
not going to influence male or female
plant and reduce plant stress to
increase the chance of producing female
plants again false statement there and
not going to influence whether that
seedlings going to be male or female
radical production so in about three to
eight days the seeds will produce a
radical in your Caden determination
process has been initiated her much as
you may want to see this happen the best
places for this to happen directly in
the media you want to be transferring
these seed because see how small some of
these radicals are the damage the odds
of damage are great during that transfer
process may lead to damaging and if you
break this radical in a stunt or even
kill your new perspective plants
remember it's not like sunlight or be
disturbed
this is why it's best suits put them in
the media and let them be
that meeting that you're using this
hopefully a propagation or germination
mix this is a finer mix it's a finer
kind of substrate here and allows for
better soil moisture contact with the
small seeds less air pockets will
develop causing more consistent
conditions for your ceilings a groin
media score certainly result in
potentially dry pockets reduced your
germination rate so for the germination
profit process uses a germination or a
propagation mix brothel can also be used
for germination
there's tubes that can use it's
essentially inert material McLeod for
students to be directly planted into
larger containers with minimal root
disturbance there are some companies
that make a small area you put your seed
in there in larger blocks that easily
can accept the smaller blocks they're
three girls if you're chosen meat it's
important to precip the material and
have it ready before you soak your seeds
get everything ready and then start the
seeds don't do it the other way around
in case you're missing something once
you start those seeds in water the
germination process ideally will be
demisch you