welcome to this debaco university video
looking at germinating cannabis seeds
in soilless medium and kind of giving
you some
tips and advantages on why you would go
about
propagating your cannabis seeds in this
medium
[Music]
all right let's get started with the
video well first off it's important to
keep in mind of the basics for
germination no matter what substrate
media you're using certified seed source
these temperature moisture
air conditions how deep to plant your
seedlings and the light to provide them
at that early development stage
are all those germination basics you
need to keep in mind
so why would you use soils media what's
the advantage to using
stylus media well it can be purchased in
large quantities which is great
it's very easy to acquire typically and
when you do get it it is
disease and weed free so it makes for a
great starting material
it also has good water holding and
draining characteristics which is
very advantageous to growers to allow
those seedlings to establish themselves
quite well
it can be used in a variety of
containers which is great it's not
limiting to any one particular container
type a grower might be using
and growers can purchase specific blends
to best best match their needs as you
can see here
this one uh on this side says high
porosity
um so it's going to allow it to drain
and breathe very well typically maybe a
little bit better for a larger
um seed or to be used after the seedling
stage there
there's many different this is just
pro-mix it's just one example of the
many that are
out there the specifics when looking at
stairless media well regardless of the
manufacturer
a plug or germination mix should be used
and not a pot or
grow mix reason being is those plug or
germination mix will be made from a
finer material
to help ensure good seed to soil media
contact
while still providing air there's two
big air pockets in there
that seed could dry out or be at reduced
moisture level
and that could reduce your germination
percentage
and we could see just some comparisons
here of a finer material
down this way and a little bit coarser
material here so again you could use
that plugger germination mix just for it
says
the germination process and then
transition these seedlings to that grow
mix
or that pot or container mix when they
get a little bit older and don't need
that
fine material to allow for the
germination process anymore
now as the plant grows keep in mind that
plants can be upholded in a grower
potting mix could be used for this point
for in the grow cycle so you only want
to use that germination mix really
just to get them germinated typically in
those small trays it
packs in really well to the cells and
then you can continue to use the grill
or pot mix
for the duration once they have roots
for the duration of the growth cycle
there so that's your bulk media should
be that
and your germination next should only be
used during the germination process
to again help increase the odds of your
success
with your cannabis seeds