welcome to this tobacco university video
if you're looking at this video you're
probably looking at dribbling your
cannabis seeds in
rockwell or oasis and debacle university
here
is to provide you with some helpful tips
and tricks
to increase the odds of your success
[Music]
let's get into the video specifics well
first off when we're looking at
germany's seeds we have to keep in mind
that
we have some basics to be sure we're
adhering to
want to make sure the seed is from a
certified source we're keeping the
temperature within the accepted ranges
moisture level target level air
percentage depth
and light all need to be adhered to for
the basic environment to help ensure the
environment is supportive
of basic seed germination properties
now why would you use rockwell or oasis
well natural properties of both
are conducive to early plant
establishment both materials hold water
well while still providing roots
adequate air exchange allowing them to
respire and essentially breathe
and they often come in space efficient
trays with individual cubes per cut
which allow for very efficient
production on both a small scale as well
as a large scale so what are some
specifics particularly to rock wool
you want to typically soak your rock
well first before planting seeds in it
sometimes this may require soaking in
water that's ph tested
and if it's not required it might be a
good idea and should be something pretty
quick and easy for you to do
typically the small cubes are
recommended no matter where the ceiling
will be going for the rest of the growth
cycle
because they can be put into larger
blocks as we see here
common used example would be the grodan
o a cubes
they're a kind of name brand but they're
very established particularly in the
rockwool arena there for propagation
now as the plant grows we want to keep
this in mind that as the plant's growing
the cubes
are designed to fit into larger blocks
as we can see here is a small
cube that can easily be placed into this
larger block as a pre-cut hole
to allow during the trans planting
process
minimal root disturbance this is where
grodan block delta for example
they sell a series of different
sizes that all fit into one another that
allow for that natural progression
for a growing plant now both substrates
this is again for rockwell
and oasis are easily put into trays for
easy mass production in a small
area you can grow a lot of plants in a
very small square footage which is
advantageous
leave one planting spot empty though if
you're using a tray and particularly in
the middle
so that the water and the tray can be
properly determined to make sure you're
not under or over watering
your newly developing seedlings and
again this is true for both
substrates they can also be used for
clones as well as seeds
but here provide you hopeful with some
quick kind of general
tips for germinating your seeds
in either rockwell or oasis