okay here we're gonna look at a very
common question of should I get a
separate germination or propagation
media and should I get separate grow
media or can I just get one now familiar
with the germination process and what
that requires starting to recede and in
the girl process of the actual plant and
each of these can't have specific media
associated with that but is it worth
going through that extra staff there
well first off let's look at our
germination media also sometimes called
propagation mix
these are contains typically smaller
particles that help improve the soil to
see contact keep in mind that we need to
keep moisture levels consistent with the
seed to help increase our germination
rate and this is especially important
for smaller sized seeds this can help
reduce transplant shock so that's why
it's important to use a propagation mix
when looking at propagating or starting
especially small seeds in contrast to
that grow formulations they contain
larger particles they help aeration for
the growing of full-sized plants as we
see here our roots need to be able to
breathe even in the container here we to
allow this increased porosity so again
goes back to the question of should we
get specialized formulations of
propagation and grow media daily for
looking to maximize each step of the
process will yes but if we're going to
choose one grow formulations can be used
for propagation if there's been extra
careful attention at keeping the medium
moist and it may require increased
misting events or keeping that humidity
a little bit higher especially in the
early phases of the germination process
hopefully the answers and clarifies some
of the germination versus grow media's
and how each is specifically designed to
be used