here we're gonna look at the plant
hormone gibberellin now if you look at
the three plants pictured here in the
image and to kind of look at what the
difference is between them well it's the
distance between the nodes here the
inter known length in Gibran's do
influence the internet length of plants
so as we see here gibberellins or GI is
how their abbreviations short there's
actually more than a hundred known G
days this subscript denotes the specific
G a so this would be an example of GA 3
remember subscript is located below it's
known to be essential for stem
elongation and gibberellin or GA causes
dwarf mutant plants to actually grow
tall if you have a dwarf mutant in the
ad G A's to that you actually get that
plant to return too close to normal or
at least get taller then it's mutant
variety dwarf plants on the other hand
are often plants that lack gibberellins
and that's what causes their dwarfism we
see a very classic picture here of some
cabbage plants here's the normal cabbage
plants that we see over here and here's
ones I've been applied with GA and we
see how tall they can get how those
internodes between those leads can
stretch to enormous heights compared to
the normal jube realms are also involved
in seed germination G's will induce
genes to make enzymes that break down
starch initially we have our endosperm
that's our stored energy well TAS can
initiate the breakdown of their
endosperm so it can be used for the seed
to initially start the formation of the
root even growing up the chute to get
above the soil so two realms are
involved in seed germination the sense
of being able to initiate the breakdown
of that food source so that it can start
to be used to Germany that seedling
another thing G A's are used for is can
be the effects on grapes for example the
fruit development see the grapes that
are treated with GA is another very
classic picture are much larger and it
looks swelled up basically compared to
grapes that were untreated so if you
ever see those large plump giant grapes
could be a result of
the plant hormone gibberellin