in this debacco University video I'm
going to go over gland trium structure
and biosynthesis to give you a better
appreciation for the formation of this
plant
[Music]
structure all right let's get into a
review of the Articles so there are two
articles so this is the first one here
um again some great information provided
in these as well as the citation
provided here as well as in the
description this is the first one and
then this is the second one and based on
the slide I'll cite what source it came
from so first off kind of like this
General summary slide here uh that kind
of gives you an idea of a little bit of
the experimentation as well as the
progression of plants how long they
spend in kind of that long day
vegetative stage compared to the short
day conditions where they're flowering
also when the researchers recommend
applying that silver nitrate treatment
as we look at the development of the
growth cycle of the plant as well as
some other uh scientific studies that
they um looked at and did just good for
timing and good general
information now looking at the um
researchers and what they provided you
with the kind of the general timelines
there in more of a word form and I
provided you some general pictures here
but cannabis does exhibit a relatively
short growth cycle lasting only about 2
to 5 months the seeding stage is defined
for somewhere in that 3 to 10 day range
post germination in the vegetative
growth stage we're growing the leaves
and the plant structure and the roof
Roots it's about 20 to 30 days and this
is when the plants Focus really on that
root and choot development rapid growth
of the upper part of the plant is
maintained for 10 to 30 days and then of
course there's the focus on flower and
pre flowers we can see right here are
shoots as cuting are suitable for
asexual uh propagation the flowering is
initiated in cannabis can be induced by
subjecting the plants to a short day
conditions again not talking about autof
flowers but this short day conditions
could induce flowering at any stage or
any age you want to be careful and
that's why I show those timelines is
that's when it's most advantageous
because you want a plant that can
actually support uh flowers uh for the
end result after approximately a week
flowers begin to appear at the top of
branches post switching it to a short
day the flowering phase typically lasts
for about a month now when we're looking
at the growth experiment which I
mentioned the um silver nitrate when
treating with the hormones or silver
nitrate female plants can be transformed
into male plants which is great for
breeding purposes
the harvesting of inflorescence for
cannabinoids is typically done when the
pistols have withered and some of the
tricomes are in amber color of other
videos going into that in more detail if
female flowers are pollinated during the
flowering phase seeds can be collected
after approximately a month when they
should be mature and allowing you to
grow the next phase new varieties with
high CBD yield can be obtained through
carbonization breeding or molecular
breeding techniques which is great ways
to get new varieties while we're always
seeing new things come into the market
place now different types of uh
glandular triom so GT when you see that
abbreviation that's going to stand for
glandular tricomes so just keep that in
mind for that
abbreviation now scanning electron
microsopy analysis illustrating the
different uh glandular tricomes Types on
the surface of various tissues in our
cannabis ativa so we see type one type
two type three and type four and we can
see them defined right here where type
one is that capit struck stocked glander
triome type three is the capid cile
gland triome three is the bulbus and
four is the nonsecretory there now we
can see in the flowering uh Primary
tricomes in this area of the plant
you're going to find uh potentially all
five definitely as you get later into
harvest the BRS here are also going to
find a five in that top portion on the
stem you find primarily just the type
four which don't secrete any
cannabinoids and the leaf also primary
type four so again just because you're
finding tricomes don't mean that there
are the triom that contain the
cannaboids and tpin many Growers are
seeking so regory Network I don't want
to get too much into the detail of this
but this is a summarized transcriptional
regulatory Network and what I want you
to take away from this is the
complexities of this now this isn't done
actually on cannabis it's done actually
on tomato and sweet wormwood which also
have tricomes which are analogous or
similar uh to cannabis we need to see
some more of that cannabis specific
research but this is providing our
starting point because we need a
starting point cuz it's so complex now
where we see the arrows those indicate
an uppr regulation and where we see the
kind of ended kind of blunt lines there
uh that indicates a down regulation or
inhibition so certain things certain uh
components can upregulate things and
certain things can downregulate or
suppress things and how these are
interacting which is really important to
better understand the full development
of these tricomes in the cannaboids and
Turpin that they
contain so looking a little more at the
details here of the biosynthesis going
to break these apart into a little more
detail um we can see the basic structure
which you're hopefully visually uh used
to looking at but then we're going to go
into a little bit of that kind of that
zoomed in here so just what's occurring
in this region be is a zoom in version
of that and just what's occurring in
this region to zoom in of that so you
can see again how you want to look at it
macroscopically as well as potentially
microscopically and this is another uh
schematic model here showing the struct
trium development again different
research Pi showing how it formations on
that epidermal area there and kind of
kind of forms a little bit of a bulb and
then kind of forms that stocked region
eventually and again zoomed in versions
of different regions there great
diagrams to pause the video take a look
at or go back to the original
study now structural diagram here of
those that are secreting uh those
cannabis GL tricomes are distinctive
secretory secretory structures that are
critical in the production and
reservation of uh cannabinoids primarily
found in the brain Rax flowers of female
cannabis plants they said those founds
on the leaves those founds on the main
stems They Don't Really secrete anything
now mature granular triom showing the
extracellular storage cavity and
secretory cells on the large
multicellular stock now following grul
triome inhibition poal cells
differentiating into secretary absis and
stock cells so what we're having here is
this development these specialized
structures as we're developing this
stocked region on there it's basically
causing the droplet to form on the top
or the cavity to form on top where all
those droplets are going to be added to
that's where it's going to swell up and
that's where a lot of those storage
areas are going to be kept distinctly
and physically away from the leaf and
plant
surface now again this is what they look
like kind of if you're looking at used
to looking at through a magnifying Loop
uh they are known as the plant chemical
factories these areas here uh where
they're secreting synthesizing
accumulating and storing multiple
secondary metabolites for example
cannaboid
these structures are primarly found on
the bra and flowers of female canvas
plants and here we can see them in high
density now the isolation analysis of
Canam glander tricomes cbga and thca are
produced in both bulbless glander
tricomes and stocked ones as well and
you can see here's the bulbous ones very
very small and then the um stocked ones
that you're probably more familiar with
CBC and CBN were specifically detected
in bulbous um stocked tricomes so again
these are the ones here and stocked
tricomes have higher accumulations of
monot Turpin and this is based on auto
fluoresence studies that were conducted
there and just as reminder it's thca and
cbga because that's the plant form um
and then that's kind of the acid form
that then needs to be DEC carboxilate to
make the active form for The receptors
in
humans now canab synthesis uh the
synthesis have greater metabolic
efficiencies in hydrophobic environments
compared to aquous ones so lipid based
fat-based environments are going to be
the ones that are more favorable the
metabolite polysaccharide wall bound may
be a favorable micro environment that is
well suited for th biosynthesis and this
could explain the Abundant synthesis and
secretion of canano in these glandular
tricomes however the ability of these
glandular tricomes which again are small
in physical size to produce and secrete
these significant quantities of
secondary metabolites Still Remains a
mystery so there's a lot that still
needs to be studied let the Sy be better
understood about these specific Pathways
of how these plants go about producing
these now the stock gler triome
development then development trajectory
of stock gler tricomes from the pral
initiation which is on the left here to
the cesil like intermediate with a small
metabolite droplet to the mature
overmature tricomes all the way on the
right so we know a little bit about the
formation of the physical structure um
of these and how they go about those
distinctive stages but understanding
more about the um intercellular and the
gene regulation um is definitely
needed now that triome development again
the first step of that Trion development
is a different differentiation of those
cells trigger a series of cell divisions
resulting in that epidermal outgrowth
that stocked formation that physical
stocked towerer like look the exact
regulatory mechanisms that trigger the
development of these cells in cannabis
at least is still unknown so again we
know what kind of what happens just
don't know what triggers it what
initiate um that other species as I said
like tomato and sweet wormwood are
providing useful comparisons but we need
to research cannabis a little bit
further now the can interpreting
biosynthesis here so secretory cells
form this inter interconnected [ __ ] uh
responsible for canabo and turpine
biosynthesis transport and storage this
sinum is a single cell or cytoplasmic
mass containing several nuclei formed by
Fusion of cells or by division of the
nuclei and the formation of this storage
cavity will occur through the de
elimination of the cell wall so here we
can see again this zoomed in portion
kind of what's occurring right here
we've got all these important organel
within the cell we're looking at these
particular regions um here or where this
is occurring giving us an idea where to
start focusing some of the
research now distribution of the
plastids here so when we're looking at
the distribution of PL plaids in the
secretory stage of these glander Tricom
Placid move between cells via apertures
in the glander triome cell wall and
those are located right here so like
little spaces or gaps if you will um and
this is right below the cell wall and
leading into that storage cavity so
again we're taking this very zoomed in
kind of approach here but we're looking
at understanding at least initially
where some of these uh distributions are
occurring now the formation of the canab
oids uh this is where cbga likely
partitions into the plasmid membrane
Bayer and canid biosynthesis occurs at
the dis cell wall where thca synthesis
or cbda synthesis catalyzes cbga to
produce thca or cbga respectively so
keep in mind that that uh CBG is that
precursor molecule that then is made by
the plant's Direction into THC or CBD um
so again it gets very complex here just
trying to give a general overview and
hopefully just an appreciation for
what's occurring uh even though we tend
to only look at those end products can
it's form the lipophilic metabolite
droplets within the apical cell wall
creating a storage cavity in space and
ultimately that's where it's going and
that's where we start to look at our
tricomes going from that clear to cloudy
to potentially Amber
colorations now distribution oh
sorry now the cannabinoid bioin pathway
here again looking at a little bit more
detail from the other researchers
provided those metabolites interact with
the specialized cell wall components to
form small metabolite droplets that
basically coales into a large Central
droplet and mature in the triome the
high resolution electronic mycra
demonstrates that these canid secory dis
nonphotosynthetic uh plastids which are
producing all these GPS PS contain
unusual crystall likee lattice structure
at the core what does that look like
that's basically this kind of physical
structure which looks like basically a
pattern you might see on a weave pattern
of for example of a fabric the immunog
globe tem transmission electron
microscope using antibody specific thcas
localized thcas on the surface of cell
walls so now we kind of know where to
look at those surface of the cell walls
of those secretory disc cells underlying
the storage cavity but are not the anti-
clinical or basil cell walls so we're
developing this understanding to kind of
have this delimination Zone this area of
where things might be occurring or at
least eliminating some areas where
they're probably not occurring and the
formation of these extracellular
cavities occurs by the delimination and
separation of those dis cells walls
resulting in the wall layer that remains
continuous with the plasma membrane
which is the surface of the cell wall
and a secondary a second that remains
continuous with the with the cuticle sub
cuticle layer so we're looking at these
different layers lers when we're looking
at the building of these structures
we're having these layers the cell is
starting to develop these separate
Pockets or the separate categories um
there allowing those certain compounds
to accumulate in different areas so it's
these very specifically directed
specialization areas that those genes
that are being activated to start to
cause these separated in distinctive
regions are important to develop in
understanding for now extracellular
storage again to some cool macroscopic
pictures here canab turpine products are
warehoused in the extrasellar storage
cavity these compounds are stored
essentially outside and away from the
plant important kind of key step here
hope you tuned in this long where these
compounds are very physically separated
from the plant uh physically in a
different location yes made by the plant
but stored kind of as far away from the
plant as possible uh which is an
interesting kind of plant evolutionary
aspect of why is it developing these
compounds and why are they kept so far
away from the plant final multicellular
stocks rise to GL or triom heads above
the epidermis giving the canas flower
their Frosty appearance so while this is
a really zoomed in look to it um that's
what's a bunch of these kind of this
high density is causing that Frosty look
to them they go from that clear kind of
that milky white kind of
appearance now lastly stoms mature the
microsopy did show that once stoms have
reached maturity turning in amberik
color we can see here resin droplets are
secreted on the surface of the gland
your head and the cuticle collapses
inward so this is the point at which
we're looking at Peak maturity of those
tricomes of those kind of secretory
compounds uh put there so I no this was
a little bit of a detailed look the uh
research article is going into more
detail but gives you an appreciation for
that color change or those structures
you might be looking at and hopefully
looking at in great detail what the
plant's actually doing and also a little
maybe a little shocking to try to
understand the research that still needs
to continually be done to better
understand this process