welcome back to another debaco
university video
here looking at different types of glass
and we see three general categories
provided here
annealed tempered and laminated along
with some properties listed below them
but we're going to go into even more
detail here so first starting with well
how is glass made well glass is a hard
brittle amorphous which means
it's molecules lack organization
material so it's made from fused
inorganic materials by melting sand lime
and sodium sodium carbonate at very high
temperatures
this varies in elemental form again
depending what type of glass
and as a result many shapes and colors
can be derived
in glasses we see here with all the
various birds
and various ornamentals of glass and
here's the manufacturing process as well
so sodium soda lime glass so this is the
most common type of glass which accounts
for 90
of manufactured glass so if you're
finding this type at a crime scene
may not be the best at kind of getting
into this very something very specific
but it can still provide other valuable
trace evidence by linking someone to a
crime scene
the reason why it's so common is it's
found in window panes beverage bottles
and light bulbs
has a density of 2.44 grams per cubic
centimeter
then we have a borosilicate glass this
melts at a higher
temperature than typical silicate glass
so it's used in cookware and lab
equipment such as beakers
where high heat tends to be involved
it's also known
by its trade name pyrex since 1915
and that's what a lot of the beakers
here are made of or even this
measuring cup here we see pyrex listed
right in the center it has a density
very similar to the sodium lime glass at
2.23
grams per centimeter cubed then we have
leaded glass so this is fine glassware
and decorative art glass called crystal
lead glass
sometimes it substitutes lead oxide for
calcium oxide or lime
to make it a little bit more
environmentally friendly the addition of
lead oxide makes the glass denser and as
light passes through the more dense
glass the light
waves are bent and this gives the glass
that sparkling
effect so really important for its
visual characteristics
but now can also be used to tie in when
you're collecting it potentially as
trace evidence
we also have tempered or safety glass so
this is stronger than ordinary glass by
introducing
stresses to rapid heating and cooling of
the glass surface
when tempered glass breaks it doesn't
shatter but rather fragments or dices
into small squares
with little splintering it's used for
side and rear windows and automobiles
sold in the united states keep in mind
it's the side in the rear
and if you look at it through a
polarizing lens or if you're wearing
sunglasses and then them kind of tilt
your head a little bit to one side or
the other
you can kind of see that kind of
temperature safety glass it has a
certain look to it
particularly looking here at the rear
car window now in support i said side
and rear
a cart window because a laminated glass
is the glass used
on the front windshield and limited
glass
derives its strengths by sandwiching one
layer of plastic between two pieces of
ordinary
window glass the windshields of all cars
manufactured in the united states are
constructed of this
laminated glass because as a result we
can kind of see here
it doesn't shatter and break through it
kind of fractures but stays together
which is very important for the
windshield so nothing's coming at the
driver or passengers
then we have bulletproof glass and as
the name implies looking at resisting
the impact from bullets
it achieves this by a combination of two
or more types of glass one hardened one
in one soft the softer layer makes the
glass more elastic so it can flex
instead of shattering
the index of refraction for both the
layers must be very similar though
this is to keep the glass transparent
and allow a clear view
through the glass this is why looking
this glass in particular very quickly
won't be you won't be able to quickly
identify it as being bulletproof or not
because it should look
like normal glass the bulletproof glass
does vary in thickness from three
quarters of an inch to three inches and
that can depend how many layers there
are
this is a rough kind of depiction here
bulletproof glass composed of layers of
plastic sheeting which would be the gray
and then layers of actual typical glass
and that would be the blue
that will resist depending how many
layers the caliber or the force of
impact
how much will it resist that bullet
that's coming at it
then we have optical or flint glass and
this has a high refractive index on raf
1.45 to 2.0
a disposal poses a pollution problem for
older glass
manufactured of this type because they
tend to contain lead to oxide
now titanium dioxide and zarconium
dioxides are used making it less of an
issue
while still maintaining its great
optical properties
also used to make simulated diamonds it
has this very clear
high refractive index light dispersion
here in the image
above me is looking at the mercury vapor
lamp in a prism made of
flint glass again that really high
optical quality
and lastly we have mirrored glass and
this is glass that's been treated with
metallic
substances creating mirror-like
properties this can
be so we can be able to see ourselves in
the morning
this is just another type of mirrored or
reflective glass
and all of these have the potential to
be found at a crime scene
so now that you're well versed in them
when you're picking up these pieces of
trace evidence you can make these
connections
potentially identify the type of glass
and where it might be found at a crime
scene