welcome to another debaco university
video
here looking at glass as evidence
involved with crime scenes
so first off will what is glass we need
to define what that is and
while this glass may not have a specific
melting point it will soften
over a temperature range and that can be
important where arson
or high heat might be involved with a
particular crime scene
glass is also a uniform amorphous solid
which means it has irregular atomic
structure
which causes it to break a variety of
fraction patterns
which can vary based on impact
force of impact angle of impact and also
the type of glass
so how is glass used in forensic science
well small fragments can be used as
trace evidence to link objects and
people through
through crime scene reconstruction
process and that can be involved with
directly
for example where a bullet is piercing a
piece of glass
or sometimes even accidental or
something might be knocked over
and broken and those trace elements
might be picked up
by the person at the scene and
found later by an investigator on their
clothing or potentially within their
shoes
this is often present in like places
that are robs or
burglaries or hit and run accidents as
well so it's important to keep in mind
of this glass evidence now in the actual
crime scene work
may it be used well automobile accidents
where a broken headlight or even
windshield glass
could be fractured or damaged a store
break in as i mentioned
where shards of window glass with fibers
or blood on them can also help
link a person to a scene shots fired
into a window
the sequence into actual direction of
the bullets can often be determined by
examining the glass
these small minute particles of glass
may be transferred to a subject's
shoes or clothing and can provide a
source of trace evidence
linking the suspect to the actual crime
scene
this is again helpful but keep in mind
that we really have to be looking for
these very small
small pieces these trace evidence
when we're collecting a glass as
investigators it's important we do so
in a way that tries to collect as many
samples as possible but it's also
protective to you
we also want to in that process want to
collect these
standard reference glass should be taken
from the crime scene we're looking about
an
inch um square i want to package it in a
solid container to prevent breakage
and indicate interior and exterior
surfaces
if possible the presence of dirt paint
grease or putty may help
identify the inside and outside surfaces
if they're known
so if you're looking at a piece of glass
if maybe a window and you know where the
outside is
make note of what side that is on the
glass that you're collecting
i want to preserve garments with glass
on it that can include shoes pants
even shorts anything that may have that
potential for carrying that trace
evidence all broken glass must be
recovered and submitted to analysis
when direction of impact is desired in
as many pieces
as possible to help make that process as
simplified as can be now when we get
these pieces of glass evidence well when
the suspect
and crime scene fragments are assembled
and physically fit together and this can
be a very
time consuming process comparison of
this type uh do require the piecing of
these irregularities in the broken glass
as well as matching all these
and irregularities and striations on the
broken surfaces
the possibility that two pieces of glass
originating from different sources will
fit together exactly
is unlikely and this is a way to exclude
other sources from
physical consideration unfortunately
most glass evidence is either too
fragmented or too minute to permit
a comparison of this type that's part of
the reason why it's so important to try
to collect as many
pieces as possible it gets a little more
confusing if you have
a window that's broken into and then for
example
a wine glass breaks or some other form
of glass a mirror is shattered
you kind of get those mixing of the two
pieces there
now when we're comparing our glass
samples
the goal is to find and measure the
properties that will associate one glass
fragment to another while minimizing or
limiting the possibility exists
of other sources due to common
occurrences of glass it can present
quite a challenge
so even though there's glasses of
different types
it can be a difficult comparison to make
there there are methods
so just keep that in mind that while
this will help you tell part of the
story
it's not going to be the one defining
factor it's going to take probably
other ways of collecting of other
evidence
and this would be one component which
could be a very important component
which is why
when collecting samples we want to be
very mindful of
ensuring we're collecting a quality
sample