welcome to debacle university where here
we're going to be looking
at determining and glass density
and what can it can tell us about
evidence that might be found in a crime
scene
so glass density and refractive index
are both used most successfully in
classifying glass particles
this is a class characteristics we want
to keep this in mind it's not an
individual characteristic it's only a
class characteristic this allows us only
to exclude
glass fragments that may have originated
from different sources
can't tell us it came from the front
window it can always tell us it came
maybe from a window
compared to maybe glass that might be in
a canning jar for example or a mirror
for example might be different types of
glass
so this density can allow us to classify
that
now looking at different densities or a
little chart here of different densities
window glass does not have a uniform
density so you want to take some
samples from different locations the
edge of
tempered glass is denser than the
interior so keep that in mind if you are
looking at
tempered glass and there's a database of
glass samples for comparison so i've
just provided you with a couple
densities here various materials
just for the sense of comparison keep in
mind the densest is that flint or
optical glass and it's got
7.2 grams per centimeters cubed all the
way down to
sand being only 1.52 grams per
centimeters cubed
now when we determine the density how do
we go about this
well each type of glass has a specific
density to allow for these comparisons
to occur
density capital d here is calculated by
dividing the mass
divided by the volume so keep in mind
that
we reason why this is in a heart we want
to think about kind of like
m over v so we look at the very top here
the top of the heart kind of looks like
an
m and the bottom side here kind of looks
like a v so it's an
easy way to remember it's mass over
volume
we want to do this by kind of getting
the weighing the substance getting the
mass of the particular
glass that we have and then the volume
is usually found by the displacement
method because its shape tends to be
irregular
the formula for calculating density then
can be applied and you can get the
density of the glass
and that can help you potentially or at
least narrow down
what type of glass you have found and
are looking at identifying