so here we're going to go over what
properties define good water so for
plants are typically wanting to irrigate
with good water well what does that look
like what does that contain and I go
over some of those properties here so
starting with potable or drinking water
this is water that has a high
cleanliness rating this is the symbol
for it and what potable means now that
can be used for drinking but it can also
be used for cooking or food preparation
tap water meets the drinking water
standards but this does not mean all
water is the same this means is that
just because it's drinking a potable
that means you can drink it but it
doesn't mean that there's any set
standards for exactly what it contains
there's certain levels that needs to
meet to be defined as this drinking
water but there could be different
levels of chlorine or cured imide or
other kind of properties in it that
would still classify it as drinking
water but can have other adverse effects
if you're looking at adding microbes for
example so good water is critical so
again what defines that good water
well potable drinking water as I say is
a good start but you're also looking for
properties such as as a neutral pH
around seven low easy or electrical
connectivity and minimal additives such
as chlorine because chlorine is gonna
kill some microbes and could cause some
other issues with growing plants that
would be perfectly fine and safe for
drinking so again the drinking water
potable waters good place to start but
there are some other properties you
should be checking there's something
called grey water and this is second
grade water it's not like perfectly
clean it's kind of at this grayish look
to it this is typically used for
flushing toilets but it can also be used
for irrigation so I think you have to
use potable or drinking water for
irrigation grey water is often used for
irrigation however if it is used there
can be risks associated with it so it
needs to be used with caution and in
different situations it may be more
advantageous than others so it's good
whether it's drinking water grey water
or whatever irrigation water you're
using is to get it tested good for
multiple tests in multiple samples I'm
just taking one test at one time and
consider that good for the entire year
for example if using city water you can
get a report from the place where you
get it from the municipality and
see the metropolitan district Commission
of Connecticut is one in the local area
here that's great at providing testing
so the MDC and they prepare water
quality reports annually provide
summaries of past years water quality
the test one hundred and thirty
potential water contaminants reservoirs
treatment plants forty seven state
approved sampling sites throughout
twelve towns service areas they
distribute an average of fifty million
gallons of water per day to a population
about four hundred thousand located in
the state of Connecticut they've been
great I've personally just called them
up and I was able to get a water sample
report for water samples that they had
pulled the previous day in my local area
so again reach out to where you're
getting your water from if you are
getting it from a from the tap water
source they can provide you with reports
not only annual that sometimes very
current you can also test it yourself to
ensure that you have properties that
constitute good water