okay so here I'm gonna go over the
basics of a Gram stain and this is used
for identifying certain bacteria based
on the type of exterior structure that
these prokaryotes have so starting with
the basics Gram stain as it says in the
name it's a staining technique for
primarily identification of bacteria
there's something called a gram positive
my gram negative so what's this
referring to as gram positive bacteria
located up here they have a very thick
outer cell wall here I'll peptidoglycan
gram negative had this kind of
protective outer layer here this doesn't
allow the stain really penetrate so I
think about gram positive you've
positively accepting the dye
I'm gram negative not kind of accepting
the main die there in the outer outer
walls so for example here we have a
plasma membrane and this outer area here
is our pepto glycan this is our gram
positive you see how it's very thick
here we there's a peptidoglycan layer in
it gram negative but this exterior here
is kind of a polysaccharide in the
protein the peptidoglycan here is really
good absorbing some of this purple dye
but because it's embedded below another
membrane that's that stain really
doesn't work all that well or if it's a
gram positive bacteria because of that
thick peptidoglycan while being on the
outside it is able to accept some of
that dye so difference in diabete engine
is depend on the physical and chemical
properties of the bacterial cell wall in
this case the exterior portion is cell
wall this gram stain was developed in
the 1800's by someone by the last name
gram and that's where it gets its name
from so here's the basic procedure
so just remember grandpa's bacteria
thick dense relatively non-porous walls
long comparison gram-negative bacteria
have thin walls surrounded by a lipid
rich membranes
think of lipids as kind of repelling
things this is a detailed procedure here
I'm gonna go through it kind of step by
step for you another example of the gram
staining procedure what things are going
to look like
we're looking at basically making our
bacterial cells either purple or red
let's go through this kind of this
procedure again I got this off online
here I made some modifications myself
but you always want to be careful to set
your sources so I'm including that here
step one of a gram same procedure
prepare the smear so you're taking your
bacteria you're smearing them on a slide
suspend some material stained in the
drop stand in a drop of water and a
microscope slide spread the drop about
the size of a nickel allow to air dry
initially then heat fix by gently
warming above the flame or other heat
source what this is doing this is fixing
the bacteria so we're basically sticking
them to the slide here we just let the
drop of water dry I think when we re wet
that I'm just going to slide around this
fixing procedure not only denatures that
in basel but it allows them to also the
stick to the slide wouldn't be careful
make them as thin as possible if it's
too thick it won't work really great so
thin is very important here okay
procedure to apply the primary stain
flood stands in this case crystal
eyelets a very purple color will last
and for thirty Seconds to a minute and
rinsed water to remove excessive stain
so here just a little circles and boxes
or different bacteria we flood the whole
areas crystal violet then we let it sit
for a period of time then here's our
same bacteria we flood the smear with
iodine solution will allow that stand
for 30 seconds to a minute you'll notice
technically at this point of the Gram
stain procedure all of our bacteria are
purple a couple other important areas
will go through a little change those
colors we want to rinse off to remove
excessive iodine so now they're all the
item that was here we've rinsed all that
off and now it is ten they have all
ourselves being purple but we're not
done yet
Step five is to decolorize this is
important step when I dip it in 95%
alcohol or drip ninety-five percent
alcohol across the entire slide for only
about five seconds this will basically
decolorize those cells that aren't
holding on to that stain very strongly
you can notice here there are a lighter
purple color well these are still a
strong part more if you let it sit for
too long
all the cells so not only is the
procedure and steps important but also
timing they'll enter rinsed remove all
excess alcohol what that's going to do
is kind of leave us with the purple
cells and now these are decolorized we
want to counter stain the Safran
solution is very kind of deep red
solution pour this on the side let the
stand for 30 seconds then we want to
rinse dry and observe with that staff is
saying does is it takes those that don't
have any color and it just binds lightly
and those are a gram negatives we don't
want to sit too long or kind of mess up
the crystal violet of the gram positives
so this is why timing is important so
rinse with water move excesses stain
blot dry and observant of the oil
immersion of the microscope gives it
same basic procedure I walked you
through it and you're welcome to pause
the video and look this over you feel
this might be more helpful but this is
kind of the end result that you get and
as a result we can see if they're very
rod shaped a very circular shaped both
of these are gram positives indicating
these have that very thick peptidoglycan
wall example cream stands for the
negative here's to the rods and the
circles again King was a very thin of
neglecting and basically having a
thicker lipid on the lipid layer on the
outside here this slide contains both
this is from the previous image and this
contains both of the gram positives and
grand negatives on the same slide
looking again look a little closer look
at those gram negatives zooming in on
that you know that so cell layers here
there's cell walls we see there's an
inner and outer membrane the
peptidoglycan is located here kind of
sandwiched between the two as a result
that crystal violet can't really bind or
stick to this very well and this is why
we call them gram negatives lastly
there's a couple of video links if
you're interested in learning more if
you feel to just want to review you're
welcome to watch the video again hope
that was helpful