and we're looking at greenhouse frame
design options there's many to choose
from this one's actually an image from
the New York Botanical Gardens and while
this may look like an impressive frame
design structure it's rarely used in
production due to some of his
inefficiencies some more efficient
designs once called a nor'easter version
and this has a peak in the middle to
deal with snow that's common in the
Northeast United States it's a very
strong freestanding greenhouse structure
and it also that often has a trust
support system to offer even more
strength so this design this peak design
ideally reduces the chance of snow
building up on top as we see on this car
so instead of it building up it can kind
of work its way and slide off that
greenhouse with hopefully minimal effort
or labor needed from the outside to help
remove that that's what it has that
well-defined peak in the middle when
it's not at the peak but is also
designed to really maximize that floor
space so it's called a traditional hoop
house these tend to be cheaper they're
very simple and easy to construct and we
could see them on the larger scale here
and here and also on the smaller scale
here that inherent curved design is very
supportive and allows the structure to
be very strong even though it's just a
very simple Hoopa design we have a high
side frame this increases the greenhouse
height to allow for increased internal
space it makes it easier to put benches
upright to the side walls in addition
this increased height creates a greater
distance between a very hot air to the
crop level so that can be advantageous
especially if you're growing into kind
of extending this season where you still
maybe have an early warmup or a late
warmup this can also help moderate those
temperatures at least at the crop level
a little bit more then there's the open
roof design this is the most expensive
design for greenhouses due to the
ingenuity to open the roof and you could
see you have some partially open roofs
here and then a full open roof here
however this is the most efficient
cooling method because all the hot air
rises so this is extra an excellent
venting area and here when they open the
entire
'we really efficiently allows that heat
to be vented out of the greenhouse very
quickly as a result I think this is kind
of the best design in the sense that
you're venting the hottest air you're
alive for great air circulation it's a
very passive system but it does require
a lot of ingenuity here and structure to
make it happen but again looking at a
permanent structure this might be worth
it an option considering and see if you
can justify the upfront cost