Narrator: Okay. When looking at a greenhouse,  because it's a permanent structure, we should
be very concerned with the location and the  orientation of that particular structure,
because it's going to be fixed in place, and  we want to maximize plant productivity within
that particular grow area. Important to make  the distinction between greenhouses and high
tunnels. Greenhouses are permanent structures.  They typically have heat and electricity, and a
permanent floor. Generally speaking, compared to  high tunnels, they are more expensive and they can
cover larger areas. High tunnels are the basic  structures, are basically poly here and hoops,
plants that are grown right in soil. As  a result, they're less expensive. They
don't really allow for a full, calendar-year  production, especially in colder climates,
and typically cover 4,000 square feet or less. Now, focusing, again, on the greenhouse
production, these are permanent locations. As  a result, growers have control over many of
the climactic conditions. They also provide  consistency, and a fixed plant moving and
support structures here. Because they are  solid, fixed structures, it allows growers
to plan accordingly to maximize plant production.  They're well suited for full-year production, and
they can have supplemental lighting added, also,  to them. This is a cloudy day, and you can see,
a little hard to see, not a lot of sun. We have  some supplemental lights on, air circulation,
also, is important. That's helping us maintain  our plants in the right photo period and also
receiving sufficient light. Again, those permanent  locations allow for adequate planning, and running
here are irrigation lines and heating lines.  You can also see supplemental lighting in here.
Now, location of the greenhouses should be in  an area that gets maximum sunlight exposure for
the entire year. Large, flat areas, can have  easy access to water and electricity to run
to them is advised. It might be an ideal  location, right in the middle of a field,
here, but if we can't run water and electricity,  it's going to present an issue. Want to consider,
also, ease of access by vehicles to transport  material to and from the facility, that could
be potting media, that could be end product.  Don't want to have it in the middle of nowhere.
You want to kind of pick a good location  and consider all these particular factors.
Now, the orientation of the greenhouse should  be based on the season. It's going to match
up with the main productive cycle. For fall, and  winter, spring production, it's advised to orient
the greenhouse in an east-to-west to help  capture lower sun angle effectively. However, a
north-to-south orientation is advised to maximize  light penetration and benefit ventilation,
also. The orientation may not be 100% chosen  because there's constraints of certain areas,
but depending when you want to run your main  production cycle, may influence the exact
orientation, to the north, south, east, west  direction you choose to run your greenhouse.