within growing media what's becoming
very popular now is having companies add
biological components to their mixes
biological clones to include fungi or
abet our bacteria funny being
mycorrhizae or Trichoderma species
doctoring being vassilis if you put in
on the petri dishes he may look
something like this but they can to add
them to help benefit the plant or reduce
pathogens is the goal so these pre and
Acula it mixes while there's some
advantages to potentially reducing
pathogens typically would be best to add
the material yourself you know see here
for example this pro mix has mycorrhizae
added these are living components all
have a shelf life and it's best to add
fresh material that you know if it's
within the stated shelf life so for
example if you're buying your soilless
mix here in large bulk and you're only
using a portion of it and you're saving
it the shelf life of those microbes
could degrade over time those grower
added mixes allows the grower to know
that fresh product has been added it
offers the opportunity for growers to
interests at specific issues if you're
looking at reducing damping off for
example you may want to add products
specifically for that purpose this
provides flexibility to change the mix
based on your application just two
examples here of you know some have
blend products where they're adding on
that only mycorrhizae products but
bacillus and trichoderma blends
all-in-one along with a couple nutrients
and that's common in both of these
products here it's important to look for
the propagation propagules program or CF
use colony forming units per gram when
you're looking at comparing the
microbial density of certain products
however this brings up a question of are
they worth it this can be a debated
topic and in controlled cases where many
other plant requirements are being
maximized such as light nutrients and
water the positive effects of these
microbes might be reduced as a result
increase in the cost may not be
justified so you're looking at typically
the cost of some of these products
versus the potential benefits if you're
maximizing light nutrients in water and
potentially carbon dioxide the
availability and the
benefits of these added microbes may not
be worth it will they do any harm
typically no but the cost may be cost
prohibitive in the sense that you might
be adding more cost to the situation and
not getting necessarily a return for
that in the end product