in this video on debaco university we're
going to be looking at growing cannabis
in a grow tent compared to a grow room
so come join us
all right let's compare both of these
indoor spaces
so first off when we're talking about a
grow tent or a
room they're both indoor growing areas
and while tents can be quite large
in comparison smaller indoor locations
are grown
in tents with larger plantings or in
grow rooms
however grow tents do offer the ability
to conduct isolated small-scale
experiments in isolated conditions
and do have their place potentially
thinking about
in general terms from male plants with
pollen trying to keep that in isolated
location
this can be a special importance again
we're talking about breeders
looking at isolating those male plants
away from a male away from a main grow
room
this could be advantageous for them for
sort of looking at conducting little
trials or different
lighting sequences or something where we
need control over the conditions
grow tent maybe offer that opportunity
as well as growing full term in
so first off the grow tents what are
some of the advantages associated with
grow tents
well they're a great way to get started
with cannabis production or any really
any plant production
as it allows for small controlled
environments and
allows people the advantage of
potentially having them in small closets
or areas that might be
size limited they also make great for
isolated areas for comparison if you're
trying to compare two different things
in one isolated environment for that
grow tents offer that advantage it's
also quick and easy to set up and
maintain a variety of general room
environments for looking at having
potentially a veg grow tent
and then a flower grow tent maybe a
drying cure grow tent it offers those
advantages
however the disadvantages of rotans is
simply they're small
in size they're just a little size
restrictive even the largest ones
you can also have a high cost to plant
ratio because you have to support
each individual environment with all the
necessary equipment
and they only alter the environment to
some degree so if you have a grow tent
in a room that's very hot
to be hard to sufficiently cool that
just as the opposite it's a really cold
might be hard to sufficiently heat that
area compare that to a grow room the
advantages of a grow room is just simply
their
large area an ability to regulate the
room to match the conditions of the
plant
and allows for very efficient plant
production simply because of the scale
or the volume that's able to produce
however the disadvantages with growth
rooms is that they can be costly to
initially set up and it doesn't really
allow for plant isolations
yes you might kind of move them over to
one area or another but for the most
part they're all in the same environment
this can also lead to quick disease or
insect spread especially if you have a
high plant
density in a limited area here of a grow
room where we're looking at kind of
everything being packed in despite its
large size
the plant density is still very high
here and that can lead to some spread of
disease potentially quicker
if those plants are spaced out a little
bit more so you want to weigh the
options for your
indoor growing situation decide whether
you want to choose to grow in a grow
tent
or a grow room