welcome to this debaco university
presentation here we're going to be
going
over some growing substrate options for
indoor cannabis production
with other videos going into more detail
on the options presented here
[Music]
all right let's look at some of the
substrate and some of the options
regarding canvas production
so first off when we're growing
typically indoors the
goal of substrates is to provide
physical support for the root structure
of the cannabis plant
in addition the acid can contain some
microbes it contains some fertilizer
but the main purpose of that substrate
or the properties of that substrate is
really to support
a healthy root structure the physical
morphology if you will of the actual
roots
so the properties of the substrate are
important those physical properties of
the substrate will impact how it
interacts with the nutrients so while
some substrates do contain some starter
nutrients
and that can be important growers can
add their own we really want to look at
some of the physical properties of some
of the substrates because we can
usually add or in some way modify the
nutrients
but the physical properties are what
we're looking at in this
general comparison so some common
substrate options
when we're looking at just the general
substrates there's soilless mix so you
can see here in the middle
coco coir and rockwool now soilless mix
is used a lot not only in cannabis but
other indoor
pop productions indoor container
productions cocoa does get a lot of
kind of interest in the sense that it
does allow for the roots to spread out
pretty well
it is generally considered to be inert
but we do want to be
mindful of the increased needing for
calmag and then
rockwell a lot of times used in the
early part for the clones as we see
here but can be used to grow full-size
plants
so these are the three most common
substrates that typically are found in
cannabis production
and you're welcome to search the channel
for more information on delving into the
details
of each of these three presented here