now in growing media there are organic
components that are added I'm going to
go through some of the common ones that
are added that are added to growing
media such as peat moss bark coconut
quar and worm castings are some common
organic additives to growing media well
starting with peat moss it doesn't
degrade easily making it a stable
compound to incorporate into bags
I can also acidify surrounding so that
can be a concern and a lot of times in
growing media bags you'll see if peat
moss is added you'll also see some form
of lime also added lotta peat moss comes
off from Canada as we see here now the
advantages is that it's free of weed
seeds pests and pathogens that could
absorb up to 20 times its weight in
water this is often the time why it's
added to growing media it's naturally
hydrophobic as a downfall so this can
need time to hydrate this is important
to remember if you're looking at when
you initially are working with gray
media if it initially kind of water kind
of sheets off and doesn't really
incorporate well you have to slowly add
some more moisture to get this just
slowly wet over time also peat moss it
comes from peat bogs and there is some
concerns because most of it comes out of
Canada that with increased usage this
could be depleting some natural peat
bogs they take a very long time to
replenish another organic component is
bark chips which is commonly pine bark
uncombined pie mark and pine bark mulch
example here in bags alone like it's
used typically on the top to dress up
gardens or flowerbeds can also be
incorporating to growing media the
reason why is it proves drainage and
keeps the weight of the final product
down to a minimum and as I said it's
often used to the top dress for flower
gardens but a lot of times it is
incorporated into some growing medians
to help increase that porosity they have
coconut quar that's made from the middle
portion of the coconut and it needs to
be treated before it can be used for
growing media to leach the salts it's
naturally high in salts if you are
buying it for growing media sometimes it
will come pre washed which is great the
advantages of cocoa quoi the reason why
it is use so often that is a renewable
resource it's free of wheat seeds pests
and pathogens it's only slightly acidic
with a page
six 26.7 typically now with the
downfalls to Coco cars and it is hi
insults it can require a long shipping
distance to the United States so just
because we see them being available but
to think about where that original
product came from and that's typically
many many miles away
it does require hydration before you
used to get it to adequately absorb
moisture and quality can vary from batch
to batch depending on the original
source material so just because you're
purchasing Coco Co are often the same
company doesn't mean they're getting it
from the same source so there can be a
great deal of variability from one batch
to another some limitations of Coco car
there's a need for extra additions of
calcium and magnesium products that will
not be needed in the same allowance for
other base materials so people grow in
Coco car typically will get a cal mag
type product that they need to
supplement with to negate some of the
potential negatives that can be
associate with Coco car alasa here we
have worm castings these contain highly
biologically active products that are
high in human content they contain
nutrients to support plant growth but
the total values are minimal so while
does have nutrients overall it's kind of
a minimal percentage about the
advantages this is in near neutral pH
and there's a wide variety of uses with
minimal chance of burning the plants it
almost plant directly write in worm
castings and not burn the plant which is
not true with some other even organic
materials however worm castings can be
costly if you are growing in an outdoor
environment so the exact in a lawn
setting if there's natural earthworms
the plants can get this beneficial
product for free so in the outdoor
situations typically worm castings
aren't need to be added but in container
growing and Salus media it can be
advantageous to kind of bring in some of
the benefits that outdoor plants may
enjoy to a container or indoor setting