welcome to this debaco university video
and here we're going to look at growing
an established strain of cannabis versus
breeding your own
when we're talking about cannabis
genetics and some of the pros and some
of the cons associated with making these
decisions
so first off let's look at if you're
growing an established drain and there
are many established strains out there
many options for you
so what are some of the advantages of
utilizing the options that are available
to you
well again if you're growing a small
number of plants your options for
experimenting are minimal
that is where you're probably going to
favor something that's established
it's also great for those that are
starting out growing and want something
that don't have to work a lot at and
kind of
a set of knowns comes with growing and
established drain so
knowing what to expect as far as height
and flower time all that can be a great
advantage
to a grower particularly starting out
grower also growing the same established
drain allows for growers to refine their
skills
keep some sort of constants throughout
the different growths that you may have
these known genetics offer the source of
consistency and allow you to develop a
plan
of action and allow you to refine that
plan with the same set of genetics
restraint
now some of the disadvantages so why
would you may not want to go through
this route of going with an established
drain well you may
not have the characteristics you desire
what you're looking for
the end product might be the same as
what you can simply purchase so can you
justify the expense of time and money
to go through and develop that you know
use that strain when i can really just
go and purchase that
maybe at reduced cost overall and also
reduces your ability to experiment when
you have something that's known
you kind of have that consistency which
can work to your disadvantage if you're
looking at doing some sort of
experimentation
different plant types on there then we
also have the option of creating your
own strain
and the exact traits you desire to be
bred or created can
be an advantage of going this room it
could also increase your interest in the
growing process particularly more for
the
slightly more advanced growers that are
like okay i've grown the same stream
forever and ever
let me try to create my own also allows
for the potential to create something
unique
and different as you can see here with
maybe colorations or
um terpene profiles or cannabinoid
concentrations
allow those to kind of develop your own
maybe something a little different or
unique to the marketplace
then we also have the disadvantages so
also to consider these when we're
creating our own strain is that it can
be very time consuming
and there's also no guarantee of success
to create your own strain also requires
multiple growing locations and isolate
male plants
so this is why it's typically more
reserved for the advanced grower
so my question is what would you choose
would you grow
an established strain or would you
select to create your own strain
that's up to you to decide and as you
can see there's pros and cons to each
decision