okay here on look at grow room fan
options so I think fan is just a fan but
you can see here there's very different
than our location and also what their
intended purpose is for so first off
horizontal airflow fans is the ones we
see in the image here in here are these
help
these are circulation fans that help
stir the air the concept was introduced
by Yukon zone floor culture specialist
dr. Jay back in 1967 I linked the
article right here the idea here is to
kind of keep air moving here above the
plants these fans aren't directed
directly on the plants but they're
helped to here to keep that air moving
especially in tunneled structures now
oscillating fans we might be familiar
with they're highly recommend for grow
rooms and tents should be placed far
enough away from plans to make leaves
move but not induced water stress you
want to blowing directly on the plants
causing potential for leaf burn or just
inducing water stress just that nice
gentle blowing there is why iceland fans
there's two different types some can
oscillate internally list may oscillate
within the cage this might be one of the
more familiar this is actually a motor
will kind of rotate and isolate and
oscillate as it goes through and stirs
the air that way it helps prevent any
one plant from getting all the directed
wind and spreading that out over the
grow area now if an efficiency fans are
able to pull air about four times more
efficiently than push air so this is why
exhaust fans are directed to force air
out of a structure rather than rotated
to blow air into a site so these fans
are located inside the walls known to
blow air out here so that's what's
important because they're a lot more
efficient at pulling air than about this
four times greater than pushing air so
we may think that Oh might be good to
blow air in no it's a lot more efficient
at pulling that air out you see the
little Gary Larson cartoon here so
exhaust fans used to help keep the air
exchanging and a grow area rated and see
if em and that stands for cubic feet per
minute you want to calculate the volume
of the room the length the width and the
height that gives you the volume and
then match the fan that can replace the
air volume in under five minutes
some girls might even shoot for one
minute but under five minutes is the key
part here
if you have a fan in your room you want
make sure you want that is blowing out
even though you may think you want that
learning your face to help you make you
feel cooler if you're looking at pulling
air again exhausting holding that air
from the room and exhausting it out
would be your best option
and there could be different grow area
sizes so this is why there's different
fans that's why you want to match that
to your volume of space that's also
squirrel-cage blowers and they get their
name for the caves look to the fan
blades that they have they can move it
air well but are often noisy you kind of
like a hamster wheel in here so that is
one option that might be free fit for
your facility which want to know what
those are and they can be noisy so if
that's a concern take that into
consideration and with inline fans as I
have here in the grow ten these are used
within ventilation tubing to help pull
air through the ducting to be exhausted
so a carbon filter we have our ducting
and we have our inline fan here and this
is what it looks like this is used to
kind of send that ideally that hot air
after being cleaned through the carbon
filter taking out some of the odor and
then exhausted out here I also have a
variable speed controller which is good
for regulating how much air is being
exhausted and since this is a relatively
small grow tent a four foot by two foot
four inch fan should be sufficient for
this area now if you're not in a very
large area us ceiling fans can be an
option and they're good for super large
matters these are called Big Ass Fans
it's the name of the actual company and
they actually go through in these large
gigantic fans and help circulate air in
very large facilities they help keep
that air moving efficiently with minimum
use of fan motors