so here we're gonna looking at gross
sight temperature monitoring so there's
a lot of different systems out there
miles sometimes after home systems were
monitoring many conditions at once
through maybe smart devices or other
kind of wireless systems this is just
kind of give you an idea of monitoring
your gross sight
temperature in particular are also very
important so starting with the basics
well depending on the size of your grow
operation you may want to consider
multiple thermometers for large
operations to recommend that you install
multiple what's called min/max
thermometers they tell you basically
over time the minimum temperature and
the maximum temperature that your area
has experienced and this simply could
see here it shows you the maximum when
it pushes up and the minimum down here
so it's very efficient and quick read
and you push this button and it resets
itself leverage I say you may want to
install multiples depending on the size
of your area you may want to put me near
the ceiling in the plant canopy and near
the floor to give you a better idea
what's actually going on in the grow
environment are the most important one
of course is the one near the plant
canopy but if you're seeing something on
going on there sometimes you might want
install some other ones just to get an
idea of what might be going on above or
even below the plants now an advanced
system being in to install what's called
a data logger
this can help check multiple conditions
at regular intervals to help you make
informed decisions and also double check
to make sure everything is working
properly here's one an example of a
field one on the outside you're a great
field and this is monitoring a whole
host of things wind direction wind speed
rainfall temperature I'm out of sunlight
I'm sure gonna be a lot of things you
can look at make some very small ones
here on the monitor temperature and so
the sky's the limit on what you want to
monitor but keep in mind that the more
conditions you can monitor the more odds
you are to have control over what you
can yield from here to here the better
idea you have and what went right or
what went wrong the better idea gave you
to make modifications going forward
now there's thermostats so we're looking
at that grow room that grow area there's
something called single stages and
double stages single stage are set for
either heating or cooling when
temperature goes above or below a
certain setting
further called single stage
that temperature and turn on either the
exhaust fan that's getting too warm or
could turn on the heater if it's getting
too cold the double stage is a single
unit that has two temperatures to help
you maintain the temperature within a
very specific range so for example it
hits one temperature can turn a fan on
that's when whatever's getting too hot
for when it's getting too cold it can
turn on a heater all within a single
unit here that's why it's called double
stage and cut has an upper a maximum and
a minimum and they're the single stage
we'll just do one temperature on one
result thermostat placement is very
important so where you set to physically
place your thermostat it's critical for
its ability to function properly you
want to consider the vertical location
and also the Sun or light exposure that
you may have
keep in mind hot air rises and cold air
sinks so where you mount that thermostat
will cage in effect when your ear when
your exhaust fan may come on or also may
affect when your heater comes on so you
keep in mind of where you actually place
that should be very representative of
your girl facility now choosing between
digital or analog units that can be
debated digital's allow for an exact
control but can have a higher failure
rate in part due to the high humidity
that these are typically placed in so
just keep that in mind they're getting
better systems but it's an area where
it's going to be a lot of irrigation a
lot of humidity those have a higher
tendency of failing analogs may have
some more play in them exactly as far as
what the exact temperature may be but
often can be more reliable more robust
especially in grow facilities we're
dealing with a lot of humidity and a lot
of chance of water splash and so on and
so forth so the only books can ideally
do the same job the digital can give you
some more controls but could have a
chance at failure mechanical ones might
a little bit more play in them but once
you get them dialed in can be a little
bit more robust