okay here investigate some of the
components of growing media and
particularly here or a look at the
inorganic components so if you ever
looked at growing media the Sun
contained mixtures of perlite
vermiculite pumice sand and winning
agents we're look at each of these in a
little bit more detail so starting with
perlite it looks like this it's kind of
little white particles that are in there
so gives you a size orientation compared
to a penny and perlite is saying that's
expanded by heat and has ability to hold
water in nutrients while also aerating
the soil it'll float in water so may it
may rise to the surface in the container
especially when you first go to irrigate
something if you irrigate with a lot of
water to kind of moist in the full soil
or a soilless media I should say this
these white particles might float to the
surface
that's the perlite floating to the
surface the main goal is to increase the
drainage of the growing media it comes
in different sizes so if you're looking
at mixing your own there's fine medium
coarse of course being the most common
and this is typically implemented in
growing medium not so much propagation
medium especially for the course or a
larger particle size there's also
something called vermiculite and it
looks like this it's mica that has been
expanded by heat it offers many of the
same big benefits as perlite so does
holding water in air while also
improving the drainage however it can
hold more water than perlite and it's
more commonly seen in cutting and
propagation mixes there as the same
grading system fine medium and coarse
was fine being used for the propagation
of course being used more for the main
growing situations it's favored in that
cutting and propagation kind of area
solely because it holds more water and
moisture retention is a major concern
anything with the propagation
environment I'll Thomas this is a very
light and porous volcanic rock it's
formed when gas rich frothy of glass
lava solidifies rapidly so this is kind
of that expanded volcanic rock this as a
result this is very porous and there's
I'll actually float in water even though
it is a rock it's very light something
you may have seen in for example if you
use grills pumice can be involved with
that
due to its
like structure but extremely light
appearance extremely lightweight say
simply because of the amount of porosity
or air pockets that it has in it then we
also have sand this is the exact
composition of San varies but it is made
from rock and minerals that are finer
than gravel but coarser than silt if you
looking at a gradation the same can be
incorporated again to help aerate soil
to help create separation of particles
and while its composition may be
slightly varied the purpose there is
still the same also have the last
inorganic component here's wetting
agents and these are very important they
lower the surface tension of a liquid
allowing it to spread out creating a
water film so if we have no wetting
agents we'll just say we have this large
water droplet adding with a wetting
agents can cause that kind of to form a
sheet we see the different comparisons
here of ABC and s the wedding of
different fluids a shows fluid is very
little wedding while C shows a fluid
with more wedding see that greater
contact surface here C has a small
contact angle and that's allowing it to
spread out and s is kind of that showing
that alternate sheet there however the
downfall of wetting agents is there is a
lifespan which varies to look around
three to six month for long term of
wetting agents this is why getting new
Australis Vida is advised
sometimes the wetting agents can degrade
over time or if you're reusing media
well it may work out good initially
those wetting agents may not be as
effective the second round or the second
time that to use that soilless media