okay so here we'll look at grow nutrient
formulations typically you'll see
companies market the word grow on their
fertilizers and at least four have and
what that kind of equates to is a larger
amount or percentage of nitrogen that
they contain keep in mind it's nitrogen
phosphorus potassium this is a twelve
six six the six three three a seven nine
five and so on and so forth there's no
set fertilizer ratio typically grow
nutrients will simply just have more
nitrogen so this is containing more
nitrogen the goal is to produce a
greater plant growth more leaf growth
more top growth you might know if you
are planning on cloning the plant you
may want to watch how much nitrogen you
feed your plants because that can
potentially negatively impact your
ability to clone that mother plant going
forward now that nitrogen I mentioned
this nutrient is very quick at things so
it's better to focus on feeding just
enough because it's easy to over feed
with this nutrient if you are six
suspecting a nitrogen deficiency as some
nitrogen-based fertilizer water it in so
it gets to the root zone wait about
three to four days if you see a change
in the plant response and it was
nitrogen if you don't then move on to
something else don't keep adding
nitrogen it also comes in different
forms we have urea here calcium nitrate
and blood meal all kind of ways of
delivering nitrogen very different
amounts this is 13% and this one is 46%
nitrogen so that will adjust the amounts
that you do add to your plants
remember that growth formulations may
have higher nitrogen number but there's
other nutrients to consider phosphorus
and potassium do not simply apply for
the nitrogen and ignore the other
nutrients that you're adding this must
be taken into consideration as you plan
your long term grow cycle so for example
this nutrient here says grow we think
it's high nitrogen it is contains 7
percent but 4 percent phosphorus in 10
percent potassium so if you're just
focusing on the nitrogen here you could
be over adding on the potassium end of
things so this is where I got a look at
the entire nutrient blend and applying
it kind of as part of an entire program
for the growth cycle and not just
focusing on one particular nutrient
vilasa is called flushing the media
where plants may involve adding water
just like the total toilet bowl here
where you're flushing with about three
times the volume of the media to help
remove excessive salts in nutrient
buildup that may have occurred however
this is in part we're careful additions
are important you want to kind of
selectively add your nutrients there's a
help reduce the chance of building up a
set excessive salts which can damage the
root system reduce it your need to flush
the plants when you're flushing the
plants here you're kind of potentially
wasting out some nutrients so if you
kind of want to be very careful on your
feeding program throughout the entire
grow cycle so you're at sufficient as
possible in minimizing waste