you're gonna look at the grow tent
environments and I have two side-by-side
pictures here the same grow tent listen
with the full-spectrum LED light off and
this with it on so you need to get
appreciation here for the reflectivity
of that kind of mylar backing there and
not fully set up but these are becoming
very popular for a lot of reasons these
are the smallest of operations use that
same grow tent with the light on here's
it all sealed up they're becoming very
popular because it can be placed
anywhere they're very versatile making
place in closets bedrooms spare rooms
and you know anywhere where there is a
basically dead space as access to power
this small area is easy to regulate and
many come with many very friendly
options this makes light and charcoal
filter installation very simple very
easy kind of snap fittings on and off
you go they offer easy access and which
can be very beneficial to the grower you
can be consider right in the room quite
in an area that doesn't need necessary
outside lighting so this as part of the
reasons why protests have become so
popular they offer ability to fit in a
variety of spaces from very small to
very large so here's a small little 2 by
2 10 that's kind of one of the smallest
ones they make and they go up to a 10
foot by 20 foot it's a very very large
grow 10 2 feet by 4 feet very popular
that's what this size is and one of the
reason device popular is can easily
moved through standard doorways so it's
just fit through the standard doorway
but it makes it really easy to move from
room to room if you so choose
now that 2x4 fits in a lot of good areas
and here's kind of the underlying
supporting structure so the ease of
these grow tents is that they have this
self-contained internal support
structure which allows for attachment
here you can see of different Lighting's
here makes it very quick and easy these
grow tents allow a great way to enter
into the growing world because they're
nice small and contained you can be done
on a budget they do their popularity
there's a lot of options becoming
available for these they can also buffer
outdoor growers to continue
experimenting even during an off season
so if you find that one key mother plant
or this kind of try something out
allows growers to keep growing even if
it's very cold or not
Gusev outside what they do is they
create this isolated environment which
can allow for experimentation to occur
under constant and controlled conditions
we can see the example of some different
models here it also be kind of
considered as like growth chambers where
you're able to isolate and test maybe
one variable also due to this isolation
the cloning propagation environments
lend themselves well to grow ten even if
large areas for vegetative flower and
growth are used and easily increased new
humidity easily regulate the light and
easily keep maybe multiple racks of
clones or cuttings in a relatively small
footprint they often require odor
control especially for current for a
full term also keep this in mind you
might want to install carbon filter
again we typically would want to vent
this out the top possible this is an
easy access here this helps minimize the
square feet of space when you go
vertical here and again depending on the
operation or what you're trying to grow
that can also afford you different
opportunities having this tall design
though even if you're on only on one
level may be advantageous because
there's a lot easier management for heat
for example want to be careful so even
though these may be a small footprint of
space you want to watch the power
consumption it's easy to start stringing
a bunch of lights and fans and motors
and pumps all together so just be
careful and be mindful of the total
power consumption of your respective
Croton