now somebody consider grow a lifespan is
from when they buy it and first install
it to what it completely explodes and
dies this may not always be the case
because it will degrade over time so the
lifespan may be related to how much
efficiency can you tolerate or how much
loss of efficiency can you tolerate
before you throw that bulb out so that
usable life and put that life in quotes
there some lights may continue to
produce light but overall plant
production may suffer top growers will
change out bulbs when productivity will
suffer which is well before they
actually burn out or quote die so it's
important to consider that lifespan is
that light bulb is degrading over time
how much derogation are you willing to
tolerate before you change it out so a
lot of times these state bulbs in the
amount of hours that they can run so
it's important to have a quick little
conversions that one year is 8760 hours
if you're running 24 hours a day running
at 18 hour days you're looking at one
calendar year will be 6570 hours if
you're running a flowering stage which
is 12 hour days looking at 4380 hours is
what your bulb will accumulate over the
course of a calendar year then the
mounting position does impact the
lifespan the late bulbs operating
position affects its lifespan bulbs will
last longer when they're operated in a
vertical up and down position if the
same 20,000 our label this operated in a
horizontal or side-to-side position it
only lasts about 15,000 hours so while
they will last longer in the vertical
position keep in mind you're not quite
getting the efficiency of them from the
plant standpoint percent of light output
determines its life how much below new
to be 100% are you or the manufacturer
considered to be the life 80%
broken-down 75 60 there really is no
standards you have to develop what
percentage you determine that life to be
and this gives you the common bulb types
in the rated life high-pressure sodium
is about 5,000 hours and they'll be
about 95% and see the pen
specifically the bulb manufacturer to
choose to go with metal halides last
about $9,000 t5 for lessons last about
20,000 hours and they'll still be about
85 percent efficient ceramic metal
halides are about 20,000 hours also but
there will be running at 80% efficiency
at that twenty two thousand dollar mark
plasmas last about 40,000 hours and LEDs
are about fifty thousand dollars but
still maintaining 90% so LEDs it's kind
of important there that look at
high-pressure sodium is only fifty
thousand only five thousand degree at
fifty thousand so ten times as long for
the LED for only a 5% more degradation
so high pressure setting this is five
thousand hours knots will be 95%
efficient LEDs 50,000 hours and still
operating 90% efficiency
so again cost comes into play the
spectrum that they're producing member
t5 for us it's not good for flowering is
a lack penetration they can last a long
time so very important to keep an idea
what the rated life is depending on what
light source that you use because that
may impact the cost over the long term