have you ever wondered how growing
substrates can impact chemist plant
production
well here in this video we're going to
look at a scientific article and do some
comparisons of some common growing
substrates
and just see how they do impact cannabis
plant production
[Music]
all right welcome to this tobacco
university video let's get into how
growing substrates impact cannabis plant
production
so for as always here is the article
here's the citation here's the first
page there's the link to it
where you can always find more details
of the experiment
this can provide you with the highlights
here so first off the substrate
composition what are the different
subjects that were looked at in this
study
you're going to see terms like pm g30
and cc
pm stands for peat mix g30 stands for
peat mix substitute with 30 green fiber
and cc stands for pure coconut fiber
and you're also seeing the term the
abbreviation i should say
dap and that stands for days after
pollination
the pot size during experiment in cm is
provided right here
these experiments were conducted between
march 4th 2019
to april 9 2019 and you can see kind of
the details
of the con components of each of the
substrates
so what's the mean or average plant
height of the
genotypes studied so in the detail in
the details of the study there are some
more specifics provided
but here we're just looking at the
substrates this line or dotted line here
represents the vegetative growth
and then the generative growth this is
usually a lot of girls call this the
flowering phase
and we will notice that overall the
growing
plate trend and plant height measured in
centimeters
and we see this physical difference here
so when we're looking at the comparison
kind of what ended up
overall being the highest for plant
height
was the pem followed by the g30 followed
by the
cc and as a reminder here the pm
is that peat mix that g30 is that peat
mix substituted with 30 green fiber
and that cc there is the coconut so you
could see again how that comparison
occurred over the days after planting
now what does the actual plants look
like so this is kind of a good just
general comparison here if you looked
all the numbers that's great
but what do the actual plants look like
not only the plants as we see here in
the above image
but also the root structure of each and
we can see some differences here
coconut fiber causing the greatest
degree of kind of spacing out of the
roots the
greatest area of surface area of
coverage and the peat mix plus 30
green fiber showing a little bit more
denser pockets
in regions there we could see also how
that impacted the plant growth here on
the above
portion of the plant which growers
typically most associate with
so what's the research conclusion so we
saw the data we saw the pictures what
did the researchers actually have to say
after
doing this study they said that there
was a limiting effect on the cbd in cba
content enacted by the different
substrates could not be confirmed so
that means that one substrate didn't
necessarily
produce any higher cbd or cba in the
plants that were studied
so it can be concluded that the use of
organic green fibers to partially
replaced fractionated peat showed
genotype specific
option for consistent plant development
a comparable high biomass yield and
stable cannabinoid content
compared to a standard peat containing
standard mix there so what does that
kind of mean well a lot of times when
growers are changing different
substrates they're going to wonder how
that's going to impact the plant
and this is a study here looking at
specific cannabinoid content
and really they concluded that there
wasn't really that much of a difference
there
in the cbd and cba content extracted
from
the plants so that's important as
growers when we're looking at potential
cost or potential
for changing different substrates or
manufacturers are changing different
substrates how's that going to impact
our plant
specifically a cannabis plant this is a
great study here that shows
some information in graphical form as
well as the morphology of the above
plant structure as well the below plant
structure so growers can get a better
understanding and a controlled study
of how their substrate may impact their
plants