here we're looking at gunshot residue
now you may not think
initial fire bullet is fired how much
residue is actually exposed around the
gun but this kind of
freeze-frame high-speed shot shows the
bullet in motion
shows the fire still coming out of the
barrel and does show the residue
and keep in mind this is a revolver here
so there can be a little bit more
because we have that firing chamber
curve right in the
cylinder here so gunshot residue
a lot of times abbreviated gsr is a
mixture of material
that originates from the firing of a gun
and it's
residue that is deposited on the hands
and clothes of someone who discharges
the firearm
and really anything nearby residue can
be found on both the firearm
and the individual and this again shows
another revolver
kind of shows the angle of projection
of that residue and here's the bullet
again caught right in motion right there
it gives you a good
idea of just where this may be deposited
now gunshot residue is principally
composed of burnt and unburnt particles
from the explosive primer and the
propellant
there's also the possibility of
fragments of the bullet cartridge case
and the firearm present so it's not just
to say just a propellant we see here
with the smoke
there could also be a chance that there
could be some of that cartridge case
some of the actual bullet component
so these are other things to be mindful
of when you're evaluating
a scene for gunshot residue now the
collection
of said gunshot residue the process in
general
we're looking at investigators should
use gloves to limit potential
contamination of the scene because we
are looking at something that is very
fine
and is found in very small quantities
investigators should test the clothing
and skin of people for gunshot residue
to determine if they were near the gun
when it was discharged
as you saw with those images you can see
here it's not just around the gun there
is some
expansion of that at least near the site
of that initial explosion
the gunshot residue can travel about
over three to five
feet from the gun or about one one and a
half meters away from the gun
but keep in mind at those first kind of
ranges of that
only very few trace particles might be
present so it's gonna be very hard to
find those
that's why it's important to try to
pinpoint where the gun was actually
fired
now in that gunshot residue in the if
you go through and you go
bring it into a lab and analyze it we're
going to be looking for
elements such as barium antimony these
are typically found at high levels
you want to use a powerful microscope in
this case this scanning electron
microscope can help kind of
look for that residue that might be
present and there's other chemical tests
to determine what elements might be
present
and making the match well the if the
ammunition used
was specifically tagged in some way with
special elements it's possible to know
the cartridge used to produce the
gunshot residue using scanning electron
microscopes or dispersive x-ray
spectrometry
can also help her aid in this process
the whole goal of going through this
process is to match the bullet to the
gun
to be able to try to determine or start
developing
links of what occurred at the crime
scene to what materials were used
at the crime scene