welcome to dubaco university here we're
going to be looking at
some hair basics and getting some of the
details for what we can actually
determine
when looking at a piece of hair and what
components hair is made of
so first off a hair and fiber analysis
so
in this case cannot be used to match a
suspect with a crime scene
can be microscopically analyzed for
similarities and comparisons can be
provided to improve
as forensic techniques improve keep in
mind hair and fiber both fall into the
category
of being class evidence now here in
fibers for identification
we'll hear offers some benefits to
forensic scientists because the hair
resists decomposition so it's more
likely to be found at a crime scene
here may also indicate drug use or
poisoning and we can see with that and
analyzing the hair different regions of
that hair we could find
a potential for drug usage in a certain
period of time
and potentially link that or at least
conclude that as part of the story
for the crime scene investigation report
the anatomy of hair so you're welcome to
pause the video at this point look at
things
in detail we're going to be focused on
medulla the cortex
in the outer portion the cuticle region
however realize that hair
is embedded in the skin it's all the way
down to the dermal layer where the blood
vessels are found
but we're going to be looking
specifically at that hair
fiber and some of the areas within that
hair fiber
so first off we got to look at the
general structure of
the hair so on the outermost portion we
have the cuticle
and this has overlapping scales and we
can notice that here
in the green region then we have the
cortex which is a protein-rich structure
around the medulla that contains the
pigment
and in that center region there we have
the medulla which is
the central core in some instances that
may be
absent so it's important for
identification purposes
the reason we have the pencil here is we
can think of this hair structure as a
pencil
where the medulla being the graphite or
that center region the cortex
being the wood represented by the pencil
the cuticle being the paint
on the outside just to get you to
understand
how these layers interact and where
they're located
now that hair structure again what we're
focusing on
is kind of these different layers and we
could see that while the hair looks very
thick
in this instance it's actually made of
many many small
fibers which is part of the reason why
it's so strong
for its small diameter again just to be
aware of where it's located within the
body within the
within the integumentary system i could
see here where it's located with some
glands
where the hair matrix is located and the
hair bulb down here at the bottom
we're looking mainly here at the hair
shaft and portions of the root
so this hair follicle look at the
follicles part of the skin which
grows a hair by packing old cells
together
it's attached on the inside and top of
the follicle are sebaceous
glands which are tiny sebum producing
glands in almost
all skin except the palms lips and soles
of the feet
so here we're looking at the sebum being
produced and that's kind of what gives
the hair
some of its protective oils as well the
root of the hair
on the hair shaft is part of the hair
not
anchored to the follicle and much of
this is exposed at the skin's surface
and the rest of the hair which is
anchored in the follicle
lies below the surface of the skin is
referred to as the hair
root so when we're investigating a
potential hair that may have been
forcefully removed
we might want to identify or properly
identify an area of the hair shaft
compared to the
hair root region and there's that
sebaceous gland tied right in
providing the oils again for that hair
looking at a cross section of the hair
so again think of that same pencil
concept
this is showing the different layers of
the hair shaft that medulla being in the
center
then we have the cortex here that may
contain pigment granules and in the
outermost region being the cuticle
that cuticle being the outermost region
remember that is the covering
of the hair we can see that here it's
formed by flat overlapping
and hardened scales and the degree of
those scales again help us
identify whether it's human hair or
potentially some animal hairs
as we'll see in another video but that
here cuticle is that outermost covering
here is an example of it if you remember
back from that first one i showed it was
the green outer area
and it's important before distinguishing
between hairs of different species
but are often not useful in
distinguishing between different people
so it might be important that we found
some hair well is it
the neighborhood cat or is it someone
that
might be a human so again the cuticle
can be used for identification
purposes when comparing the scales you
want to look at how many there are per
per centimeter how many how they overlap
what's their shape
how much they protrude from the surface
what's their thickness and is there
pigment present
or all questions you want to ask when
analyzing the cuticle
the cuticle classification so well they
all kind of look the same well
actually if you look very carefully
stick with a microscope
there are different categories that they
will fall into
and this again can help us identify what
potential species
that hair might be from and can be used
to eliminate
or again looking at class evidence here
eliminate
certain hairs that might be found that
aren't of human species
the cortex so now we're kind of looking
at that next layer down it's the
thickest hair layer located in the
interior portion of the hair
between the cuticle and the medulla it
contains the hair pigments or
melanin and pigments are absent though
in gray hair so as someone
ages and gets gray hair they're simply
losing their pigments
in the cortex region that cortex
specifically the distribution of cortex
is considered the most important
component
when attempting to distinguish between
different people
again this is still class evidence not
getting to individual evidence
but still important for different people
microscopic examination can also reveal
conditions in shape of the
root and the tip and the cortex varies
in its
thickness its texture and also its color
which is kind of important for that
identification purposes
here we see human hair and we have
on the head there could be on the body
it could be different areas we could be
looking at
and we do see a difference in the cortex
the two images provided here
the cortex the pigment granule
distribution so this is both looking at
a tabby cap
and again looking towards the end most
is closer towards the root area
and we can definitely see that there are
differences in the cortex
between these two keep in mind there's
also slight difference in magnification
so you're also seeing
more detail in the cuticle region of the
hair in this image down here
getting to the medulla that center
portion
interior most area of the hair this is
the most noticeable
hair feature in many species the medulla
is that center region
so like the cuticle the medulla is
characterized by
importance in distinguishing between
hairs of different species
but they are often not useful in
distinction between different people
again the medulla may vary in its
thickness connectivity the opacity
that refers to kind of the structure is
it broken into pieces is it all
continuous
how much light is able to pass through
and keep in mind it could also be
absent in certain species as well so
again very important we're looking at
class evidence is the medulla region of
the hair
medulla patterns so there's three main
characteristics we could have a
continuous
and interrupted or intermittent more
specific you could have fragmented
or it could also just be absent and
that's basically relating to no pattern
but would be important to note the
classification of the medulla so we
could see here again
we just like have different
classifications for structure and
pattern
forming at the margins and again this
can help us
use this information as class
characteristics of the hair samples
found and collected at a potential crime
scene
there's also something called a medulla
index and this describes the thickness
of the
layer that's calculated by measuring the
diameter of the doula and dividing by
the diameter of the hair
so here the medulla index for human hair
is generally less than one-third and the
medulla index for animal hair is usually
greater than one-half
so this can help be another form of
quantitative analysis
when we're trying to classify different
hair using the medulla index
is one method so as you can see there's
a lot of different types
of ways to kind of look at here analyze
here and understand here
and hopefully this provided you with a
little insight to all the options that
are available