welcome to another video here on tobacco
university
in this video we're going to be looking
at hair in its relation to dna
you can see here's a long braided hair
and here is the double helix
of dna now dna analysis is only possible
if the bulb
at the base of the hair is intact so
keep in mind that bulb region is down
here
closer to the root end of the hair the
hair bubble foams at the base of the
hair follicle
and in the hair bulb living cells divide
and grow to build
the hair shaft this is why it's
important for dna analysis
because the blood vessels that nurse the
cells in the hair bulb deliver more
hormones that modify hair growth and
structure
at different times so that can be useful
in addition those growing cells
are more likely to contain that
important
dna when we're looking at trying to take
care which is a class characteristic
and trying to get it more in the chance
of being in the individual
characteristic category
so here at different growth stages keep
in mind
that advancements in dna profiling can
now
individualize human hair the probability
of detecting dna at the hair roots is
more likely for hair being examined
in different growth phases and here we
have the different growth
phases so here we have the early growth
phase which is also referred to as the
antigen
phase then we have the middle growth
phase that's the catagen phase and then
the telogen phase which is the
final phase here
now here in dna specifically when hair
is forcibly removed
often a follicle tag which is a
transition piece of tissue surrounding
the hair shaft
may be present and it kind of looks like
this right here this is a root with a
follicle tag
other surrounded by tissue this will
have nuclear
dna and this is proven to be a rich
source of that nuclear dna associated
with the hair
keep in mind if you're finding a hair
piece without that follow the
the follicular tag here the root is club
shaped there's going to be basically
no nuclear dna located here so this is
kind of the goldmine here for finding
that
dna you have those cells around that
kind of root of the of the hair
looking at hair in the mitochondrial dna
so mitochondrial dna is found outside
the nucleus and is transmitted only from
the mother to child
so ideally nuclear dna is what we want
to find but mitochondrial dna should not
be overlooked
because mitochondrial dna can be
extracted from the hair shaft
as a rule all positive microscopic hair
comparisons
must be confirmed by dna analysis so
again why the mitochondrial dna may only
be tied to the maternal line
still can be important information it
can still help
eliminate potential suspects on a list
to try to get to that more individual
characteristic
now when we're collecting here as a
baseline and ideally
the general rule forensics hair
comparisons involve either head hair or
pubic hair
so ahead here ideally we're looking to
collect about 50 full length
ahead here samples from all areas of the
scalp will normally ensure a
representative sample
to be care we're looking at about 24
full-length pubic hairs or
should cover the range of
characteristics present in pubic hair
hair samples should also be collected
from victims or suspicious deaths during
an autopsy
so a lot of times if you're just
investigating um a crime scene without a
body you may find hair samples
but it may be difficult to find 50 but
if you're looking at particularly an
autopsy or have the
ability to collect hair and have access
to 50 head hair samples or 24 pubic hair
samples
those would definitely be advised
because it would help determine
uh or reduce the natural range of hair
variability
to allow you to kind of get a little bit
more closer to that individual
characteristic
when we're looking at identifying
different hair samples