on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over some hand trimming
techniques tools and suggestions because
a lot of people get a start in the
industry in this area
so i want to provide you with a little
bit of background to exactly what hand
trimming is and give you some tips and
recommendations
[Music]
all right let's get into hand trimming
techniques and tools for cannabis
so first off hand trimming well hand
trimming is a process that allows for
attention to detail
and for each bud to be treated in a very
unique way
this allows the grower to best showcase
the bud through selective trimming
to help the bud show its best qualities
why do you want to go through and have
the best qualities being shown
despite this time consuming process the
end result can bring
top dollar to make the process
worthwhile in the long run
so as a result even though all these
individual people may have their own
special
a unique kind of way of trimming the
overall process is
to kind of showcase that bud in the best
way possible
to again so it can bring top dollar
now how do you go about this process
well step one you want to remove the fan
leaves now you want to cut away fan
leaves as this will aid in
air circulation during the drying time
this will also help reduce the chance of
disease developing because you're
getting allow allowing more air
circulation
we can see here the family is being
removed and the
kind of what remains is the actual buds
now this is here it's remaining on the
plant
here we're seeing it stacked on a
separate container now
next would be to remove the buds from
the actual branches so this is
pertaining to dry trimming and the buds
should be removed from the branches
after a few days of drying time
or a little bit longer depending on your
exact conditions
some length of supporting stem note
should be kept
and these buds will be transferred
directly to a container ideally with
minimal physical contact
some growers will take them directly off
the plant and transfer just the buds
other growers will take larger branches
down and trim them again
this method can be sometimes more
advantageous simply because it allows
you better manipulation
of that branch can be a little more
difficult when it's physically on the
plant to go through
but if you have a smaller operation this
would work just fine as well
then you want to fill your trimming
station so most growers prefer a tray
and some will add a special light or
magnifier to aid in the process
once you have a bud in hand you
typically want to start at the base
basically near the stem
and remove the small branches that may
exist a lot of times are known as like
crow's feet
down this lower portion here then
proceed to remove additional plant
material around the bud with attention
to detail favored over speed
some trimmers will even use different
scissors at various
levels of detail some use a certain set
to kind of go through remove some of the
leaves
and then a finer set to as they get
closer to that
core bud there the goal is to go
completely around the bud at least once
to ensure consistency and to inspect it
make sure you forget anything these
trays are really advantageous because
they allow
a great place to kind of rest your uh
rest your arms there
and they're very ergonomic so they're
very um kind of grower friendly so you
want to make sure or trimmer friendly
because you want to make sure you're
comfortable
during this process now the equipment
that you might need to have around would
be of course the scissors comfortable
sitting location a clean tray indoor
surface cleaning supplies and it's an
optional light or magnifier
depending on your comfort or the room
that you're in
so we're looking at the trimming
scissors they're sharp
sterilized scissors are essential to any
trimming process while each trimmer may
have their exact preference
the goal is to get down to these
agronomic scissors that have a
comfortable grip
and this is where you're paying more uh
maybe
might be better now some prefer kind of
the encapsulated kind of grips here some
just prefer the straight handles
doesn't matter whichever you prefer
someone you should be getting
if you're going to be trimming for long
periods of time be sure to get scissors
you can find that are comfortable
and comfortable to you not because
someone else recommended it
some growers get some different types of
scissors to ensure that they can have
the proper tool
for the different detail pruning that
bud may require
others can go through and just use the
same set keep in mind that some might be
very very small
on the trimming end and that's great for
that detail work but to
initially remove those leaves might be
wiser to have a slightly larger blade
length to your scissors
now as i mentioned comfortable sitting
location that's comfortable for you or
the person doing the trimming
this does not have to be complex but
should be comfortable for you or the
trimmer
getting the chair and table heights
adjusted in space are
very important and depending on the
exact table that you're using your
environment
change but make sure again it's a
comfortable chair and location that
you're going to be in
in a clean tray and surface so many
different types of trimming trays
but all have the same purpose watch the
color as this can be your background as
your trim
some may like a you know more stainless
steel approach
something like a green approach there's
black backgrounds white backgrounds
uh just keep in mind as you're trimming
you're gonna be looking at that in the
background
black can be preferred as it does create
good contrast
others prefer more of a green color so
again just take that into consideration
if you have that option and as i
mentioned cleaning supplies
so this can involve those sterilizing
agents as well as resin cleaners from
the blades
the goal is to have one of these on hand
the second goal is to actually use them
some cores will just trim trim trim and
then kind of guys you're getting later
and later it's getting harder and harder
take a time give the blades a quick
little kind of clean there
make the process easier make your
details much sharper
and hopefully produce a higher quality
end product
and then lastly optional equipment would
be a light and magnifier
this can be grower microwave dependent
but some prefer to have an
external light source this as this can
depend on the room
if you're in a very dark room external
light source would definitely be
recommended
and a magnifier will allow the most
precise cuts to be made
as the bud is being manicured some come
with this nice light and magnifier
option
which is great you're going through and
trimming you're able to see it in much
more detail
particularly for spending long hours as
you can see here maybe have some coffee
nearby
sterilizing equipment it just shows the
very basics that a trimming station can
include
and the ones that you should be
considering so you have a very efficient
operation as you go through and trim
your final end product