so hopefully you've been taking some
notes and you can kind of
apply some of this handwriting analysis
to something you recently have written
to be able to appreciate some of the
details within your handwriting
more than you may have realized so
starting with each person has a unique
handwriting style if you ever looked at
your friends or anyone else's you
probably know this to be true
everyone has natural variations which
can be due to writing instrument
mood the age the time restraints
audience is writing for you might be
sloppy might be
messier this could all play into exactly
the style
of the particular handwriting you're
looking at so factors that kind of
in general that will influence
handwriting would be the size of your
fingers your hands your arms
they're small they're large the muscular
makeup that can be impacted by your
sports or
work or hobbies that you may have
education where'd you learn
to write did you learn certain nuances
or details
style and personality are you in a rush
are you detail-oriented
these are all factors that influence
someone's handwriting
and when we look at an examination of
handwriting
given an adequate amount of handling
samples there will not be identical
features so every person has a range of
natural handwriting variations
because no one writes like a machine
it's not the exact same
font so to speak so this is important to
remember when you're looking at making
comparisons if you're not looking for an
identical perfect perfect identical
match you're looking for some of these
characteristics
and consistencies within these
so one characteristic you're looking for
a letter form this includes letter shape
curve slant size continuous stroke
incorrect appearance
typically for this you're looking at the
letters g y h and k
i can see some examples here of g y h
and k
and how they may look with different
people so the letter form what's the
curve what's the slant
um is it how far is it slanted what
letters are slanted
these are just some definitely things to
be looking for the general form
of the letters you also have to consider
line of form and this includes the
smoothness of the letters and darkness
of the lines
of different strokes so how are they
writing it can be you know this can be
very messy and you know maybe not be
able to read what name it is
but they'll be again these
characteristics can be carried through
looking at line form if it's written on
a piece of paper that does have
lines that can help it can affect
certain things as well as the darkness
of the lines and strokes and the pen
pressure that the person
may be utilizing we have the
formatting as kind of our last and main
at least characteristic to kind of look
at we'll go to these in more detail in
other videos
but format includes the spacing between
the letters the words the lines the
placement of the words
and also the margins are there gaps
between the handwriting are there no
gaps
between the words are there gaps or
they're kind of following a margin line
all different characteristics when
you're looking at the handwriting sample
to consider whether it's a match to
something you're trying to make
because they won't be identical how many
of these characteristics match up
and to what degree do they match up will
help you analyze someone's handwriting