this video is going to show a
hardy-weinberg application involved with
sickle-cell anemia and why this is not
following what we might expect so
looking at sickle cell anemia what it is
an inherent mutation of the genetic code
in hemoglobin hemoglobin remember is
oxygen carrying the blood protein the
recessive allele is this H with this s
and this double s here the normal allele
would be the B so this s and this s is
standing for sickle-cell low oxygen
levels cause red blood cells to sickle
which is this kind of shape here as you
see indicated here this is a normal red
blood cell maintaining a very high
surface area to volume ratio you see the
sickle shape is not really the protein
formed in the proper shape not aligned
to its proper function breaks down a red
blood cells clotting small blood vessels
damaged organs can often be lethal so
you do not want sickle-cell it's because
is a very short life expectancy
however the alleles for this still exist
we're talk about why so high frequency
of heterozygotes one in five in central
Africans are heterozygotes for
sickle-cell we have a normal allele and
also a sickle cell allele unusual for an
allele with severe detrimental effects
in the homozygotes so one that of a
hundred individuals will be homozygous
for sickle cell and they usually die
before we productive age meaning these
genes are typically not passed on so
this kind of brings the question of why
is the sickle cell allele maintained in
such a high levels in African
populations this suggests or some
selective advantage for being a
heterozygote so why is that investigate
that a little bit here so first off just
quick general malaria it's a parasite
it's transmitted by mosquitoes causes a
bunch of negative symptoms can often
lead to death see here it's a life stage
that it goes through it is blood-borne
and it does multiply in the human body
and again transmitted the parasite at
least by mosquito bite be very deadly
and a single-celled eukaryotic parasite
spends part of its life cycle in red
blood cells and that's what causes here
or mass multiplication that then a
mosquito will bite someone who's
infected and spread it to another person
so sickle cell anemia this was first
detected in December 31st in 1904 sickle
cell anemia is a hereditary disease
affecting hemoglobin molecules in the
blood so initially might be asking well
how does this relate to the malaria I
just talked about you'll see how this
connects the sickle cell mutation
changes six amino acid in the immigrant
chain this causes hemoglobin molecules
to clump in normal red blood cells the
hemoglobin change do not Club so sickle
cell almost a Saiga si leads to reduced
lifespan if you have sickle cell your
red blood cells are going to look like
this you could see the forms long and
flexible chains this is how hemoglobin
should look and this can lead to
clogging of red blood cell blood vessels
here leading to all sorts of issues and
problems of not being able to exchange
blood efficiently versus if you have
normal blood
let me see everything these nice little
round of red blood cells can move it
very efficiently heterozygotes though
they produced enough hemoglobin to keep
the red blood cells healthy even though
there is still some sickle cell
heterozygotes have enough to basically
keep most of the red blood cells healthy
and a lot of individual to survive so
why is the defective is still around
then yes if you can survive with it it's
okay but if you have the homozygous for
sickle cell you end up dying why is this
allele still around wisent has been
selected again well it affects this
disease affects central Africa one in
500 Africans but is almost unknown in
other racial groups just draws the
question well why people who are
heterozygous for sickle cell allele have
less susceptibility to malaria this is
an example of what's called the
heterozygote advantage so that malaria
that I talked about that lives in the
red blood cells if you're a heterozygote
and have one of your alleles for
sickle-cell you're actually resistant to
malaria this stabilizing selection is
just acting on the sickle cell allele it
occurs because malaria resistant counter
balances the lethal anemia so
in green here we have the presence of
where malaria tends to be found and here
we have the frequency of the sickle cell
allele the darker Reds are where there's
a higher frequency up to 10 plus 2 12
and a half percent plus and the lighter
regions or whether it's less found
you'll notice if we kind of look at both
of these in comparison we see that where
the sickle cell allele is present is
also areas of the world that malaria is
also present this is referring to that
heterozygote advantage so in tropical
Africa where malaria is common the
almost I get down it normal if you're
almost a it for normal which is what
most people are you would die from
malaria if you're homozygous recessive
for sickle cell you would die from
sickle cell however if you're a carrier
or a heterozygote you're relatively free
of both you survive and reproduce more
and therefore more common in the
population so we need one of those
alleles to carry normal hemoglobin and
having the other one encoding for sickle
cell if you're where malaria is present
we actually become basically resistant
to it so if I sit this is in malaria
detected cells the lower oxygen levels
is lowered enough because it's Ikhwan
which kills the cell and destroys the
parasite so why is this heterozygote
carrier in damage
well it's causing the parasites breaking
the life cycle of the parasite so in
this case to be heterozygote isn't
advantage the downfall is we still need
that sickle cell gene to be in the
population and there's that chance you
could your offspring could come up with
the homozygous for sickle cell and up
dying before they able to reproduce
again most of the world's normal
hemoglobin but affected by malaria if
you're this heterozygote you're able to
have enough normal hemoglobin to survive
but you'd have a little bit of reduced
effect so that the sickle cell gene
would kill and break the life cycle of
the parasite just an interesting
phenomenon that shows that tied in with
hardy-weinberg that this is not follow
the expected allele change because of
the advantage of the heterozygote