you may hear some people say oh I've got
hard water and we're trying to give a
little shed some light on what it
actually means then what it doesn't mean
it doesn't mean ice or ice fishing
fishing the hard water hard water has to
refer to water here that contains a lot
of minerals in it it can present some
challenges to people in piping systems
here so hard water is water that
contains elevated levels of calcium and
magnesium typically above 150 milligrams
of calcium carbonate per liter that have
limestone it deposits can be located in
soil and what hard water forms when
water passes through these limestone
deposits as you did would be in the soil
kind of the unscientific way to test for
hard water we identified water that will
not allow soap to form bubbles when
mixed are added and that's because of
the calcium a high levels of calcium
magnesium that it contains so we can
damage metal fittings this is important
you're running an irrigation system you
can cause some issues with fittings that
you may have over time you can also
result build-up or calcification so here
we can see the outline of a pipe here
and you can see the layers that it build
up and how small the diameter is of this
pipe so now that you have all this build
up in here this is also reducing your
flow and this could be important if
you're looking at maximizing movement of
water and planning out an irrigation
system this can severely restrict it you
can cause issues in the total volume
that you're getting to your plants can
have cholera can also have high sodium
levels which can lead to nutrient
deficiencies chlorine is needed by the
plants but only in small quantities they
may like a small pinch of salt they want
to be adding spoonfuls of salt here
because it can really mess with the
cation exchange capacity
so while chlorine is needed it's not
needed it in very high amounts in plants
high amounts can damage plants alas I
will watch for high levels of chlorine
in a Corvette imide sorry since this can
kill beneficial microbes that you may be
trying to add or trying to propagate so
when we're looking at hard water or
sometimes treatment of that if you have
high levels of chlorine you can be
damaging microbes that you're directly
adding to your water before you even
apply it to your plants especially if
you're considering using organic compost
tea
other micro conditions you know might
keep a plate nice and sterile but if
you're adding with the intention of
adding these microbes you add to water
that contains high-level Corrine or
these other sterilants you can be
basically killing the good microbes that
you're trying to add