all right here I'm gonna go over a
hardy-weinberg practice problem this
will hopefully clear up any issues you
might be having they'll give you an
example and work it through so you can
understand the process that you go
through
remember don't practice until you get it
right practice until you can't get it
wrong so review this as many times as
you need to and hopefully this will be
overall helpful with you understanding
the process so Hardy Weinberg problem
down here remember this is our equation
Lu constantly be doing that this would
be constant
you're welcome use your calculator to
help yourself work work through this
problem
so given a population of 100 individuals
remember diploid individuals of 200
total alleles 16 exhibit a recessive
trait so the problem is to finally
allele frequencies for big a in little a
and find the genotype frequencies for
the homozygous dominant the heterozygous
and the homozygous recessive this is all
you would be given and you'd be expected
to find these answers in this feed I'm
going to go through this step process
the points process to help you gain some
experience so the allele frequencies we
want to calculate first how can I go
about doing that
well P plus Q equals 1 and since P
equals a big a and Q goes away then we
can simply say big a plus la will equal
1 so the question is something out of
200 plus 32 to 200 will equal 200 at 200
you need to work with the total allele
so we're the number 200 come from that
was the total alleles where did the 32
come from well the 16 that exhibits the
recessive trait mean that they're these
individuals here through the homozygous
recessive so 16 times 2 is the 32 so if
this equals the 16 percent then
something plus 16 percent has to equal
hundred percent which means 84 percent
because 84 plus 16 is 184 percent are a
combination of the homozygous dominant
and the heterozygotes now in order to
calculate what the almost I guess
dominant and the heterozygotes are and
to take this the next step further so 16
percent and
full form is represented by 0.16 and
this is the same as Q squared those are
two little A's or q q or q squared a
representative right here remember
that's our recessive or 0.16 we simply
take the square root of that to get Q
which is point four now this one's point
four we know 1 minus Q equals P or 1
minus 0.4 is 0.6 so the dominant allele
here is represented by 0.6 and the
recessive allele by 0.4 this is a big
help because now we can start to input
this into our equation and help answer
the genotype frequencies so the
phenotype frequencies if P equals 0.6 in
cused 0.4 then we simply plug into the
equation P squared is 0.6 times 0.6
which is your 0.36 Q squared is 0.4
times 0.4 just point one six and the
heterozygotes - PQ two times 0.6 times
points point four eight what these
decimals refer to is the homozygous
dominant represent 36% of the population
the heterozygous dominant is 48 percent
and recessive is 16% hopefully this is
helpful going through an example here to
help you understand how to calculate the
hardy-weinberg equation and to test your
knowledge here is another question here
Fraggles are mythical mouse-like
creatures that live beneath flower
gardens if a hundred Fraggles in a
population of 100,000 of population 91
have green hair we're going to represent
with capital F and nine have gray hair
lowercase a' assume in june at
equilibrium what are the gene
frequencies of big f and little F and
one of the genotypic frequencies I
invite you to pause the video here so
you can go through and work this problem
on your own before I proceed with the
answers all right we're going to proceed
now with the answers hopefully you can
compare your own to the answers that I
have presented here so the answers are
simple F is a point
little F is 0.3 and going through our
hardy-weinberg equation as you can find
at the beginning of this video the
homozygous dominant it's 49% the
heterozygous is 42% and the homozygous
recessive is 9% this is another
graphical representation to help you
work through the problem and kind of
shows it with the punnett square if that
helps you understand that a little bit
better but invite you to go back and
review this video so you can be a feel
comfortable calculating with the
hardy-weinberg equation