okay here I'm going to go over your
harvesting and curing the squash and the
curing process which I'm going to focus
on here applies only to your winter
squash summer squash will be harvested
daily and sold with their relatively
short shelf life but curing a winter
squash can significantly increase its
shelf life so far our winter squash the
length of time that you can store it
will depend on the particular variety
delicata will only store for about three
months while some others can last almost
a calendar year we want to harvest in
mid to late September or about 60 days
from pollination often color can be a
poor indicator so look at the stem and
the days from pollination as an
indication whether that will be ready
for curing and harvesting you want to
cut this stem right at the volume you
want to bring all of your squash from
the field and store them in an area of
about 80 degrees Fahrenheit for about a
week with some Sun some good air
circulation want to put them in an area
that's gonna hold a lot of moisture open
bins slotted bins here Medinah pellets
allow for air circulation and they are
advantageous give you some links here
for some fact sheets and some ideas and
how to properly cure your squash so you
get the longest storage time possible