in this debaco university video we're
going to go over the harvest process
of cannabis going to give you some
options such as whole plant or selective
as well as an indoor and an outdoor
environment example
so you can try to apply this process and
be thinking about
your chosen path when you go to
considering harvesting cannabis plants
all right let's get into the harvest
process of cannabis and remember those
real world examples
we provided at the end here so first off
even before you get into harvest while
many growers focus on the harvest
process
remember that before you begin the
process of harvesting you should have
the next step
all set to go and that next step very
important drying and curing process
make sure you have that set up before
you start taking any plants down
there's no sense harvesting if you're
not ready to move the material through
the final phases of the process
simply because you have a greater chance
of losing
that crop and material there so how do
you determine
when to harvest when's the best time to
harvest well this comes from an
inspection of the buds themselves
a combination of stigma and trichome
development is used to pinpoint the peak
harvest times
if you want to see some representative
images of both the stigma the trichome
looking at the bud size
and development there are other videos
on this channel that can help you with
that
in short though when the stigmas are tan
brown coloration and the trichomes are
mostly cloudy with a few starting to
turn amber color
this is typically a sign that the
harvest time is basically
quote unquote now when you're kind of
seeing that age of development that's
kind of that peak harvest time
and you want everything set up for the
drying and caring phase ahead of that
so when you get to this you can go
through with the harvest process
so preparing the plants preparing the
growers as well
when you determine that the plants are
close to harvest time be sure to allow
some time to flush them when you're only
giving them water
and not nutrients to remove any excess
buildups of nutrients or salts in the
root zone
also by just giving them water you're
reducing your input cost
without impacting your yield for more
information on that again more other
videos
keep in mind that this is applied to
both indoor and outdoor operations as
well as hydroponics
uh hydropodox you have the shortest
duration of flush time
and for soil you're with a higher clay
base you're gonna have the longest
duration of time
between uh for flushing
so we need to move uh we need to have
more than just the plants uh be sure you
have the following on hand to make the
harvest pricing as efficient as possible
you need to have pruners a transport
surface as well as time and labor
to go through the actual process of
taking down the plants
harvesting them now there will be other
videos on what trims and dry trims that
you can look at in this channel
as far as doing the final detail trim as
we see here but just taking the plants
down can be quite labor intensive
so those pruners that i had mentioned
when we were talking pruners or when i'm
mentioning pruners i'm talking something
more like the image here
they're used for cutting back branches
and are different from scissors
that are used more for detail work so i
consider these to be
scissors these are more your pruners
they're typically the rough and tough
plant takedown tools
they're especially useful for moving the
central stem on that ground level
on smaller plants and larger plants
you're kind of cutting that plant down
that you're going to use pruners for
your scissors i consider to be more your
detailed trimmers
for example now that transport surface
that i had mentioned
since you're likely to have the growing
location separate from the drying
location
a method of moving the plants needs to
be implemented depending on the size of
the harvest and distance this can
involve a trailer or even a cart
in either situation the goal is to have
a clean surface
and to not overly pack the plants during
transport to avoid
physically damaging the plants during
this process
some go with like cattle trailers and
actually hang plants right
in there others will go with selective
bins so all of these are different
options
but the key part or consistency with all
these is clean
we have to wash them out between
transport and not really kind of like
packing them in there
you're kind of kind of loosely putting
them here or even hanging them
are both good options and as i mentioned
the time
and labor so having an idea of the scale
of your operation which we'll see in
some
videos here showing indoor and outdoor
scale the operation is important
and the plants you determine to be ready
for harvest make sure you have enough
time in helping hands to get the job
done
often this is a labor intensive process
so be sure to pace your progress and
keep an eye on everyone
for both typically to make sure that
plants are being harvested in the way
you want
but also just a good practice to keep an
eye on everyone that's working for you
i make sure no one gets lost or
dehydrated or heat stroke or anything
like that so again keep that in mind as
well
now we've got two ways we can harvest uh
pro campus in general
we have the whole plant harvest and then
we also have selective plant harvest
well whole plant harvest the advantages
is allows for clearing the entire plant
material
all at the same time which is great
makes for easy planning and clearing of
the area
great if the planned end product is uh
concentrates because you're taking all
the buds all the fla
all the plants at the same time the
disadvantage is it's the most labor
intensive of the harvesting options
and all the plant material has to be
handled at the same time and it's going
to be very difficult to kind of
hang and dry entire plants but as we can
see in this image it is possible
the other option if it doesn't sound
like it fits your operation we have also
going on to selective plant harvest so
this allows growers to select
only the buds at their prime can provide
the opportunity for other buds to
continue to develop and ideally get more
yield
in the same area however the
disadvantage does require multiple times
to go through the plants and harvest
and time and care needed to be taken to
carefully remove
only those buds that are at the peak of
harvest
so you've now you've learned about these
methods you have an idea about the kind
of harvest process
now i'm going to go into both an outdoor
and an indoor operation
so you can get an idea of applying what
method you might choose to these actual
real world
situations so i hope you enjoy
now keep in mind this is field grown so
you are going to have some natural
variability especially growing this many
plants with some very
with the variable of the weather and
reaction to maybe the transplant of
going into containers
but overall i can see that there's
definitely this
great kind of transition from the
vegetative stage right to the flower
stage
and now getting to late flower stage
which will soon progress
to the harvest stage and that will lead
to the drying and curing
stage as well so this is a nice kind of
view here of just kind of the end of the
season harvest there
and we'll look some of these buds a
little bit closer up here so you can get
that appreciation
for exactly what all these plants have
gone through and are producing
so here we are out in the field looking
at the development of the buds and
assessing how far along they are
and we can see looking at some of the
leaves near the buds we're seeing that
coloration that amber
kind of change to the leaves we're also
going to be getting into
looking at the actual bud themselves
now we're seeing a full kind of
development here we're noticing we're
going to get a little closer view here
of the actual stigmas to see how they're
actually looking and they're developing
quite
long we're seeing a lot of that brown
coloration indicating
they're kind of nearing that end of
development now we don't want to always
compare to what's around us because it
can
depend on the planting time of the
actual crop depending a little bit on
the weather
but looking behind me we see the leaves
turning so this is a sign that
we're having that reduction in light
that change in photo period and that's
signaling these plants to go through and
develop
now here as we're taking a real specific
look at this bud in particular
you definitely see some of the
development that is occurring and the
degree
of development that's occurring now
those leaves definitely getting some of
that little purple coloration to them
indicating we are getting to the colder
times of the year
indicating hopefully also those
infosight might be as just a stress
response
and some some varieties will produce
more of that purple
however we're really looking at is kind
of the stigma and hopefully the
development of trichomes with the loop
and we're noticing here that we're
getting that kind of brown coloration to
the very end
that's a sign that we're getting near
that end of development
okay that this bud's going to be ready
to harvest pretty soon
here's another bud on the same plant
also inspecting this one
not the apical meristem this is one of
the side branches
but we can see continued and consistent
development which is great to see
realizing that this may not get to the
full development that we saw the first
one
but definitely seeing very consistent
colorations very consistent stigma
development so again it may not reach
the full size
as the apical meristem but definitely
progressing along the same
progression that we saw the apocalypse
and indicating this plant might be
harvested
all around the same time which makes it
great from a grower standpoint
we don't have to go through and harvest
all the individual buds at separate time
tables
so this is that little zoom out here
looking at the whole plant
and the many located behind this one
so overall here you can see in total in
this grow space it's about 6 000
plants so it's harvest time
which is a busy time and sometimes you
can be a victim
of your own success but just keep going
through
keep harvesting and hopefully you'll be
rewarded
in the end with a very successful crop
and there's plenty of work to do here
that we can see so as we're going
through the greenhouse here we can see
all of the plants
see kind of this greenhouse environment
have some fans on for air circulation
try to prune those lower leaves out now
we are getting close to the harvest time
so we are seeing the buds developing and
here we see the
upper portions being where the light is
exposed and of course
that's where most of the prime or apical
buds
are positioned see some lights there
those lights are there for early stage
growth and if it's cloudy out
offers a little supplemental light the
main light source for these plants
is of course the sun which makes this
greenhouse environment very
energy efficient now there is some heat
and cooling of course and some lights as
you can see
but for the most part the sun is the
energy now utilizing that sun we see the
screen of green method here where all
those buds have kind of been pruned
and kind of directed to go through that
mesh
material and that mesh material allows
them to support themselves allows a
great way to be able to support
all those plant materials to try to
maintain these those apical buds
so they get the maximum amount of light
and that's why we saw earlier the lower
portions
being pruned out with the leaves now
there are about 6 000 plants here
so quite a lot to take care of getting
ready to harvest
so there is a lot of work to come
with the harvest process of all of these
plants