so I'm going to go through the basic
harvest process for cannabis as we see
that has occurred on the plants in this
image right here so first one the
general process got four basic steps
step one is to reduce or stop
fertilizing one or two weeks before the
anticipated harvest date now the length
of time can depend on the growing media
and the fertilizer regimen that the
grower is choosing to use typically for
soils you're looking at the one a two
week span of time for cocoa Clara about
weighting about its seven-day or about
it that week or so timeframe for hydro
may only be one to two days so again the
area that you're growing in may
influence that and also the
aggressiveness or the degree of
fertilizer that is being applied by the
chosen grower so after reduce or stop
fertilizing I'm looking at flushing the
plants with enough water to have about
25% leave the root zone as excess so in
this case for indoor operations you want
to catch pan to allow that to occur for
outdoor applications you're looking at
that a little bit extra water that
you're adding to flush the nutrients
flush the water beyond the root zone
behind where those roots are capable of
taking that up they'll reduce the
potential for unwanted fertilizer in the
buds or plant next step is to remove the
entire plant at the base this is a
downward image here cut right the base
for an outdoor operation with pruners be
careful not to disturb the buds which
could impact trichome structures in
resins here we're seeing the basic plant
structure left in place and pruned off
here starting at the outside working its
way to the core gonna be careful not to
lay the whole plant on the ground here
in particular problem with potential
outdoor operations because that may kind
of mess at some of the structures and
the resins here that the plants spend a
lot of time creating lastly I want to
manicure the buds taking care remove all
small leaves with sharp scissors here
and you could see you have an area to
store them I can dry them but this is
where a little bit of that manual labor
does come in this can be kind of a
time-consuming process here there are
automate automate adoptions for larger
operations this is kind of the general
kind of recommendation here this summary
adds a little bit of a care
fully plans kind of coordinated event
here they got a chess match because
they're trying to or ultimately your
goal is to maximize the production here
that you have now this bud trimming and
manicuring that takes place with those
small detailed scissors and it's advised
and that's grower preference there as
far as what scissors you use now when
you are cutting the plants down on a
larger scale want to make sure you are
cutting them at the crown or something
moving large branches is the most
efficient the main root ball can be left
in the container as this does not
contain any valuable cannabinoids so
cutting it right down here soil line
we're just removing the buds here will
ensure you're getting the maximum amount
of cannabinoids post-harvest bud
trimming as I mentioned should have the
smaller leaves pruned helps us be the
drying process out we want to leave it
all kind of there Mike chopped unwanted
moisture and it could be a site for a
potential mold to develop this is a
labor-intensive process again there are
automated machines that can help do the
majority of the initial work there is
usually quality control it does come in
at the end and all this process should
be purged shortly after harvest
shouldn't be waiting a long time to do
this bud trimming process now the
equipment for bud trimming typically
wearing disposable gloves of some kind
having good scissors pointed ends are
recommended was e with even the variety
of a good idea to maximize the finished
production sometimes you could have can
I do an initial trim and in a more
detailed trim now you are saving the
buds but you do want to potentially save
these trimmings to improve the overall
yield and can be made into hash or other
concentrates so the areas close to the
buds may be trimmed out but they still
may have elevated levels of anoints that
are worth saving in going through some
further purification process
lastly saving the trimmings is suggested
to improve the total yield it could be
made into hash rather concentrates and
that is important because rather than
throwing this away won't may not be as
potent as the actual buds it can be a
way to help increase overall yields and
to try to recoup some of the expenses
and time and labor that you spent
cultivating the crop