here I'm gonna go over the hurt diagram
and how it does not look like the image
pictured here I suggest you get a clean
sheet of paper out and a pen or pencil
so I want you to be able to draw a heart
and diagram I'm gonna go over kind of
the may seem like awkward way we're
gonna draw it but I think it'll make
more sense
so starting we'll just get you familiar
with the simple heart diagram these are
some of the basic components you should
be familiar with the atrium the
ventricle some of the valves well if you
I asked you to draw this it's a little
bit difficult the orientation where
everything is located so what we're
going to focus on for our sketch or our
drawing is not a necessarily
anatomically correct picture of the
heart but a square heart and what does
that look like well this is kind of a
square heart diagrams I think these are
very helpful the sense of understanding
exactly how things look and where things
are located so I'll draw attention to
this image first we see on the left hand
side here our a and our V you might
think well didn't they label this wrong
is in this little left side why is this
the right atria why is this the right
ventricle well that's simply because
we're looking at oriented in the body to
be the right side the body in the left
side of the body
so from our perspective looking at the
square diagram this would be the
deoxygenated this left hands had to be
the deoxygenated side or the right side
of the heart would be deoxygenated on
the left side of the heart is the
oxygenated blood and that's indicated in
red here the top here is our pulmonary
circuit going to the lungs that here's
our systemic go into the body so
starting with that right atrium that is
receiving blood from the body the
deoxygenated blood from the body so
that's where blood is first entering at
that right atrium then passing to the
right ventricle where then it's going to
be pumped out to the lungs
you see our blue line becomes our red
line our d'action blood becomes red even
though in real life it's just different
shades of red
after that blood comes back from the
lungs it's entering the left atrium from
that left atrium it's going down to left
ventricle
this chamber of the heart has the
greatest amount of muscle because this
left ventricle needs to pump blood out
to the entire body so we've got our
right atrium going to our right
ventricle going to then the lungs coming
back from the lungs so that left atrium
and into the left ventricle now we're
going to make this a little bit more
complicated that blood that's coming
into the right atrium well that's coming
in the vena cava so we want to label
that it's getting a pass to the right
ventricle when it leaves to light the
right ventricle it is going to the
pulmonary artery where it's entering the
lungs after it gets oxygenated in the
lungs it returns from the pulmonary vein
remember arteries carry blood away from
the heart veins carry blood towards the
heart this is oxygenated blood coming
back into the heart at the left atrium
it's Indian passed the left ventricle
and going out the aorta to the rest of
the body now one last thing I want you
know make note of and add to your square
heart diagram are the valve names so I
want just back here for a second from
our right atrium to our right ventricle
watch the label that says the tricuspid
valve then after the blood leaves the
right ventricle heads to the lungs
before it goes out the pulmonary artery
has to pass through the pulmonary valve
then that gets oxygenated comes back in
the left atrium as it travels from the
left atrium to the left ventricle goes
through the material valve from that
valves there before it pumps to the rest
of the body there at the aorta it has to
go through the aortic valve so make sure
you have the atrium the valves and also
the proper veins and arteries labeled
and in a square heart I find that's the
most easiest way for students to
understand once you have this completed
way to look now at this image the heart
detailed image it's heart to be able to
put together all the different
components there I do want to make note
that the a trio pin ticular valve here
is sometimes that is what it's called
here see our tricuspid valve and the
trail valve here they do kind of go by
name's I think it's a little easier to
tell them apartment a tricuspid here
between on the right atrium and the
right ventricle in the material between
the left atrium and the left ventricle
hopefully this is helpful starting to
understand the complexities of the four
chamber hurt and the pathway blood takes
through the heart as it receives from
the rest of the body goes out to the
lungs comes back in the lungs after it's
after need they get sent out the aorta
to all of the necessary components of
our body