in this debaco university video we'll be
investigating heat source
as a carbon dioxide delivery for
cannabis production
if you're looking for a way to add some
heat and carbon dioxide
this can be a great way to combine both
of these methods into one
so first off many times growers need to
heat their spaces
and a lot of times we're trying to
maintain that nice plant conditions a
lot of times
supplemental heat is needed so heating a
growing air with a heater that also
generates carbon dioxide
seems like an obvious choice and it can
be very beneficial
however growers need to realize that
when when the heater will actually be on
in a regular 24-hour day if the heat is
only needed during the dark or
night period the addition of carbon
dioxide will not provide the plants
with much benefit only when the lights
are on or the sun is out
will the plants actually utilize carbon
dioxide efficiently
so we have the fall winter spring area
as well so in colder regions there may
be the need to heat
a grow space during light hours which
may only be during the cool
to cold seasons of the year this will
cause a slight unevenness in growth
related to the amount of carbon dioxide
enrichment
but when heat is needed anyway it can be
a worthwhile
addition so it may not be something
you're adding in the summer time because
it might be
adding cooling systems but this could be
a way to help benefit
during the colder months with adding
some carbon dioxide at least
now we have also the springtime push so
to get seedlings or clones off to a
quick and early start
this method of carbon dioxide generation
seems logical due to the typical need
for additional heat
anyway during this stage while this may
not be continued for the remainder of
the season
it can be a great way to give plants a
push early when fertilizers are
typically kept at a minimum
to avoid damaging of the small seedlings
or the small clones
supplementing that area with carbon
dioxide typically it's going to be
cooler anyway
it can be a great way to boost growth
with minimizing potential damage
to the plants and again the springtime
especially typically heat is needed
so why not use a heat source that will
also provide some additional benefit
by enriching your area with carbon
dioxide