okay here we're a very important protein
structure called hemoglobin it's
involved in our red blood cells and is
vital to keep us alive to allow oxygen
the carbon tax hit to be exchanged
within our body so hemoglobin first
oxygen moves within the circulatory
system piggyback then the protein called
hemoglobin because it's a protein in
shape is very important hemoglobin
contains iron which combined with oxygen
in a reversible way it's a good thing
it's reversible we want oxygen to bind
and also be released from that we also
want even the open to transport our
carbon dioxide this gives you an idea of
the chemical structure F sees that iron
located in the center and actually if
you compare this to chloroplasts in
plants it actually is a very similar
structure with magnesium being in the
center so hemoglobin each hemoglobin
molecule can carry four oxygen atoms the
presence of oxygen turns hemoglobin a
bright red if it's not down to the
oxygen those would be a shade of red but
not quite that bright vibrant red they
see the binding here of our oxygen
molecules seeing one down to see the
options for to being down for 3 being
bound and then for 4c that same image
kind of pictured here at T State and our
state TV stands for 10 state R stands
for a relaxed state so if kind of that
relaxed state that fully for oxygen
molecules being bound to that hemoglobin
keep in mind each red blood cell has
multiple and many many hemoglobin
molecules so that's allowing it to bind
a lots of oxygen and transport that to
cells that are actively respiring
continuing on when oxygen binds it
causes a conformational change in the
proteins so we can see here is our
change deoxygenated versus our
oxygenated you can see there's a change
in shape here non-planar versus planar
because this is a protein again shape is
very important an additional can impact
proteins well he is one also pH is
another factor that can affect that we
see here a decrease in pH causes greater
release of oxygen from hemoglobin so pH
of seven point four to seven point two
you can see that shift that nose will
shift in the effect of the saturation of
the
this is why our blood is kept in a very
tight pH range as we want the protein
hemoglobin to be able function properly
something in the news did you hear quite
a bit is carbon monoxides I want to make
sure I mentioned that carbon monoxide
binds tighter to hemoglobin than oxygen
not allowing for these gases to be
carried
so what's occurring let's look at this
here we're looking at our oxygen bound
to hemoglobin and here's our pressure of
oxygen we're noticing under normal
hemoglobin with no carbon monoxide down
we can bind this much of our oxidant no
I high amount as we start increasing our
carbon monoxide
here's 20% carbon monoxide 40% 60% we
see this plateau occurring very early
now allowing us to carry potentially
enough oxygen which could either allow
us in a good case to pass out or
potentially die anemia and that normal
hemoglobin we had this severe anemia
this is another way to kind of
graphically represent that so our blood
our blood in our body system may need
this about this much oxygen you can see
how carbon dioxide can negatively impact
that what it does is it's kind of
clogging up the binding sites not
allowing oxygen to give it anywhere to
bind to and be carried by the red blood
cell kind of found this a little
humorous there where we have hemoglobin
with oxygen and it tends to bind higher
to carbon monoxide and as a result it'll
kick out oxygen so we kind of see that
represent a funny way here but there is
some supporting science and if the
graphs don't help you remember it maybe
this will lastly cover the oxide
poisoning I feel I should mention
symptoms of carbon dioxide poisoning are
basically symptoms of low oxygen
however carbon dioxide is tasteless
odorless gas that we can't detect
dizziness headaches
impairment of brain function
ultimately you know could be a coma and
muscle weakness cramps nausea all these
are examples of carbon monoxide
poisoning extremely deadly poisonous gas
just for comparison carbon dioxide which
is in your body right now that's okay
it's an amount of the person
that you may have so one three five or
eight percent a percents extremely high
and it can cause unconsciousness and
tremors one percent just could be
drowsiness three percent because we
reduced hearing increased heart rate and
blood pressure your Bloods trying to
move and get rid of some of that carbon
dioxide five percent to be shortness of
breath dizziness confusion headache and
eight percent serious case even didn't
sight so keep in mind there's a
difference between carbon dioxide and
carbon monoxide with dioxin being a lot
easier to have or a lot easier to
recover from then lot outside this finds
very tight to human globin molecules