welcome this tobacco university video
we are investigating hemp-based cannabis
for
fiber and also grain production so
looking more on a little bit of a large
or
industrial scale here hemp production
so first off when we're looking at
producing it for grain and
fiber here that can be highly mechanized
because we are looking at a large scale
here
with the labor demands per acre similar
to that of other
agronomic crops except for wheat control
and harvest operations which require
relatively
more time for hemp so again we can
mechanicalize harvest it can be a large
area
make sure you're having this equipment
so you can be able to process those
large volumes of plant material
now we're looking at seed sources uh
hemp used for fiber or biofuel or other
products grown about
six to seven feet in height it's gonna
be very tall crop
the goals produce long fibers for
industrial processing
there are some varieties listed here to
have some
validation based on some data for
nebraska conditions
is the best information that i could
find here so again for looking at
your particular region you might want to
try to see if there's been any research
done on particular
varieties for your particular climate or
growing location
now these hemp varieties just in general
should be certified as having
less than 0.3 percent thc so they're
below that federal limit
grain production tend to favor early
maturing varieties
if you look more for fiber production i
tend to favor later maturing varieties
to allow for an increased cellulose
concentration
in yield as the season progresses male
plants do die off during the season
and manage these female varieties are
generally preferred for industrial hemp
production
so again keep that in mind when you're
looking at planting or purchasing
seed now planting for grain and fire
production the whole planting process in
general for grain
grain production may be optimized with
no more than 150 000 plants per acre
and sowing 20 to 30 pounds of seed
per acre to kind of get to that number
now for fiber production this is data
based on europe but fiber yields were
not increased by having
more than 182 000 plants per acre
and this plant density results in better
quality fiber
than with higher planting densities
that's a prime example there where
more plants aren't better per acre you
want to try to maximize
your production within that growing area
now keep in mind that soil temperature
should be around 55 degrees fahrenheit
an emergence is likely to be three to
five days
after spring planting now should be
about that 55
it's warmer than that probably a little
bit better if it's cooler than that
that may stunt or reduce the rate of
germination that you notice with your
seeds
now harvesting for that grain in fiber
you know how do you go about that
harvesting
process there for grain as with many uh
any grain crop
really the proper harvesting processing
transport and storage are critical to
prevent spoilage
and also ensure the highest value for
the harvested grain
a grain drying facility is needed and
grain drying should be
again within an hour and a half of
harvest so it's always good to have or
make sure
you have the full process for said crop
before you go through and plant it
drying can be done at 140 degrees
fahrenheit with a continuous flow dryer
but grain temperature should not exceed
100 degrees fahrenheit
to avoid the chance of toasting your
crop there
now for fiber harvesting hemp is usually
grown in wider
windrow and cut for fiber production at
about eight inches between early bloom
and seed set
when the lower leaves of the female
plant begin to yellow and bailed at
twelve percent
moisture content this is where kind of
have an idea knowing your crop and
checking the fields
to try to hit that kind of peak time to
harvest
if you're looking at fiber now the
market for
grain and fiber just in general again
it's always a little hard to kind of
gauge
your particular market but it appears at
least using 2019
as an example the supply greatly
exceeded the demand
and hemp fiber and grain stock uh sorry
feed
grain for feedstock prices plunged
during the 2019
season with specific regions getting hit
harder than
others so processors offer growers a
profit share
agreement on the product when sold in
place of outright purchasing of
feedstock at an agreed
price so this again this is always a
little bit of
a kind of a challenge with any sort of
perishable crop or crop in general
looking at demand versus supply
and if supply really kind of becomes
very high demand might go down
so always good to kind of have an idea
what the realistic price will be
what it was in previous years and any
sort of data you can
you can gain so you can make an educated
decision
but it is a kind of variable market so
it's not a guaranteed sale there and a
lot of this can come with agreements
growers may establish ahead of time so
again just keep that in mind
that with again any crop you got to keep
an idea of the market
so you can make sure that it's
profitable to use in your growing area