now a threat with any using of any
herbicides is
the potential for drift well here we're
going to see some images of what some
common herbicide
drift damage looks like on hemp plants
welcome to this tobacco university video
where we're going to look at
herbicide damage symptoms on hemp so
first off there is this great reference
article and you're welcome to take a
look
at it from the university of california
and they look at herbicide damage
symptoms on hemp
pride the link here and they go through
more herbicides that i'm going to cover
here
try to pick out some of the very common
ones that might be utilized that you
might see or be familiar with
but this article has even more resources
if you want to take a look at that
so first off looking at herbicides in
general well here's the active
ingredients in trade names
a lot of people kind of focus on the
trade names but looking at that active
ingredient is important
understanding also common registered
uses at least in california at the time
that this data was pulled just to give
you an idea probably the most famous one
is roundup
is and the active ingredient is
glyphosate we'll also be looking at a
couple more kind of listed more by their
active ingredient
so compared to this list here because
you might be familiar with the trade
name
now glyphosate as i mentioned that first
one they are typically you know roundup
it's a post-emergent herbicide meaning
the weeds need to emerge before you
spray them
and it affects the meristematic regions
likely damaged by
drift on the hemp plants you want to
look for chlorosis which is a yellowing
that can progress to browning over five
to ten days it's a slow progression
we can see that evident here where it's
a little lighter in that yellow
coloration here it's a little bit more
evident here
this would be clear signs of glyphosate
drift that may have occurred
on your hemp plants then we also have a
paraquat
here and this is another post-emergent
let's see kind of
an example here it's a group d acts
rapidly within hours and drift can
appear as droplets browning necrosis
so we kind of get that little like
speckling effect now of course it occurs
in a larger degree you will get browning
of the entire leaf
but sometimes evan is that little like
speckling that might occur
and that can be an indication that
you're getting some spray drift from
this particular herbicide
then we have glucosinate which is injury
often
a function of concentration as well as
coverage
common trait name would be x out if
you're familiar with that type
typical symptoms initially occur within
a few days beginning with wilting
and chlorosis and progressing to
necrotic tissue here we see a little
more
aggressive of that kind of spotting
there a little more aggressive spread
and again this occurs typically a few
days again the evidence that this
herbicide
might have been drifted then a propanel
we see that one right here
injury is usually first observed in the
older fully formed leaves so that's
again an important distinction to make
here
looking at the older leaf damage not
necessarily the meristem
injuries often initially noted at the
leaf margins
such as the edges of the leaves and then
moves further into the interventile
areas
of the leaf it kind of starts at the
margins and works its way
in if the plant survives of the spoiler
exposure
newly formed leaves may not be effective
so this is one
that the plant can potentially grow out
of it
where is this herbicide typically used
well typically used for barnyard grasses
so if you have those in your particular
area might be spraying this at higher
frequency
this would be evidence of what drift to
be on the lookout for
and then lastly mentioned here synthetic
auxins and there's different types
at the whole plant level this abnormal
growth can take the form of leaf and
stem twisting
cupping bending cracking sometimes
curling
may occur and we see kind of the
evidence here of the plant just kind of
like
gets a little funky uh look to it again
just because you see leaf curling
doesn't always mean it's a herbicide
that was applied
but if you know one of these has been
applied in the area particularly 240
very known for its drifting abilities
and you see this curling that's an
indication that you may be getting some
of that herbicide
drift so just things to be cautious
for so i just wanted to provide you with
this kind of comparison here
if you are choosing the herbicide route
to be mindful of what product you'll be
using
and to be mindful of what those symptoms
may look on hemp plants
to be aware if you if drift is occurring
after your application