hiren look as the high-intensity
discharge pro-lite basics typically
abbreviated hid on lights they're just
the basics here we can consider cannabis
plant here under high-intensity light
probably a high-pressure sodium looking
at just kind of a yellow tint so
high-intensity discharge lights are HID
lights the basic types these are used to
try and replicate the natural sunlight
there's many different subcategories
such as mercury vapor HTS from mercury
vapor metal halide or high pressure
sodium and conversion bulbs two most
common you'll find our metal halide
which will tend have a more of a wider
look to the to the light spectrum and
HPS or high pressure sodium to have more
that yellow appearance these HID lights
and the suggested coverage area
depending on the wattage of bulb you're
using will depend on Natalie the
coverage area about how far away from
the foliage it should be a 400 watt
covers a 3x3 area and should be kept
about one or two feet above the foliage
600 watt covers a four by four area
effectively and should be about a foot
and a half to two feet away from the
foliage a thousand watt covers a five by
five air and should be kept about two
feet away from the foliage the
manufacturers will often state greater
areas and what's quoted above but this
is assuming dense plants for maximum
yield soak another thousand watt to a
six by six probably but not really
effectively it covers a five by five
area very effectively and that's what I
recommend here high-intensity discharge
lights the popular waters are four six
and thousand Watts thousand watts
trigger to the standards which allows
for the greatest coverage areas we just
saw here's a bunch of lights here all
thousand watt double-ended kavita pros
for this particular grow facility how do
they work well they produce light by
pressing electricity through a vaporized
gas and a seal tube under high pressure
on the mix of sevens is in the vapor
allow for different spectrums to be
produced and there are a few light bulb
manufacturers but odds are you pay for
what you get so higher price bulbs well
I can produce a better spectrum so it's
it's important not to go for the
cheapest light I you're trying to look
for when that's going to produce the
greatest spectrum because that could
have a large impact on
or total and yield