can we talk about HP escrow lights which
stands for high pressure sodium they're
very easy to distinguish because they
tend to produce this kind of yellowish
orange coloration to their a light
spectrum at least interpreted by the
human eye these high pressure sodium
lights much like metal halides are most
common in 600 and thousand watts super
bulbs just says with middle halides will
be brighter than this standard bulb the
most commonly used during flowering or
fruiting phase but can be used over the
entire grow cycle I've had plants go
from germination and little seedlings
all the way to flowering over the
fruiting under high-pressure sodium
lights they can generate more light than
a middle halide because of increased
efficiencies that they have but they can
also increase stem stretching is a
possibility to occur
want to be careful watch on which part
you're giving the plant that can help
reduce the impact of that making that
nice yellow kind of oranges look is very
common with HPS lights they produce that
yellow orange color light favours the 21
100 to 22 K will to Stanford Calvin
spectrum again that's just referring to
the coloration very little that is
impacted the plant or how we perceive it
high pressure sodium bulb life is rate
about 5000 hours but again most growers
are changing their bulbs out in a year
or less about 5000 hours in higher
quality lights will still give you about
95% efficiency so some growth will run a
little bit longer but be mindful of the
yield that you're looking to get and the
efficiencies can be very important the
pros I bet your sodium lights we see two
right here just cooling down the very
cost efficient as prices have dropped
with other technologies and during the
marketplace so that's another great
option that they're becoming cheaper per
fixture overall the technology is very
good although it's reached its peak it
may be replaced by LED lights going
forward and bulbs need to be replaced
and at least a yearly basis and the
reflectors typically every other year to
maybe every three at max every four
years example the high-pressure sodium
light this is a Kavita Pro 1000 de this
is a thousand watt double ended a light
fixture here and ballast all
inclusive well Kavita there kind of
claim to fame is they make lamps for
plants they're very much involved in the
horticultural lighting they ship
everything all inclusive they basically
pull out of the package and plug it in
you're good to go
these also have a dimmer on them which
is great if you're looking at maximizing
the versatility of using these lights
they run cool and efficient these
ballasts are cool to the touch even when
they're running they can be used for the
veg phase in production due to the broad
spectrum that these lights produce
that's just one example here of the
category under high-pressure sodium
lights that abbreviated HPS