okay here I want to talk about high
intensity discharge grow light bulbs and
here's an example of one right here I
hopefully understand that was a little
bit more after this lecture so HID bulbs
installation and removal well never
directly touch the bulb as the oils of
your hands can weaken the glass and
increase the odds of breaking here using
our plastic gloves in addition to paper
towel also here putting them on paper
towel right from the start to ensure
you're not going to go and touch them
also on the not if you're gonna be
removing the bulb make sure that it is
not warm why make sure it's fully cooled
before you're even going through and
touching it with anything before you're
removing it from the fixture so bulb
breaks hopefully you're not in the area
when it does you want to make sure you
turn off electricity as soon as you
realize it and give it sufficient time
to cool off then to remove it because
it'll be shards of glass when I take a
potato cut it in half take the flat side
and jam it against the broken shards of
glass and then we're also holding onto
the potato you want to then turn to
loosen the bulb without way it's a very
safe way to remove a bulb that has
broken which is not a good condition to
be in but it is a safe way to help
remove that bulb with minimal chance of
damage to yourself
want to replace the bulbs well lumen
output will degrade over time resulting
in less heat and poor growing spectrum
when a document the day the month in the
year of purchase if your grow shop does
not do this when you purchase it bulb
replacement is often debated but chip if
the stated life of the bulb you are
using and then by having that
documentation of that day that month in
the year allows you to make a judgment
of how long when the hours to be running
in today and what the expected life
would be of that bulb make sure you have
some bulbs on hand and that can means
you need to match up with whatever type
of fixture you're using keeps in spirits
on hand replacing bulbs after six to
eight months is not unheard of in
depending what type of light you're
running do not look at the bulb all it's
on turn it off a lot to cool and then
inspect the arc tube for a cloudy or
dark discoloration if you're not sure
how old the bulb is this will indicate
it you need to change the bulb when they
get that kind of arcing a net blackness
there some grow
so even keep extra fixtures on hand in
case of Alice goes out but make sure
you're having definitely plenty of extra
bulbs especially for running many of the
same light structure there's a debate
between single and double ended bulbs
it's a single ina this is a double ended
see lemons produce less heat they're
better fit for smaller areas with low
ceiling height and they're typically
used in growing operations double ended
as this as we see the de this is single
ended in double and these are typically
used for a large-scale production as
they produce more heat but you're
getting more light for the same energy
and as a result these are typically used
in larger areas or grow rooms than the
single ended ones are and both very
effective but looking at just maximizing
the efficiency that much more in a large
area that you can cool the double-ended
is the way to go