okay someone who's new to cannabis
growing or just gets a recent medical
license and ones that start growing
typically economy refer to those it's
kind of a hobby cannabis growers and
they will look for locations that are
kind of easily accessible so I'm gonna
give you kind of some basic ideas of the
room locations they may choose also with
some pros and cons associated those so
first off the basement for Hobby
burrowers it's relatively consistent
conditions easy to access kind of down
below is a nice typically as to deal
with water potentially easy to access to
bring large plant materials it can be
hard to kind of clear out or get
prepared to grow also hanging lights
convenient issue want to be careful of
the moisture of the basement does flood
so there can be some issues associated
with that an attic or hobby growers
typically mill minimal effort to set up
typically large and airy access to fresh
outside air our temperature fluctuations
can be extreme so it's important that
climate control is considered in this
type of setup looking at the garage or
shed for hobby growers typically there's
a quick easy large space easily defined
access to power can be very easy as long
as bringing in outside air
however the downfall is here what we're
looking at you know garages or sheds
there can be issues with having enough
power moving cars moving certain
furnitures keeping things clean and
sterile can also be an issue as garage
or shed operations this is why if you're
going to become a dedicated grower
especially for medical purposes you want
to have a room that's specifically
allocated with good cleanliness good
access to power to allow not only an
efficient grow and a safe route but also
one that is clean and won't breathe a
lot of diseases and cause issues so
that's one of the issues with the hobby
growers in general is that they can kind
of be quickly put together and that can
lead to a lot of negative effects both
in the plant and in product