so on this debaco University video I'm
going to go over the Hope going forward
with hops light and viroid it's been a
lot of Doom and Gloom try to give some
positivity here and give you an
indication of where this viroid might be
trending within the industry
[Music]
all right so let's go over the Hope
going forward with hop Layton viroid now
question a lot of Growers are asking is
it getting worse and honestly it's hard
to tell how to help the viroid is
actually spreading or if the awareness
is actually spreading and that's
resulting in more Growers looking for
this thyroid and actually identifying it
and finding it so are we on an upward
Trend are we on a downward Trend it's
really hard to tell we do have more
people looking for it and it is quite
prevalent and so that doesn't
necessarily mean it's getting worse it
means we're just identifying something
that's we that was already there before
we're even screening for it and again
stress is the point of testing screening
and actually looking for it not just
turning a blind eye to this
uh so why should I be concerned as a
grower well it reduces yields so that's
kind of a concern and if that's not
enough of a you know reason to be
concerned the pathogen does easily
spread uh so that is another concern to
both your operation as well as others
and there is no cure for this as well
this is why we need to be mindful of
this test for this and cull those plants
out as soon as possible so we're not
creating more of a problem
now being aware is the key part and that
comes through testing you want to know
what to look for and not be afraid to
test your plants don't think uh I don't
think that's hoplite Environ test to you
that you have uh to know whether it is
Apple and diet or something else
carefully tell others because if you
think their plants might be infected or
showing symptoms encourage them also to
get their plants tested and that's again
if they're showing symptoms in the
leaves plants can also have high viroid
loads in the roots that will then lead
to Upper portions of the plant
exhibiting symptoms so be aware testing
is very important roots and leaves
should be tested early on in favor of
the roots older plants you can test the
leaves particularly the petioles is a
good area
now this does not mean if you test
positive you're an unclean grower you
know like the you saw with all the you
know unclean all the leprosy all the
negative correlations with that if you
do have plants that test positive is not
indication of bad practices this is a
very prevalent uh viroid so it's more
important to test your plants and know
whether you have it so you can remove
and Implement protocols then it is turn
a blind eye to it and kind of spread it
to your operation as well as potentially
others uh operation as well
as again comes again with the value of
testing seed testing clone testing
asking for screening reports this is
really important if you're bringing
plants in do they get tested for hoplate
and thyroid you know do they have any
sort of documentation for that is it
something any new plants you get in you
should be testing your mother plants who
should be testing there's a lot of value
in this testing because that really
allows you identify plants early remove
of them and hopefully by discarding them
you're limiting the chance of it
spreading to many of your other plants
and hopefully saving your operation
now finding resisting cultivars this
would be a great thing to date no
cannabis cultivars are known to be
resistant to hoplite and virate some
aren't showing potentially what we call
tolerance meaning they're not as
severely affected but still coming to
this viroid however remember this is
still a new disease being identified and
more cultivars are now more cultivators
are aware of this and will be actively
seeking potentially having a resistant
variety to this but right now screening
and removing plants is the most
effective way
now sanitation protocols come along with
this be aware of your workers limit
contact with known infective plants know
who was around the infective plant
follow sanitation protocols or products
that actually work against hoplite and
thyroid alcohols do not work basically
your s and your bleach are really the
only two that really effective and
that's for surfaces and tools really
hard to clean the actual plant material
so keep that in mind resides in the sap
mainly and shows High viral reloads
early on in their Roots but then we'll
spread through the entire plant in only
about six weeks
lastly this is a problem but research is
ongoing so sharing of information both
at universities and also with companies
and getting more people aware doing
research on this is a way we can start
to understand this better and hopefully
find a way to reduce its spread to know
where it is to remove those plants and
eliminate this from the entire canvas
population going forward