okay here we're gonna look at some very
specific classifications of hormones a
little bit more detail on how the
different classifications of these
hormones have different ways of entering
and affecting cells so starting first
hormones in general well hormone is a
chemical signal that's produced in one
part of the body and acts at a distinct
site there's three main invaders to the
body to using these chemical signals one
is it can spread to all tissues via the
blood so our blood goes which is
throughout the entire body these
hormones can travel in addition they can
persist much longer than our electrical
signals electrical signals for example
would be in our nervous system which
also causes effects all over the body
but for a very short period of time
hormones persist much longer in the body
they can act as mini axes hormones so
we're looking here these chemical
signals right there acting an example
would be as hormones which we're going
to investigate here now different
hormones can target different tissues
it's very important because what is
secreted into the bloodstream will only
affect target cells it's not gonna
affect all cells doesn't affect target
cells which I have the image here is
these hormones create a balance that
needs to occur also a lot of times
there's a lot of stresses on the body
and hormons need to maintain this
balance or homeostasis on a daily basis
now how this is occurring is hormones
need receptors so we see a signal we see
a receptor and we have an effect that
occurs for example here's a hormone
entering the cell this one molecules
causing this cascading effect which is
then resulting in a ribosome producing a
protein which is changing the cell's
function so one little hormone can cause
a bunch of different steps to occur that
ultimately in this case cha caused a
change in the cell function now there's
homology in hormones so what does this
tell you about the hormone prolactin so
we have prolactin yeah affects mammals
and birds and fish and amphibians it's
related to kind of a growth hormone so
how does this hormone produce different
effects it's the same hormone as we see
here that's
milk production with the animals for
birds it's Fatma taslim metabolism for
fish it's salt and water balance in TV
ins its metamorphosis and maturation
well this kind of leads us to believe
that this suggests that prolactin is an
ancient hormone whose functions have
diversified along with the evolution of
various vertebrate groups so we have
this kind of single hormone that
depending on what animal it is can
affect but I have different effects
within those particular species so it is
kind of a way that we're looking at kind
of one hormone that were consuming this
is particularly for the man-made
hormones how that might be produced for
one animal how can negatively impact or
have a different impact on other species
that continuing hormones target cells
well there steroid hormones are
manufactured from cholesterol the lipid
soluble and making cross the lipid
bilayer in the cell membrane they bind
receptors within a nucleus usually
hormone receptor complex that live in
cDNA causing changes in gene activity
then we also have anabolic steroids
which are synthetic compounds resembling
testosterone these cause muscle cells to
produce more protein so you have our
steroid hormones that are in a box
steroids which are synthetic man-made
compounds kind of that version here of
the Hulk
now classification of hormones we have
two major classifications
one is protein-based hormones that are
polypeptides small proteins
glycoproteins or large proteins with
carbohydrates and amines which are
modified amino acids then we have our
lipid side will based hormones which are
steroids and they're modified
cholesterol and so it's important again
it's still keep in mind of the
macromolecules and discover hydrates
lipids and proteins and their different
properties and these may have now
looking specific at lipid soluble
hormones to investigate them just a
little bit further here we see a lipid
soluble hormone in the right in the
blood cells here here's our red blood
cells it goes through the blood vessel
and we see the lipid side with hormones
diffuses through the plasma membrane
hormone binds with a receptor in the
cytoplasm forming this complex the
receptor hormone complex enters in
nucleus triggering gene transcription we
see here a change in the DNA and are
transcribed mRNA messenger RNA is
translated into proteins after the alter
cell activity so this single hormone
gets into the nucleus changes a gene
expression ultimately resulting on a
protein being made they can alter
cellular activity a steroid Homan
directly initiates production of
proteins within a target cell so we want
to compare lipid silyl hormones to some
of our other hormones
now steroid hormones are gonna fall
under this same category this might be a
little clearer to say because here we
have our steroid hormone directly
entering the cell creating complex going
into the nucleus binding the sites and
the chromatin activating mRNA
transcription resulting in the cellular
response these steroid hormones enter
through the cell membrane and bind
receptors inside the target cell these
hormones may directly stimulate
transcription of genes and make certain
proteins because terrence steroid
hormones work by targeting gene activity
the response is slower than the other
group were look at which is peptide
hormones so steroids follow the same
category as lipid soluble water-soluble
are a little different here so our water
Seibel hormone we notice here is binding
to a surface receptor so water Seibel
hormones are membrane soluble they bind
them membrane receptors so if we look
back at the other one here there is no
membrane here I just kind of went right
through right to the nucleus these are
lipid soluble here we're focusing now on
water side they bind and activate what's
called the g-protein this then is then
causing it to then go through and enter
the cell so we're noticing we're not
directly going into the nucleus who are
binding to surface proteins because they
could not diffuse directly through the
cell membrane they're water soluble they
can't get by that phospholipid bilayer
these hormones must find a surface Selmy
membrane receptors before initiating a
cell signal as we see here so we're
still inactivated protein in the end but
it's a very different pathway than our
little bits
continuing on is peptide hormone
pathways we see that receptor binding
these peptide hormones these short
peptides or full-sized proteins they do
not enter the cell directly they bind to
receptors embedded in its cell membrane
as we see here when the hormone binds
receptor a secondary messenger molecule
initiates a cellular response you see
that here initially in this response
that then ultimately is going into the
nucleus and causing the initiation of
indirectly of secondary messengers this
signal transduction is this multiple
fold increase in our message being
received within the cell peptide
hormones are water-soluble and often
produce faster responses then the
benefits of this secondary messenger
system you have the signal that's
binding we have a receptor protein and
the key part here we have this
amplification steps that are occurring
so one single binding going through we
see these multiple implications then we
seen implication from that so from one
binding we generate one two three four
five six seven eight
cyclic EMPs here from those eight each
one of those can develop a protein
kinase which can produce a whole bunch
of enzymes which introduce a whole bunch
of product so this cascade multiplied
our response is also a very quick
response this is how we can produce the
body commuters very small amounts of
hormone and have a very large effect
that occurs or large response of product
within the body system so the benefits
of the secondary messenger system is the
implication that can occur in the large
amount of product that can be produced
from a very small or relatively small
amount of signal being produced
initially by the body