ever wonder just how water travels
through a soil profile
here on debaco university we're going to
see some cutaways of some soil profiles
and see just how water travels through a
soil profile
giving some varying different conditions
[Music]
all right let's get into how water
travels through a soil profile
well first off special thanks to this
video here that is uh provided
information because this is the video
where i
captured many of the screenshots that
we're going to see here presented so if
you want to look at the original
by all means look at the reference below
and look at the direct link there as
well
so getting into how water travels
through the soil profile
keep in mind that water does travel in a
unique way through soil
that depends on the composition of that
soil and also the potential layers of
different soil types that may exist
we're going to see this in a couple
examples now looking at the soil profile
in general
a lot of times soil scientists will
refer to horizons
the o horizon means the organic or very
very top layer here
the a which is the surface layer b
subsoil
see we're getting down into that deeper
areas typically where roots do not
travel
and are down here which is the bedrock
so this is why
understanding the type of soil that a
grower has is important
as it will influence how water it moves
through it
also do the different soil types this is
why what
may work for one grower may not say work
for another when it comes to irrigation
frequency
and also duration so keep that in mind a
lot of it has to do
which is how water travels which a lot
of growers really don't necessarily
understand
so first off we want to consider
capillary action
so what just is capillary action well
kind of it's shown here
in this kind of example that we're
saying capillary action basically is the
ability for a liquid
to flow in narrow spaces without the
assistance of
or even in opposition to external forces
such as gravity
it occurs because of the intermolecular
forces between the liquid
and surrounding solid surfaces so what
we're looking at here
is we see kind of a see a glove we see
kind of a clear looks like a
piece of glass and we see this kind of
blue liquid here well what's happening
is down at the bottom there is a blue
liquid and there's actually two pieces
of glass and what the person is doing
here is they're pinching those two
pieces of glass together
as they make those two pieces of glass
tighter they're going through and
pushing those closer
they're reducing the space and that
creating a very small space you see
pushing here
causing that water to flow against
gravity pushing it in tighter making
that space
even smaller there allows that water to
travel even further
if the space is sufficiently small then
the combination of surface tension
caused by the cohesive properties of the
liquid in this case looking at water
and as adhesive forces between the
liquid and the container wall
act to propel the liquid that's exactly
see here that space gets smaller and
smaller crushing that together
increasing the height that that water
can travel because this smaller space
allows to water to
move further so that's what we're seeing
here in these images
now we also have the path of water in
soil so we're looking at just a
sandy loam alone and a clay loam and
basically we have large particles
medium-sized particles and smaller sized
particles at least in a relative
comparison
sandy looms will drain very quickly the
medium-sized loam is kind of that
medium-fast drainage and then clay alone
would be the slower drainage
and what we're looking at is those
cutaways are those profiles
now what we're seeing here is we see
little droppers and we're basically
simulating a rain event or maybe a drip
irrigation and this would go through in
drip
water at a very consistent rate well
what we're noticing is that the sandy
loam
over the standard set of time here fully
saturates by the end
the loam we see that slower and of
course the clay loom much more slower to
kind of
have that water percolate through what's
something we're also noticing in this
example as well as others
is that water does not travel in a
straight line water
actually slowly kind of cones outwards
from the original point where it hits
and comes in contact
with that surface this is why we're
looking at drip irrigation
we can have those drip irrigation lines
spaced further apart
and even though the very surface may
appear dry
what happens is the coning effect here
of the water
saturates the area or the root zone it's
a very important concept that a lot of
growers
forget about or don't fully understand
is that we're seeing this conan effect
of that water kind of cut it's here so
it's here it's right here and starts
coming out
and this is how we're able to saturate
these
root area the root zone with the
irrigation water and so we don't need
irrigation lines right next one
they can be spaced out and that distance
will depend on the exact soil type
because that's going to affect the
degree that that cone will go out
now here we're looking at an example
we're starting
up here so we're starting basically
right where i am
we have a deep sand layer and how does
that impact so in this case we have loam
we have a sand layer and we have loam
again so same soil type with a sand
barrier and then loam
what we're noticing is we're seeing that
same coning effect here saying that soil
starting to kind of go out
here it's just coming are initially in
contact with that sand layer
what we notice with that sand layer is
that it actually is a little bit of a
barrier
it prevents that water really from
percolating through as it normally would
we're seeing here spread out as well as
here again
and here we're seeing it definitely
continue to spread out but between the
two
images between me we're starting to see
a little bit of that saturation
penetrate that sand layer however once
it does penetrate that thin layers we
see the two images around me now
we are seeing the same coating effect
relocating below that area
but keep in mind that here that top
layer is fully saturated see that's
spreading out from that
a single point of entry spreading out
this full area
then it kind of breaks its way through
and that center point and then we're
seeing the coning effect
repeat itself again so it's very
important to understand now with soil
type you have this at the top
but if there's a a different layer there
if there's a barrier there if there's a
difference
type that occurs that can really impact
the way that this water percolates
through
the profile of the soil now lastly
in many fields they have to deal with
what's called a hard pan
this is considered the clay layers we
see here so we have low megan alone
again in this case instead of sand
now we have a clay layer it considers to
be like a hard pan this is commonly
found in tilled or plowed fields
where we have that equipment constantly
going over that certain depth and at
that bottom
where that scraping occurs we kind of
get a little bit of that hard layer
and we're seeing again that everything
starts out very similar in that lone as
we would expect it water's coming out
and then we have water kind of coming
out to the point that then comes in
contact with that clay or plow plant
layer
unlike with the sand layer while we do
see that the water is come in contact
and spreading outwards just so we stop
the sand
however even after a period of time we
really do not see the water penetrating
or percolating through that clay layer
so on a quick look of the profile of the
soil while this hard pan
or clay layer looks very similar to this
previous one we looked at with the sand
because the properties of sand are very
different the water is eventually able
to percolate through after a period of
time
however looking at a hard pan plow plan
layer or the
dense clay layer here as thin as it may
be
this example the water is unable to
penetrate that and that's going to
create a
pretty substantial dry pocket down here
so hopefully this allows you to better
understand
exactly how water percolates through
soil
regardless of the type and it's
important also to look at your soil
profile
to see if these any of these layers
though they may be thin exist
because that is going to impact how
water travels through
your soil profile this can be very
important for
spacing out drip irrigation lines
understanding this coning properties of
the water
is very important to ensure you're
delivering water to the root zone that
you want
without over irrigating or under
irrigating so you don't run the risk of
disease
or wasting water