in this debaco university student series
video we're going to be looking at how
power readings change what the light
type and the distance those plants are
away from those lights we're going to be
comparing an led light with a
fluorescent light in this video
[Music]
before i get into the video i just want
to show you the two different types of
lights are going to be
looked at in this video the led light is
a fluent spider x plus 660 watt and the
fluorescent light is an aggro bright
designer t5 324 watt fluorescent light
just to have some background hope you
enjoy the video
so right now we're taking a par reading
with all of our lights on to measure how
different the readings are at different
distances
so right now at the absolute top we're
at a good
650.
now at 6 inches down
we lower down to just 370.
at another six inches down we're
measuring 216.
go down another six inches
we're
just 120
and finally another six inches
we've made it down to 64. double digits
so that's why it's very important to
know how far away you're going to want
your plants to be from your light source
so now we're comparing our 600 watt led
lights to our fluorescent lights that we
were just showcasing as you can see
they're pretty much at the same height
level so this is just to compare how
drastically different the par rating is
at the same level just from a different
light
so right up at the top here we're
reading at two thousand
if we go six inches down
we lower down to a 780
12 inches down we're reading 630
18 inches down we're reading 558
and 24 inches down we're reading four
now i mean 390.
so you can see this is very different
and much more intense than the
fluorescent lights that we're currently
using on our clones
you