this debaco university video is going to
go over how to set up a mechanical timer
for your lights now it's important to
plug your lights into the wall initially
to test them but then you want to go
through once you know they're working as
we're going to see here in our student
series with kiara she's going to go over
how to properly set up a mechanical
timer so you can ensure your plants will
be exposed to the right photo period
enjoy
[Music]
so now that we know that the lights work
we don't want them just plugged into the
wall anymore because we need them to be
able to turn on and off by themselves so
that's why we invest in a timer for our
plants
this adjusts the light based on the time
that you set for it so if you wanted to
it could be for 12 hours 18 hours six
hours adjustable for whatever your grow
is
so the first step of setting up a timer
is to align it to the time that it is
right now so i'm going to set it
to
4 20 p.m
so right about there
next you're going to want to decide how
long you want your lights on for so
depending on
how many of these you push down is how
long the timer is going to be on for so
i want it to be on for 18 hours of
flight so for going from 420
right around 11 20
is where i wanted to end then we have
our one two three four five six hours of
night time
as you can see here
the switch can tell
where
it the time of day is based on the timer
so go around and see that it's night
time well night time for the plants
lights off
and then turn back on
and click once it gets back to the
turned on section of the light
and then again once it goes to the end
it clicks off
then to make sure that all of your
effort was accounted for you're going to
want to make sure that it's set for
timer and not just indefinite