in this debaco university video i'll go
over how to identify
male and female cannabis flowers both in
pictures
as well as take you out in the field to
do some identification
there as well
[Music]
here in this image we see a nice female
flower in this
video lecture we'll be going over how to
identify male and female cannabis
flowers
both in pictures as well as in the field
so first off those
important pre-flowers so when we're
looking at plants the first ones are
going to produce
are those little pre-flowers growers
should first look at the nodes or which
is the junctions between the leaves and
branches
and the stalks of the plant this is
where you're going to find those
pre-flowers to begin with
pre-flowers begin to develop four to six
weeks into the growing cycle
at the nodes and during this time
growers should be able to identify the
gender of the plant
as being male as we see here or females
we see down here
these immature flowers these are
immature flowers and will show the male
or female morphology
well before they're able to produce
viable components for seed production
so if you're identifying a male plant
here no problem no pollen is reproduced
or released
and a female plant here they're not
ready to kind of receive any sort of
pollen
removing the males at this time will
help ensure no chance of accidental
pollination will occur
male preflowers we simply want to be
looking for small
pollen sacs and for female pre-flowers
we want to be looking for two stigmas
which are typically
white in coloration these would be the
areas that would be receiving the pollen
these would be the areas would be
producing the pollen
now those female plants just focus on
those just a little bit more
specifically
right here well females are are the
plants that will produce the
cannabinoids and the greatest
concentrations within the flowers
if female plants receive pollen though
from male plants
seeds will be produced which will
drastically reduce the cannabinoid
production
cannabis is grown via cincimila which
stands for basically seedless
by removing male pollen producing plants
to prevent seed production
this allows the cannabis plant to focus
its energy on cannabinoid production
instead of seeds female plants will only
be
pollinated to produce seeds for breeding
purposes for the most part we want those
buds we can see right here female plant
to produce higher cannabinoids not seeds
so as we go over to male plants now for
comparison
male cannabis plants are grown for
pollen sacks instead of buds and are
often discarded
to avoid female plants from becoming
pollinated
male plants are important in the
breeding process pollinating
male plants shape rate of growth pest
and mold resistance
and climate resilience can be important
for breeding purposes
so knowing how the male plant performs
could offer some importance
for breeders because that will influence
the seeds or the following
generation male plants can also be used
for hemp and fiber in some cases
concentrate production but concentrate
is much less
than female plants and how we're going
to go about identifying those
well these are going to be our little
early pre-flowers
for male plants i've showed you some
great pictures
give you some great information now
let's take a second let's go in the
field
and compare both male and female flowers
here we see those brown pistols this is
an early indication
of a female pre-flower so it's important
to identify these early
male versus female plants and this one
will be a female and this will be kept
in the field
this is an attempt to show you the
stages of development here we have a
male
flower very early on in development
as we work our way down the stem here
you can see
further and further developed male
flowers
so again none of these have opened yet
so no threat to the field
but the earlier you can identify and the
earlier you can roll out these plants
the better as you can see the structures
of that male flower definitely here is
going to be where we're going to be
producing our pollen so this is what
defines it here
as male flowers see that these are the
most developed
we have some that not are quite that are
not quite as developed as
this moment in time located right here
uh this is definitely the time you want
to be able to clearly identify
them as male and he should be removed
from the field if you're looking
at producing higher cannabinoid and
terpene production
rather than seeds
so here you can see a very early male
pre-flower
it's located right here so i know it's a
little difficult to kind of
see there but the earlier you can
identify male
pre-flowers the earlier you can robe out
these male plants in the field
reducing any chance of pollination in
producing
seeds to get the maximum yield from your
buds
now if i work our way down a plant you
can clearly see
how those male flowers can really start
to stack up there
and this plant if not removed would have
produced a lot
of pollen that pond would not be wanted
in
this field you can see just the plethora
of male flowers and how they cluster and
develop
great look here at male pretty flowers
great look at
male pre-flowers here very early on
you can see as you work your way down
they do get a little bit more advanced
but trying to identify male plants is
important
to rogue those outside any cross
pollination
if you look down the plant in general
you just get an idea of this male plant
how much
flowers they can produce and how much
pollen it is possible for them
to release one plant left in the field
can really cause an issue
to all of your crops yeah to your entire
field here
that one male plant could easily
pollinate these thousands and thousands
of plants
or at least reduce the yield
of flower