and this debaco University video we're
going to go over how does hoplate and
thyroid spread which is important for
any grower to understand we're looking
at prevention uh in a way to combat a
potential issue in your growing
operation
[Music]
so there's a lot of concern over hoplate
and virate well here we're going to
learn about how does it go about
spreading
first off a great presentation I'm here
took some screenshots from this by Dr
zamir apunja welcome to check out his
presentation here at can mid 23 as well
as others information provided in the
description link
so how does high blood and thyroids
spread well mechanical damage such as
trimming the sap contact is actually
what is causing that viroid to be
transmitted so that results in the
grower being the most common Vector
insect vectors are possible but at this
time they're not really well understood
so if you grow our trimming from one
plant move to another plant you've kind
of just inoculated or infected the next
Plant sadly also in addition to trimming
the above portions of the plant root
contact and this could be root contact
physically with the roots or water
curing that from the roots of one plant
to another this is where the thyroid
load is actually very high and early on
as I'll talk about in a moment seeds are
not the potential way or method of
transmission this hop latent thyroid
so potential roots of transmission as I
said about the water I can go through
the water so flood and drain systems
dwc's deep water cultures clone trays
flood and drain really any operation
that recirculates water this is of
concern it can also reside in the
irrigation tubes the growing substrate
as well as the root all areas potential
of transmission this is why or how it
can spread so quickly through an area
it's also a very stable viral Aid and it
can survive in water for up to seven
days about a week and that can help
speed its infection of many plants in a
growing operation
now this phloem Trends transmitted so
not to get too much into the biology
aspect but entry into the flowment is
what allow us to move up as well as down
the plants in contrast xylem is mainly
roots to shoots or bottom to top phloem
can go basically any direction uh floam
Falls the sugars and it does translocate
through the entire plant or at least
environment via this root in about six
weeks time so very quickly
an experiment provided here some of the
data they made a stem cut they did an
artificial transmission of hot plate and
thyroid to exposed stem Cuts as we can
see right here the Violet was inoculated
at the wound site in two weeks post
inoculation it could be detected already
in the roots of the plant as well as the
upper stem portions of the plant four to
six weeks post infection the entire
plant becomes infected so it's kind of
has a little bit of this unique jumping
right it doesn't just start in one point
and just radiate out it actually goes to
specific portions of the plant they've
outlined that here where it was found in
we're seeing points of inoculation found
the roots in two weeks in Youngs in four
weeks and then the rest of the plant in
six weeks so what was interesting about
this path of infection is it is you know
stem top inoculated The Roots were
actually the first point where it
reached detectable levels
than other top growing tips and then the
lower leaves or branches became positive
properly and virate in that order and
that two to six week time frame so it's
important we're looking at potentially
taking samples Roots may be a good area
to sample
uh this kind of shows another visual the
virus travels down first to the roots
indicating that it is phloem transmitted
and then spread to the apical meristem
followed by the full plant infection so
there's a point of infection two weeks
later right down to the roots
accumulates down there then after
accumulates down there then it goes back
and kind of shows up at the very top of
the plant and then six weeks later then
it's well distributed amongst the entire
plant so keep that in mind
the flowering can also increase the
thyroid load the stress of flowering can
increase the amount of area that's
present in the plant this shows the
importance of testing a plant multiple
times as early veg it could be below
detectable levels you could have that
virus it could be very low that really
stress not really proliferating
testing and veg is still important as if
a positive is found in veg that plant
should be removed immediately and but
just because it tested negative in early
veg following up with another test
during flowering would be advised to
ensure that that small potential small
viral load then when it becomes much
larger the easier to finally identify
would be worth a second test there
now as I said water transmitted which is
again a little bit scary this is in part
how it can travel so fast for a growing
operation plants are not even have to
come into direct contact with one
another can spread infections via water
transfer contact any recycling water is
uh is at risk with two common methods
occur where the cloner tray transferred
only on water we could see here where
there's a physical separation between
these plants but there's a water
connection and that allows that healthy
plant to become infected from that
unhealthy plant and flood and drain
growing as well you can also see in the
cloner where the virus detected two
weeks of exposure of healthy roots in a
solution containing infected Roots there
was no physical root contact but clearly
we could see that it is able to
basically go through that water and take
down healthy plants also on a tray where
they're physically separated water going
between the two not far it goes from one
to the other
also infected mother plants so since the
thyroid is systemic to the plant cloning
the plant will produce many infected
Offspring so it's not advised you take
cuttings or clippings from an infected
mother plant this is also why testing
and re-testing mother plants is so
important all cuttings picture tested
positive for highly environment
infection so if you get a mother it's
positive you want to remove that mother
and do not take any clones from that
you'll just be spreading the infection
even faster
now seed transmission gets a little
confusing on here I mean showed that
when female plants are infected this can
increase the odds or the percentages of
the seeds that are infected most of the
hot plate and thyroid found is on the
outside of the seed coat 10 to 15
infection can still be found on the
inside of the seeds
if the seedling typical catalyden has
any physical damage the hoplit
environment can easily enter the plant
from the seed coat should be a prime
example here that seedling is kind of
coming out and unfurling that seed coat
might still be attached you get a little
physical abrasion well that operate is
right in the on the seed coat you can
easily now get into this very young
plant
it's also present in dry flowers and
it's not just the super young plants it
can also be the fully mature and
harvested dry flour 40 sampled from
dispensaries do show positive for hot
plate and thyroid now this was study was
done in California I believe which shows
how widespread it actually is it's also
found in male flowers so it's another
reason for concern that just because
only only using it for breeding purposes
you don't want to have any male flowers
or male plants that have the hotline
environment as well
glove transmitted so it survives on sap
on gloves up to five days at room
temperature showing how very stable it
is so when you're discarding your gloves
after trimming discard them in a trash
can and leave them there and get that
out and removed from any part of the
groin area it's that stable can survive
for five days even at warm temperatures
would be considered room temperature
leave transfer can survive for four
weeks so be sure to clean remove leaves
that are being trimmed this is why it's
important for your gloves to be disposed
of and physically removed as well as
leaves survival and dried leaves tested
one two three and four weeks later Forex
is still getting positive there so it
just shows you the stability of hoplate
and fibroid and how easily it can
transfer from material that Growers
might be not worried about or not
thinking about it can really do any harm
to their operation
that root tissue ever important root
tissue it's very stable thyroid heating
it to 70 degrees Celsius which is about
158 degrees Fahrenheit for 30 minutes
did not destroy the RNA that RNA is kind
of looped over itself very very stable
has a very longevity in The Roots
um you know it just speaks to the you
know reason why it's probably becomes so
prevalent in the growing world right now
because it's so stable that it's able to
transfer very easily and once it gets
kind of established it's very hard to
get rid of
now those male flowers that I mentioned
at this time there's no real evidence
that hopefully very can be present in
the pollen but it can be present in the
male flower structure it can be found in
the male flowers as well as in the
anthers but unconfirmed in pollen and no
evidence of transmission yet that
statement doesn't happen but this at
least not right now apparently obvious
that it does but again another reason
for concerns even in breeding if you're
like I'm not going to wear that plant to
you know for to produce flowers for
dried flour I'm only breeding with it
still reason for concern still a reason
to remove that plant from your operation
hopefully if you do see overall of
thyroid load