okay so you've selected a carbon filter
to reduce
your odor in your cannabis production
you go to buy a carbon filter and you
realize there's a lot of different sizes
well here at tobacco university i'm
going to go over how to size a carbon
filter for odor control
in cannabis production
[Music]
all right let's ensure that you buy the
right carbon filter the first time
so let's go over some things you need to
take into consideration for
sizing it properly so first off the root
measurements and calculations
so calculate your room volume not just
your growing area so what does that mean
you want to take into account the full
size of the room and not only where the
plants are
you don't want to simply be looking at
the you know length and width of the
room
you also want to take into account the
height to get the full
volume of the area so an example
if you had a room that was 20 feet long
a 10 foot wide and then 8 foot ceilings
you would have 1
600 cubic feet of volume that's what you
want to take into consideration
now cfm is cubic feet per minute so a
lot of times you'll see
on filters they'll list things in cubic
feet per minute
at the very least you should exchange
your air about every three minutes
however typically you should aim for
really exchanging air in your grow rooms
volume at least once a minute you want
to continuing with this example that we
did in the previous slide
if you if you had that 1 600 cubic foot
room
the minimum would be every 3 minutes
which means you would need a filter that
would
have a rating of at least 533.3
cfm however you really want to be
targeting something at 1
600 cfm so like why don't you go larger
it will simply that it does become
more of an expense so this is why people
try to sometimes
reduce the size of the carbon filter but
this can restrict airflow
and this could cause other issues with
ventilation so again shooting for that
once every minute to three minutes it
should be your target
favoring closer to that minute if
possible
and however while we did those nice math
and it seemed nice and easy and
hopefully you're continuing to watch
this video
there's other factors to take into
consideration it's not as simple as
doing a quick math equation
you also want to take into consideration
your lighting if you're using high
intensity discharge lighting
will require more ventilation and also
provide grow room cooling
also the filter types how restrictive is
the actual filter you're using
you know some of the more expensive ones
have that finer carbon
particulate and they're going to flow a
little bit better also what is the
ambient temperature warmer temperatures
will typically increase the airflow
required to aid in cooling
so you should be closer definitely to
that one exchange
of the grow room's volume per minute
and we also need to consider the cfm
loss meaning everything is not perfect
uh how much cfm is lost through a 25
foot section of ducting
well approximately three percent if it's
a straight hard
cast uh to seven percent if it's
flexible ducting
and also one to four percent additional
loss for every 90 degree bend
this is why ideally if you had that
straight hard kind of casting
that is the most efficient way to move
air through a
ducting if you have this flexible duct
tape which makes it great for
installation
you do lose about one to four percent
and you want to minimize as we can see
not shown here minimize the amount of 90
degree bends you want to have everything
to be as straight as possible
so you have as efficient movement of air
as possible
to allow you to use the quote the
smallest filter so you can try to reduce
the
cost as much as possible and also
maximize the efficiency
of your ventilation system