in this tobacco university we're going
to answer the question
how do you create feminized cannabis
seeds and walk you through some of the
scientific
literature supporting this uh protocol
and also provide you with some of the
details on how to create the proper
ratio of silver style sulfate if you
want to do this
on your own here on debaco university
all right so let's get into the video of
how to create feminized cannabis seeds
well here's that reference article if
you want to look at more some more of
the details and i'm going to provide
just a brief kind of summary grower
oriented if you want to know
look at the original study this is all
the proper citations
associated with where the information
was originated from
so first off basics of creating
feminized seeds well
in order to produce all female seed
what's required is the induction of
female plants
to develop male flowers that produce
pollen that will be genetically female
why is this well female 6 chromosomes
are an x and an x
a male sex chromosomes are an x and a y
therefore
when a female plant which is xx is
induced to form pollen since there are
no
y chromosome all the resulting pollen
will be the xx or
female genetic type when pollinated with
a known female plant which will also be
xx this will result in the offspring
also being female and this is
the basics for creating feminized seed
now how do you induce male flowers on a
female plant because that seems like an
obvious question here
well three millimolar silver thiosulfate
abbreviated sds
was applied as a foliar spray on three
occasions seven days apart to produce
male flowers the three millimolar sds
treatment was shown
on four strains of female hemp having a
thc content that of
equal to or less than 0.3 percent
and those different strains were
designated cbd
hemp a cbd hemp b cbd hemp c
and industrial hemp so what are
some of the specifics of the study well
their materials and methods they used
rooted cuttings that were about six
inches high
with two shoots when foliar sprays of
the sdas were initiated
silver thiosulfate solutions at 0.3 and
millimolar were prepared by mixing
silver nitrate
with sds in a molar ratio of one to four
and this is per previous study now if
yours is kind of getting a little
scientific
for you if you wait till the end of the
slideshow
i'll show you the exact process of
preparation steps to make that three
millimolar solar silver thiosulfate
solution
and i'll walk down the steps on how to
do that the reason why i walk you
through the three
millimolar is that's what was shown to
be most effective in this study
so plants were sprayed till runoff which
was about 20 milliliters per plant
on three occasions seven days apart
being on april
30th the year 2018 for the first
replication and on
the 14th of may 2018 for the second
replication of this study
control plants receive sprays of water
only to act as that kind of nice control
in this scientific experiment
on the 30th of april and the 14th of may
plants began receiving short day
conditions of about eight hours
using blackout curtain to initiate the
flowering stage
so what were the general study results
here when we're kind of doing this
comparison
of the study results between 14
and 21 days after the first sts
spray treatment plants transitioned from
first flowers
to full flowering phase the most
complete inflorescence a conversion to
male flowers occurred
at the 3 millimolar sds for all hemp
strains
at 3 millimolar sds the majority of
inflorescence had 100 male flowers
and the remaining influence inferences
had 75 percent male flowers
untreated control plants or all four
hemp strains produce only female flowers
as expected
so just this again shows you the actual
numbers here shows the actual
percent of male inflorescence shows you
the different treatments again if they
were not treated we could see that there
are
no induction of male flowers which would
be expected
you can see the greatest percentage here
at that 3 millimolar sds
treatment so however it's important to
note that during this study
that male flowers that developed on
genetically female plants did produce
pollen so that's a good thing
however the pollen did not appear to be
as plentiful or freely released as
observed on
truly genetic male plants that's an
important distinction to make there
the pollen did produce seed which was
harvested germinated and exposed to
short day conditions
and resulting plants were confirmed to
be female so that's a great kind of
conclusion of the study just be aware
if you're used to growing traditional
male plants while there is pollen
produced
it's going to be slightly different but
still can produce viable offspring
so it's a possible explanation for this
you know sds why is this kind of you
know
why is this showing to be effective well
ethylene blocking by sts which
absolutely is another plant hormone is
likely responsible for the production of
male flowers on female hemp plants
in our study this is the one that i'm
referring to that i cited at the
beginning
it's genetically believed that ethylene
blocking is extended when a series of
sprays of sds is used
compared to a single spray of sds that's
based on a previous study found in this
article
it may be possible to induce male
flowers on genetically
female hemp using other ethylene
perceived inhibition chemicals
but this shows here that sds can have
an effect and could be very notable
effect as well
so this what's the general conclusion of
this study
well this study demonstrated that male
flowers can be produced easily
consistently and female plants through
application of foliar sprays of sds
under short day conditions
overall sds at 3 millimolar was the most
effective treatment for producing the
greatest number of male flowers on
female hemp
plants we did not observe any plants
phytotoxicity or delay in flower
development which is again
another great plus furthermore we're
able to achieve 95 to 100
conversion male flowers for all of the
hemp strains produced here
this just shows you some pictures from
the study provided now you're probably
wondering at this point well how could i
create a three
millimolar concentration of sts well
here i provided you with the
how to exactly go about preparing that
particular
solution rate in solution now i give all
the information here so
it's important to probably pause the
video here print this out take a
screenshot or
utilize the information provided here i
do want to make note of
a kind of a key point is that as you're
going through and reading this
now always add the this is the silver
nitrate solution to the sodium
thiosulfate solution
the opposite will create a black
precipitate so when we're mixing things
getting into the chemistry it's very
important the order
that you mix things and what you mix
into what so just keep that in mind
also to use a 3 millimolar
solution here for spraying cucumber
plants this is what the
example was given for this survey that i
found
or the resulting study you want to
dilute to three million
solution by mixing the six millimolar
solution
with double distilled water and a one to
one ratio and store it in the dark
so this does make a slightly more
concentrated solution but then you're
going to dilute that down
to the three milli molar so again it's
important to go through make sure you
have precise ways to measure things
make sure everything is cleaned ahead of
time you don't want any chance of any
cross
contamination here spray plants in the
third to fifth leaf stage for terminal
flowers
use two light squares from the spray
bottle mix two applications one week
apart
this was used in a cucumber plant study
but as we just saw here
this same process and procedure directly
applies to the
creation of feminized seeds on cannabis
plants so i wish you the best of luck
and hope that this is successful or at
least that this provided you some
information
on how to create feminized seeds on
cannabis plants