as the title implies on this tobacco
university video we're going to learn
how to identify and control army worms
in cannabis plants as well
as at the end seeing one actively
feeding on a cannabis plant
[Music]
all right let's get into how to identify
and control army worms on cannabis
plants
so first off the general description of
the army worm
when we're looking at the army worm
there's yellow striped army worms as we
can see in the above pictures
there's also the one of the largest this
is one of the largest
in most brightly marked of various
caterpillars that might be found on hemp
there is then also down here the beet
army worm
this is a caterpillar that feeds on
leaves and developing flowers
fruits seeds of a great many plants
we're going to see the one pictured
later of the yellow striped armyworm
variety here very distinctive coloration
and very aggressive feeder
this is the adult stage should be on the
lookout for that as well
as part of the general life cycle
looking at armyworms
so we look at the identification of them
it
is a generalist feeder that feeds on the
leaves of a wide variety of plants
it's not specific just to cannabis this
shows the adult beet armyworm
kind of moth and this shows the bee
armor and feeding on a hemp
flower so again very different
coloration than the yellow striped one
now managing armyworms just in general
here's that yellow striped one cultural
controls corn can be planted as a trap
crop
that will attract them to that you can
spray and control them on the corn
and hopefully they'll avoid feeding on
cannabis plants
tillage uh since overwintering occurs in
local soils
soils as a pupate tilling will help
destroy them and reduce their population
pressure for the following year
then there's also biological controls
which is the use of egg parasitoids
there's biofungus that can specticular
strains that can really attack them
and then as a last resort typically
there's insect and insecticides
biafran um as the active ingredient
now if you want to know just how quick
these can feed on a cannabis plant
i captured some video of them actually
feeding on a leaf and you can welcome to
view that
now all right in this video we see an
army worm eating a cannabis plant now
the audio
is not necessarily true to the actual
what's going on but we can see in real
time
just how aggressive one of these
caterpillars can basically be
these worms are how quick they can eat
and devour a plant
you can see here really close to the bud
so that's of course of concern
and usually where there's one well none
pictured in the image here
i'm sure there's a few more and this
implements more scouting as well as
control