so here we're kind of questions you may
not have thought of that is how is light
produced sure you've all seen a rainbow
do you know why the colors are organized
the way they are or do you know even
what generates the colors
hopefully this lecture will help explain
a little bit of that just starting first
with just what is light light does that
require a medium like sound to travel
one so sound requires air to be able to
travel through and the air pressure
differences are perceived by your
eardrum the speed of light represented
by the letters C famous in the equals
mc-squared
equation is about could say roughly 300
million meters per second in a vacuum or
that's about 670 point six million miles
per hour
and of light we can only see what's
called the visible spectrum at a look at
that little bit to put this into
perspective the speed of light from the
earth to moon is represented here the
scale models the earth in the moon was a
beam of light traveling between it at
the speed of light takes cracklin 1.6
seconds for that beam of light to lead
for earth go to the moon we all know a
great distance that is so wavelength we
look at light here consider wavelength
so wavelengths defined as the distance
between two crests or two troughs so you
see here's a Craster's a crasus should
be considered the wavelength here's a
trough here's a trough here shown here
is a wavelength it's measured in
nanometers and and in different
wavelengths equal different colors and
to put this into perspective when we're
talking about nanometers the human hair
or a single human hair it's about a
hundred thousand nanometers we're
looking here on nanometers in the 400
and 700 range just to eat an idea and we
look at the white light passing through
this prism we can see the different
wavelengths we see the red wavelengths
on top here had a much longer wavelength
and then see down we get to the the
violets and the blues having a shorter
wavelength now I say that can one see
the visible spectrum so what is that
spectrum that's visible spectrum is this
a very small portion of this entire
electromagnetic spectrum
sixteen long radio waves microwaves
infrared rays and then we're getting
smaller and smaller and wavelengths
could see your x-rays gamma rays very
damaging very penetrating our visible
light is only this very very small
portion here it's expanded in this
region here C's 700 nanometers to about
400 nanometers is this spectrum or the
portion that we can see even though
radio H are going through we can't see
those microwaves infrared UV light we
can't see that can only see this very
small portion what we call the visible
spectrum to play this into perspective
moving energy levels who are looking at
the atom again in our energy levels in
order for an electron to move the energy
levels it either needs to gain or give
off energy or we can't create or destroy
energy that's the only food transferred
the ground state is the lowest energy
level is located closest to the nucleus
so now example here this would be the
ground state here since our ground state
and these energy levels would represent
different levels excited States and
increasing energy as we get further away
from the nucleus so absorbing energy
electrons can gain energy from heat
electricity or even other light sources
when electron gains energy it jumps up
in energy levels we see that here here's
an electron gaining energy jumping up an
energy level an electron that is gained
energy will enter what we call the
excited state then jumped up a level
what kind of electrons can't exist in
between they can I exist at different
energy levels so here we're gaining
energy jumping up an energy level we
really don't visually see anything
happen when this occurs but that
electron now is what we call the excited
state moving on when the electron
releases energy their energy released as
it jumps down a level as a photon and it
falls down closer to the ground state
the further the electron is from the
nucleus the more energy it has we'll see
that example here where the same
electrons now losing energy it's losing
the same amount of energy but here it's
giving off as a boat
of light which we can see so it's kind
of put that in the kind of a motion here
we see an electron here giving off
energy that we can see jumping down in
energy level well Shannon gains energy
it jumps up you can see it's moving a
little bit quicker the same thing here
it's gaining energy that's called the
excited state and what looses that
energy given off photon of light here
down here it's drop into the ground
state
so that photon of light each photon
matches a distinctive energy level jump
with a specific wavelength emitted so
here's our before out of an excited
state during we're dropping down at
energy level giving off that photon of
light in depending on what energy level
or what I'm gonna do the levels it may
jump will depend on the wavelength of
light given off so it puts that into an
example here we have an electron to
third energy level when I dropped out of
that second energy level it drops down
to that one level there it emits a red
wavelength which is 656 nanometers now
let's take an electron at the fourth
energy level and drop it down to the
second energy level here and we see that
will give off 486 nanometers this kind
of greenish color and for a 5th energy
level we drop that down you see 434
nanometers that purple spectrum now
let's make an assumption here for at the
six energy level and drop down we're
gonna be in this range here so we see
there's these different changes in
wavelength and sure enough the part the
six energy level we dropped down felt
more this purple at 410 millimeters so
you see the different colors are
produced and depending on how the
electrons are jumping around these all
these different colors will blend
together to a single color that will
perceive hopefully this gives you a
little bit of a better idea of how light
is produced