here on this tobacco university video
we're going to be looking at
vapor pressure deficit and how it
relates to cannabis plants
[Music]
all right let's get into how vapor
pressure deficit impacts cannabis plants
well first off it's typically
abbreviated vpd and it will be
throughout this presentation
and this is an advanced method for
understanding and measuring the indoor
or technically outdoor growing
environment
for outdoor it's more used for
monitoring and for indoors it can
calculate you can calculate the vpd and
then make changes
to your growing conditions this does
require more equipment to gather
information and understanding of the
overall growing environment
which is why this is considered to be a
more advanced technique
we also have the vapor pressure of the
air to take into consideration the leaf
vapor pressure and together
these in combination or information
being used to get the vpd the vapor
pressure to deficit between those two
now the equipment that you need you need
a thermometer
because you need to have an idea what
the air temperature is you also need a
hydrometer which is basically measuring
the humidity in the area and an
infrared ir thermometer that because
that is going to be used
to provide the temperature of the leaf
with the data generated you can
calculate the vpd
of the growing space so keep in mind
that the vpd does take into account the
entire
environment this allows a consistent
measure that takes into account three
main variables
within any given growth space so when
we're looking at
the influences on vpd one is
transpiration
as epd increases the plant is going to
transpire at a greater rate it's going
to move water
through its material at a greater rate
the stomata opening as vpd increases the
stomata get smaller or basically start
to close
up for carbon dioxide uptake as vpd
increases the stomata gets smaller
and that's going to reduce or restrict
carbon dioxide uptake because those
stomata are porous the underside of the
leaves
allowing for gas exchange and when
they're smaller or get closed up
we cannot have as much carbon dioxide
being taken into the plant
and then nutrient intake at the root
level increasing vpd and transpiration
rates will mean the roots will pull
more nutrients which can be important
implant stress increasing vpd will
increase the plant stress as well
now this is a great kind of summary
chart here
it's cited in the description so if you
want to go through and find the original
source you're more than welcome to
but you're also encouraged to kind of
take a screenshot of this pause the
video here
and do a little comparison look at the
temperature of the area
and here we have degrees fahrenheit and
here's the relative humidity
of the growing space you can kind of see
where those match up of course your goal
is to be in this nice
dark region dark green region right here
now the vapor pressure looking at
conversion factors because
different meters read in different units
it's important to know or be able to
compare two different sources
so the most common unit of measure is
kilo pascals or kpa
however inches of mercury or ion of hg
is also used
here are the convol following conversion
factors we can see if you have kpa
and to get kpa from inches of mercury
you
multiply whatever reading you get in
inches of mercury by 3.386
and if you have kpa you want to get to
inches of mercury you take your kpa
reading and multiply it by 0.296 to get
your interest of mercury
if you're looking at hectopascals we see
the conversion down here at the bottom
now some suggested target levels of this
vpd by growth phase typically as the
plants get older
we want to increase the vpd propagation
or early veg and again just general
targets to shoot for
0.2 to 0.8 kpas for late veg and early
flower
looking at 0.8 to 1.4 kpa for mid flower
to late flower 1.2 to 1.5 kpa
and again here's some other suggestions
and these are a great way
to have that target level set at least
initially as you're looking at different
phases of your cannabis plants
how does the environment impact the vpd
now as you increase the temperature so
does the vpd
and inversely as you decrease the
temperature so does the vpd
those are directly correlated however
humidity
as you increase humidity you will
decrease vpds those are inversely
relation
inverse relationship simply as you
decrease humidity you will also increase
vpd and that inverse relationship there
as you increase the light intensity
you're increasing the light temps which
will also
sorry increase the light intensity this
will increase the temperature
of the leaf is that light is impacting
the leaf there
with that increase in leaf temperature
that will also increase your vpd
decreasing the light intensity decreases
leaf temps and
then decreases vpd so just to give you
an idea
how these three environments will impact
this now relative humidity at given
temperatures
so suggested values are required to
maintain ideal growing conditions
this is when the lights are on so this
again gives you kind of a fahrenheit and
celsius temperature
and kind of that humidity there and
looking at that target ranges there
for those vpds as expressed earlier
again
sources in the description there if you
want to look at this but again gives you
a good kind of general
target range to be aiming for now
transpiration that was talked about this
is movement of water
in the plants water first enters the
roots of the plant and will travel
through the plant and exit out small
regulated pores
called this stomata this general
movement of water is called
transpiration and
allows for nutrients to move through the
plant and also is a method of cooling
the plant
most of the plant's water that's uptake
is used for cooling
the humidity is considered to be around
100 inside the leaf
and this represents saturated vapor
pressure so here we see you know
roots in the ground water being absorbed
mainly by the xylem
moving its way up through the plant and
coming out the leaves
there now transpiration the details of
transpiration may be more details than
you care to know
uh here we're looking at the kind of
properties of water
the hydrogen bonding of water the
adhesive and cohesive properties of
water
allowing them to kind of like work their
way up the
stem here so this is kind of the within
the xylem vesicle and there's xylem
there's also phloem
phloem is more of the minerals and
nutrients and phloem can move up and
down the plant
xylem is basically going from what's
called the roots up to the shoots
and you see we see here that getting in
the intermolecular forces the partial
positive partial negatives
kind of linking of these water molecules
together helping this move its way up
through the plant
so a little kind of plant biology there
for you
then those transpiration rates will
transpiration rates will be faster in
hot and dry conditions
rates will slow in high humidity because
water
has no place to evaporate to so when
it's hot and it's kind of your sticky
that's because you're evaporating
we're trying to evaporate to cool
yourself there's so much moisture in the
air
you kind of have that sticky feeling at
high humidity conditions
the stomata needs to be regulated
because when they're open they can let
co2 in for the photosynthetic process
which is great
but at the same time the plant is also
losing water so as to make sure it's
adequately hydrated
plants need to balance out the ability
to photosynthesize and also remain
hydrated
general conditions here we can see the
rate of transpiration increases with
temperature to a certain point and then
we'll plateau
so even though the temperature is
increasing that kind of rate
transpiration is kind of flat line there
wind velocity for those that have a fan
on their plants or growing in the
outdoor environment
typically as the wind velocity increases
so will the transpiration rate
now the humidity as our humidity
increases
our rate of transpiration will decrease
simply because the water within the leaf
has nowhere to evaporate to and if the
water's in order to evaporate too
it's no point for the plant can take in
more water move it up through the xylem
move it up through the stem
therefore the increased humidity not
allowing water to escape out the stomata
will decrease
those transpiration rates so hopefully
this helps you better understand the vpd
and allows you to maximize the growing
conditions of your cannabis plants