here on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over how to use a
pressurized mixing tank or easy flow
for cannabis plant production
ever wonder how to use a pressurized
mixing tank or easy flow for canvas
plant production
this is the video for you so this is
what one typical setup looks like
we're going to go into some of the
details here in this video so first off
we have to understand the system
parts typically this system easily
attaches to a faucet hose
which is why it became so popular it's
very easy to hook up
with essentially part that allows for
some water to divert into the tank
you see here uh that contains the
fertilizer can slowly be
fed into the mainline hose or irrigation
system
so basically it's pumping water in
pressurizing the tank forcing a little
bit out that has fertilizer and
irrigation water
and putting it into the irrigation hose
so a very simple
concept how does it operate well the
basic method
is that the mixing tank injector
operates at the discharge line
on a pressurized differential concept so
we do have some pressure
difference pressure coming in pressure
coming out and kind of the device
in the middle there so the water is
diverted from the main flow
mixed with the fertilizer and then
injected or drawn back into the main
system so it kind of comes in gets
through
mixed around and then put back into the
system a measured amount of fertilizer
required for one injection is placed
into the cylinder
flow back into the main line is often
controlled by a metering device
installed at the inlet side of the
injector
to operate again as described previously
there must be pressure difference in the
injector line and
inlet and outlet so there is that
pressure uh differential that is needed
and the valve there now there are some
fittings that should take care of this
but keep in mind in low pressure systems
this may not be the best option for you
so there's a visualization of the
process which is why some growers like
it
the connection here of the injector
the concentration i should say of the
injector fertilizer
does change as the chemical becomes
diluted as water enters the tank
so think of it this way showing over a
long period of time this is a very large
tank
we have kind of a solid amount of
fertilizer over time
we're using up more and more and more of
that fertilizer
we're getting more and more diluted to
the point we essentially just have pure
water
uh irrigation water left in the tank at
this point we'd go through and we change
that and then we'd go through and we'd
refill it
and repeat the same process again
so the key points to remember are that
only install
uh in an on off pressure applications
where the system's
only under pressure when in use you do
not want to have this
tank under constant pressure you want to
have a valve before it so when the valve
turns off the pressure is alleviated
from the tank
also this will prevent the chance of
fertilizer back feeding as well if you
have that kind of
additional device in line do not use if
there's over 50 psi or pounds per square
inch as this can damage the system or
some of the components of the system
do not let this tank freeze because
water expands when it freezes
it can damage the tank or the upper
portion the internal workings
as well now the feed rate you'll notice
some of these do have a listed feed rate
so there are different flow rates which
can change the ratio of irrigation water
fertilizer
while this is a range since it is not
exact it does provide grower in
approximation
of the dilution rates for different
fertilizers
and see we have a slow and then we have
a number one setting here and it tells
you the capacity this is a
0.75 or three-quarter gallon tank in
gallons to empty
at the slow setting it'll take about 750
gallons to empty the tank
and in a faster setting it'll only take
375 so growers can make this adjustment
for the speed or rate that they want to
add their fertilizer
now the general fertilizer application
rate example here
just to provide you with some numbers so
you can see how well
you can apply it to your own situation
there will be some adjustments made but
this can provide just a good
starting point growers will often add
food dye to the fertilizer to be able to
see
the dilution and consumption visually
and allow them to further and quickly
dial in
their rates here if we're applying 3.5
pounds of triple twenty two thousand
square feet per week
once you have fruit set apply five
pounds per one
thousand feet of 16 326
with calcium so if you're growing
tomatoes peppers you should
spray them weekly with calcium chelates
at a rate of one
at a rate of two ounces per thousand
square feet this is what the
manufacturers recommend there
so you could also search them up when
you purchase one
look at the important documentation
because the one that you purchase
well it might have slightly different
recommendations as we just see here some
are for very small
some for very large operations we also
have different tank
sizes so keep that in mind however they
all work on the same
really basic concept where you have your
faucet you add that little fitting there
you attach your hose to the end of the
fitting
this little um
apparatus attaches to the tank and that
tank then can go through
and inject the fertilizer here keeping
in mind it's not under constant pressure
don't let it freeze
and this can be an effective way to very
easily add fertilizer to your irrigation
water
and your plants will thank you