here on this debacco University video
we're going to go over hemp russet mites
identifying them and how you go about
controlling them if you do identify them
on your cannabis
[Music]
plants all right how let's go over how
to identify and control hemp russet
mites on cannabis plants so first off
that General description and they are
small just to give you an idea I guess
we go back here to the actual
measurements they are very very small
this is evidence of one right here we
can can see them right here um on the
leaf itself cannabis is the only
reported host for hemp russet mites and
attempts to establish it on related
plants in the Cannabis basically general
family canca uh such as Hops and
Hackberry have so far been unsuccessful
so it's kind of very specific to um hemp
cannabis while this may not uh be
studied very well there are indications
that is related to the Tomato russet
might so if you're looking for something
to compare to that might be a source of
at least Initial Ideas uh for methods of
control hoset mites can likely survive
year round in indoor production
environments and possible on outdoor
plants as well as those indoor plants
hemp mites can crawl only very short
distances and uh immature stages are
particularly immobile so keep that in
mind they're going to be a little more
localized in at those stages however
adults are capable of crawling fall in
and may move to the edge of leaves where
they can then be picked up or carried by
air currents enclosed areas fans can
quickly spread mites as well so just
because they themselves cannot fly uh
because they're so small it's very easy
for them to get picked up uh in wind or
fans and be dispersed that way indoor
small breezes can distribute the mites
uh through a field um so indoor we have
those fans outdoor small breezes easily
to spread them even though they
themselves may not be able to fly so how
do we go about a ifying hemp mites um on
on the actual plant well they can
develop on the upper Leaf surface as
shown in the image uh as you can see
here but the highest numbers are found
typically on the under side of the leaf
infestations can result in a dull Leaf
coloration reduced Leaf size and also
reduction in plant growth kind of see
that stunting going on right here Leaf
Edge curl can be an indication but this
same visual cue can also be result of
many other situations so just because
you have Le Cur doesn't mean you have
russet mites but it is something you
should be considering and at least
scouting for when you go about managing
those uh russet mites what should you go
about to do to manage them as Industrial
Hemp is relatively new legalized crop
many MDES utilize for specialty crops or
field crops have not yet been registered
so be sure to check your local and
current regulations studies on Citrus R
mites in Florida in Israel show that the
interruption of broadspectrum pesticide
applications for more than 3 years may
increase populations of pricious mites
an industrial hemp making judicious use
of pesticides may be an effective tool
to reduce hemp russet mites oil-based
MDES may have some Effectiveness since
they have been shown to be effective
against spider mites and we talk about
that leaf curl leaves May curl upward
near the pedal so down here we're seeing
relatively normal flat appearance to the
leaves but we are seeing near that P
pedal near that kind of central portion
we are seeing that tendency for them to
kind of upwards can also see the yellow
yellow kind of variegation here on the
edge yellows to the margins Um this can
also be an indication of potential
nutrient deficiency but also worthwhile
to check with that kind of high-end uh
loop to be able to go through magnifying
glass to check these also for rites even
though they don't have the traditional
kind of little leaf curl at the pedial
still we're checking that Underside for
those very small mites because if you're
dealing with an insect versus a nutrient
deficiency
that's going to change how you go about
managing your potential issue in your
cannabis plant uh in a much different
direction you want to make sure you're
putting time and effort into the most
effective method of correcting whatever
problem you have but it starts with an
accurate diagnosis