in this debaco university video we're
going to give you a brief
overview of how to identify and control
cercospora in cannabis plants
[Music]
so circo's not unique just to cannabis
but this is kind of what it looks like
in cannabis and on a microscopic view
this kind of looks like this long
straight little like thread almost or
worm looking like thing
so first off how do you go about
properly identifying in
cannabis plants well it starts as kind
of small
yellow flecks developing into lesions
which turn into light
tan or white with yellow halos
and in severe cases it develops
chlorosis leading to defoliation as we
see down here
the infection begins on older leaves and
moves through the canopy from there
general conditions of the fungi is that
the pathogen survives mainly in plant
debris
as desiccated resistant pseudomonas but
can also survive as canadia in debris or
seeds
since multiple regions where it can hide
when moisture is sufficient new canadia
are formed and spread via rain splash or
wind
to to new leaves or plants and that's
how it's spreading
optimum conditions are 77 to 95 degrees
fahrenheit with nighttime temperatures
above 61 degrees fahrenheit
and a relative humidity of 90 to 95
percent
infection is greatly reduced or
non-existent at temperatures less than
59 degrees fahrenheit
or during periods of leaf wetness that
are less than 11 hours
so if you're looking at kind of beating
back the disease and you have control
over conditions well not great for
growing the plant below 59 can really
reduce or really eliminate its chance of
spreading
so what about the life cycle as with any
disease good to understand the general
life cycle and we can see those kind of
finger like thread like uh protrusions
there
that are the leading to the canadian
which is the primary inoculum
they have our healthy plants we can have
our leaf spots we can have secondary
inoculum kind of infecting that way
we get infected plants that then lead to
infected debris
and the stroma is surviving an infected
plant to ruin soil where it resides
and then the stronghold producing can
spores can then go through and cause
that primary infection and repeat that
life cycle
here we see the same thing where we have
our disease develops as the leaves
appear as leathery dark kind of bronzy
colorations
we have the disease can cause a
defoliation those leaves fall the ground
and that's where this fungus will
survive
it's particularly looking in soybeans
but the same basic process occurs in
cannabis
wind or rain can spread spores to young
plants and then the fungal toxin
and sunlight interact causing the petrol
foliar symptoms as we see
here and a repeat of the cycle again
now how do we manage this and this is
showing it in some other plants as well
but identifying and developing resistant
varieties will be important going
forward
three-year rotation in outdoor fields
that have had a positive identification
of the fungus
avoid planting sugar beets near cannabis
because they definitely are more prone
to this
and that could potentially cause an
increase in the local pressure
so be mindful of what it is what it
looks like how to identify it
may not have be able to identify in the
microscopic level
but hopefully these descriptions as well
as macroscopic pictures provide you with
a little bit of understanding
and you can kind of hopefully not plant
sugar beets near the area
rotate if you can and try as a way of
methods of
management to mitigate the negative
impacts surcospera can have
on your cannabis plants