so in this debaco university video i'm
going to walk you through step by step
how i go about setting up a ventilation
system
for a cannabis grow tent
as you may have figured out this is a
little bit of a longer video but i'm
going to go over how to set up a
ventilation system for cannabis grow 10
in detail and the structure of this
video despite its
length is i'm going to show you the
setup starting with the intake and
following the path
air would take specifics of the design
will be covered to help
maximize airflow in the tent while also
minimizing the potential for plant odors
to escape the growing environment how to
adjust airflow with the use of speed
control valves will be shown
lastly specific products used in the
video will be highlighted
to allow for an easy replication of the
system
now the basics kind of equipment that i
will be using i've seen me twice there
i'll go over the intake i'm going to
show you a hepa filter an inline fan
with a speed control i'm going to show
you some ducting
for exhaust we have a pre-filter carbon
filter more ducting and inline fan
followed by exhaust end ducting to
another carbon filter
so enjoy the video i go through step by
step in detail
hopefully you make it to the end
so then after to take you through the
path of air we have the air first coming
in here with our shroom filter our hepa
filter
going through our first fan and going
through this six inch
tubing going right into the bottom of
the tent
you come around the bottom of the tent
as we come around the bottom of the tent
you can see here this is the air where
it's actively getting added
in this is adding air at the lower point
right above our reservoir for our flood
and drain table
then as the air kind of gets mixed
throughout we'll have some plants
growing here
fan for circulation the very top here
you can notice we have
our first carbon filter that's a six
inch by 24.
that air is going to come up through
here and work its way it pulled through
this other fan this other inline fan
there's our fan gonna come out the fan
here
here it is here's our continued air
ducting
six inches running down the side only
because i wanted to run it through
yet another carbon filter so we have
another carbon filter
right here and that is ultimately going
to take out any potential odors
before they get into the room here so
just a quick flow of a great example of
a high-end
ventilation system that also will remove
any cannabis odors
okay so what you're going to see here is
i'm going to go through this 4x2 grow
tent
the ventilation system because we know
it's important for plants to have air
circulation
but when we're in a grow tent we want to
be isolating that air
so this not only is going to add air to
the environment we're going to see a
carbon filter that's going to help
filter that air so there'll be no odors
leaving the grow tent here
so it's important that when we seal this
structure
we have a way to get air in and a way to
get air out
so let's start with the intake well here
we have a hyper fan
this is a stealth hyper fan picture
right here the actual
fan what's great about this fan is it's
called a hyper
stealth fan so it gets that name because
it runs very quietly
the fan itself is very small but what
ends up happening
is there is a lot of foam
that foam acts as a way to cancel out a
lot of
noise so this is a great fan we're
we're here in a lab room now that people
share so we want to make sure it's as
quiet as possible so we're going to have
fans in this area
with a lot of foam that's going to take
air in here and go through and
add it to the tent however we don't want
to leave this area on the top
open so to prevent anything from getting
into our fan into our
grow tent there's something here called
like a hepa filter
this one's called a shroom to be
specific what's really great about this
is it easily fits
right on top is a great way to kind of
filter out any particulate
so we're looking at our fan here it's
open up here it's going to be the intake
and it's going to send the air down this
way we don't want to just leave this
open to the air for multiple reasons one
we want anything to fall in there
but two we don't have anything to get
into the into the fan to damage it
or into the grow tint itself so they
make these little
nice little filters here these little
hepa filters this is particularly called
a dust
shroom this will go right on top of our
fan motor
here in a moment so this is a six inch
fan so i've got the
six inch dust room what's really easy is
the installation
literally is just looks like a little
little mushroom there
it will literally just go basically sit
right on top
so while that's really easy to to do is
a vital component of this
ventilation system so now i've got the
cord here going to plug the
stealth hyperfan in we're going to hear
it spool up immediately
so what's the excellent thing about
these hyper fans is they also have a way
to control them
so there's a way to regulate exactly how
much air
flow is here is going through this fan
okay now as we look at the fan here we
see that there is a
speed control that comes with this fan
so this uh
stealth hyper fan what's great has its
own little speed control
i'm going to see how those adjustments
come into play in just a moment
keep in mind we do have the top here
with our hepa filter
so this is filtering any air that comes
in the air flow through here is going
down
through the fan which is running right
now it's gonna come down through
the tubing here that's ultimately going
to go
into our grow tent i want to see that
intake
okay now in this grow tent this is a
four by two grow tent
we have a flood and drain table here and
that intake that we saw with the air
comes in just above the reservoir there
so if we look down we can see the
reservoir for the flood and drain table
right there and that tubing that's
located right there is
actively adding air to the grow tent so
as i mentioned it's important for air
circulation so this is a great way to
kind of go through and
be adding air um into the grow tent but
we also now
for adding air we're gonna need a way to
exhaust air
and we're gonna see the exhaust phase
next okay so as shown before that's
our intake down by the water reservoir
for the flood and drain table
and as we work our way up
here's our 4x2 row tent we're now going
to focus our attention
at the top of the structure here so
what's
immediately in our view right here is a
carbon filter
now it's got a covering over it to help
any particulate but underneath that
is the actual carbon component so let's
take a look at that
so the reason why the carbon filter is
mounted here towards the top
if you want to remove the hot air as
well so we're adding air at the bottom
and we're going to be removing the top
warmer air there's been a pvc pipe
installed we've got some
of these light adjusting hooks here to
help keep this
as high as possible but still allowing
some
kind of clearance at the top now what
we're noticing here
is we have just a little pre-filter so
they come with pre-filters
you can wash them but always good just
have an extra on hand just in case you
tear it or something goes wrong with it
chiefs are easy they're easy easy to
store
and they're very light so that's the
pre-filter
what's below that is our actual carbon
filter
the one i've chosen here is kind of an
oversized it's an activated carbon
filter
made by the company fat and it's
designed for
500 cubic feet per minute
so this filter is sitting basically
right here we're going to see another
one of them in a moment
what this is doing now is we're going to
have a fan on the other side
this is going to pull air through that
so any
air that has any odor with it or the
warmest air is going to come through
this activated carbon filter
be removed from particulate which will
help the carbon last a little bit longer
remove of odor and then go through the
fan which is our next step
so continuing on with our ventilation
system here's our carbon filter pulling
out the hottest air
and deodorizing it as it goes through
those activated uh
carbon and then it goes right through
another one of those
stealth hyper fans so the reason why
another stealth hyper fan
is right here is to help move air
through here
and out of the grow tent now we don't
see any branding here because the way i
had to mount it but we can see it is
mounted high
and this is kind of the size of the fan
this is all that sound cancelling foam
installed in there which really does a
great job of reducing any noise
i mentioned before the one on the
outside has got a speed control which i
have installed
this one could have the same option but
i choose not to run a speed control
the reason why i choose not trying to
speed control is this is very
restrictive
to pull through this carbon filter it's
got to exhaust through another carbon
filter
so i run this one at 100 percent and i
adjust the one
on the outside so let's continue a
little bit further
with this ventilation system okay and as
we follow that air if it's been through
one carbon filter and through the fan
it's now coming outside of the grow tent
so if you can follow this
down here we're starting to see there
that air is coming right through
it normally just be exhausted to the
outside environment but here i've chosen
another step
chosen actually to run it through
another carbon filter
something you typically won't see
there's a reason for this
so this gives you a little bit closer
inspection
of that carbon filter and how fine all
of those little
pores are the reason why is run through
another carbon filter
this is to help ensure that there's no
odor that is exhausted out of the tent
so again as we come down that exhaust
air is coming through here it's going to
go run through another carbon filter
now this one unlike the one we saw
inside the grow tent doesn't have
one of the pre-filters on it the reason
being that
the air's already been through the hepa
filter and through the other pre-filter
not really needed if you do want to run
one i'd run it on the inside because
that would trap any particulate
then on the outside we want to make sure
it's exhausting as easy as possible
so this is just another one a
exact same size of the one that we saw
on the
inside there some of those fat filters
uh
definitely oversized it's six inches in
neck diameter here by
24 inches so not only do we run it
through one or ran it through another
and air that comes through here that
will then be the air that goes
into the space so by running it through
two carbon filters it really
eliminates all sense of odor uh we
are in a shared space here so it's
important to keep that in mind
now you saw me mention about the speed
control
on the fan and how i run the one in the
tent at full blast
and i adjust the one on the outside so
let's see how i adjust it and why i
adjust it in that way
okay it's a little bit hard to show on
camera but i'm gonna make an attempt
here
what i have done now is i've got both
fans running and i've got the entire
grow tent sealed
now to determine what the right amount
of air circulation is
is you kind of want the grow tent to
kind of be
flat you kind of want the material not
to be building out or
pushed in and when you kind of give a
little bit of pressure on it you can see
it bounces
back this is a sign that's dialed in and
the air coming in
the same relatively speaking is the air
going out
keep in mind that main one at the top
running at full speed and i'm adjusting
the one
on the outside adjusting how much air
comes in this is the correct amount
but now let me turn that way down and
see how things change
so for the purposes now i've basically
turned off
the fan on the outside it's really just
a very minimal amount
you can start to see this side being
pushed
in reason being the exhaust fan at the
top is still running at full speed so
it's exhausting more
air than it's coming in now as a result
you can notice it's much tighter
it has a lot of negative pressure that
air is being pulled out very
aggressively
there's not a lot of air there so this
has created a great billowing
effect here this is a sign when that air
is too little this is a sign that
you want to add some more air let me go
to the other extreme and let me turn the
outside one on a 100
just like the inside one is
so now i've turned the outside one to
100 percent which is not very
restrictive so that's going to be adding
more air than the
exhaust fan is going to be able to take
out you can see this already starting to
rise it's getting closer to me
and now it's billowing out so because
we're adding more air then it can be
removed you can notice that we
definitely have this billowing effect
this is a sign you're adding too much
air aggressively then you are exhausting
so what's great about a grow tent is it
allows you very quickly to be able to
assess
uh your airflow a little harder in a
larger grow space but this kind of gives
you that idea here and i'll get the
building effect
if i go through now and turn it back
where it was at kind of the ideal amount
we'll notice this will kind of come in a
little bit but it's not going to be
pushed all the way in
it's not going to be pushed all the way
out at the convex or concave it's going
to be
kind of even it's going to have a little
bit of pressure there just
getting it there's airflow but not super
tight or
super loose so this is a great way to
make sure
you're ventilating your plants properly
but also controlling odors
and this is the fan way down
this is turning it way up and
immediately responds so it's a great
little speed control
and then for the grow tent i have here
dialed in it's pretty much
right about there so it gives you that
nice kind of way to quickly be able to
assess
the speed of the fan to dial in for your
grow setup
okay so here i'm just going to go over a
couple products that we saw today again
i'm not sponsored by any of these
companies but
let's go over a couple of them so the
first one here is
the hyper stealth fans
why did i choose to add not one but
actually two of these well what makes
these kind of
so great is that they're very quiet so
when you're in the area that has a lot
of
other people around or if you're running
two of them in particular
you just don't want a lot of disturbance
these are a great fan to kind of add as
i mentioned the fan
is the same hyper fan that is sold
singly
but what makes this so big is that there
is a lot of foam and insulation
there's a lot of kind of area here to
help
dampen that noise and it really does a
great job even running at full speed
i mentioned the hyper fans in addition
also come with these little uh variable
speed controls
which are great a lot of other companies
have to purchase them separately this is
great to kind of have come
come with it i'll plug it right in and
as you saw
in the grow tent this works quite well
so again these
stealth hyper fans are going to pay a
little bit more probably for all the
extra features that it has
but in my opinion definitely worth it
and we saw it functioning very well with
our grow tent
another product you saw downstairs was
the actual carbon filter
so while this might be a little
oversized everything that you saw
was all matched and sized appropriately
this is a six inch
by 24 inch carbon filter the hyper fan
that we saw also was another
six inch so what is so great about these
carbon filters is that they really are
able to kind of
reduce any of the odor and we saw two
installed so i had one where air was
kind of being pulled through this
and then one were areas being kind of
exhausted through it
with a hyper fan in between so that
ensured that
movement of air was adequate so you can
never really go
too big with one of these as long as
your fans are inline fans or sized
appropriately
so that's why i chose to go with not
only one that was probably
sized appropriately for that tent but i
went with two just to ensure there'd be
no
chance of any odors escaping that tent
while still maintaining good ventilation
for the
plants inside now these do come with
what i do always purchase separately
little pre-filters but it's important to
get some of these because they'll just
prevent any particulate
of them clogging up the very fine pores
of the carbon you want it very fine
it's also important remember with carbon
filters you want to keep your humidity
kind of below 75 or 80 percent because
the moisture in the air
will really reduce the effectiveness of
that fine surface area
of the carbon filter if you use them
appropriately and get them size
appropriate they can work
great now something else we saw with the
grow tent downstairs was kind of one of
these
hepa filters so i want to try to
maintain and keep your air as clean as
possible
coming into the grow tent and this is a
great way to do that
so these hepa filters allow that kind of
purification of the air
now there can be another hassle to add
another filter but what makes these so
great is you saw these kind of fall
right on top
and they can rest right there they
prevent any large particulates from
getting into the fan
and they also prevent any fine
particulates do you have to be cleaned
and washed occasionally
uh but well worth work worth with this
one
because it's very easily washable it
doesn't restrict any in the flow it's
reusable
uh and again you can see at the bottom
here uh it is sized appropriately so
again we're sticking everything
being six inches with the setup that you
just saw
so the stream filter here great way to
kind of help ensure
air entering about before it enters your
grow tent
is already gone through at least one
stage of filtration to do a quick recap
of everything we saw
we started with that hepa filter here
allowing air to get kind of initially
cleaned and purified preventing from
getting to our filter
the the fan that we used was a
hyper hyperfan stealth edition uh so we
allowed this to kind of help pull the
air through its brakes at a speed
control on the outside
then ran through some six inch ducting
into our tent
and then at the very top of our tent
where the air is the hottest
we had a carbon filter if you don't
recognize it
keep in mind that we did have the
pre-filter um on there you're always
good to get an extra
ran through one of these came back
through another hyper fan
and then back to another carbon filter
on the outside of the tent
to have that double kind of carbon
filtration to reduce any chance
that odors would be escaping the grow
tent okay now something i mentioned to
kind of make
all these kind of products come together
and work appropriately is that in-line
kind of ducting so you can get some that
is insulated to make it even more quiet
the key part is here watch the eggs
because the metal can be quite sharp
when you cut it but it doesn't take very
much it can be a very small piece
can really expand outwards uh
quite well there so when you're running
it
keep in mind this is going to have a lot
of air inside it so that it is going to
want to expand
so keep in mind that you do want to
expand it and then have an idea and cut
it to length that way
you can always buy a little bit extra
use it for a couple other things but you
saw it kind of a nice way to kind of
hook
and join everything together and keep
the system of air controlled
and you want to try to eliminate as many
of the right angles or
180 degree turns as you can the
straighter the more efficient with
everything that you flow
here everything because it was a little
oversized allows for
some chance for having a little bit of a
saw a couple
nine degree turns but try to minimize
those as much as possible