in this debaco university video we're
going to go over how to set up a venturi
style
or what's commonly referred to as a
massey fertilizer injector
for cannabis plant production
[Music]
ever wonder how to use a venturi or
massey fertilizer injector for canvas
production
well this video here is for you
so let's get into some of the details so
first off the method of
operation well chemicals are injected
into a pressurized pipe using a venturi
principle so here basically you have a
large area of restricted area and that's
the venturi concept
the venturing injector is tapered as we
can see right here
to constrict which operates in the
principle the pressure drop accompanies
the change in the velocity of the water
as it passes through the constriction
point the pressure drop through the
venturi
must be sufficient to create negative
pressure which is essentially a
vacuum to some degree and as measured
relatively atmospheric pressure
with that result that pressure loss
may cause not to operate properly in
systems that already have low pressure
because you are going to or these
operate with the change in pressure
if you already have low pressure to
begin with this may not be the best
option for you
under those conditions the fluid from
the tank will flow into the injectors we
have that pressure difference that
vacuum that negative pressure
it's going to start to pull some of this
liquid up and inject it into
the irrigation water most ventricular
injectors require at least 20 percent
pressure differential to initiate this
negative pressure
a full vacuum of 20 inches of mercury is
obtained
with a different pressure of five
percent or more and we could see here
that also depending on the size of your
irrigation
they make different sized venturi
operated injectors
typically called massey injectors now
this pressure drop is needed so small
venturi
can be used to inject small chemical
flow rates to a relatively large
main line by shutting a portion of the
flow through the injector
to assure that water will flow through
the shunt a pressure drop must occur in
the main line
since our inlet and outlet sizes are the
same but there will be a pressure
reduction
as a result the injector is used to run
a point of restriction such as a valve
orifice or pressure regulator or other
device which creates a
differential pressure so placement of
this could also be
important just to ensure that it
operates properly now there are some
additional components
in here gaskets and springs also be
mindful of
but overall basically very minimal
components
now the venturi advantage so why would
someone choose to operate
uh with this style we can see that right
here is that it doesn't require external
power to operate it's a great advantage
does not really have any moving parts
associated with it has a long
operational life expectancy
low probability of failure both great
things for growers
resistant to many chemicals do the heavy
plastic construction
requires minimal operator retention once
it's set up very low maintenance
reduced cost definitely compared to some
other systems and adaptable to new or
existing
systems again assuming sufficient
pressure so this is why these can be
very popular
with many fertilizer injector systems
so when we're looking at the liquid
levels they mentioned venture injectors
come in various sizes and can be
operated on different pressure
conditions
the suction can pass capacity or the
injection rate
head loss required and working pressure
range will depend on the model you
specifically select
so do that research ahead of time it is
important to realize that suction
capacity depends on the liquid level in
the tank
and as the liquid level drops the
suction head
increases resulting in a decreased
injection rate so there will be some
inconsistencies particularly using a
very thin
but tall container to avoid this problem
some manufacturers provide an additional
small tank on the side to supply
a supply tank their float valve
maintains the fluid level relatively
consistently
the fluid is injected from this
additional tank however this may cause
inconsistent fertilizer dilution rates
at the start compared to the end of the
irrigation
cycle unless you're injecting in water
of the same
fertilizer concentration so again just a
few little things to consider
but this is why this one is so popular
because it offers a lot of advantages at
really reduced cost
especially for operations that have
sufficient or excessive
pressure