if you have leaves that look like this
on your cannabis plant
odds are you probably have septoria in
this tobacco university video we'll
provide you with
proper identification as well as control
techniques for this particular disease
[Music]
all right let's look at how to identify
and control septoria on cannabis plants
so first off proper identification is
important
inceptory leaf spot can cause leaf loss
and reduction in photosynthesis
and is one of the most common leaf spot
pathogens among
hemp leaf spot diseases and we can see a
great image of that here
scout lower leaves and within the inner
canopy where leaf wetness and high
humidity occur
as this is likely a place for the
disease to start look for small
irregular shaped spots with bright
yellow margins
spots expand to about a quarter inch in
diameter and appear brown with
predominant yellow halo
so you can see here that predominant
yellow halo clearly evident
as spots in large brown areas become
more regular and develop gray to white
centers
yellow halos expand outwards from those
spots the entire leaf rapidly becomes
yellow and can drop from plants in
advanced cases so the life cycle of
septoria
and looking at from two different
aspects here showing you kind of what's
happening in those little spots
showing you kind of all those little
fungal spores that are developing the
pathogen can overwinter as mycelium
and then can reinfect plants the
following year so it's good to clean
those portions up we're seeing an
example here if again wind and rain
splash spores kind of knocking those off
those can then go through and develop as
early lesions as yellow spots on newly
emerged plants
the cycle can repeat itself if
conditions are favorable when those
leaves do drop off the plant
they serve as overwintering areas now
this is showing soybeans but the same
thing does apply to cannabis
where the overwinting spore can occur
proper conditions cause it to kind of
proliferate and affect new plants so how
do you go about managing this and this
kind of shows a really good kind of
zoomed in version here
while this is not cannabis this is
showing you the great image of what
septoria can look like
this is an example of it in cannabis
when excessive moisture or high humidity
is available
the fungal life cycles are shorter and
larger number of spores are produced
both
negative things if you're looking at
trying to mitigate this disease
so this can increase the chance of
disease later in plants life cycle when
the plants are more dense
during rainy summers disease can spread
rapidly through fields if you're growing
this in an outdoor application
separatory species can overwinter in
fields unaffected plant debris
under cool conditions with low relative
humidity the
pinidia can remain viable for up to nine
months in debris
the in contrast piniti survives
decreased dramatically in hot weather
and when in buried soils for example
tilling for less than one month
so if you do have infected material over
large scale and you till that in
that can be a way to reduce the life
expectancy
of septoria although although
alternative hosts have not been
identified for septoria's species that
cause leaf spot in hemp
it is likely that weeds and other
similar green bridges are responsible
for survival
from one growing season to the next and
we're still looking at investigating
this more
but odds are these green bridges it
spreads to another
weed host another disease host resides
there and then the following year it can
then jump from that original host that
it carried over
and infect your hemp plants so hopefully
this gives you a little insight into
septoria
which is sadly very commonly seen on
cannabis