this is a question i'm often asked how
do you calculate 100 parts per million
of nitrogen fertilizer
well here at debacle university video
we're going to go through and we're
going to walk you through the process
and exactly how to go about calculating
so grab your calculator
and let's get into the video
[Music]
all right hopefully you got your
calculator and we're going to go through
how to calculate
our parts per million of nitrogen
fertilizer for your cannabis plants
so why 100 parts per million and ppm
does stand for parts per million
well typically the goal of nitrogen for
cannabis is 120 parts per million
so for simplicity we're going to go how
to calculate 100 parts per million will
be shown
in addition i will show 120 parts from
the example
this will allow you to see the multiple
examples so you'll be comfortable with
the process
and apply it to your own particular
growing situation so you know just
how much to add without over adding on
anything to your plants
so first off we have to start with how
do you read a fertilizer label so
fertilizers will provide three numbers
which are percentages the order is
important
it goes nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium since this example will
calculate nitrogen
we simply are going to be looking at the
first number so on this one it's four
percent nitrogen
and this one 17. so looking at this
example here
we're just going to use a standard jacks
a water soluble fertilizer
20 nitrogen 10 phosphorous 20
potassium we're going to again focus on
that first number here
because we're calculating nitrogen now
for actually fertilizing we can't forget
about those numbers
but for the purposes of this calculation
we're going to focus on the 20
nitrogen so first question how much
fertilizer do you add to one liter of
water
so you get a hundred per million
solution great question
well let's go through the calculation
steps here so
starting with that 20 percent nitrogen
the goal of 100 parts per milli of
nitrogen
so since the goal is 100 parts per
million how much fertilizer are we going
through and adding well our goal is that
100 parts per million
so note that 100 parts per million is
the same as 100 milligrams
per liter so we're doing a little metric
conversion here so our goal is to get to
that 100 so how much do we need to add
well we've got we want 100 milligrams of
nitrogen per liter
we have 0.2 grams per
0.2 grams of nitrogen per 1 gram of
fertilizer this is 20
so 20 of 1 gram is 0.2 grams so we have
0.2 grams of nitrogen from one gram of
fertilizer
we simply go through we multiply the top
we
divide by the bottom and as a result we
get we would add
500 milligrams per liter which is the
same as
half a gram per liter so you can go
through and make some modifications here
again our target here is 100
parts per million we have 20 percent
nitrogen which is where this number
comes from
multiply across the top divide by the
bottom we get
500 milligrams per liter or simplified
0.5 grams per liter
so if we're continuing on to question to
that continued question
if the ratios calculated previously was
0.5 grams per liter
how many grams do i add for a 50 gallon
tank well we have that ratio there of
half a gram per liter how when we
do a conversion from liters to gallons
one liter is the same as
0.24 i'm sorry 1 liters the same as
0.264 gallons we want to add
to 50 gallons so the question is how
many grams do we add
again multiplying across the top
dividing by the bottom we would get
94.7 grams per 50 gallon tank
so something might be more applicable to
a reservoir that a grower might be
utilizing
now let's go to question two how much
fertilizer would you add
to one liter of water to get 120 parts
per milliliter solution so now we've
upped the concentration
really to what's considered to be ideal
for cannabis so again we're still
starting with that same 20 nitrogen but
now our goal is 120 parts per million
you can see it's set up basically the
same way here we're noticing
except we've changed that 100 it is now
120.
we solved that 20 nitrogen so it's still
0.2 grams per gram of fertilizer
multiply everything in the top divide it
by everything multiplied in the bottom
we get 600 milligrams per liter or in
this case 0.6 grams per liter
and we continue that step a little bit
further if the ratio calculated
previously that was 0.6 grams per liter
how many grams would i add for 1 gallon
of concentrate tank
to using a proportion injector set at
one to two hundred ratio
and touring gallons of irrigation water
to be used so now we're getting a little
bit more complicated here
now we're looking at using like a
dosatron or a chemi injector or some way
of injecting that fertilizer
so since 200 gallons will be used the
grower should add
454 grams into a one gallon concentrated
source
to make sure everything dissolves and
does not settle in this concentration
so how do we get that well we get that
0.6 grams per liter
we do our conversions here we're looking
at 200 gallons
well we want to have 454 grams uh to be
dispersed over that 200 gallons so we
take that one gallon concentrate
which is where the tube of our dosatron
would go into we'd mix in 454 grams stir
that up well
run it for the duration of time to get
out to our 200 gallons because a
1 to 200 ratio means 1 gallon of
concentrate will be used
for every 200 gallons of water that goes
through so this is a great way you can
ensure that your plants on
even a large scale are getting the right
ratio mixed
so this just again acts as a starting
point you're welcome to go back through
review this video a couple times do the
math yourself with the information and
numbers provided here and make sure you
get the right numbers
and then apply it to your own situation
so you can get your
fertilizer fertigation dialed in to the
benefit of you
as well as your plants