ever wonder how to select the proper
size container for your cannabis plants
well this debaco university is going to
help you with that very topic all right
let's get into the video so you can
select the right container size for your
cannabis plants
so first off there are factors that can
depend on this there's not one quick
really easy answer hopefully i'll kind
of go through and just give you some of
the basic rundowns here so you can make
an educated decision
first off you want to consider what
strain you're going to grow in the sense
that
how big do you plan on that plant
getting also the substrate you select
what's the water holding capacity of
that substrate
pruning method keep the plants small or
you're letting them grow
quite large that can affect the size of
the container that's going to be a best
fit
also your growing environment meaning
how large of an area do you have to grow
in
this can be both in square footage but
also you want to be thinking about
height
as well and how that impacts the
container you can see here a bunch of
plants growing together
very variable sizes of containers
probably not maximizing the production
here
we also want to consider factors such as
the cost
the container and or the amount of
substrate you might be using
smaller containers can save costs but
will increase plant stress
duration of the growth cycle how old
will your plants be at harvest are you
looking for a quick turnaround time
should be something that's going to be a
little bit longer or grower preference
simply what do you like
what kind of size do you prefer what
kind of
substrate are you buying how is this all
going to kind of factor into things
so providing some general suggestions
and again underline the word here
general because it is just that i wanted
to provide
just some example here some suggestions
plant size and suggested container size
and they send use this as just a general
guide or at least a starting point
for your kind of 12 inches you're
looking at about that two to three
gallon container
for 24 inches you can up to a three to
five gallon container
for 36 inches or three foot tall you're
looking at six to eight gallons
four feet tall eight to ten gallons and
60 inches
or above a 12 gallon container would be
recommended
again this could depend on your pruning
style go back to your substrate growing
area
but at least if you are looking for an
area to start
this is where i would suggest you at
least start to see how well this may
work for you
i also have things provided here in the
metric system
so you can get again another idea of
height in centimeters
compared to the size of the container
expressed in liters
and this is a natural progression you're
looking at the larger plants typically
being grown in
larger containers now it does not mean
that
as a plant goes from 12 inches to 24 to
36 to 40 to 60 you're constantly
changing the containers
you might want to skip one start with a
little bit larger size maybe not let the
plants get quite as big
so again this does not mean you're going
to be transplanting uh this plant from
maybe
propagation to a 12 in when it's 12 inch
and
every foot increment from there so just
keep that in mind
now for commercial production setups as
we see here typically these will use
about a five to seven gallon
max size container for their plants and
will reserve larger sizes
only for mother or stock plants if you
want kind of a comparison for production
typically five to seven gallon sizes is
kind of the max that they're using
for their production plants in general
so again use that as just a general
guide
and hopefully this provides you with a
good starting point to help maximize
your production
by selecting the right container to grow
your cannabis plants in