in this debaco university video we'll be
looking at how to identify and control
pythium or crown rot
in cannabis plants so we can see here
can affect them at the early stages
in later in stages so one to be mindful
of
as a grower
[Music]
so because pythium can affect plants at
early stages in later stages
it's important to be able to identify
this and also
have a control idea because it's
something growers should be scouting for
through all stages of the plant cycle so
first off identification is important
and there are several different
pathogenic species that can cause
disease in a wide host range
python is a water mold so it can travel
to new host plants via water
and that can be irrigation water root
rots and lower stem decay cause above
ground symptoms such as marginal leaf
scorch
stunting poor plant vigor and or
inconsistent stands if you're looking
down a long row
it can also produce oh spores that can
overwinter which can be an issue if
you're looking at planting in that same
field the following year
most notably causes root rots that can
be field identified
by pulling out the roots and then trying
to strip the outer layer so this is your
kind of your root area
you take your roots and try to strip off
that our layer if it comes off really
easy
that can be a sign you may have pithium
the above ground
seedlings can damp off which is a common
propagation areas
and larger plants will express chlorosis
of leaves once pythium infects hemp
plants there's really no cure
so being able to identify and know that
you have it is important for making out
for making ideas and plans for following
years as far as probably not planting in
that field or rotating out so what's the
general
life cycle of pythium well we can see
here it is uh it is root based
uh it can cause that kind of infection
we see that spores oh spores as i said
swimming kind of in the water zoospores
germination attaches to the root infects
that portion
grows up in the plant causes a blighted
plant causes a dead plant
when that plant dies all those roots and
have all those
additional spores or elantrium
fertilization occurs causing it to
spread to directly germinate to infect
more
and really can cause this to spread
quite quickly
so what are some common methods of
spreading as it does a pretty good job
of it on its own
but soil substrate transfer such as
tools containers or even
shoes can transfer epithelium from one
field to another
contaminated water containing irrigation
water or runoff can also cause it to
spread
infected plants should be isolated
removed tagged and bagged
to prevent any sort of spread to healthy
neighboring plants
there's winter over inoculum present
from previously infected plants and also
poor sanitation protocols
particularly if you're in an indoor
growing operation so how do you go about
managing pythium or crown rot
we want to manage soil moisture in the
root zone inspect any new plant material
entering the growing area
for disease as well as insects ensure
proper aeration of the substrate
keep nitrogen at optimum but not
excessive levels and you want to avoid
salt accumulation within the substrate
that will cause
plant stress as well have sanitation
protocols in place
even if this is not identified if you
think your plants are clean hopefully
they are that's great
still implement those sanitation
protocols so that if there's any small
portion of pithing that tries to get
started your sanitation protocols
should take care of that to eliminate
the chance of you seeing that
in your subsequent crop particularly in
those indoor locations