this tobacco university video is going
to look at the identification
and control of fungus gnats related to
cannabis plants
[Music]
all right let's go over how to identify
and control gnats on
cannabis plants particularly fungus
gnats so let's start off with a
description here
fungus gnat larvae need wet conditions
to thrive and are typically found
growing in
the substrates and typically near the
kind of surface of those
substrates you can see here the fungus
now larvae how it looks and then we see
the adult
uh now in the actual soil here we see
one actually affixed to a yellow sticky
card
which are used are hung in and around
plants
to capture insects so that growers can
identify or know
what's in the area as far as pest
pressure goes
now the identification here we see a
large yellow sticky trap with all sorts
of fungus gnats attached to it
those yellow sticky cards can be helpful
for early detection however you can also
use
sliced potatoes placed near the soil or
substrate surface
as it should only take about four to
eight hours for maggots if they're
present
to find the potatoes so if you're
looking for something that you can just
easily go
maybe right in the kitchen and grab take
some potatoes slice them up put them
near the plant
and you should know very quickly if you
have any
fungus maggots it's because the insects
tend to feed on the roots of the
cannabis plant so placing it near the
soil substrate structure
will put it near where they are and
they're very likely to find this
basic area here to feed on as well
now a good about managing them so how to
go about managing fungus gnats
well wet substrate surface is key to
their proliferation
so sometimes putting a layer of sand or
rice holes on the surface of a container
substrate
will reduce the surface moisture and
thus result in less fungus gnats
keeping that real high surface moisture
very wet
really increases the likelihood and
pressure of your plants will have
fungus gnats in general keeping that
substrate surface dry
is important for their control so those
rice holes are sand
dry very easily let water pour through
very easily keeping the upper layer dry
will reduce the pressure of fungus gnats
on your plants
some do suggest application applications
of bacillus thuringiensis or bt
can be helpful but really that moisture
is key
the last resort should be insecticides
that contain pyrethrum
in neem oil as these need several soil
based applications
and can also damage the plant roots as
well so i want to avoid those at
all cost start with the environmental
change reducing the moisture
hopefully that will take care of your
numbers especially
if you're able to identify them early