on this tobacco university video we're
going to be looking at
root aphids so while we may be familiar
with aphids that typically are seen
affecting the leaves and the stems
can't also forget about these root
aphids which can also
negatively impact your cannabis plants
[Music]
so here we're going to be looking at
root aphids something we might be more
familiar with in the top growth of the
the plant but they also can affect the
lower portions so how do we identify and
control them
on our cannabis plants well first off
the right through aphid is what's going
to be focused on
this is a dark green insect with
generally around body form
so wingless stages develop on roots and
they survive on plants
the wing stages periodically emerge from
the soil and they fly to new places
new plants and that's how they're able
to spread their infection
they do have a wide host range including
indoor cannabis plants
even when grown hydroponically so just
don't think because you're not growing
in a solid substrate you don't have to
worry about root aphids even hydroponic
growers should be mindful of this
threat root aphids identification and
the plant damage so
at 73 degrees fahrenheit and optimum
temperature rice fruit aphids can
populations can double every 1.6 days
so they can go very quickly here we can
see what they look like
at the kind of wingless root aphids at
the base of a plant here we see the
winged
rice root aphids trapped on a cannabis
leaf here
then we have them developing within a
hydroponic system so we can see the
roots and we do see them identified
right here
and then within the soil of the rice
plant like here
and here these rice fruit aphids i
should say the cannabis plant
appeared in the lighter and lower
portion of the picture
which can be difficult initially to see
and do require that attention to detail
this is also kind of highlighted here
what they look like
kind of mixed in with the substrate that
the cannabis plants are growing in
so again identification clearly evident
but can be a little more difficult
because of their size so careful
inspection and scouting is important
so i had to go about managing them if
you do identify them
well root aphid management is especially
challenging in organic systems
study was conducted at least in celery
so it's something to evaluate the
effectiveness
of certain products applied via drip
irrigation drench
evaluations were pre-treatment
post-treatment 1 which is application 13
days after the treatment
and post applica post 2 application 10
days after the first treatment
let's take a look at their data so this
was
their results and they determined that
when
the overall change in aphid populations
after both applications compared to the
pre-treatment numbers was considered
there was and we can see the results
here untreated over here
three percent reduction in untreated
control 24 18 and 129
increase in
so let's look at their data well these
were the results and when the overall
change in aphid populations after both
applications compared
to the pre-treatment numbers were
considered there was a three percent
reduction in untreated controls we see
those listed right here
24 18 and 29 percent increase in
these three listed products uh
respectively however
milotrol oh along with uh as a guard
provided 62
reduction in aid populations followed by
a 29 percent reduction in grandivo
and 24 by then or eight this study
demonstrates the potential for
non-chemical options when managing aphid
populations
at least in organic celery these
microbial pesticides especially in
combination with botanical pesticides
can play a significant role in pest
management
understanding the modes of action and
different options and using the right
combinations is critical
to pest management decisions so trying
to find data like this
well not in cannabis can at least
provide a good starting point
and for all the products we see again
the first one is the pre-treatment
post-treatment one and post-treatment
two looking at
mean number of aphids per plant we can
see how the changes occurred again
utilizing a combination
definitely showed a pretty significant
here
reduction so again worth considering and
at least a starting point if you're
looking at what products
may be effective if you do identify root
aphids
in your cannabis crops