in this tobacco university video where
we're going to get into
how and where are cannabinoids produced
we're getting to some really
in-depth scientific research articles as
well which might be a little bit more
advanced
than some people may want to know but at
least here you can get some good
detailed information
look at some good images and if you just
want the basics
that'll be provided here also on this
video lecture
all right let's get into the detail on
how and where are cannabinoids
produced in cannabis plants so first off
here's a great research article that
you're welcome to take a look at
the images will be provided from here uh
and
again to provide you with that extra
level of detail then just a quick simple
answer
however i realize many of you are
probably here for that quick and simple
answer so
uh when we're looking at where these
canonies are produced while
phytocannabinoids are synthesized
in the capital like stocked granular
trichomes
or the csg as they'll be referred to and
this is kind of the structures that they
look like that's the quick answer if
that's all you wanted
you're welcome to depart from the video
at this time we have a lot more detail
to get into
now what i've provided here is some
great um images uh to be able to really
look
at the details of provided in these uh
trichome structures and we're looking at
light
micro microscopy and a and b so
typically what you might
be used to seeing uh we're looking kind
of a side shot as well looking at like a
top
down shot there of the cross sections
then we're also getting into some sem
which is some scanning electron
microscope images which provide
great level of detail almost looks like
something kind of
from space here and we're seeing kind of
the
scale bars and give you an idea of size
we'll look at some of the definitions
here of all the letters correspond with
basically the caption presented here
we'll go through and read it all but it
does give you if you do have an image
you're really interested in
match it up over here and you can find
out some more detail
a little more detail and maybe you want
to understand but basically trichomes is
what we're looking at here
so looking at the trichome development
to kind of
pull back if you will chemist trichomes
because as a salsa glands
lacking a stock and they start near the
surface
of the floral or leaf epidermis remember
epidermis like our epidermis is kind of
the outer skin
on both the adaxial and epidaxial
sides the top and bottom of the um leaf
surface
and plant surface uh these cecil glenoid
trichomes are present on the vegetative
plant
but they are not expressing the
synthesis for cannabinoid production
or monoterpenes they produce primary uh
subsequent terpenes there kind of like
the early early stages there
this kind of shows you just some great
images here really looking at some
detail
uh with on the cannabis leaf surface at
those trichomes
now production of these academics will
only occur
at certain points so they only occur
when the plant reaches
floral maturity do these cecil trichomes
begin to grow stalks
kind of see here and become that csg
kind of
trichomes and only during this phase
does it begin to produce cannabinoids as
well as terpenes
so this is why we don't want to harvest
plants too early because if the
trichomes are underdeveloped
well so are the cannabinoids so are the
terpenes going to be very low in
concentration
so trichome example image you know kind
of looking at kind of the large scale
kind of more of a zoomed in version
the little crystals on the flower are
actually those uh
capitae stocked granular trichomes those
csgs
which sparkle when they catch the light
especially when they're dried these are
the structures we really want to be
careful with
as far as avoid damaging they're also
located right here we can kind of see
that zoomed in version right here
of how the density of the trichomes is
quite high in this particular image
so these csgs close-up picture here
within the glans are secondary
metabolite excretions which are the
primary
the cannabinoids are going to be present
in these
structures so again these are ray
structures they are three-dimensional
we don't want to do any damage to these
and this is why that handling of the
final dried flower
is so delicate and important
now more detailed images again i think
these are also great
to kind of give you that kind of really
advanced
level and look at some trichomes and
we're looking at the flowers here and a
kind of stained
different images these stock granular
trichomes and mature canvas flowers have
a proliferation of cells
and their secretory discs looking kind
of the interior portions
these cecil trichomes with greater than
eight gland cells will develop these
csgs and are typically located on the
calyx which is the structure of the
flower
only csg trichomes produce cannabinoids
and monoterpene so it's very important
we have as many of those as possible
since they're the only structures
responsible for producing the
cannabinoids
if we're looking at the details of these
images again you're kind of not looking
from the side you're kind of looking at
the top
down and we see the kind of description
provided here for all of those and then
it also provide a little bit more of a
macroscopic image
and appreciation for the level of detail
provided here
then there's granular trichomes again
looking at another great kind of
detailed image
there of some of these these granular
trichomes exhibit distinct
intrinsic inflorescence and metabolite
organization
csg is developed from those cecil
granular trichomes and here we're seeing
some side shots
as well cecil trigons produce
predominantly
the terpenes these subsequitarian
terpenes
and minimal cannabinoids and produce red
auto
fluorescence that we see here the csgs
produce cannabinoids and monoterpenes
and produce blue autofluorescence as we
kind of see here so that staining also
goes through
and we see them kind of average
intensity here of our intrinsic
fluorescence and trichomes different
wavelengths being produced
and we see the degree and there are some
variations i don't think that's just
this is a perfect curve there are some
degree of variations there
but just to kind of get an appreciation
for different wavelengths
average intensity here and the intrinsic
inflorescence
now if we're looking at the images some
great images some great really detailed
images
again the kind of caption provided here
below
to provide you some of that detail as
presented in that research article to
kind of
show you that level of advanced level of
complexity here
so another kind of morphological kind of
look here um these sem images scanning
electron microscope images really
detailed images of the morphology of
three different types of glandular
trichomes
we have uh again d e and f here
we have the stock cecil and then the
bulbas located right here
keep in mind we are looking at the
epidermis there so we're looking at
structures that are raised from the
epidermis
the unique features of these particular
trichomes we can kind of see image right
here the canvas
csg trichomes are responsible for
cannabinoid and monoterpene biosynthesis
these are the sites where those are
being produced this does require gland
cells in a secretory cavity
so within those structures what you're
looking at you know that cloudy
appearance or amber appearance or clear
appearance this is kind of what's going
on inside of those regions
there's genetic mechanisms regulating
the biochemical and morphological
changes that occur
during the csv trichome development and
really they're not
that well understood we know that they
occur but not really well understood so
an
area great for future scientific
research to be done
and we can kind of see the location
really close to eight disk cells here
and then we see that building of that
initial stock and that true stock
developed here
it's what's occurring within here that
the plant is regulating
that development of those cannabinoids
as well as those
terpenes so exactly the genes are
responsible for that
again not well understood but a great
area here for
scientific discovery going in forward in
the future
it was just kind of a zoomed out version
of kind of a grain layer trichome
again occurring on that leaf surface
these cecil glinter trichomes will have
secretory vesicles
encapsulated by a waxy cuticle keep in
mind the outside portion
of plants is waxy lipid-based and has to
be water repellent
much like our own skin we produce a lot
of oils and lipids
very water repellent this waxy cuticle
will contain
several smaller vesicles which are
extracellular components
separated by apple plastic space so
we're kind of getting that development
of these three-dimensional structures
within
or with on top of that epidermis the
entire vesicle apparatus is attached to
a rosette of gland cells
which are themselves connected to the
rosette of striped cells
which are connected to a basal cell
which is connected to the stock cells
so we're having these multiple kind of
building blocks
to create that stocked alt trichome in
the end
the stock contains cells which are
designed to pump substrates into the
secretory cell rosette
which again in this area up here where
typically growers are looking to be
whether it's cloudy or amber color
this is the actual location they're
looking at where they look at the
coloration change because there's some
indication
to when the cannabinoids are being
produced within those glycotricones
now hopefully if you stuck together this
long our last little bit here are
secretory cells
the plastids within the secretory cells
produce the cbga
and terpenes which are then transported
through the cell wall
into the secretory vesicles where they
form what auburn describes as high lean
areas
which form secretory vesicles in that
area these little bulbs
uh these little bubbles are where the
secretory secondary metabolites are
synthesized
and then stored cbga is produced in the
secretory cell
plastid and then exported into the
secretory vesicle
for further manipulation by proteins
called synthases and this is looking at
enzymes
all occurring in that one little top
bulbous uh category there
most growers just look at as a cloudy is
it clear there is a lot going on
in that region a lot more than i think
most growers realize and maybe
appreciate
hopefully future scientific discoveries
can unlock some of the pathways here
so we can better understand exactly
what's going on in these
trichome structures