here in this tobacco university video
i'll go over how many roots does the
cannabis colon need
well it's not enough what's too many uh
we're going to assess
some actual roots and give you an idea
of what the ideal rooting is
[Music]
all right let's go over how to evaluate
your cannabis clinton's
roots so first off when is a clone
adequately rooted what is that kind of
ideal amount that's a common question
and it really has a variable answer you
want to consider
what substrate or lack of substrate
where your plant can be growing in
where is the plant going to be going
ultimately and how old
is the plant with the variability images
will be provided as a comparison for
evaluation
mainly looking at clones that were
rooted in aeroponic cloner because we
can actually see the roots in the
structure of them
in general the goal of a quality clone
is to have a well-developed root system
roots are starting to branch and the
length of the roots will actually
support
the growing plant you can see here with
these initial roots developing
it's a good sign but not nearly
adequately rooted enough
so this is kind of the image of what i
would consider to be the ideal rooting
because there's even rooting on all
sides the roots are just starting to
branch
when i say branch we're looking at these
small little development of these kind
of root hair like appendages
there's a nice even white coloration to
the roots and this makes for easy
transfer
into whatever selected substrate the
grower will be going into with the
with the clone when we're starting to
root so what does this kind of look like
here we kind of flip these over
and while these could be transferred at
this stage it is possible
typically we recommend you wait for
another few days it would be recommended
why because while there's roots starting
you want them just to kind of develop a
little bit further so they can be able
to support the plant growth
as i said an aeroponic cloner is an
ideal environment so the roots will
likely develop
faster to ease the plant transition
process
so they can actually produce more roots
and faster with an aeroponic system
before you transfer them and that's why
wait just a little bit longer
now this rooting here looks like it
would be you know ideal this would be
like what
every grower would want their roots to
have but this is actually a little bit
past
prime there's many roots this column is
a little bit class prime but only about
about a day or so
this does not mean it will transfer
poorly but the multiple route here is
forming and multiple root branches
forming at the main site for nutrient
absorption
so upon transfer there likely will be
some damage there's just so many roots
here no matter what
media you're going to put in what
substrate you're going to put it in
you're most likely to do some damage to
that root structure
the plant though will likely be to
recover well but be aware that those
finer roots is where the majority of the
absorption of water
and absorption of nutrients occurs in
the plant
more branching is better than a thicker
root structure you want a thick carrot
root you want that branching
but you want to be damaging that
branching so that's going to be damaging
the uptake
of water and nutrients for your plant
and we also have here where we just have
simply
uh too many routes here this is
just kind of letting it sit in the
cloner a little bit too long missing it
by
sometimes only a short duration of time
they can grow fast once they start
growers still they should be still
transferred to the next stage but
realize they're a little past prime
and that will kind of hinder that
transition process
in the end the plants will likely
perform well but this may be a little
bit slower to make that transition
since they are a little past primal too
much rooting is occurring here
the clone can go quickly from no root to
too many so daily inspections is
recommended
to catch that ideal day to make the
transfer and this is why so many growers
like the aeroponic cloner
which allows them to pull plants at the
ideal time to ensure the minimum amount
of
transfer shock or transplant shock
that's occurring and maximizing their
production