okay I'm gonna look at something we
probably take for granted it's how we
breathe so a very important component to
us breathing is the diaphragm now what
the diaphragm is is actually a
dome-shaped muscle I intended plays a
vital role in the breathing process we
could see here the diaphragm does it's
kind of this green line here not a
complete accurate depiction but it's a
line of change in volume so this is a
picture of that muscle and that kind of
increasing and changing in volume so
it's causing air to come in and air to
come out breathing is the act of pumping
of air in and out of the lungs so while
the diaphragm is completely separate
from the lungs is affecting the volume
of the lungs which is affecting the air
coming in or air leaving so the
inhalation and exhalation process when
we're breathing air in the diaphragm
contracts and flattens and you can see
here it's being pushed down taking our
lung volume and increasing it this chest
cavity expands downwards and also
outwards this creates a negative
pressure and air comes in so the
expiration or the exhalation process is
basically the opposite the diaphragm is
relaxing in this case volume of chest
cavity is decreasing and the pressure in
the lungs is forcing air out and that is
the exhalation process we can see it
represented here when we're looking at
the Boyles gas law is a key component
here and we have peak and pressure and
vehicles volume so p1 v1 equals p2 v2
well what does that kind of look like
well when the volume is decreasing our
pressure is increasing so here we have a
constant temperature and we have our
pressure increasing when our volume is
decreasing so we take our set volume
there and we're compressing it the
pressure is increasing so keep in mind
as the volume increases the pressure
decreases and you have this in verse
relationship as the volume decreases the
pressure will increase it's then linear
it's kind of this kind of this
exponential scale but you can see
overall the pattern is
the volume either increases the pressure
will do the opposite and here we see
that example of that volume decreasing
and that pressure increasing now the
mechanism of breathing in humans we have
typical breath at rest is about half a
liter so this is called your tidal
volume when each breath is completed the
lungs still contains a volume of air so
it's about one point two liters left
behind and that's called a residual
volume each inhalation adds about 500
milliliters at resting or 3,000
milliliters during exercising we were
three liters each exhalation removes the
same volume as inhalation added so does
this kind of relate to if you compare to
a two-liter bottle or $2,000 soda bottle
this kind of puts this in perspective
again your tidal volumes here and you
have its raishin volume expiration
volume and any residual line and there's
still some air in your lungs you can't
exhale at all so this gives you a little
bit of a background on how we go about
breathing