not sure if you've seen this insect in
your cannabis plants but
corn earworms can be a major pest
so in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over how to properly
identify and control them
in your cannabis plants
[Music]
all right let's go over how to identify
and control corn earworms
in cannabis plants and this is kind of
what they look like hopefully you
haven't seen them
but if you have this video should
provide you with some helpful
information so first off the description
of them
well corn earrings is one of the most
widespread common
commonly damaging insects in much of the
united states affecting both field crops
as well as vegetable crops
all in addition to hemp most damage is
done by the late stage caterpillars
which are present 10 to 14 days after
egg hatching
and feed for a week or two before being
fully grown
so kind of at this stage often there
will be a granular form of fecal kind of
like pellets or frass
left around the feeding site that can be
used for diagnosing an injury
this is also what the adult corn earworm
may look like there
and this is kind of what the larval
stage looks and that's what the egg
looks like now the proper identification
of at least looking
on cannabis the adult moths fly at dusk
and evening
although a few are sometimes active on
overcast days
on other plants the moths lay most of
their eggs on the leaves or in corn the
green kind of
silk area so i get the name earworm on
hemp though eggs are likely laid on the
outer areas of the plant particularly on
the younger leaves
such as those surrounding the flower
buds and developing seeds that's why we
see the kind of caterpillar up here
feeding
and here we also see the damage to the
blood region
as far as what can we do regarding this
particular pest
well for the management of corn earworms
entrust
was the only product that provided
really effective control
unfortunately this is the one product
that was evaluated by uh
this is vermont and is not allowed to be
applied unhemped so it's the one that
they really looked at
does show some effectiveness as we can
see clearly here
but not certified so hopefully that was
the time this publication
maybe things have changed check your
local restrictions and current
restrictions at that
the insecticide and trust is army
certified however so that's a plus and
here we could see the mean coin rooms
per
um 10 plants and trust definitely doing
a great job at reducing it
according damage rating also was reduced
by interest so that is definitely
something to look at
to see if it's available to use in your
particular area or regulations
because it might be a first step at an
effective control
for corn earworms on your cannabis
plants