on this debaco university video i'll
show you
what bud rot or gray mold also called
botrytis
looks like on cannabis plants as well as
i'll give you some ideas for identifying
it and controlling it
at the very end i'll show you a plant
that was right near harvest time
that sadly was identified to have blood
rot
[Music]
all right let's go over how to identify
and control bud rot or called grey mold
or botrytis
on cannabis plants so first off
bud rot or botrytis provides two most
common names
or also called gray mold develops
primarily in dense portions of the plant
sadly such as the flower buds and is
favored by high humidity
grain mold growth can be seen as masses
of mycelium which are basically fungal
strands
and clusters of canadia which are
asexual spores that are produced in
large numbers
if it starts internally to the bud this
could be a very unwelcome surprise at
the end of the season harvest
when you're going through and kind of
peeling back and trimming it your
earbuds you could find that actual
residual in the center portion there
so it's good to do inspections ahead of
time now the life cycle
of botrytis here just this is shown on
strawberry but very similar metrics is a
disease
in strawberries but the sources of of
this inoculum include infective leaves
or
sclerosia primary infections of flowers
and secondary infections of fruit
are depicted here now keep in mind this
botrytis
species looks like this on a close-up so
think about all these little kind of
branches that can easily break off
and go and affect other portions this is
also what gives it that very fuzzy like
appearance because you literally have
these like tree leaf branch-like things
that occur
and here we see the canadian infecting
the fruit or infecting the flowers
causing more infection
causing those to develop into
candiospores and
going through and mycelium going through
infecting causing repeated infections
and in areas of high humidity which are
typically in cannabis late in the season
this just encourages this perpetuation
of this life cycle
so how do you go about managing this
well high humidity 90 plus
for 12 hours or greater is very
favorable for botrytis development
physical damage can also increase odds
of detritus getting an initial start
remove all trimmings and prune plant
material off-site
away from the plants as they may contain
potential residual spores
if identified in the area remove the
infected plant material and then apply a
control product
since this is commonly seen late in the
growing season be aware
of potential residuals and current and
local regulations for any product you're
considering applying
also once identified you may want to
harvest sooner rather than later to
ensure you get a good some clean plant
material
because some harvest is better than none
now let's take a look
at a bud rot that i was able to identify
in a late
in the late season of a cannabis crop
now suddenly we're going through
investigating this is something we don't
want to see
so here we see a bud that's getting
close to finishing
but on this side here we see the
evidence of some bud rot
this is typically caused by a species of
botrytis
and this can spread very easily once you
get in one area to other parts of the
plant
as well as other plants that you may
have increasing air circulation and
trying to reduce the amount of moisture
that's kept in there
by sometimes just removing some of the
leaves here and trying to increase
that chance that maybe some natural sun
could get in there um can all help
things as well
but you can see kind of once it gets
into an area it can spread very easily
so this is something we want to be
scouting for
if we do see it removing it as soon as
possible and in monitoring areas
in and around this one particular bud
here you can see this plant compared to
some of the others we've seen
a little bit more stress a little bit
more nutrient deficient we see some more
yelling to the leaves
it could be for a variety of reasons but
a little bit more stressed
and sure enough that's the plant that
has one of the buds at least
that is starting to show this bud rot so
worth inspecting the entire plant