okay here i'm going to go over an
introduction to biology and how to be
successful so you're not feeling like
this cat
[Music]
so looking at biology i don't want you
simply to memorize that's what a
textbook is for and
as a reference what i want to be able to
do is to look at something determine hey
this is a normal quote healthy leaf
how can we work with that information
that we may gain
looking at this leaf we can see what
makes it different people might say it's
brown but
noticing the brown is kind of located in
a certain region so being a little bit
more specific and
looking at seeing what that tells us
this all goes back to being able to
problem solve being able to take a
situation and
figure it out even if it takes a couple
tries now while there's many educational
resources
available hoping that you choose wisely
and
found this channel and continue to look
at some of the other videos here on
debaco
university now what makes tobacco
university so great is
anytime anywhere you can access it
breakfast
dinner snack time nighttime daytime it
doesn't matter it's accessible for you
and when you're watching some of the
content you always want to ask yourself
how can i apply what i have
learned i can teach how all the pieces
of chess move but
how do they interact and how can you
put a game together and that's what this
is looking forward to
producing as i said this is less of a
concern of the actual process that you
go through
we have to watch videos once or twice or
look at subtitles
i'm more concerned with the final
product to kind of grade the ability the
problem solving to work with the
information
not necessarily how you go about
learning the information at least
initially
this working with the information is
great for long-term memory retention and
that's kind of the intention and goal
here
is to be able to not just remember for
the test but remember for the
longer term some of the topics that
we're going to be going over
in biology are kind of broken apart by
quarter here
we have everything from biology
fundamentals to kind of cells
in dna and then we get into kind of
a progression of evolution plants and
animals and lastly we
end with body systems so hopefully you
have a lot of learning to come in the
future
[Music]
you