okay here a little bit about how we
learn in things how do we process
information how do we go through a
problem I work together to solve a
solution or how do we look at a
situation it might be ever-changing how
do we maximize our returns there so
thinking is allowed in this section here
in particular so first off looking at
how we learn in thankful our brain is
where most this action occurs and
consists of billions of interconnected
neurons our senses to a specific neuron
pathways we have something called
short-term memory which is residual
sensitivity pathways and they have
long-term memory which is physical
changes that may occur and long-term
memory can cause by repeated stimulation
intense emotion sensory input in memory
storage share the same circuits and it's
causes associations to occur so you'll
find a lot in the slides that I provide
here there's pictures produced the
pictures here so you can kind of try to
make associations in connections to
hopefully take something a topic that
might be new to you that might just go
into the short-term memory and try to
make it a little bit more longer-lasting
in your memory
so how II know things well our brains
are gated two major things recognizing
patterns and filling in sensory gaps
through typically through the process of
storytelling so you can see there's a
different pattern here just as here
there's a pattern we can look at this
pattern determine what comes next
so take a look here for a second
determine what comes next
well if you said a green rectangle you'd
be correct let's do this again for this
pattern what comes next
if you said yellow star you'd be correct
and lastly what comes next here if you
said blue square you would be correct so
you can see it were able to quickly
recognize and identify these patterns
however want to be careful because this
can get us into trouble
through pattern matching record we could
recognize patterns that may not be real
or misinterpreted or we could not
patterns that are real so we're looking
at developing patterns while we're very
good at doing that want to make sure
that we're not have matching a pattern
that may not exist there for
storytelling
not checking to see if stories are true
could be an issue
80% personal disagreements are between
people that begin as wrong stories each
has told himself about the other's
motivations so you get into this like he
said she said type things so you want to
make sure when you're doing storytelling
that you're able to fact-checked
certain things you want to just go off
rumors in hearsay in science we're
looking at testing our patterns and
stories we typically do this ooh a
variation of the scientific method where
we have observations that lead iPod this
is allow us to test our hypothesis that
then through analysis observations we
can modify that Baathists go through
more observations this is what we tend
to get into this kind of circle here if
you have observations that lead to
questions those questions and hopefully
hypothesis that we can test we
experiment analyze we draw a conclusion
and we do more observations which leads
to more questions and so on and so forth
so we kind of have this kind of
revolving kind of circle here doesn't
known as you have interloop in internal
loops that occur here the key part here
in science in general is to stay
inquisitive to keep asking questions to
keep trying to find something else to
develop some conclusions but also
develop some more questioning as you go
through and do some more observations
specifically for studying relating this
to class three hours of study at one
time is not effective for long-term
memory information staying the same
thing 20 minutes three times a day for
three days is more effective for
long-term memory formation so we don't
want to focus on there's a lot of the
topics we're going to go over we're
going to come back and relate to and I'm
going to assume that you know down when
we first went over them using your brain
to B phase or reworked material is more
effective for long-term memory formation
then repetitive reading or listening so
the effective as these video lectures
may be for listening and repetitive over
I'm sure you can rephrase and rework the
information hopefully we're able to do
more of that in class they're able to
develop that more long-term memory
implication
for the material that we go over we keep
in mind cram studying for three hours a
night before the test is not as
effective saying the same thing for 20
minutes three times a day for three days
is much more effective hopefully you're
able to plan ahead and do some of that
throughout this course