well this is entirely titled how
scientists think it's important to
realize that scientists do think a
little differently and I'll have their
different kind of ways to approach
things this is kind of how science is
thinking or how scientists approach
certain problems or issues and how that
kind of can look so let's investigate
this little further so as scientists
same kind of two main ways we have
deductive reasoning which involves
telling stories based on patterns this
uses accepted general principles as a
guide to explain specific observations
it starts out more general and
progresses to become more specific the
example would be all humans are mortal
Albert Einstein is human therefore
Einstein is mortal using this deductive
reasoning pattern it's forming a general
theory of explanation based on specific
observations that have been made
previously deductive reasoning here
opposite this would be inductive
reasoning so what's in depth reasoning
well this is recognizing patterns this
uses by scientists develop hypothesis
about how the world works start with a
specific observation and progresses to a
broader generalizations and theories
again what's an example of how this may
look well poll shows that 75% of
students at school X take the bus to
school
harren goes to school apps therefore
Aaron probably takes the bus to school
this is an example of inductive
reasoning making a specific prediction
based on a general principle believed to
be true inductive reasoning so how do
these kind of two compare well if you
look above here we can see that the
deductive reasoning for general
principles inductive reasons based more
on observations now for conclusion wise
conclusion is more special than
information and premise provide this is
reached directly by applying logical
rules to the Pradas that's deductive
reasoning inductively knows these more
general information that the premise
provides it's reached by a
generalization of the premise of
information
validity and deductive reasoning it must
be true for India the reasoning it's
probably true as we saw the example
there was 75 percent of students taking
the bus so we're assuming it's probably
true that Aaron takes the bus because we
have 75 percent of students taking the
bus lhasa first usage deductive
reasoning is using one leads facts that
are definitely true in that the reason
using evidence instead of proven facts
helps support that conclusion that's
reached so just a quick comparison
between deductive and inductive
reasoning which is you'd see how
scientists intend to take a little bit
more of this inductive reasoning
approach now because we don't know
everything we can't be 100% sure of
everything that would be comment to the
deductive reasoning process