in this debaco university student series
video we're going to go over how to set
up a digital timer for your growing
operation so if you're a little confused
exactly what all those buttons do
hopefully this will provide you with the
explanation so you can utilize it to its
greatest effectiveness
[Music]
hi today we're going to be showing you
how to set up a digital timer so that
you could automate your grow by using
this timer to time your pumps or your
lights
so this is what you will see when you
open up your digital timer it's a little
different from the mechanical timer as
you can see we have a few more buttons
we have the ability to adjust the day of
the week the hour the minute and even
the second this is our reset button
to set the time you hold down this clock
button and hit hour well first i'd want
to change the day of the week to reflect
that it is thursday so i'd hit clock and
week until it hits thursday
then while still holding clock i would
change the hour
to 4 pm
still holding clock i'm going to change
the minutes
over to
4.
20 pm
now to set when we want our
our
lights to come on and off we're going to
hit program the first one is when we
want our lights to turn on
so
like how we were setting up our clock
we're gonna hit the hour button
i want mine to turn on at midnight
so again just those same buttons for the
hour and minute to adjust
and then to set for when you want
the lights to turn off you hit program
again
and do the same thing i want to set it
for 6 pm the lights turn off if you hold
down it'll make it go faster
now once you're done setting the on and
off time you can hit clock again you
want to make sure that it says auto on
the bottom down here
since that's the only way this timer
will automatically turn your lights on
and off you have the option
for on which keeps them on constantly
or off which turns them off constantly
you want auto so that it reflects the
timing that you just set
once you're done programming your
schedule you're going to want to make
sure
that the timer says auto on it that will
make sure that it'll perform to the
hours that you set it to
you could also
turn it on so that it is on constantly
or off so that the lights are off
constantly
you