welcome to this debaco university video
where i'm going to cover how to set up a
grow tent for cannabis production
i'm going to walk you through the
process that i went through to set up
this
sun hut grow tent uh the big and easy
i'll kind of walk you through the
process starting with taking everything
out of the package here
and setting it up that ultimately
received the canvas plan so hope you
enjoy
this video
[Music]
here we'll be setting up the sun systems
big and easy
grow tent this size here is two feet by
four feet
and we're going to see how easy it is to
assemble
all right and here we're looking at the
instructions so always good to
have these handy look at them ahead of
time make sure you get your parts list
make sure you have some idea of assembly
and in this case make sure you have the
right grow tent instructions that you're
following
so there's those list of materials now
here is them all
here they all are spread out just
checking to make sure
we have everything before we begin so
now we're not missing anything which can
be a very frustrating part of the
process but luckily here everything was
present
okay i've organized that with the bottom
being down on this end
and this area here is the top also i've
taken all the poles out
and you can see that they're nicely
organized
so these are all my number ones
to the number twos and then over here
i've put my
number threes also so this keeps
everything nice and organized
i'm going through and simply following
the instructions here
for the 2x4 size okay so what i did is i
went through
attached all the corners there opened up
the whole bottom
fit it right in you'll notice this is
the top all unzipped so a little messy
right now
but we're gonna work on building the
upper sections so that we can start to
have the grow tent
come together okay working on installing
the upper ones here
start giving it some height
there's the base building up here on the
vertical
need to put one of these connectors
insert that
right on top of there taking our next
bowl number three
putting it in there to get us to our
near final height now
go through and we'll do the rest so i've
gone through and attached these
here after we attach those you can see
we're
putting on the other bars and slowly
forming
the rest of the structure so now we've
got the basic frame for the entire
structure built
the way up supporting at the top now we
just have to take the covering
and put it over the supporting structure
so now for the most part it's all
assembled key part is you want to make
sure that all the corners are nice and
snug
and tight to give it a nice structure
and support
there now we got a couple more things to
do but
kind of the hardest and most struggle
part is done
okay so when we're installing the
vertical supports we want to make sure
we have these
in the down position you can see here
and then we're running the other support
ones in this way in the up position
what this allows is this overlap to
occur
so that when we're gonna hang something
between our such as our lights and
carbon filter
creates a much stronger uh structure
here
so again organizing your upper supports
correctly
can help ensure that you can hang some
weight off it and everything will hold
together just fine
so at the bottom of the grow tent make
sure we install this in liner to catch
any water that might spill out
just simply just hold it twice right
here and go through and attach it with
velcro to the poles here tape this
inside to keep everything nice
and contained in case we do have some
water leaking out it will not leave the
grow tent and spill those surrounding
area
so on this grow tent there's a screen
here a fine mesh screen for ventilation
it's also a viewing area they also make
these velcro
reflective mylar pieces at one place to
block that out if we want to you can
help seal that up
right there allow us to open it later if
we want
i also have great ports here for
power exhaust fans so we can also
through
inside if we look i also have the
ability to kind of seal those up here
this is that screen port that we just
blocked off and this will have an
area we can pull tight when we install
our cords
and here's our finally assembled grow
tent recommends it to people
be a little easier at times or two but i
did it with just one person
so it is possible you can kind of see at
least how initially
the general setup looks in here and
looking good this route and adding a
couple more um
options to it so they can support some
plants
for growing it's nice about the 2x4 size
fits right through a doorway so if
you're going through and put it in one
area and go into another
it'll go right through a standard door
as we have here
without need for disassembly
you