while precisely diagnosing a problem may
not always be possible
this debaco university video intends to
help you classify
problems of cannabis plants in general
categories so you can better direct your
efforts
to reduce their negative impact on your
plants
[Music]
all right let's get into how to classify
a problem with cannabis plants
so while many things can go wrong the
goal is to try to classify the issue to
help the diagnosis process along
with the potential corrective action to
be taken the main categories covered
will be
biotic and abiotic under biotic or
living diseases and insects
abiotic will look at nutrients spray
products moisture temperature
as well as physical damage so starting
with biotic probiotic is again living
these typically refers to a broad range
of disease insects or
animals while biotic means living
viruses are typically included within
this group
you'd also consider fungi bacteria
protists animals
archaea all these are classifying our
biotic factors
now disease is probably the most obvious
one that most people go to here we see
some powdery mildew getting started
diseases can have varying degrees of
impact depending on the variety being
grown in some cases but not always
some varieties may have different levels
of resistance to some disease especially
when the pressure is
low or when it initially comes in
diseases also tend to spread over time
with the rate being impacted by how
favorable the environment
is for that particular disease then
there's also insects here we see some
aphids on the underside of this cannabis
leaf
insects can have hatches meaning their
numbers can increase drastically
in a very short period of time scout
scouting the
shadier portions of the plant is a good
starting point controlling insects is
important as some particularly aphids
pictured here can vector diseases and
viruses as well
then we get to some abiotic factors so
these are non-living factors that can
impact plant growth and development
typically the rate and extent of damage
of plants is uniform across varieties
as also ages of the plant abiotic issues
tend
not to slowly spread but occur kind of
at a point in time
it could be a drastic change in
temperature sunlight
climate humidity things like that so
let's start with
nutrients looking at nutrients to begin
with note that these can be impacted by
ph as well as concentration
being able to recognize deficiencies is
important but at the same time
understanding how much to feed the plant
is key to avoid potential nutrient
toxicities
which often times with cannabis tends to
be more of an issue keeping records and
following manufacturers suggestions are
both good
starting points to ensure you're not
going into the toxic range
or the deficient range when it comes to
nutrients
then we get to spray products growers
may have to apply control products to
their
leaves this can offer very efficient
and efficient effective coverage but at
the same time it can risk damaging
tender leaf surfaces
particularly your newer leaves watch the
concentration
method and timing of your application
you want to avoid forceful applications
at high light intensity times as well
to reduce the chance of getting sort of
grower induced spray damage to your
particular leaves
then we have moisture to consider so
growers tend to over water their plants
and this reduces aeration within the
root zone
since plants roots need oxygen or over
watering can cause plants to drown
and also cause stunting of plants
underwatering though can cause wilting
which if caught early can be corrected
and remember a plant's water demands
will change
as it ages so as it gets older more loot
more roots
larger top structure the demand or the
amount of irrigation it will require
is going to be greater then we get to
temperature so when we're looking at
different temperatures
more is not better the goal is to keep
plants in a natural
daily rise and fall of temperatures
extremes will cause plant stresses
while outdoor environment regulation of
this may not be possible
other measures such as increased
irrigation frequency or potential use of
shade netting
should be considered when possible to
reduce plant stresses in an outdoor
environment
also keeping an idea of the high and low
temperature
uh the humidity as well kind of that 24
hour monitor
is a great suggestion temperatures above
nine degrees fahrenheit below 55 degrees
fahrenheit will be outside the
acceptable range and will hinder plant
performance overall lastly
we get to physical damage and this may
be easy to say but be careful around
plants especially when pruning and also
scouting
and also transporting some growers
simply are just tougher on their plants
than others so be mindful if you're one
of those growers it just has a heavy
hand
when transporting plants this can cause
damage to the branches maybe as we can
see here
and try to implement and reduce the
chance of that impact has on the plant
if growing outdoors wind can also cause
physical damage so be sure to provide
plant supports
if your plants will be growing in a
large size where this may be a likely
source of damage
hopefully this allows you to generally
classify potential problems you might be
seeing with your plant
then you can further refine a more
specific diagnosis
once you have the proper category
determined and hopefully this video here
in tobacco university
helped you categorize your problems