in this debacco University collaboration
video with Shane from migro we'll be
investigating how light spectrum can
impact plants looking at Spectrum versus
yield as well as Spectrum versus canabo
production as well as a few other common
questions so I hope you
[Music]
enjoy so welcome we've got Shane here
from migro and we're going to be
discussing a topic that I know gets a
lot of attention and that's Spectrum
when it comes to plant production and
optimizing those spectrums we're seeing
new lighting technology come out with
all sorts of dials and options on it to
modify and change blue light red light
and different kind of ratios between
those so we're going to get into a
little bit more of the details here
we've got Shane to help us provide us
some background for that so looking
Shane as we're looking at our optimizing
Spectrum how does this change as the
plant grows you do we want to give the
plants the same thing the whole time do
do we want to modify things how how
would we modify it as that plant goes
from that early stage through the veg
into flowering
phase I suppos useful to put a bit of
perspective here and a few reference
points for people with regard to
Spectrum so we take grow sunlight
Spectrum what plants have evolved um to
work with you know to absorb um sunlight
Spectrum has about 25% blue and then
about um equally just close to 40% uh
green and red in terms of its overall
composition there is of course UVB UVA
and far red in that Spectrum as well but
we have established through
experimentation that that for efficient
photosynthesis really plants only really
absorb the par range which is
efficiently which is from 400 to to 700
nanometers there is a little bit uh of
photosynthesis happening at at the
Beyond um that range that part range uh
but um it is the most efficient within
that range in terms of looking at at the
effect on plant shape and development
and quality then um as we said before uh
in previous videos blue is very
important in terms of regulating plant
height particularly for indoor Growers
so having at least a minimum amount of
three or 4% blue is essential to have
short and dense growth an absence of
blue will have very tall stretchy plants
um so having a high proportion of blue
is is critical however in terms of
modern lighting technology grow lighting
technology most Growers these days are
using LEDs and LEDs so if you take for
example even a a relatively uh warm um
color spectrum so something in the the
color temperature range of of say 2,000
two and a half thousand um we we would
you would still have uh around seven or
8% blue um even even in that relatively
warm spectrum and that's plenty for
short and dense growth and typically
grite manufacturers these days have a
mixed color temperature because they're
using H cool white and warm white LEDs
together and often um 660 nanometer or
deep red LEDs as well all those combined
together usually result in a color
temperature of about 35,000 K and this
uh has a percentage blue of about 12 or
four 12 to 14% so plenty for short and
dense growth again as we just discussed
before there is um green the proportion
of green and red really is um is not
critical in terms of of um the plant
shape um they are fairly neutral in
terms of of how that plant is going to
develop there is an argument um for that
again we covered this before about using
far red for example at the early stages
of growth far red can um increase the
leaf size in Plants um but I think those
that that benefit is marginal and
limited um and often with these things
it's a compromise so you do one thing
and it'll affect something else so using
too much far red you will get tall
stretched stretchy plans so in summary
in terms of the modern tech that we have
which is white LEDs mixed with 660 nanm
red they are really very close to what
we would want as an Optimum uh to
deliver efficient rate of
photosynthesis and develop healthy
plants which are short and dense it's
one of the main characteristics we want
um and um and as we said previously
under white light we can visually
inspect them and see them clearly
so look at these uh spectrums in these
Spectrum recipes that we have have
access to you know dialing in literally
um how's this compared to like uh
sunlight know you touched on some of the
the percentages you know why don't we
just kind of if we have the option why
don't we just set all the dials to
basically sunlight and kind of leave it
at that why should we bother nessing and
pushing or you know changing things why
it just we got the option make it
sunlight that's what plants are used to
and just kind of leave it at that what
the advantage of going through and
optimizing our Spectrum yeah so so we
absolutely could we could have so for
example white LEDs and we could add far
red LEDs and we could add UVA LEDs and
even UVB
LEDs um to um to mimic the sun Spectrum
as as close as we possibly could however
it would cost a lot more to do so so um
from a couple of points first of all the
UVA LEDs and UVB LEDs uh are more
expensive than the white ones in terms
of the amount of photons you get per
watt and the dollars per watt that
you're spending on those LEDs in the
first
instance um and secondarily they're not
as photosynthetically efficient so they
don't
contribute um as efficiently to
photosynthesis as um as our wh a range
of our par range so on two fronts you're
spending more up front on the fixture
cost and then secondarily you're going
going to cost more in electricity terms
um to provide these um these wavelengths
which are not necessarily beneficial to
the uh the mass of plant who are
producing so the rate of growth and the
the yield that we're going to ultimately
get or the quality of the um the produce
that we're going to come out with in the
end so not shown you know changing your
color temperature for example changing
the proportion of blue is is is not
shown to change the um the percentage of
cannaboids or the potency of cannabis um
and it's not really shown to have much
of a any other qualitative effect so
really if you want to grow as much as
possible um stay within the efficient
par spectrum and luckily that coincides
with theyd the cheaper photons to
produce uh and the cheaper fixture cost
to purchase in the first
they're kind of along the lines of just
because we can doesn't mean we should
type thing really taking that maximum
efficiency there um so kind of taking
the sunlight using that as a gauge but
then narrowing it down to really what
the plants are utilizing from all that
light that they're essentially exposed
to they just touched on this before
we've got previous videos on the par
things like that so just going over just
a little bit more when we're looking at
this efficient Spectrum uh comes back
again I think to to par again so if you
just kind of reiterate just for everyone
what that par is and kind of where that
efficiency lies in our lighting that is
going to produce the most of our plants
as efficiently as possible yeah so um as
a scientist called McCree developed the
McCree curve um which is still used
today and it is h a it was experiments
were done to look at the effect of
different wavelength of light on the
rate of photosynthesis in Plants um and
this was done for for a wide range of
plants under different conditions and it
was shown that again the the most
photosynthesis happens with the in the
power range between 400 and 700 there is
a trail off or a tail off on on each end
so UVA does cause cause it somewhat
although it reduces as you go into
shorter wave length and far red causes
photosynthesis as well um that within
the par
range um red is considered to be the
most photos photosynthetically efficient
um blue is the next most
photosynthetically efficient and green
the last but there is not a huge
difference between them and as we've
said before it is um you do need a
proportion of blue in that Spectrum so
we need a certain amount of it to get
the right plant shape and with green it
may not be as photosynthetically
efficient in in in narrow terms but in
terms the whole plant photosynthesis
green penetrates deeper into the leaves
so it gets to uh cells which other um
which which blue or red photons wouldn't
reach and green green photons also
Bounce Around the canopies so get to
parts of the plant that um green and red
photons wouldn't reach so having that
mix of blue green green and red leads to
a a more efficient uh system overall in
terms of the lighting
efficiency and also the the overall rate
of photosynthesis of the plant yeah
thanks for providing that uh that
breakdown of those important you know
wavelengths so hopefully no one's you
know setting your dials to sunlight or
setting a color wavelength to zero
probably not the most efficient
utilizing that and kind of work on that
recipe as we would for new s working on
that recipe for Optimum lighting
Spectrum also plays into the efficiency
of plant production do all come back to
par um does all come back to kind of
this greater understanding hopefully the
new scientific research that will
continue to come out uh I want to thank
you Shane again for um for migro for
participating in this giving us some
background giving us some insight uh for
this little short series here uh links
comments everything down in the
description I encourage every to check
those out let us know know if you like a
video let us know if you like a topic
let us know if you want to hear about a
different topic all here this is our
goal is to provide you with some good
scientific based information so Shane
thank you very much again you have any
last words you're welcome to contribute
them but I want to just thank you for
the information you provided both to me
as well as our viewers well thank you
very much for having on your channel
just for viewers please check out the
debacco university Channel um a lot of
fascinating uh information on there um
plenty of in topics uh really well
presented and um well worth checking out
and subscribing
to the great C collaboration mro's links
will be in the description as well thank
you Shane very much for this and
hopefully we can do some going forward
in the future as well appreciate it take
care