okay here i'm going to describe why if
you're going snorkeling it's easier to
hold your breath
after you inhale a bunch of air than
after you exhale here at tobacco
[Music]
university
now why is it easier to hold your breath
after your inhalation than after
exhalation
well this actually is because your body
cannot detect low oxygen levels
could only sense high carbon dioxide
levels
your brain actually uses blood carbon
dioxide levels as an indicator
for blood oxygen models so when carbon
dioxide levels are too high
you're signaled to take a breath at that
point
now as you can see here in the whales
they're taking a breath before they're
descending they're filling their
lungs full of oxygen and this is why the
suit allows them disease to emerge
for long periods of time
you