ever wonder how to go about selecting
the correct grow tent for cannabis
production
well here at tobacco university we're
going to walk you through that process
all right if you decided on a grow tent
it's going to be your environment
let's go through how to choose the right
one and what to look for
so first off there's many grow 10
options it's important to kind of
realize and that's going to be a good
thing
reason for all the options is a variety
of location that growers use
them for there's three main categories
and that is grow tint kits where you
could purchase something that comes all
inclusive and all together
there's multi-chamber grow tents where
there's different isolated components
within the general
structure and there's just a standard or
single chamber
grow tent and we'll walk you through
those examples here so first off the
grow tent kits you know there's
many different kits out there many
different options
many different kind of setups to fit
different needs by different growers
so they're ideal for someone who wants
to get started right away with a system
that works and doesn't require
much research or attention they're often
sold by the type of light that they
utilize
and that can be included and have a
large impact on the total price
while there's a lot of other little
pieces of equipment usually the light is
the driving force and the
main overall cost kits often include the
tent itself
a grow light a ventilation system
growing substrate whether it's soilless
or hydroponic
and a basic collection of general
accessories that would be needed
the focus here is to learn how to select
a setup that best fits your specific
growing situation so these kits are an
option
but will not be the focus of this video
going to come all included
essentially the information provided
will help you customize your own
specific kit
for your needs or if you're looking at
certain kits these are certain features
you might want to look at and seek out
so you're ensuring you're getting one
that's going to work
well for you right off the initial
purchase
so going to the multi-chambered grow
tents
and just as the name implies they have
multiple chambers
they are intended for very space limited
growers
and they do offer at least ideally a
perpetual grow harvest
by being able to isolate all different
stages of the growing cycle
in one tent propagation the vegetative
stage
and also the potential for flowering
some may even have a clone chamber or a
mother room as depicted right here
another better suit for entry-level
growers not looking to produce total
yield in general and using separate
tents can offer
better overall control conditions and
allow for more plants so these will be
what's focused on
in this series but realize that these
multi-chamber ones do exist
keep in mind though you do self-delight
each one have good ventilation for each
one keep them isolated so you're not
getting cross-contamination or
light spill over from either so again
this is why these multi-chamber ones a
little bit better for your smaller
operations
the standard or the single chamber grow
tents of course these will be the main
focus
you can always add more tents to get
isolated conditions so instead of having
them all have multi
chambers you can just simply have more
tents and then isolate them that way i
have a flower tent have a veg tent if a
mother or propagation tent
can separate them out that way so where
will you be putting
the tent this is a good question just to
ask yourself in general regardless you
want to measure the area
usually at least twice to make sure you
didn't get anything wrong and get an
idea of the natural environmental
conditions
will you be needing to heat the area
more we need to cool the area more what
will be important to you
and keep in mind that if the area is a
little on the cooler side
if you're going to be running certain
lights or high intense lights
you may be heating the area sufficiently
with just the light source
common growing locations are a large
room a closet garage a shed even in
attic
but there are many other options even
beyond this so again you want to get an
idea of what environment
you're generally going to be putting the
tent into so that then leads to the next
question
and this is where all the growers
configure is bigger always but what size
grow tent are you looking for
you want to start with the square feet
of floor space the amount of plants that
are grown can be dependent on pruning
style
and total size of each below some
general idea of the average sized plants
provided as a guide
so you're looking at a four by two tent
you can get two to three plants
four by four tent four to five four foot
by eight foot six to eight and ten by
ten about twelve plants
then you also wanna be considering the
total height
so just because you're looking at the
square footage you also want to be
considerate of how tall
um what type of ceiling you have are you
feeling limited
how tall can you go can you get a tent
that's a little bit taller a little bit
street when it's a little bit shorter
so other than just a square foot you
also want to be considerate
of the height of your space because that
will dictate the height of the
how tall the tent can be as well so how
tall you go for your tent well the best
center is really as tall as you can fit
in your area you know they all look the
same if you're looking at them online or
in pictures you want to make sure to
tell us
it can fit in your area the reason for
this is it'll allow for more light
hanging adjustment options the plants
can be bigger if you need them to be
and there's more room for air
circulation as well some come at fixed
sites some allow extensions so again
what's the best fit for your particular
area once you've measured it
then when we're looking at looking up
anyway we want to be looking at the
ceiling support
many grow tents have a ceiling support
bars that allow for multiple options
running lights filters
fans while also bringing structural
support to the actual structure itself
so it's good to see
if there is good or adequate ceiling
support
because you're going to be hanging a lot
typically off this area so it's a sign
that you have a good quality
uh tent there lower temp vents uh in
access having
vents on the lower side of the tent can
help ensure cool air is drawn into the
crow
tent if possible if you're looking for
that passive ventilation system
in for the small and large access ports
it will draw
with drawstrings as we can see right
here this is a large one this is a small
one
those drawstrings help seal the growing
air environment this not only will
reduce a light splash but also carbon
dioxide links if you are
leaks or if you are looking at going
through and enriching the area
while there's still reason why you would
have these in the first place is you
want access to power cords
ventilation systems all these are going
to be components that you're going to
want to be adding to your grow space
and you always don't want to have them
going out kind of the main zipper or the
main outlining door this asks for a very
clean and neat installation process
now the upper vents we're looking
towards again the top of the tent those
multiple vents of different sizes offer
growers a lot more flexibility
there can also be a close so if there's
no real negative having more
at least initially need but then
initially needed by the grower meaning
here we see three vents you're like i
never need three events well you can
simply just
pull the drawstring seal up and no
problem there is a point in time where
you do need all three maybe an intake
an exhaust and some power will you have
that opportunity so there's no real
downfall if you're comparing two tenths
and everything's equal
one is a couple more uh vent options
here
uh typically go with the one as more
even if you don't initially need them
it'll allow you to kind of
uh be future proof for your structure
and lastly there are many manufacturers
so ideally all serve the same function
but there are some specifics to look for
i'm looking for what the type of the
frame is made out of
a strong frame at that because you need
to support lights fans filters and many
other
things the reflective material on the
inside
a tear resistant material on the outside
would be great a quality zipper
double floor to prevent water leaks
outside the tent because you will be
watering even if you have catch fans as
we see
here all these are worthwhile to
consider there's other videos on this
channel that will get into some of the
manufacturers some of the comparison so
you're welcome also to check that video
out
here on debaco university