in this debaco university video we're
going to attempt to
give you some information regarding two
spotted spider mites
on cannabis plants
all right let's get into how to identify
and control two spotted spider mites on
cannabis plants
so first off the general description of
them and this is kind of gives you an
idea what they look like when you zoom
in
a little bit more of a zoomed out
approach just to show you how small that
they are
they are a type of arachnid so the term
spiders rightfully sell
as they are related to insects they are
very thin at about 1 150th of an inch
long so they are small
yellow to orange in color with two dark
spots one on each side of your body
which is evident clearly when you are
able to zoom in
and a 30x kind of jewelers loop is
recommended so you can be able to zoom
in on the plants
so you can be able to see or identify
them much easier
when heavy infestations occur webbing on
the plants can also be present
which a water mist may help visualize if
you go through and kind of like take a
light mist and kind of miss the plants
you might be able to see that fine
droplets of water
attached to their webs which make it
easier to identify where they might be
located and where you should be spending
time
scouting and investigating your plants
so that identification what are we
looking at here well that webbing occurs
when high numbers become established the
goal is to first identify them
when the leaf flecking initially occurs
this is kind of what we're talking about
that kind of like initially looks like
someone went through and just scraped
off
tops of the leaves because they are kind
of that feeding insect that's what we're
going to notice
initially positive id may require that
30x loop as i mentioned earlier
that lens if you can get it with an led
all the better because it really allows
you to shine a bright light
to a small area to make identification
of the plants visually
much much easier you can also shake the
leaves over a piece of clean cardboard
to help you detect their presence
because they will be knocked off and
land on the cardboard as i mentioned
when they become
well established you get this definitely
kind of marking of the
leaf surface here that leaf reflecting
also have that webbing of course this is
an advanced stage once
when there are much lower numbers this
web will be much thinner and that water
mist will help
you visualize that so how do you go
about managing two-spotted spider mites
well in general they
are very difficult to manage
so this is want to be mindful of being
very preventative
in limiting their numbers as much as you
can certain species of lady beetles uh
and predatory mites
naturally control two spotters two
spotted spider mites
at least when they're present in low
numbers and that speaks again to the
importance of keeping spider mite
numbers as low as possible
using long lasting pesticides like by
ethereum or
prethrins kill natural enemies and
should be avoided and encourage
the natural enemies to help regulate the
population if you're using soaps or
horticultural oils
that shows some effectiveness to ensure
greater efficiency be sure to apply them
to the underside of the leaves
well make sure you're getting a good
coating of that and also getting the top
sides that's usually the easier portion
of the plant to get
and also you may need to make repeated
applications of these products
to get some sort of effective control
but keep scouting for them be mindful of
any new plant material you bring
in because you definitely want to avoid
these within your cannabis plants