on this debaco university video we'll go
over how to properly flush
cannabis plants
[Music]
ever wondered how to properly flush a
cannabis plant we're going to go over
some of the specifics
here in this video so first off
this information was provided here by
this thesis
so you're welcome to take a look at it
here this doctoral
dissertation if you will so great
information provided in there
only a brief summary of that will be
provided here on this video lecture
so first off flushing in general so
typically at the end of the flowering
cycle prior to harvest the root zone of
cannabis plants will be
watered with plain water that does not
contain any additives such as fertilizer
fertigated water is water that contains
nutrients so given minus these
regular water with no nutrients added
depending on the substrate the plant is
being grown in will dictate the duration
of the flushing period how many days
how much water will be added and the
goal here is to kind of take those
nutrients that might be kind of all
bound up
in that area and adding a lot of water
can kind of
cause them to be flushed out or removed
from that root zone and that will
dilute that plant there and create more
of just
express the plant or allow the plant to
have more of its just natural
cannabinoids and profiles in there
without having the necessarily the
chance of having any of the nutrients
and fertilizers held in that final
product
so flushing specifics looking at in
relation to the study
flushing occurred over the last two
weeks of production when the nutrient
solution was replaced with clear water
during routine
irrigation events so a lot of growers
will add fertilizer to their water
well in this case water was still added
but no nutrients were added to that
water
another flushing method was applied to
an additional 10 liters of water without
any fertilizer to the plant
over two irrigation events at the start
of a two week period of clear water
irrigation and then clear water is just
again no fertilizer being added
that's what this study was looking at in
part so here are the specific treatments
we can see them all listed here control
treatment with 10 liters
initial flush completed twice of
non-fertigated water until harvest
then another control treatment was
without 10 liters of an initial flush
and non-brigade water until harvest so
one they did
add an extra irrigation event and then
continued with just plain water
here they did not use that additional
flushing
irrigation event there then they had two
mild stress treatments
they called with uh non-fertigated water
until harvest
and then one was with fertigated water
until harvest for a comparison
then the moderate stress ones were uh
treatments with non-frigate water until
harvest and then treat with fertigate
water
and to harvest there and the durations
that they went through and did this
were kind of part of that mild and
moderate stress so the control treatment
was considered to be the standard for
the facility
to control which is what normally
happens with irrigation occurring events
for the plants occurring every
two to three days mild stress was
irrigation applied every two days
and then moderate stress was irrigation
applied every three days
so here we can see that's how you're
getting that mild stress even though the
treatment was basically the same
the amount that it was applied was
different that does put a moderate
stress on the plants when you're
watering only every three days
so when we've got that bud dry yield for
flower
so i'm only presenting grass here that
show statistic difference
note that there was determined to be no
significant difference in the flowering
of the whole plant dry flower in cycle 1
or the bud dry flower and cycle 3. what
was different here in cycle 2 and they
did multiple replications of this
dry bud mass was measured after the
drying period by removing
all the buds from the plant the control
treatment was significantly different
from the mild and moderate stress
treatments
as we can see here dry blood mass was
definitely more
in those control treatments compared to
the mild and moderate stress
remember the mild moderate stress we're
also looking at the changes
in irrigation frequency now
important components when we're talking
about cannabis we'll be looking at the
example here would be the thc percent
percent by mass for the flower note
there was it was determined to be no
significant difference in the following
being the tg presented by mass and
flowering cycle one as well as cycle
three
here the percent in cycle sorry cycle
two and cycle three
what was different was the thc percent
by mass for cycle
one the thc percent was significantly
different
in the mild stress treatment so here
we're seeing the thc by mass
was the same in both the control and
moderate stress
in this example the mild stress actually
caused a reduction
on the percent of thc by mass there so
kind of an interesting note
now the essential analysis of buds for
the three flowering cycles this kind of
brings that general summary here and i
tried to stack them right on top of one
another here
you're welcome to pause the video and
look at this in more detail
solving cycle one elemental analysis of
bud after flushing
shows a percentage of concentration by
mass of the nutrients
within the dry bud era bars represent
standard error
there's no significant difference
between any of the treatments in all
size
so if you're kind of looking through and
saying oh where are the differences
between these
really as far as the researchers go they
determine there's no significant
difference between any of the treatments
looking at the control the mild stress
flushed the mild stress
no flush moderate stress flush moderate
stress no flush
looking at the different flowering
cycles looking at the percent nitrogen
sulfur phosphorus potassium magnesium
and calcium
no significant differences across any of
these very important note there
people always want to see a difference
in their treatments but in this case no
difference
is also an important result
so it's also we're looking here looking
at the water reduction from the
treatments
so we see the uh volume in liters of
irrigation applied
number of irrigation events uh added
flush amount
total liters per plant and percent
reduction using the control the 10 liter
flush being the
um standard in the sense that every that
uses the most water
everything else uses less water uh 22.9
percent
up to 45.7 percent less water
we're looking here at just kind of the
information
we're looking at the moderate stress
treatments was able to reduce water
use by over 45 percent so that's great
from a production standpoint if you're
able to reduce that water
bill by that much minus just treatments
were looking around 25
and removing that 10 liter initial flush
was still
able to reduce water use by almost 23
percent
so important notes to take into
consideration now what's the general
summary well when we're looking at kind
of reducing that water reducing the
irrigation frequency there were
large reductions in water use with
little impact on overall yield
in thc concentration so here we are
saving water
but really not impacting the overall
yield or thc concentrations
that's a great thing removing the two
time 10 liter flush reduced water use in
the same treatment
without the two time 10 liter flush by
22.9 percent
with the non-significant impacts on dry
yield and thc concentrations
so again this is great to see no
difference in dry yield and
concentrations
and we're reducing water another option
for using water is to
use examine the flushing practices
particularly late in the growing cycle
a significant reduction in water use for
irrigation will lead not only to
reduction in
water bill but lead to a significant
reduction in the humidity within the air
handling system
must be you know contented as well so
less water added
less humidity less stress on your
ability to kind of go through and
regulate that environment
flushing nutrients from the substrate so
the practice of flushing is a
current common industry practice but
there's really no
evidence in published literature of its
effectiveness in reducing nutrient
concentrations within the bud
or even whether or not it's a desirable
result
this result showed that the intended
purpose of flushing to reduce nutrient
concentrations within the bud
really has no effect the data shows that
for the last two weeks of the flower
cycle in cannabis it was possible to use
no fertilizer water
for irrigation with no significant
impact and yield while saving input cost
on fertilizer so that's a great
conclusion
if you're looking at the end adding just
water
flushing the nutrients maybe not doing
the flushing of the nutrients
but it really didn't change any of the
nutrient concentrations in the final dry
flour
really did not change the the
concentration why is that significant
well you can forego any fertile
fertilizer additives in the last two
weeks cutting down your cost
cutting down your potential for
environmental contamination with not
impacting your final product so this
applies to both
indoor as well as outdoor growers while
there is a difference for each growing
environment the same general concept
does apply
specifics for each are provided in other
videos if you want to know some more
details for best fit your growing
conditions
but the key part is here we are really
approaching that really close to
flowering and harvesting stage in that
flowering cycle
that flowering cycle is coming to an end
you may be able to get away without
adding any more costly fertilizer
and having no change or reduction in
your total yield now the amount of
duration of time that you would
forego the nutrients may depend of
course on your growing media
soil having the longest duration of time
and hydroponics having the least
duration of time that you would
be watering your plants with only pure
water but again this
is great to kind of know and understand
to help reduce not only your potential
water bill
but also to reduce your fertilizer cost
with no
impact on your final end product