in this debaco university video we're
going to go over how to identify and
control aphids
as well as the end you'll get to see
some actual video footage
where i was able to sadly find some
aphids on some plants
you get to see actually how they look on
cannabis
[Music]
all right let's get into how to identify
and control aphids on cannabis plants
and we can see in the image here
the plethora of aphids sadly on the
underside
some will be very small some larger all
these though piercing sucking insects
going to do severe damage to your plants
as well as
could also transmit diseases such as
viruses
so if it's what's the general
description of aphids well most of the
time
aphids are wingless but in the spring
and fall aphids can have wings to
increase
their dispersal so they can kind of
spread and jump from one plant to
another
these are small insects that can be
found in large numbers
and can also be found in clusters so you
might go through an area where you don't
find any don't find anything you get
like a little hot spot
at least in the initial point of
development this is the wingless form
of the aphids here they can be green to
whiter to kind of like a brownish
tannish kind of color
a little black stripe so there are some
variants that does occur
these are the eggs of cannabis aphids
laid in late september
we can see here that kind of everything
from that green to that kind of almost
see-through green to that dark
coloration there
so there are some variables there keep
in mind that normally females
are present which gives a live birth to
genetically identical daughters
it's almost like they're kind of like
giving birth to
the genetically identical so they can be
literally born
pregnant kind of a weird feature to
aphids and part of the reason
why they can mass multiply so quickly
now the identification of aphids on
cannabis plants is that they can produce
a
honeydew or a sugary secretion which
often turns black
with the growth of a kind of city mold
fungus
some aphid species inject a toxin into
the plants which causes leaves to curl
and further distorts growth
as well as can transmit viruses we can
see just here a mixture of the winged
and wingless
cannabis aphids most of the wingless
aphids are in the immature stage
and here we have these little white dots
these are what we call
cast skins of cannabis aphids and these
are shed in the aphid mulch to a new
larger stage and often collect on the
leaves below colony
can be an indication that aphids are
nearby
so i would go about managing aphids well
uh reflective or silver mulch can be
added
to not allow the aphids to easily detect
the underside of the leaves
that kind of reflective mulch allows it
to kind of like look like the sun
aphids get confused and will reduce
their pest pressure
garlic sprays can help repel them from
initially entering an area
as well as the utilization of beneficial
insects such as green lacewings and lady
beetles
can be effective if they are established
early
here we see some aphids and we see the
ladybug larva feeding on aphids
here we also see the um tiny wasp which
can
uh parasitize certain aphids and we can
see what it looks like at the kind of
mummy stage there
so as a kind of ways of control how do
they actually look on a plant
well i'm going to take you out to an
actual plant and show you
just how aphids look on a cannabis plant
now here we see some anthocyanins being
produced and it's a coloration to
some of the small leaflets near this bud
so just as for comparison
here we're seeing some of those
anthocyanins being produced that kind of
purple coloration in this case
a lot of times it can be response to
stress early on that could be water
stress it could be light stress
well kind of the stress going on here is
evident on the underside of the leaves
you look at the underside of the leaves
here in particular sadly we're seeing a
lot of
aphids on that underside of the leaves
so
these aphids are piercing sucking insect
and they're causing a water stress
on the plant and you never really find
just one
there's usually many of them and we can
see that clearly evident here so
something we want to be looking at
controlling
early on and scouting for so we don't
get into issues
like this where we have a lot of insects
kind of reducing
the plant performance and ultimately
cell they're going to reduce the blood
quality
i think just looking at that blood there
kind of speaks volumes when you're
looking at not really having the
greatest amount
of cannabinoids or terpenes that are
going to be produced
overall yield considering the effort
that went into producing a plant
of this size