so this video in debaco university i'm
going to go over how to germinate
cannabis seeds
what's the proper method rising some
do's some don'ts
here on debaco university
[Music]
all right let's get into the information
here on how to best germinate your
cannabis seeds
well keep in mind that seeds are dormant
so seeds are nature's way
for offspring to wait for ideal
conditions to take place before
initiating the grow cycle
canvas seeds typically only have uh
about nine percent moisture
uh typically sun drying is is practiced
or as low as five percent or even less
while dormant with minimal respiration
and the lower that moisture content the
longer
you're going to be able to germinate
those or keep them stored and still have
high germination numbers so the
germination process of a seed there's a
lot that goes on when a seed initiates
the germination process
first off absorption of water stimulates
the germination process that's the
initiator to the event
the embryo will synthesize gibberellin
it's a plant hormone in response to
water uptake
there's a protein layer that synthesizes
mlas which is an enzyme in response to
the gibberellin
so sometimes people add you'll hear
people adding gibberellic acid
for older seeds help encourage the
germination in the sense they're trying
to push that step along that would
normally be initiated by the water
and kind of causes cascading event to
occur the amylase
mobilizes energy reserves in hydrolysis
starch to maltose means it breaks it
apart
maltose is converted to glucose and
respired to release atp
which is the energy source and that
initial energy source
it's going to cause the kind of
formation and pushing out of the radical
or root
and then the sheet is going to grow up
or in the upward direction it'll be
break through the soil
to start to absorb the sun there and
produce its own
sugars so consistency is important when
we're looking at germinating
seeds we want to be mindful of the
conditions we have our plants growing in
and try to keep them as consistent as
possible once the environmental
conditions uh
ranges are determined it's critical
they're maintained for the duration of
germination process that can always be
exactly the same but as long as we know
the range
we're not exceeding or that above or
below that will help
vastly increase your consistency and
your percent germination
as always you want to start with quality
seeds so this is the start for any
chance that a good germination or
emergence
rate getting seeds from a source that
also provides a coa certificate often
authenticity can be well worth it
that's important for knowing what seeds
that you're
getting there's also stand for a
certificate of analysis as well
keep in mind that while this image right
here shows a nice
seed pack this is not an official form
of documentation
this over here this kind of black and
white kind of simulink boring one
is can be a more official form of
documentation
and any person you're purchasing or
company you're purchasing seeds from
should be able to supply with that upon
request now the temperature you're
looking at what should you germinate
your season what temperature
above 90 degrees fahrenheit or above 30
degrees celsius will kill the seeds
we'll render them basically denature the
proteins and basically kill them
so what's the ideal germination
temperature you're looking at generally
that 78 degrees fahrenheit to 82 degrees
fahrenheit 25 to 28 degrees celsius is a
good starting point
um there that will allow for efficient
or hopefully
high germination rates for the moisture
level you're looking at about a 90
relative humidity and that can be
achieved in many ways through misters or
humidity domes or even just plastic bags
over
little cups here for seedlings that's
also very important here to maintain a
very high
relative humidity keep in mind seeds
also need
it to breathe so remember they're
respiring they're taking in oxygen
so there should be some air pockets no
matter what substrate you're using
to prevent seeds from drowning in water
we want them constantly soaking in water
and basically drowning in water
we do want them to have at least 10
percent air to allow that respiration
process
to occur now planting depth
can vary slightly typically you're
looking at an eighth to a quarter of an
inch which is about three millimeters to
six millimeters deep
many different ways to measure the key
is consistency and having a tool to
speed up the process
here can be a little dowel with just a
little marker on it to know exactly how
far to place that seed down
in the germination media that you're
choosing to use
now for light for um seedlings so
it doesn't matter to say the light
source but we're looking at kind of
uh what's the intensity of that it's the
par reading to being 150 to 300 um
micro moles is what um suggested and
remember ppfd stands for photosynthetic
photon flux density
pars typically what might be heard of in
the literature that's photosynthetic
active
radiation while not needed for the
germination process it's a good idea to
have this
light source over the plants upon
emergence so the seasons can immediately
start the photosynthetic process you
want to see that emerges and there's no
light
and then they can start stretching and
causing other issues keep the light
diffused to avoid burning newly emerged
seedlings
and then you can slowly work its way up
especially if you're going to an outdoor
environment now some growers recommend
or talk about well should i be soaking
my seeds
should i take my seeds and kind of like
put them in water for a duration of time
well for the most part some growers will
put seeds in the water
before that you know for a predetermined
soak time others will go straight into
planting them
a short soak and let's say short two to
maybe four hours is a good idea as this
will help
water infiltration and also allow the
growers to cull out
seeds that float that might not be fully
developed floating seeds often have
those air pockets in there now
poorly developed endosperm which will
directly
reduce germination or emergence rate so
sometimes it's a good idea to
maybe soak them for a little bit to see
which ones float which ones have that
kind of hollow appearance
and cull those out very early now plain
water or treated waters as often
growers will ask seeds should just be
soaked in clean
just regular water there's no need to
add fertilizers even if small amounts
there's no need
to the soaking water someone may add
kelp to help provide a small amount of
hormones
if older or poorly stored seedlings
seeds are being used
but again even that necessary isn't
necessary just plain water
is all the seeds need to initiate this
process
now this summary of those cannabis seed
germination processes always start with
quality c they have a coa
i give the temperature the humidity or
moisture levels i should say
the air should be about 10 air the
planting
depth the light and water should be
filtered or at least
drinkable water there now what i
recommend you don't do
or try to avoid is starting your seeds
in paper towels to start the seeds
for later transfer into whatever media
this is a poor idea due the increased
likelihood of damage to the fragile
radical
it can get caught in the paper towel you
might miss them
they're very small seeds they're very
fragile seeds it's just something that
is not
advised maybe from germany larger seeds
potentially but definitely for cannabis
seeds
not really advised to start in paper
towel even though many growers do that
what i do recommend is i'll show here in
a short video clip is kind of what you
would see kind of at a large scale
tray system using oasis so let's take a
look at that now
so here we're looking at a bowl of
quality uh
cannabis seeds or that nice dark
coloration you can see the area all set
up you see the trays we see
the oasis we see the dibble we see a fan
to keep the
planter happy and this is a great way to
be efficient with this process
all right as we saw there kind of at the
large scale once you go through that
process well how long will it take
well germination typically you're
looking at two to seven days emergence
can be expected about three to ten days
quality seeds in conditioned conditions
and this
stated range will fall in the lower end
of the expected range
so here's just an example of a
collection of ceilings here
15 days from the initial seed soaking
time and this just again shows you what
you can hopefully
expect to see in that three to ten days
now where will you germinate your seeds
this is an important consideration
uh will you be using you know while
general germination process is the same
what do you intend to place the seeds in
when and
different substrates will have different
uh specifics that you should be
following
so for example rock wool is favorable
for seed germination but disposal of
that material can be an issue
soilless media is easy to get but can be
very messy direct seedling is requires
no need for transplant but needs
specialized equipment particularly going
into a field or soil based area
so when looking at these options when
you're considering germinating seeds
which growing substrate would you select
no matter which one you select
search for that video on this channel
and you'll find more details
for your selected growing media to help
increase your odds of success
with your cannabis seedlings