okay here Minh go over how to weight
objects which might seem rudimentary I'm
not gonna focus on triple beam balance
we're going to focus more on a digital
balance which might seem easier but does
have its certain quirks and proper
procedures to follow so key terms we're
looking at here gravity force that pulls
objects for the center of the Earth's
mass is the amount of matter that an
object is made of
this does not change with gravity and
weight the amount of gravity acting on
an object so we're talking about usually
getting the mass of something so well it
may seem easy just put it on the scale
yes but it's a bit more complicated than
that
again that's essentially what you're
doing but these details that you need to
pay attention for will ensure more
accurate results over time so we want to
take care of the balance want to make
sure it's on a level surface so a lot of
balances will have a kind of a bubble
built into them so you're able to tell
whether they're on a level surface or
not this is important to ensure accuracy
in the sensor especially for digital
balances you want to keep it clean this
includes before during and after its use
and calibrate the balance most balances
that you'll use in class are already
calibrated but they typically need to go
through a calibration process at least
initially and then repeated it every so
often and again helps ensure the
accuracy their balance basic electronic
balances need the time to warm up before
being used often this is not a very long
time but it can feel very long sometimes
they do a countdown until they're ready
to be used other times there is that
required warmup time especially with the
more higher end balances they can take
five sometimes ten fifteen minutes to
warm up
we also want another zero the balance
typically there will be an indicating
for that choice want to start with it
reading all zeros who want to check that
to be sure tearing the balance it's
called after the balance warms up make
sure it reads zero it is not zero then
make sure to zero it then place the
weigh boat on the balance the scale
settles to zero before adding the chosen
substance so what you're going to do is
it reads zero put your way boat on there
which is a little plastic dish then
you're going to tear it that's going to
cause it to read zero even though there
something on the balance they're able to
kind of get to read zero so that you can
easily know exactly how much whatever
substance you're adding to that
particular container in depending on the
degree of detail that you're looking for
or the number of digits that your
balance reads to will depend on how
precise you have to be with these more
precise balances you can see they're
typically enclosed in some plastic case
to eliminate other movements of like
wind currents that can't and cause it to
be difficult to get a consistent reading
lastly balances generate a more accurate
weight for larger samples understand
limitations and the equipment a more
precise balance is not necessarily
better so two three just because you can
read the four decimal places doesn't
mean it's let's say a better balance
depends on the detail that you're
looking for and weighing something on
the very end of any balance is not going
to give you the most accurate so a lot
of times we're looking at scaling that
up or treating dilution rates or
something like that to be able to get
the most accurate inconsistent reading
possible