so here i'm going to outline how you
would dust for latent fingerprints and
keep in mind latent prints are ones you
can't initially
visually see so word of caution when
you're going through
this process of identifying these kind
of hidden prints
is that it can be messy but also a fun
process
it's a challenge to to clean this very
fine powder
because it does need to get into all
those little porous surfaces
so if you get it in areas you don't want
it it's very hard to clean from those
surfaces you want to keep your working
area small and try to work on paper or
tray surface when possible to make
cleanup a lot easier and keep things
organized we don't want it looking like
the holy
festival of colors when we're working
with these powders
so dusting and lifting prints from glass
or plastic
first you want to make the print so to
make a quality thumb print on the glass
or plastic surface
you want to rub your thumb usually
against your forehead to help ensure
there's enough oils present
especially if you just recently washed
your hands the goal is to press with
moderate pressure
in a linear vertical motion on the
actual
surface don't press too hard or roll or
smear your print
because remember you can also clean the
area and try again a lot of students
sometimes try too hard
initially so you just kind of want to
for example it's the glass just grab it
like you normally would
and odds are you're going to be
transferring just enough there
of oils without ruining the print
then uh for dusting and lifting the
prints on this glass or plastic surface
option one is use magnetic powder and
a brush so pick up it's called a beer of
magnetic dust this is kind of this
little
area here it does look like a beard in
dust while keeping the plunger of the
brush pushed
down the goal is to have it hang from
the bottom of the brush as we kind of
see
example here and we see the person going
and doing here
you want to gently brush the hanging
dust particles over
the latent print you want to smear the
print when i have too much pressure
just want to just very lightly go over
it because if you have too much force
or use a plastic brush comes in contact
with the print you're going to damage
the actual print
you want to pick up the loose and
excessive dust and put it back in the
original container
keep in mind it does take very little
dust to accomplish this
option two would be using just regular
dust powder and a brush which is going
to follow very much
a similar method except here you're
going to dip the brush lightly into
container powder and then tap off the
extra into the lid
you want to use only a very small amount
of powders you need to dust the print
this comes with kind of some experience
but if you're starting out
use less than you think is will be my
suggestion
you want to lightly swirl the brush over
the print and rotate between your thumb
and fingers careful not to smear the
print
lastly the brush to re use the brush to
remove any excess
powder that you may have and hopefully
you'll be able to see the print become
visible
dusting lifting prints from glass or
surface you want to then lift the actual
print so great you've gone through
you've dusted it
you've created a wonderful print here we
see a whole kind of hand print
here we see an identified fingerprint
how do we lift that print how do we get
it off the surface
we want to acquire a piece of tape
that's larger than the print start by
sticking a portion
near the print and then smooth it over
the rest of the print so you're kind of
causing a fixing in one spot
you're smearing it over that print
and the goal is not to have it shift or
move
smoothing action the smearing over we
want to have it consistent in even
contact
then after it's fixed as we can see here
i want to slowly peel the tape
off the surface and stick it to a clean
flat
piece of paper surface for inspection
it's good to have that ready ahead of
time
so when you immediately lift it off
you're immediately going right to the
your paper on that clean
and flat surface now dusting for
fingerprints
if you're on paper so just one example
here
touch your thumb or forehead to your
forehead and press it on a piece of
paper
if you don't see the print uh don't
worry because these are latent prints a
lot of students will kind of make the
print on the paper and then try to look
for and see if they can see it
a lot of times you'll be able to see it
and that's okay these are latent prints
you want to dust and lift
following the same method and procedure
on the previous
kind of example for a glass and plastic
surface the same applies to paper
if you do it correctly you can get a
print that looks very
much like this and this does allow for a
lot of
ability to go through and identify what
type of print it is
but also see some of the very specific
classifications with that print
to be able to see if you have a match
between two prints
so hopefully this was helpful in going
through and knowing how to dust for
latent
fingerprints