here on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over how to properly take a
soil sample
because it's very important that you
follow the right protocols
so that you're sending a quality sample
to the lab that you'll be basing your
results from
[Music]
all right here i'm going to go over the
steps on how to take a proper soil
sample
and then walking you through the process
myself as well hope you enjoy the video
well first off why would we be taking a
soil test and a soil test
can help tell the chemistry of the soil
that cannot be seen
based on only a visual inspection it can
also aid in deciding what amendments
need to be added to an
area with the proper sample can end up
saving the grower a lot of money so
it's important to not just take any
random soil sample to be sure that
you're going about it in the proper
method
because you're going to be basing
hopefully a lot of
amendments and a lot of end kind of
processes from here
based on the results of that soil test
so take a quality sample
it'll pay off in the end for you and
your plants
so how to ensure a good sample well the
goal is to get a field
representative sample this is
accomplished by collecting many sub
samples
that are put together to create an
average sample you don't just want to
sample from one area and send that off
to the lab
you want to get a collection of samples
do not sample only in that one area as
simply put this will not produce results
representative of the field
as will only provide information about a
point in that
whole field area many point occurrences
can
many point clearances can occur that can
lead to non-representative
results so it's an example if i only
sample from this area what could have
happened in that area
well there could have been a fertilizer
spill it could be in the vehicle parked
or a tractor parked in that lot
there could be animal droppings there
could be uneven drainage in that area
a whole potential host of reasons which
is why i don't want to stick from one
area might take from multiple regions
collect them together to get a good
field representative sample so what
equipment do i need
and this can vary depending on your
exact sample method but in general you
need a map
it's good to know what area or areas
you'll be sampling and where each is
located
and what each is referred to as as far
as naming and labeling
your sample a shovel spade or coring
device i'll go over some of those
the goal is to collect a consistent soil
profile
you may want to avoid rusty iron tools
as this could artificially inflate the
iron
numbers just as a side note need a
bucket or some sort of holding device
this is where the
soil subsamples will be collected and
then mixed to ensure isolated samples
the bucket may be lined with a plastic
trash bag
to avoid any potential contamination
allows it to label that bag
seal it up and then you can move along
with that soil
small plastic bags here is where the
final representative sample will be
placed
and it should be double bagged when sent
to the lab and be sure you label each
bag with the name
of the field or identification name as
well as your own name
and then a marker to label label label
to make sure
you don't end up with all bags of soil
in the end and not remember where any
were exactly from
now where to collect the samples so this
uh we see here
how do we go about collecting samples
some different methods here well
first question is how large of an area
and really in short it depends on where
you go about collecting samples
fields that will be sampled individually
but if areas are seen to be different
there should be separate samples and
labeled separately as well
it could be field one good field one bad
it could be a good and bad area of the
field a high area in a low area
a wet area in a dry area for large
fields it's advised to break them into
smaller
subsections such as field four upper
field four or lower field four
north field for south feels for east and
west something a way to kind of separate
those
to create little smaller areas um just
to give you an idea of what might be
going on in one part of the field
compared to another now how deep do you
sample
well the goal really is six to nine
inches deep and this is considered to be
the main
root zone so you have to go through and
measure it you can measure some tools of
measurements on it
idea how deep your spade is put a little
marker line on it
but six to nine inches deep that's your
goal
now sampling methods so here we're going
to look at the spade method we see some
nice
uh pictures located right here first
part of course is to clear the surface
litter
uh and plant growth from the sound from
the spot you want to start with just a
flat soil line
you want to dig a hole about as wide as
your spade and as deep
as the layers you're going to sample
then with the spade tip place
one inch outside of the edge of the hole
cut down and remove a slice of one side
of the wall
so here we see the area cut a little
hole there we're going right down we're
cutting a one
slice thickness by six to nine inches
long area
keeping that slice at the blade of the
spade use a trial knife or stick to cut
away the sides and slice
leaving the center section about one
inch wide so we kind of keep that area
you can cut it down a little bit or you
can just use that same whole sample
there
ideally this one inch by one inch
vertical section your soil is your sub
sample so that would really cut down on
the amount instead of having one area be
so
large you can cut it down or you can
just use the whole thing
for using a larger pail you want to
place all these subsamples into a
plastic container mix them together well
and then remove about two cups or one
pint of this mixture
this is your composite sample to send to
the laboratory for
analysis and this is an ex explanation
here
looking at the spade method then we also
get into the pv
pvc pipe sampling method uh where we're
looking at
the same thing can be applied to a pvc
pipe or also a coring device as well
so so when we're looking at our core
device or pvc sample
acquire two foot length of inch and a
half pvc pipe
mark six and nine inches on the pipe
pound it into the ground
at least to the six inch mark but try to
get to the nine inch mark remove the
core dislodge into the pail and repeat
this
six to nine times this now the advantage
of the coring device
is it's typically stainless steel and it
makes it a lot easier
but if you don't want to get one of the
kind of higher end stainless steel
methods
if you've got a sledge hammer and two
foot length of inch and a half pipe
you can go through and do this same
exact method realize with the pipe
you'll be getting more samples so again
that five gallon pail is advised
mix it all together take your subsample
label label label
send it off to the lab now preparing
your
soil sample for analysis in the sense
that you want to mix your subsamples
together
you've collected into one large sample
this is
too much to send to the lab you want to
take only a two cup sample
from what you have collected as an
estimation if you're in the field how do
i estimate two cups
well let's kind of think about what two
hands uh can hold there
that would be the consideration of about
two cups
place that soil should be placed into a
labeled bag double bag the sample
include your paperwork and send it off
to the lab
and as i mentioned before do not forget
the paperwork
for your own sake as well as for the
sanity of the lab workers
be sure to clearly label everything and
you also want to double check to make
sure you've also included the
necessary paperwork with your sample
don't fill it out and then back
everything up and
forget to send it off so make sure you
have that paperwork included
with your sample in any payment as well
that might be required
so with this you want to make sure
follow this method
sounds like a little bit of kind of a
laborious
task but in the end this will definitely
save you a lot of work and allow you to
make informed decisions
to maximize your plant yield overall
all right so here i am in the field i'm
going to go over how to take a
soil sample with a couple different
methods now the goal is going to be the
same the end result that we're going to
get is going to be the same amount of
soil
field representative so while i'm in a
large corn field here
we're going i'm going to show you an
area at one point but we'd be
replicating this
soil sampling technique throughout the
entire field to get a representative
sample
and there's two main methods one there's
a soil core method
so in this example here i've got an
actual soil core
this is the probably the you know
easiest way if you're going to be doing
a lot of samples this is by far the way
i would recommend
you're going to take your soil core this
area here is about
six to nine inches depth is what you
want the reason why you want that to be
that deep is that is basically the root
profile
now that what makes the soil core so
nice is it stainless steel
it's all inclusive you don't have that
you can take a little simple
inch and a half piece of pvc pipe put
that in the ground mark it with that six
to nine inches your goal is to get to at
least six inches
if you if you can if that goes well go
up to nine inches
you don't want to really go much more
than that because that's really your
root zone profile there
you would take this you'd pound this
into the ground and you take that
core and put it into your bag right here
i've got a bag
over a five gallon pail to make sure
everything is consistent
i've also got the measuring i've got
some bags i got gloves
i can take this out when i get my soil
sample and label this
because i'm in one field here we might
be going through doing multiple fields
so keep that in mind that keeping
everything labeled is very important and
that's a great way to do that
in addition the bag also keeps any
contaminants that might be within the
soil in the bucket
separate so again you could use a pvc
pipe i like the inch and a half because
it comes out
relatively easy you're kind of going
through and able to dislodge it much
easier if it was a smaller diameter pipe
but since we've got the official soil
core here it operates in the same method
so here's my sample area and here's my
corn plants plants or whatever
and put that here on the soil and then
i'm going to push that down
to about that mark i give it a little
rotate and when i go to pull this out
you're going to notice
i've got my nice core right here
now with this core that i have i'm going
to be taking that and adding that to
the bucket right here so what's great
about the official soil probe is that
because it's got this half cut
makes it really easy to go through and
now replicate this
however i realize not everyone has a
soil core so what's something that you
may have around
well you may have a regular spade and
you can do the exact same method
so in this area here what we want to do
is we want to make a
we want to make a hole so we go through
get our spade
now we're going to remove chunk of soil
now we don't want to take this
as our soil sample what i'm doing is i'm
cutting a
hole down here got some earthworms
always nice to see
and i'm going down that same about six
to nine inches but with my spade what
makes this why is i want to speed with
this
flat point here is i'm going to go
through now and not take this soil as my
sample
there's a profile here i'll take my
speed take about an
inch away from that go straight down
and take that out so what essentially
i've got now
is that one inch profile of the soil
now you could take this entire sample
put it in there you're going to be doing
a lot of samples i don't want to carry
around that much
weight of soil because the bucket gets
heavy you can go through and you can
remove a portion of that
as long as you're consistent and take
only maybe the center portion there so
you can take out some of this
keep in mind you want to keep that side
of that center region
why that's going to be your consistent
soil there because you got a lot of
enough moisture in the soil here
take that essentially that core that
profile
add that to our bag go back through
refill this in so we don't trip over it
in the middle of the night
and then go through and replicate that
again and again when we're done
we've got all of our soil we don't need
to send the whole full bag of soil
we only need approximately
if we mix everything up from all of our
cores
get a good kind of representative sample
and what we need to send to the lab is
basically what
two hands can hold this is all the soil
sample we need we want to send them a
five gallon pail
we also don't want to send them a
thimble amount we want all that
basically two hands uh
can hold and that's the volume of soil
we wanna add
i recommend just a regular little lunch
bag
when you get your old soil mixed up and
you get it nice kind of
together you want to remove anything
large that you see them this
the lab will screen that out but why
send it to them you know they're going
to screen that out anyway
visually what this generally looks like
it's approximately this much
label the bag double bag it and as
always when you're sending this
make sure you also include the
appropriate paperwork the lab will thank
you
and those help you ensure that you're
getting accurate results and they know
exactly
where that soil who that soil belongs to
and where the results need to go to
all right so we're going to use this
field as a representative field for
taking soil samples so when we look at
the field overall we don't see any major
like really low spots or any dips so we
can do this to normal random sampling
so this here is going to be my first
point to randomly sample
and let's go through and see where else
i would sample
this particular field i'd also take a
sample from here
i would take another sample from here
and i take another sample from here
and another one from here and this looks
like a good spot i'll take another one
from here
and another sample right from here