here on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over how to identify
and control grasshoppers on cannabis
[Music]
plants
all right let's get into how
identification and controlling of
grasshoppers on cannabis plants
we can see here here's one actively on a
cannabis leaf there
looking to probably uh conduct some sort
of damage to that plant
so that description of the grasshoppers
well they're
visually distinctive compared to many
other insects
the cultivated gardeners don't seem to
be
kind of a common sight for egg egg if
you're growing in a cultivated garden
may not see as many of them grasshoppers
tend to prefer undisturbed areas
such as pasture areas if you're growing
cannabis on a larger scale
might have a better odds of seeing it
particularly if it's next to a large
pasture area populations may vary
considerably also from year to year so
keep that in mind
because you didn't see them last year
doesn't mind you don't see them a lot
this year
there's different types of grasshoppers
and there's many
many different types try to provide a
general kind of visual guide just right
here
with all of them listed as well as some
additional resources here
provided by the usda the presence of
weeds and hemp plantings that support
various grasshoppers can increase the
likelihood of this pest pressure
on hemp crops so that managing of area
and local weeds
is important to reduce their population
so they're less likely to jump to the
cannabis plants
some grasshoppers specialize on certain
weedy plants and hemp
is not their target plant species so
hopefully they'll just kind of be a
graze feeder and a nuisance
more than actual leading to crop
complete failure
now the feeding and identification of
that feeding of grasshoppers if you're
seeing some damage on your plants
grasshoppers do tend to be stem feeders
and this poses the greatest threat to
the cannabis plants
you can see here gnawing down the stem
breaking the stem causing that kind of
top to fall over
leaf chewing is a common injury as well
but it occurs on the stems that can
stunt the plant that can cause it to
fall over
that can cause longer term implications
and negative implications at that
so how do we manage grasshoppers well
control can be difficult while physical
barriers can offer some protection
grasshoppers have been known to chew
through protective materials such as
insect netting
if you really want to get in there and
they're really determined they can
however chickens aren't excellent
natural predators but they can often do
unintentional damage to your plants as
well
so it's that kind of risk reward aspect
chickens are great for removing
grasshoppers maybe not necessarily in
your canvas plants but maybe in those
neighboring weeds or pasture areas
let them kind of free range in that area
to help control the population
there so it's a reduced amount of
grasshoppers that could make it
to your cannabis plants