on this debaco university video going to
go over how to identify and control
white flies
if you identify them on your cannabis
[Music]
plants
so kind of a unique look here at some
white flies
this video is going to focus on how to
identify them control them
on cannabis plants so first off the
description of white flies well white
flies are piercing and sucking insect
that feed
on the plant's sap they can develop
quickly
in warm weather and they can mass
multiply you want to inspect the
underside of the leaves for the actual
insects as you can see here
and you can also inspect for the small
dots which are the eggs
which will show just the pressure that
is to come for
white flies on your cannabis plants now
identification
of white flies well luckily white flies
are large and typically easy to spot
with regular inspections
they're not super small like some other
insects are they feed on young plants
this can cause leaf curling
and plant distortion because they're
just basically piercing and sucking so
it's going to cause that plant
to take on that kind of crinkled look
another reason for concern is the
potential for viral transmission
via white flies being the virus vector
kind of general feeding you can see that
kind of stippling on the leaves here
flipping this over would likely reveal
white flies
so how do you go about managing white
flies well white flies can quickly
develop a resistance to pesticides
so this should only be used if there's
an initial large population
to kind of reduce or knock down their
numbers before implementing
another method of control then those
that other method of control should be a
biological control
such as the pirate bugs and green lace
wings here you see part bugs feeding
on the larvae of larvae of white flies
they can be in effect of control at
least if they're established early
when populations are small and that's
why if you have a large population you
can catch it early
knocking that down with pesticides
potential option but really
utilizing these beneficial insects is
what's advised
because it requires no chemical residue
or applications to your actual cannabis
plants