interested in learning more about hps or
high pressure sodium lighting
with regards to cannabis production
you've come to the right place here at
debaco university where i'll be
explaining some of the options
with hps lighting
so let's get some of the options and
details with hbs lighting
for cannabis production so first off
we're talking about hps
lights is a sodium vapor lamp that is a
gas discharge lamp that uses sodium in
excited state to produce
light a characteristic wavelength near
589 nanometers which has that yellow
orange appearance
they are high pressure sodium or hps
bulbs belong to the high
intensity discharge hid lamp family
which means that they produce light in
excited gases and vaporizing metals
with electrical current to sufficiently
excite them to produce
the light just as a note that low
pressure sodium lamps are commonly seen
as street lighting
they are not the same as these high
pressure sodium lights
high pressure sodium lights are commonly
used as plant and grow lights
because of the high output that they
have and ability to grow plants
when we don't have the sun now the
structure of a high pressure sodium
lamp or the bulb here as we can see
that there is a lot of internal
structures now they can be purchased in
250 400
600 or 1000 watt setups these are all
single ended they can also be in
double ended particularly 1000 watts so
realize that there's a lot in here
there's a vacuum there's a lot of metal
so when you're purchasing these lamps be
sure you inspect them
to make sure that nothing is broken
internally in the light
so it's safe and it will actually work
now the distance between the high
pressure sodium
and the plants hyperstem cellulites do
generate quite a bit of heat so when
using higher wattages
the distance between the light and the
plants should be overly overall
increased typical distances for high
pressure sodium grow lights can be
mounted anywhere between 6
and 34 inches away 6 inches is very
close and if you have a dimmable one
or a low wattage output one maybe six
inches but for the most part
it's better to start further away than
than closer and also when in doubt you
want to measure the light intensity with
a par meter to start
with a greater distance to reduce it if
there's no burn or damage notice if you
start too close you'll torch potentially
everything
so starting further away and bringing it
closer can be advantageous you also need
to set up a ventilation system because
these will be generating a fair amount
of heat even if you're only growing with
one light
to be able to cool the environment that
the plants are in
as i mentioned that heat so often when
growing with high pressure sodium lights
growers will likely need a way to reduce
the natural heat that this light source
produces
a single commercial reflectors are the
most efficient
this will often result in growers
adjusting their growing environment to
either increase air circulation or
adding a cooling system
this is also if some growers grow in
colder climates and they're completely
indoors
they may choose to run these lights at
night why because they're going to
generate heat anyway
and when it's nighttime on the outside
in the natural environment temperatures
tend to
cool so it might be a more advantageous
time to generate some heat to keep the
plants warm
and also provide them with light because
if they're an indoor facility they're
not going to know what the natural light
is anyway
now hbs replacing bulbs and the
reflectors here
so a lot of growers typically think of
only the bulbs but we also have to keep
in mind the reflectors
hps grow light should be replaced about
every five thousand to ten thousand
hours of usage
the light intensity should be checked
with a par meter note that the bulbs and
also
reflectors degrade over time so for
canvas production where light intensity
should be maximized
growers will use the 5000 hour mark to
change out their bulbs out
and not run them any longer the
reflectors
you can use a parameter kind of check
that typically every about two years
keep them clean
and that could be another thing very
easy to replace not that expensive it
can help
increase the intensity of light that
gets down to your plants
so those reflectors commercial
all-in-one units are preferred like the
one
right next to me over here over build
your own options to maximize production
and eliminate potential chance or inc
capabilities i also would not recommend
you taking the old
kind of turkey tin here and flipping it
over and using that as a reflector it
may look like it does the same thing
but from a plant standpoint it's not
going to be nearly as efficient as these
commercial options
however even with a quality commercial
setup reflectors should be replaced and
growers are advised to purchase
replacements when you're producing your
light initially
to maximize production reflectors should
be checked replaced about every two to
four years
to maximize your cannabis production
there
now atreus lights for the entire grow
cycle can you use them from seedling
stage to the end flowering stage
well it is possible but usually not
recommended to use hps lighting for the
entire grow cycle
if this is the case early grow plant
will might stretch more evident
stretching more evident meaning your
seedlings might be taller than they
should be
simply because the amount of red light
is great for photosynthesis but does
induce stretching of the plant to reduce
stretching growers can select a bulb
that produces high blue light as well
or exposed plants with some natural
sunlight to fill in some of the missing
blue spectrum
to help keep those internet spacing down
a little bit
now high pressure sodium common wattages
are about 600 and thousand watts of the
common ones
600 watt grow lights are the most
efficient hps grow lamp
these grow lights produce more like
output per watt
used in other wattages and their
suggested coverage areas of five by five
in a bedroom or four by four in a flower
room
definitely no more than that for a
thousand watt
they're the most powerful and cover the
largest area six by six for a bedroom
and five by five for a flower room
so deciding on what wattage will also
determine the type of bulb you use
and the type of area you can cover
now there's also single ended and double
ended bulbs
so over here you can see that there's a
single ended and then below me is the
double double-ended
single-ended bulbs recommend to be used
with 600 watts in
lower wattages they're easy to replace
and use
considerably considerably more at the
hobby level
to operate and reduce temperatures so
advise for small grow tent
settings uh compared to your double
ended your double endings are
recommended for a thousand watt bulbs to
ensure maximum light intensity
and associated with commercial settings
they allow for greater light intensity
and even more even distribution of the
light compared to the single ended
and they can produce more wavelengths
outside the par range including infrared
and uv
light that's why they're typically
preferred at that commercial
setting again single line is a little
bit easier to change recommend for the
lower wattages commercial setting 1000
watts you should be going with the
double ended because that is pretty much
considered to be kind of the industry
standard
when it comes to high pressure sodium
lights