so on this debaco university video go
over the human endocannabinoid system
how it relates to the cb1 and cb2
receptors
[Music]
all right so focusing on these receptors
is as a side note the cb2 receptor here
is involved with the immune system found
in the thalamus and the cb1 receptor is
in the brain there so we're going to
talk about two different locations
within the body
so realize that there are different
types of cannabinoids and a lot of
people get hung up on just one or two
that they like to focus on we realize
there are many types and you know we've
got the side chain of all right there's
a whole bunch of different types here
these are produced not only by cannabis
so keep that in mind as well that
cannabis does produce these but there's
other plants in fungi and other species
basically that do produce these as well
liverworts for example rhododendron are
just some examples cannabinoids are
defined generally as specific species of
terpenoids molecules that has the
potential to interact with the
endocannabinoid system typically
abbreviate ecs
now don't forget about the terpenes
remember also some terpenes that
interact with the endocannabinoid system
as well
one established example of this effect
is the beta carothylene which has been
identified as a cb2 agonist acting as an
allergistic way to suppress the
suppressor of neural inflammation and
with this property this makes it a
candidate for the treatment of multiple
sclerosis remember an agonist is going
to allow for the activation of the
binding and activation of that molecule
and antagonist is going to either lessen
that activation or block it entirely
now cannabis are inside of you your own
body contains a system of anginas
receptors and ligands which work to
regulate a vast number of cellular
functions in tissues throughout your
body they do play a vital role with
these cannabinoids in maintaining
homeostasis so they are very important
keep in mind here looking at the graphic
we are talking about the synapse area
here which is that area between those
two neurons and this does work on a
negative feedback loop system
at least two of these cannabis produced
by your own body are called anamide
which is
an analog to the thc molecule and this
really long name here two
aractodontylglycerol
is an analog and a degenerace analog to
the cbd molecule both produced by
cannabis
now specifically for these receptors and
try to provide a nice little graphics
here to try to separate out the two
target regions and classify them a
little bit more for this cb1 and cb2
receptors as
these do determine the behavioral
effects when it's consumed by the
individual as well the effects of your
own body to these cannabis receptors so
it's these receptors that is the reason
why
different people may have different
after effects or
different responses to this because of
their receptors might be slightly
different from one individual to another
now looking here just highlight here the
cb1 receptor
they are expressed most densely in the
central nervous system and are largely
responsible for the meeting of the
effects of the cannabinoid binding to
the brain there so there's a lot of
depolarization going on it has to result
in a decrease neither glutamate or a
gaba release which are examples of
neurotransmitters so with this research
when we're looking at the cb1
receptor and they're kind of in
inhibitory effects
it's looking like that this receptor
might be able to inhibit or play a role
in inhibiting neurotransmitter release
in general looking at the physiology of
this particular cb1 receptor
now in contrast if we look at cb2 here
remember these are found in the immune
cells particularly cells of the
macrophage lineage these receptors only
indirectly affect neural neural function
modulating cb2 signaling could be
promising for the treatment of various
inflammatory conditions
so that's an important note to keep in
mind and this is why we need more
research on this topic
now kind of tying this all in another
kind of graphic here looking at the
human endocannabinoid system
thc cbd and cbn again we're talking at
the neurotransmitter level these
chemicals and how they interact with
both the brain as well as you know the
immune system so there's a lot that goes
on this is a very complex system and
hopefully with more research we'll be
able to understand this even better