now when people say growing cannabis a
lot of people think of the plant the
soil
the water the fertilizer the substrate
lighting and all of that
however we also particularly for indoor
growing need to be
aware of the importance of of hvac jobs
so this debacle university video is
going to cover the importance and some
of the details
associated with an hvac job if you're
considering that and
merging that with the cannabis industry
[Music]
all right let's get into hvac jobs in
the cannabis industry
so first off the general job description
is that it performed
skills mechanical maintenance duties in
the inspection repair
installation and alteration of heating
ventilation
air conditioning and refrigeration
systems and related equipment
and facilities perform preventative
maintenance and routine servicing
of that equipment so there's a lot there
but for indoor facilities where you're
really creating a specialized indoor
growing environment
this is a very important job because
we're trying to maintain those
consistent conditions
as a result made to heat one day cool
another day add humidity reduce humidity
there's a lot going on here now the
day-to-day activities of someone
specializing in hvac and
kind of in the cannabis industry is
inspect repair modify hvac equipment
that's your heating ventilation air
conditioning equipment
that can be referred to condensers and
chillers and pumps
valves so there's a lot going on even in
a small
cannabis growing facility you want to
conduct regular preventive maintenance
inspections that could be changing
filters out for example
inspecting units as far as boilers go or
gas or electric operated air
conditioning systems
as well as evaporative coolers the goal
the hvac person is to repair
or replace defective parts indoor units
and equipment in their controls and that
can be thermostats
fan controls heat exchangers safety
valves
and a whole bunch of other things as
well they operate a variety of hand
and power tools welding torch vacuum
pump testing equipment
to ensure that all the parts and tools
inventory is present
and working properly now what are some
qualities if you're looking at pursuing
this as
a potential career well work is
performed while standing sitting or
walking
so being physically fit is important
also requires the ability to communicate
effectively in speech
vision as well as hearing requires use
of hands and simple grasping of fine
manipulations
requires bending squatting crawling
climbing and reaching so there's a lot
of
physical um labor involved here
installing all this not always not in
the easiest part of to be on your side
through things like that
requires ability to lift carry push or
pull medium weights up to 75 pounds
aquarius activities involve being around
moving machinery exposure to mark
changes in temperature and humidity
exposure to dust fumes as well as gases
typically high school diploma or gd
certificate is required
two years documentation of hvac
journeyman level operation maintenance
and repair experience in the hvac and
refrigeration trade is
also highly sought after so what's the
connection to the cannabis industry
well the cannabis industry is widely
considered to be the fastest growing
industry and heavily reliant on hvac
technicians
typically hvac techs will have little to
no knowledge of what it takes to grow
cannabis
and that can be perfectly fine there is
a need for technicians who specialize in
various areas of hvac
but understand the needs to create a
healthy cannabis growing environment
which creates a new area of study in the
hvac canada space
and if you do have some sort of
background in plants having the hvac
background as well
can really make you a potentially a
highly sought after
future employee