welcome to this tobacco university video
looking at hybrid cannabis and
explaining some
of the nuances associated with it this
can be a little difficult because
many of the cannabis is actually
becoming a hybrid because growers are
looking at blending different traits
so masby's blended is kind of this cat
and bird here but we're getting this
kind of blending of indica sativas and
even
rudalus so just the origin of hybrids
just in general the goals that try to
obtain the best of both worlds
in one plant there's often there's a
popular demand to combine the autoflower
plant characteristics with another
desired cannabinoid and or
terpene profile this is why growers are
bringing that rudalus with some of the
indicas or sativas
whose growers are really looking for the
ease of plant maintenance with also a
high quality
end product so it's that kind of nice
kind of mixing of that blue
and that yellow to get that green that
kind of merger of two
to get the best of both worlds and to
create something new as well
so the hybrid plant morphology how does
how do these plants in general look
well hybrids can be very variable so you
want to make sure you're doing your
research
is highly advised so that you know what
you're getting
into you want to start by getting an
idea of is
indica or sativa dominant in morphology
it's going to be really tall
or it's going to have a tendency to be
shorter and squattier this will give you
that general classification
oftentimes the goal by breeders is to
take a standard strain
and to breed it in the autoflower into
it but keep in mind that other
morphological features need to be taken
into consideration
more than just it becoming photoperiod
independent
now popular cultivation locations again
it can be very
diverse because with the autoflower
characteristics
this is a morphology that fits in many
different growing conditions both
indoors and outdoors
with an improved cannabinoid or terpene
content this makes it very easy
for selection for a wide varieties of
growers however breeders need to
continue in this area and make
improvements
because while we have the rootales kind
of gene and autoflower characteristics
and we've got our
dominant indica sativas with
cannabinoids the merger of the two
they're still working on
ensuring you get the best of both worlds
right now these hybrids might favor one
versus another
so there is still lots of room for
improvement some people have tried some
of the early hybrids
and weren't really thrilled with them
but there's continual improvements
for this particular type of cultivation
of cannabis now it's hard to kind of
pinpoint any one or a couple
varieties but we can see here there's
many different ones that fall into the
classification of
hybrids i just listed a few here because
remember a lot of growers are breeding
in different types indica sativas
the whole goal is to get the best of
both worlds all
in one plant with an established
cultivar established strain here
to help uh create this ability
for growers to produce a high quality
product but still meet the demands of
their particular growing conditions
quite well