if you were to look at hydroponic
substrates while most people think
hydroponics is growing purely in water
there is the option to run some
substrates these substrates qualify
under hydroponics because they're not
eating any mineral content to the plant
they're purely adding an area for a root
support in gross in these substrates
they allow for a wide margin a wider
margin of error for the plants compared
to if we're growing in just pure water
solution they hold nutrients in water in
case of pump failure so that can buffer
you in case you're looking you know
monitoring the pump and then the pump
fails use a little bit of that window of
opportunity to realize that before you
lose the entire crop they also provide
physical structure for the roots they
also important to insulate the plant
roots from large swings in temperature
versus just a water based system now
there's water holding capacity is the
amount of nutrient solution that can be
absorbed so how absorbent is the media
or substrate that you're using here Coco
car and Rocco wool rock wall can hold
five to eight times their weight in
water which means less irrigation events
are needed it can dress expanded clay
pebbles hold very little water resulting
in the need for almost continuous
irrigation with those so again it's
important to know what substrate or what
media you're using and how absorbent it
is for materials because that's it's
going to depend on the irrigation events
that you choose to use air-filled
porosity so the amount of airspace in
the media it is important since roots
need to breathe or respire to be able to
exchange oxygen if making your own mix
using perlite can help increase the
amount of air in the root zone in the
overall drainage and we could see that
evident here of a high porosity mix a
lot of area for that air pockets to fit
in a lot of opportunity for your roots
to have access to oxygen now CEC or
cation exchange capacity how well the
substrate can hold on to and release
positive ions at the plant roots low CC
is poor ability to hold nutrients for
example rock wall this doesn't
necessarily mean it's a bad substrate it
just means we have to be aware of that
when we're making our plan Coco car is a
very high seating can hold on to key
nutrients so strongly that the plant
cannot have access to them this is why
for growing in a Coco car solution
our media I should say typically a
calcium in magnesium based nutrient mix
is recommended on regular intervals for
those growers in that situation the
cocoa cars derived from the husks of
coconuts
it can hold calcium and make it
unavailable to the plants and this is
why a cal-mag solution is typically
recommended you want to make sure that
you're rinsing and removing any unwanted
salts from the original material if they
are not done so when at the time of
purchase it can be a variable product
from batch to batch so keep this in mind
that just because you have a good batch
don't expect that necessary that same
quantity edge in every batch should
always be testing those and making sure
that everything is flowing within the
parameters that you need however it does
hold moisture very well so that is one
great positive to it but also keep in
mind of the source material and
sustainability of that now with expanded
clay pebbles one they are replacement
for soil they're easy to use in the RV
usable though you want to make sure you
always rinse them before you use them
because there will be a fine kind of
clay dust that will wash away if you
don't do that ahead of time that could
clog your pumps or caused asura residue
and other issues I also want to make
sure you take the time to get them
properly saturated when first using
these do have a very high CEC and can
basically not be over irrigated as a
result many people run irrigation over
them 24 hours a day there should be at
least four inches deep to prevent light
penetration which can negatively impact
root growth if they're too shallow and
roots try to grow and they see light
well you'll stunt the roots having that
four inches or so barrier prevents life
and penetrating and allowing the roots
to expand normally they can get about
fifteen percent more weight after they
sow broccoli maybe like a hundred sorry
thousand and eleven hundred percent or
so greater on in their weight so if
you're transitioning from a rock wall to
a clay pebbles or clay pebbles to
Rockville keep in mind that can be vast
different eleven hundred percent greater
more water retention with Rockville
versus only fifteen percent with clay
pebbles again doesn't mean this is
necessary bad MIDI to choose just be
mindful of its natural characteristics
that Rockville is a commercial grower
favorite need to pre-soak the cubes if
you do use them about five to fifteen
minutes depending on their size longer
time for larger
cubes I'm not sure you shake the cubes
before inserting them into a tray or
whatever holding the device that you're
using you don't want to squeeze them you
squeeze them to kind of crush in all the
air out very quick and easy for
transplanting that's why the commercial
growers favorite and they have a great
ability to hold water and also air to
allow those roots to breathe sand
provides good plant support it should be
sterilized before you use it but it can
be very heavy also it doesn't hold water
very well due to its large particle size
and it can also make the transplant
process difficult what happens is when
you go to pull a plant out if you're
using sand I can disturb many of the
fine roots and cause increased stress
for your next step down on the growing
scale of the season so all these have
pros and cons with them you want to
choose one that fits your size or your
production well this is why there's so
many options out there and available to
you so take a look at them hopefully
this was helpful and allowing you to
understand hydroponic substrates and
realize hydroponics is more than just
growing in pure water-based solution