here we'll look at some of the basics of
hydroponics we see a great image here
showing some plants being grown
hydroponically but this is not the only
way our plants can be grown for it still
to be counted as or classified as
hydroponics so first off hydroponics is
the science of growing plants without
soil a lot of people think hydroponics
means purely grown in water that's not
necessarily the case because this can
include Rockwell's coconut fiber clay
pebbles and others that do not contain a
high neural base content all of these
would still be classified technically as
hydroponics addition of these or more
traditional aerated water conditions are
also classified as hydroponic so think
of like if you're growing plants in
water or some aerated water that is
hydroponics and that's typically what's
associated when someone says hydro
products but keep in mind Raquel coconut
fiber and clay pebbles can also be
classified as hydroponics simply because
they gave very little minerals to the
planet now hydroponic production allows
growers have near complete control over
a nutrient uptake we can see this row of
tomatoes grown in the greenhouse they
are grown in Rockwell's but again this
is classified as hydroponics the part of
the reason why is this allows for higher
yields than soil production however
growers also can
incorrectly feed the plant which can
reduce overall yields so because you can
control everything that plant is getting
with the exact nutrient solutions exact
concentrations that's great we have
great control but with that comes great
responsibility
so with great control comes great
responsibility and this is where you can
maximize yields but the grower can also
sadly mess things up if they're not
careful the advantages they said
efficient production per plant could see
very little area being used here ideally
getting high yields the grower has
control over the nutrients as a result
can healed better than soil production
it's also very clean and sterile
to try to eliminate or reduce the chance
of getting disease however the
disadvantages are it can be expensive to
initially set up can have a more complex
setup or an arrangement does repair time
and technical knowledge some cost to
ideally have good quality need to have
continual monitoring of the operation
and it's not as forgiving as soil
production so again a little bit more
dialed
it can add nutrients very quickly but
can also go to nutrient deficient as
well limitations for hydroponic is
burning the roots and nutrient uptake
you got to watch that pH I want to make
sure you're not over feeding the plants
either when I ensure nutrient solutions
are well mixed before adding them to
plants and want to keep the root zone
area oxygenated keep in mind the roots
no matter how small or large do need an
oxygen source because they are respiring
and taking in that oxygen breaking down
those sugars so that they can grow so
keeping that pH of that water correct
and keeping that aeration are very
important things with any Crudup onok
production