so here we talk about hydroponic
reservoirs which are basically
reservoirs or holding containers for
water see one here in a very large scale
to be we have these on much smaller
scale for smaller hydroponic operations
so in general should be as large as
possible for the given space you want to
have something overly oversized and
something undersized it needs to match
the area or space that you'll be growing
it should be located an area that does
not cause them to overheat keep
evaporation to a minimum I want to keep
the heat down as well
the level the EC and the temperature
need to be monitored when I say level I
mean the height within the reservoir you
want to let it get too low because if
you're running pumps especially that
could cause pumps to burn out or it
could cause not enough water to reach
your plants and cause them to have water
stress and could ultimately cause them
to die that target temperature being
sixty and seventy five degrees
Fahrenheit 18 to 24 degrees Celsius we
want to keep temps below eighty five
degrees Fahrenheit or third degrees
Celsius anything higher this should be
avoided do you see increased odds of
route damage because water holds oxygen
on a much poorer level at these warmer
temperatures if the heater is at it be
sure to circulate the wire to allow even
temperature distribution this would be
needed if your temperatures falling
below sixty degrees Fahrenheit for
whatever reason below eighteen degrees
Celsius sometimes a water heater is
advantageous to add depending on your
location of your reservoir but keep in
mind you want to stir that water
otherwise we'll just be a small area of
really warm water and it will cause
stratification in the aquatic
environment you have covers are advised
there should be covers to limit light
and reduce the chance that algae look
growth so want to have some sort of lid
on them it could be simply a piece of
plastic here that eliminates light
penetration it can also help control
water loss prevent unwanted items from
falling into the tank so you see here
there's a cover but there's also a more
solid great cover here through an aiding
from falling in to this reservoir tank
lastly having the lids that seals
airtight may initially sound like a good
idea but actually this can cause suction
and reduce the flow of water to the
irrigation system so
while you may want to put a you know a
lid on that I want to make sure that
there's some form of air exchange that
is occurring especially if using pumps
to pump water out when I mix those pumps
working harder and increase the chance
of failure having some sort of
breathability is a good idea you don't
want to necessarily have it sealed
simply having it mostly covered unsealed
from the outside from outside light is a
good idea but keeping it sealed so that
it's airtight is not advised because you
can reduce your evaporation loss vastly
but is having this cover over it you
don't need to keep it airtight