welcome to another debaco university
video
in this video lecture we're going to be
learning about identifying cannabis
point anatomy
some you might be familiar with like the
picture here of this nice
female bud but we're going to get into
some of the other details that you might
have seen before
but maybe not familiar with their actual
terminology
so first off if you want to learn a
little bit more i have this link to this
reference article here and cited here i
will use some aspects of it in this
presentation
but there's even more detail provided
there so first off i want to talk about
rooted cutting now rooted cuttings are
simple form of vegetative propagation
and we see the example here exhibit a
with the rooted cutting about two weeks
after rooting
and this bar represents 10 centimeters
for a size orientation
now other cuttings they don't all have
to look like this is an example here of
some other
rooted cuttings now these are vegetative
propagation meaning these are
what a lot of growers refer to as clones
these are genetic copies of the mother
or
stock plant going to carry on those same
terpene profiles
the same cannabinoids as the mother
plant it's a great way to ensure
genetic consistency then we also have
the internode
of the cannabis plant so there's a lot
of terms here we have
the the chute that kind of comes out to
the side it's called the axillary chute
we see that located right here
two bracks and there's kind of the areas
that kind of like little
that branch out and we have two solitary
flowers in this image we have a solitary
flower here on the right hand side
and another one here on the left this is
all located at the node here
where the axle leaf kind of comes in
here the kind of the
uh petiole of the leaf enters at the
node here and this would ultimately
kind of lead to one of the true or fan
leaves here
now in this image the bar represents
about two tenths of a centimeter
just to give you another orientation of
their picture showing the same general
area we can see
a lot of the same anatomy features
located
right here keep in mind the distance
between two nodes is called the inter
node space when the plant stretches
the spacing of the internodes increases
then we get to the cotyledons and these
are the embryonic or seed leaves which
are the first two leaves to appear
from a germinating seed they tend to be
more rounder in appearance you can see
them clearly evident here
uh and it's kind of a nice little way to
kind of see that little seedling come up
and that ceiling can kind of go through
and be those first leaves to start
capturing the sun
so you can start to go through the
photosynthetic process so it can start
growing exponentially
now after those cuddlings or seed leaves
go by we get into what called true
leaves
now true leaves as you see here's our
two seed these are cutaweens
these would be our first our next two
leaves is we are true leaves and tree
these are basically
any leaves of the seed plant other than
the catalines
so these second and
sorry these third and fourth leaves
right here and everything after that
would be considered true leaves
now when they get older they kind of
look like this and higher up in the
plant a lot of growers will refer them
as fan leaves
it's just a further classification of
true leaves
then we get into sugar leaves these
leaves kind of grow
out of the bud and have many trichomes
on them and it's the trichomes that give
the appearance of the sugar on the
leaves if you've kind of cooked
something you kept put powdered sugar on
it
kind of looks like that same appearance
this is why they get the term
sugar leaves is it looks like you kind
of took that powdered sugar and
lightly coated it what you're actually
looking at there is a series a
density of trichomes then we get male
and female pre-flowers
so the male flowers they produce the
pollen we can see those right here they
want to look for these kind of
pronounced
sac like flower structures in comparison
the female pre-flowers located right
below me here
these will ultimately produce the
cannabinoids and or seeds if they get
pollinated
you want to look for these fine little
wispy white hairs called the stigmas
now you want to hear the term stigma i
think of sticky stigma which might
always look like
even finer hairs on them is this
structure would be responsible for
capturing pollen
for the plant there'll be something
called popcorn buds now popcorn buds
get their names simply because they're
similar size to a popcorn kernel
these are b grade buds do the overall
size of those buds
and the potency will be similar though
slightly lower than a grade buds
produced on the same
plant they're often offered at a reduced
price if you're looking at purchasing
them due to their lack of visual impact
compared to those
large a-grade buds they're getting the
max amount of light
and have the maximum amount of terpenes
and cannabinoids in them
then we get to those trichomes that i
mentioned a little bit earlier it's kind
of a focus on them and they are hair
like out gross
that are the site of cannabinoid terpene
and flavonoid production
that kind of zoomed out look kind of see
how they get the term those sugar leaves
coated with those trichomes as you zoom
a little bit closer closer and closer
you can see they're kind of like clear
to whitish
mushroom-like structures and again this
is where you're going to find your
cannabinoids and terpenes and flavonoids
it's going to be kind of condensed in
the plant so they're going to store them
this is a calyx structure this is found
in all flowering plants
and it's the first part of the flower
that forms it's composed of a collection
of small leaves called sepals that form
near
where the flower meets the stem and we
can see that evident
right here provides stability of the
flower and creates protective structure
for the reproductive organs of the plant
then we go back to the stigma here kind
of looking a little bit more of a zoomed
in kind of
a stereoscope image of developing female
flowers
and we can see those stigmas here on a
premature stigma here just starting to
kind of develop and come out
here's a fully mature you can see it
much larger and even like small little
fine hairs
because remember it is again responsible
for capturing
the pollen a little more macroscopic
scale
we can see here kind of those stigmas
there that are produced again at high
concentrations and those female flowers
because they're going to be responsible
as the plants trying to do that to
increase the odds
that will intercept pollen floating in
the air
they have the early female pre-flowers
so we have this stipule here
that calyx that i mentioned earlier
again this image located right here then
we have the
pistol here and which includes the
stigma and then the stippy wolf right
here and this is a small leaf-like
appendage of a leaf typically born in
pairs at the base of a leaf
stock so again might be something you
see in pairs again looking at that node
region of a particular plant
then the apical portion of the main
shoot the apical part of the shoot here
is five days after transition to a short
photo period
and we see that here in the can this bar
represents half a centimeter
this apical area this shortly after
photoperiod is going to induce flowering
and we can see here
that this plant is female because we
notice the induction of
female flowers being produced and then
lastly we have the shoe apex and this is
kind of image d and e here they're about
11 to 12 days of growth under short
photo period inducing that flowering in
the plant
and that apex phase determined by the
first day of visible inflorescence at
first they have a visible flower
these bars represent half a centimeter
and looking here again that apex that
region here particularly that top of the
plant
is going to where a lot of cell division
occurs it's a meristematic
region and it's going to be our site of
that flower production
so hopefully this provides with some
details about
general cannabis anatomy of the plant