welcome to this debaco university video
entitled identifying a white powder
here in this video we're going to be
looking at an unknown white powder
and some procedures and tests that can
be done to work towards identifying it
so here we're looking at a disclaimer
here that we'll be identifying in this
example some common household
items now those common household items
i've enlisted here again everything from
table salt baking soda table sugar
but i want you to realize that these
same concepts can be applied
to items that have increased toxicity
levels
now keep in mind that while the
substances themselves are unknown and
they might be just simple
household items may have lying around
just remember all laboratory safety
procedures should be followed
because we don't know what the substance
is and also some of the reagents used
might have increasing toxicity levels
themselves so
treat everything as dangerous and you'll
be
plenty safe following all the proper
safety procedures
so looking at again focusing on our
household items here
one common test that can be done is
simply solubility
insolubilities is a chemical property
referring to the ability of a given
substance
the solute to dissolve in a solvent how
well does it essentially dissolve
it's a measured in terms of the maximum
amount of
dissolved in a solvent at equilibrium so
how much
for example if we're looking at water
and we'll say simple table sugar
how much sugar can you put in that water
before you start to get a
it falls out of solution how much can it
suspend in there
what's its solubility so a water
solubility
test for example water solubility is one
of the most important and frequently
used physical chemical properties of
chemicals
this test to see if the substances is
polar meaning it will dissolve
or nonpolar the extreme example would be
oil
and salt for example oil won't dissolve
in water because it's nonpolar
salt is an ionic compound it is polar
and therefore it will dissolve quite
well in there
you want to add about a quarter of a
gram of a sample to a test tube
and then add about five ml of water and
a stopper and shake that test tube
and then a judgment will have to be
determined whether the cell does
or does not completely dissolve in that
water
so again solubility test is a great
quick little test you can perform
then we get into hydrochloric acid
solubility
this follows the same concept as water
solubility but for some of the items
listed
here's a few there are a few hints
bicarbonates and carbonates react with
acid to form
carbon dioxide and bubbles will form
calcium sulfate in
in corn starch are not soluble in 10
hydrochloric acid
so that's kind of a little bit of a hint
there the rest of the powders
are soluble at least the ones listed in
those household
items list so this gives you an
indication for at least an initial step
for classifying what white powder you
might be dealing with
then we have vinegar so bicarbonates and
carbonates react with the acetic acid
which is
basically the acid in vinegar vinegar is
five percent acetic acid
and they'll form carbon oxide bubbles as
we see here in the image in the beaker
it's the same as 10 hydrochloric acid
test so again
i want to typically do multiple tests to
confirm uh
what a substance we might be have as an
unknown white powder
we have the iodine test so starches
for example react with iodine to form a
blue complex
okay so i want to use about that a
quarter gram of powder
that you suspect to be cornstarch in a
test tube at two drops of
a tincture of iodine which is a solution
of iodine dissolved in alcohol
to the test tube in a few drops of water
and mix the contents and note the color
if it's kind of a yellow orange be a
negative if it's a purple black that
would be kind of a
positive test there going to iron
nitrate test so here we're going to
transfer about five
drops of the substances that were in the
water soluble
well plate test we're going to use those
same components from there
place a drop or two of the iron nitrate
solution in each test well
indicate a purple which is a positive
coloration as you can see here
or a light brown orange would be a
negative coloration now that purple if
it's well lit you can see that deep
purple color however it could almost
look black if we're depending on the
lighting so keep in mind
this would be an example again a
positive and a negative test if you have
it lit well you'll have that nice kind
of deep
purple color now the sodium hydroxide or
naoh test magnesium sulfate reacts with
sodium hydroxide naoh to form
insoluble magnesium hydroxide which is a
solid precipitate
okay so only about that quarter gram of
powder you suspect is magnesium sulfate
in a test tube and about five mils of
water
stopper and then shake the test tube to
dissolve the magnesium sulfate
add about 20 drops of the 0.2 molar
sodium hydroxide to the solution and
record your observations
this is again another great visual test
here
getting here we get a nice purple to a
nice pink color
of phenophalene test phenolphthalein is
often used as an indicator in acid-base
titrations and turns colors in acidic
solutions
in pink in basic ones so note that
phenolphthalein is slightly soluble in
water and usually dissolves in alcohols
for the for use in experiments we kind
of see that example here
of that ph of 8 to 12 we definitely have
that
pink coloration we have a ph here
a very acidic ph of that zero to eight
very clear
keep in mind though above 12 we can also
kind of get a clearing
of the solution um as well sometimes so
just be aware so that we add it as drops
we start to see that pretty pink color
we're indicating here that we have kind
of a base going on in that test tube
to get a little bit more precise we can
also go to ph testing this is
using a universal indicator can be used
to test the ph
of only water soluble substances via a
color change so keep that in mind
that it fails the water solubility test
the ph test is not going to be
one we want to use simply add drops of
the universal indicator directly to the
test tube of the water
solubility test and record the color and
that will help indicate
based on the color matching what ph
you're dealing with for those water
soluble substances
then we've got benedict's reagent this
is to test for simple sugars
i have the procedure all listed here
keep in mind banister reagent does
require the solution to be added mixed
and then heated in boiling water bath
for about three to five
minutes after that time you may observe
a color change of the solution or at
that time is when you want to observe
the potential for a color change you
have that aqua blue to kind of green
coloration that'd be a negative
test you have that yellow to orange that
would be an indication of a positive
test
after heating note this test cannot
detect the simple sugar
sucrose so again these all do have
limitations so just be mindful of those
now we have our birette's reagent here
and here we're looking at
the test for proteins so there's a
procedure
listed here i keep in mind that we want
to observe any color change again but we
want to allow this
reaction to curve potentially for up to
five minutes it's not a quick reaction
and go look at it
want to let it sit for about five
minutes and we have that kind of like
denim blue
coloration that would be negative if we
have that lavender purple coloration
that'd be indication of
a positive test so again hopefully this
helps kind of for the common household
substances
be able to determine what those white
powders are keep in mind to file all
laboratory
procedures stay safe even though they
have a low toxicity
some of these are reagents here we want
to be very careful with