when trying to grow any plant material
there's always pests to consider
in this debaco university student series
video we're going to look at identifying
rabbit damage on cannabis plants and
we're going to see kind of the damage
that they can do as well at the end i'm
going to suggest on how to properly
install a fence to reduce the chance of
this problem happening to you
[Music]
so this plant has just suffered some
physical not biological damage you could
tell this because the rest of the plant
doesn't really seem to have this issue
it's just localized right here towards
the bottom of the plant it also doesn't
really affect how each of the leaves
come out how their color is and
everything like that this is actually
physical damage that comes from being
nod by a bunny now you usually wouldn't
think that bunnies would be an issue
when it comes to growing cannabis but as
you can see here one decided to come up
to this plant and gnaw just the outside
causing this physical damage
this is localized to the bottom of the
plant because of their size and height
pretty much but
they do come and will eat your plant so
unless you have proper fencing up you
have animal issues to worry about
and this shows the proper way to install
the fence to prevent the rabbits from
simply digging underneath