welcome to another debaco university
video
here looking at identifying basic bones
of the body
so here we're going to look at parts of
the skeletal system and some of the
major bones that you should be
able to recognize and identify
well starting in general with bones well
bones are comprised
the vertebral skeleton of animals which
protects the various organs of the body
this is an endoskeleton it looks kind of
very porous as we can see here
and in those pores when the organism is
living
it will produce red and white blood
cells it also store minerals provide
structure and support for the body
and enable mobility bones come in a
variety of shapes and sizes and have
complex internal and external structures
that's lightweight but yet
strong i'm going to go over some of
those focusing mainly on the human body
here
so when we're classifying our bones we
have
four general classifications as
presented here
we have the long bones which include the
femur tibula
tibia fibula humerus radius and ulna we
also have short bones and those are the
carpals
of the wrist and tarsals of the ankle we
have our flat bones like for example our
skull
or sternum and an irregular bone such as
our vertebrae or our pelvis
and here we have the skull and mandible
and the skull is the bony structure that
forms the head
and vertebrates it supports the
structure of the face provides a
protective cavity for the brain
and over here we see a collection of
skulls
the mandible is the lower jaw or what's
typically referred to as a jaw bone
and is the largest strongest bone in the
human face and it holds the lower teeth
in place
in the image directly over here we
notice it's highlighted
in green to highlight exactly where the
mandible is located
uh in distinct relation to the skull
now we have something called vertebrae
and these are individual bones that
comprise the verbal column that has
curves
the natural curves have more add more
strength and a straight line so it can
support the weight of the body and
provide balance needed to walk
the sections of the verbal column
include the cervical thoracic
and the lumbar regions we can see the
cervical
here's the thoracic here's the lumbar
and then the fused areas way down here
would be
the pelvic region in addition
then we have the rib cage and ribcage
functions to protect the heart and lungs
in the thoracic cavity
also aids in respiration provide support
for the upper
limbs three main classifications of ribs
based on different points of attachment
we have our true or fixed ribs that have
a direct point of attachment to the
sternum
we have our false ribs and these kind of
have this kind of cartilage connection
that then attaches to the sternum
and then we have the floating ribs here
which are simply not attached in any way
to the sternum
however this image is a slightly
inaccurate this rib here should have a
piece of cartilage attaching it there
there should only be two floating ribs
those attachment points
those again those true libs true ribs
one through seven are attached to that
coastal cartilage directly to that
sternum
the false ribs here are
8 through 10 and are not attached to the
sternum but to the coastal cartilage
of the 7th rib above then the floating
ribs will last two 11 and 12
are only attached to the vertebrae and
no direct attachment even with cartilage
to the sternum
then we have the pelvis this is the area
of attachment of the upper leg bones and
contains portions of the vertebral
column
those fused portions down here and we
can see this is definitely an irregular
bone
one of the strongest bones because it is
the main point of attachment
and a lot of the weight and pressure is
exerted in this area of the body
then we get to our leg bones and these
uh we have the femur here the large
one here it's a thigh bone it's the
longest bone and is considered to be the
strongest bone in the body
they have the patella which is known as
the kneecap it's a flat circular
triangular bone
that protects the knee joint we have the
fibula
which is the long thin and lateral bone
of the lower leg and is parallel to the
tibia
and helps stabilize the ankle and
support the muscles of the lower leg
and we have the tibia here known as the
shin bone and is the second largest bone
in the body
a lot of people confuse the tibia in the
fibula tibia you can think as
thicker i'm here because it is a thicker
of the two bones
in the lower leg looking at the arm now
we have the humerus
and we have the radius in the ulna here
so we can see initially kind of a
similar structure that we saw in the leg
but of course on smaller bones overall
and the radius and ulna
allows a rotation uh to occur there
we get into the hands and the hand is
located at the distal end of each arm
it's the end
and we can see we have our carpals which
are kind of the wrist bones there
the metacarpals and then the phalanges
um that we have here
and there would be an interior and a
posterior view when we're looking at
the rotation of how those would be
presented
and lastly we have the feet and this is
the terminal portion of the limb which
bears the weight and allows locomotion
or movement
can also be important for footprints
looking at the foot here in the bone
structure we see
very similar to the hands so be
mindful of that that there are a lot of
similarities between the
upper limbs and lower limbs and being
able to provide a distinction of those
can be important when you're looking to
identify bones of the body