so welcome to this tobacco university
video we'll be looking at identifying
chemicals
with spectrometry we're going to get
into some of the details but this is
that quick
overview we have a light source this
sample
we have a dispersion element we have a
detector and we're going to generate
at the end a spectrum here so first off
we have to understand color because
we're going to be looking at different
wavelengths and light is a form of
energy and travels in a wave
and the light's wavelength measured in
nanometers between nm
determines the color so you can see here
the red wavelength
has a red coloration and then we have
the green and we have the blue
we have all these different wavelengths
red has a longer wavelength
than the blue example here and that
allows us the separation
of colors you see the uh kind of also
represented here in the upper portion
now the color that you see so the color
that you're interpreting for looking at
this
ladybug here we're seeing a red color
well white light's coming in
and this bug is absorbing many of the
colors
however red wavelength light is being
reflected
so keep in mind that objects typically
selectively absorb specific wavelengths
of light
the color you see is the color or
wavelength that is being reflected
in the case of a white surface all white
light is coming in and all the
wavelengths are being
also reflected off that surface and we
interpret that as
white coloration so we take a white
light and put it in a prism you can
separate out into the different
wavelengths
we see start seeing colors we're seeing
the color that is reflected
now the basics of kind of the spectro
the spectrophotometer is that it
measures the absorbance of
a solution as light of a specified
wavelength is passed through it
so what does that look like well here we
have a light source that goes through a
lens
and it goes through a prism and
basically separates it out into
different wavelengths
we then have a machine that can select a
very specific
wavelength from there so here we're
seeing we're selecting that kind of
yellow wavelength here
then we have our sample solution in a
cuvette and we have a detector and we
have a digital meter
or display here so we're observing or
we're
seeing what gets passed through we know
what the machine knows what was
basically
sent then we're looking at passing it
through the sample
and we're detecting to what is basically
passed through
that sample so what does a spectrometer
look like well this is an example of one
here and they have sensors that
determine the amount of a specific
wavelength of light
is being absorbed by a chemical solution
if no light is absorbed the absorbance
meter will read
0.00 as wavelength is
being adjusted the absorbance will also
change this will be a difference
in that absorbance reading results can
be graphed to develop an absorption
spectrum for a given
chemical and what does an exorbitant
spectrum look like this is a very basic
example here
but this simply acts as like a
fingerprint for a chemical
this can also allow for comparisons to
occur since
two different substances to determine if
they're the same substance or if they're
the same substance
and then known to unknown also for a
chemical comparison there
so based on the absorbance spectrum
generated will tell us the similarity
of two substances particularly if two
are unknown whether or not they're a
match
for each other so we're looking at
preparing our chemicals for the spec
analysis chemicals must be in a liquid
form which may require dilution so it's
important to keep in mind
cuvettes must be used that match the
experiment and there's different types
of cuvettes available
use distilled or tap water depending on
the material you're being tested
keep in mind we often will use just the
kind of
the chemical solvent as what we call a
blank so this is a
cuvette that just simply has the
chemical solvent which is being analyzed
and dissolved in
the known or unknown sample and this
allows kind of for that correction of
any potential data noise
now proper cuvette handling so keep in
mind that because this is such a precise
procedure
we want to be very careful on how we're
handling our cuvettes
we want to ensure that we're using the
proper cuvette materials for step one
and then we also want to avoid direct
contact when handling the transmission
sides
so when we talk about transmission size
what does that mean well if we look at
our cuvettes example here
you can see there's definitely two clear
sides and two more opaque sides
the clear sides are the ones that's
going to be that lights going to be
projecting
through so we want to avoid contact with
those we want to be sure that before
we're placing that into the
machine here we're wiping that cuvette
with tissue paper
before placing there to ensure there's
nothing on the outside that's going to
conflict
with the ability to get an accurate
reading of our sample
and when we're using the
spectrophotometer here i want to follow
the directions since each is unique
however the basics that apply for all of
them is you want to let the machine warm
up
that can be very short duration or very
long duration make sure you're allowing
that sufficient time for that
i want to enter the desired wavelength
that we're going to be studying insert
the cuvette containing a blank solution
making sure the clear sides are where
the light is passing through we don't
want to insert it the wrong way
and then we want to zero that solution
we want to repeat the basic process
for the samples we first start with the
blank that kind of controls
any of the solvent takes out any of that
noise and then we want to proceed with
our samples
there some are digital some will have
knobs some meters
so just keep that in mind there when
we're creating that absorbance
spectrum so with a sample plot the
absorbance versus wavelength
keep keeping the same sample the same
the wavelengths will be changed and the
resulting
absorption reading should be documented
so we're noticing as we change our
wavelength here in this example we're
also having a change in absorbance and
we're documenting that
the goal here is to determine the number
of peaks the sample may have
which will aid in developing an idea
of specifically what substance we might
be dealing with