as the title suggests this is gonna go
over the immune system basics the graph
here kind of gives you the very brief
overview we have an initial response
protective immunity and memory that
occurs keep in mind that memory can
occur over years and this is what makes
vaccines effective our initial exposure
will have a dramatic rise in antibody or
effector T cells I also provided links
here to two other YouTube videos you'll
also find the links to the slides and
references in a description below so
first off the immune system in general
looking at the human body the human body
is a wonderful place because it's safe
it's nutrient rich and it's temperature
and pH are optimized this is the fact
that your body is able to maintain
homeostasis to keep the cells nice and
protected this is quite an attractive to
other organisms that don't belong in the
body these are conditions which are very
difficult to find as a result we have
those organisms that want to get into
the body
many of these provide value may help
maintain the environment by breaking
down macromolecules that we can't such
as an example of some enzymes
synthesizing needed nutrients and
keeping harmful organisms in check
however not every organism is out to
benefit the body there are some bad
apples for example these bad apples want
to essentially compete for nutrients
overload the system with toxins take
over and destroy cell machinery and kill
body cells as a result we can have that
sick feeling and these are
disease-causing organisms that our body
must defend against physically such as
for example via our skin and with
biological means such as white blood
cells the supporting infrastructure
ought to the immune system is something
called the lymphatic system but not only
touch on that now I'm going to bring
that more in when we do circulatory
system because as you can see here it is
closely related
however the lymphatic system is a
central location for storage and
distribution of immune cells and
proteins if you're sick so we might say
oh my lymph nodes are swollen
that's a network of capillaries ducts
and nodes throughout our organist and
you can see that here how it does look
very similar to our circulatory system
now a pathogen so my
or tourism that can cause disease have
some examples of some pathogens here are
viruses bacteria fungi parasites but
it's important that can cause disease so
pathogen is only one third of the
necessary components that cause disease
we have a pathogen that needs the proper
host and needs the proper environment to
result in disease and often give the
examples in throat of focusing in humans
here certain pathogens that may affect
plants tobacco mosaic virus powdery
mildew are a pathogen that affect plants
so they need the proper host an
environment to cause disease that
pathogen exists in the air particularly
powdery mildew we've breezed those
spores in we're not the proper hosts
so therefore with disease is not caused
you need all three of these factors to
come into play the same time to result
in a disease what is the enemy look like
so what is our immune system protecting
us against well there's a wide range of
organisms that try to exploit our bodies
this is just a few examples keep in mind
there's cellular enemies it's parasites
and fungi but also a cellar or nonliving
one such as a virus
remember viruses DNA or RNA wrapped in a
protein coat and we have our
procure-to-pay for example our bacteria
so all of these can do our body harm as
a result in their immune system to be
able to handle all of these we have
different blood cell types so RBC again
stands for red blood cells now and we
refer them as erythrocytes there is an
example of them transporting oxygen we
talked about them we did a hypotonic
isotonic and hypertonic situations here
how they can swell up and in trouble and
then white blood cells WBC they're
called leukocytes and as you can see
here there's many different types of
white blood cells there's only one type
of red blood cell red blood cells have a
biconcave disc which are important for
increasing the surface area to volume
ratio elements of blood so red blood
cells white blood cells gonna be our
main focus I don't want you to forget
about we also have platelets in our
blood which we'll talk about when we do
the circulatory system white blood cells
are probably the most important part of
the immune system let's see here the
large table kind of discussing them and
see their importance here's our
overthrow sites and here's our platelets
there and you can pause the video and
take a look at those in greater detail
but we're gonna focus mainly with the
immune system the white blood cells so
some of those white blood cells this is
a great summary chart if you watch some
of the other immune system videos to
come back to this kind of events at a
nice cell type characteristics location
and in general image these are four main
types here and on the last slide here we
have the other four so again good slides
to come back to use as review to make
sure you're able to identify some of the
different white blood cell types of the
immune system