in this tobacco university video we'll
be looking at impacts
on insect development so while there are
many we're going to focus on a few
very important key ones here related to
forensics
to take into consideration when we're
trying to time out the development of
certain
insects so keep in mind that stages
follow
a pattern within insect development so
because there's a progression of the
insect life cycle that follows this
predictable
unknown pattern as a result the rate of
stage transition
can be altered by various conditions and
knowing
what that alteration may be can allow us
to kind of
develop an idea of exactly the time or
backtrack that time
to when the original first kind of
time of death may have occurred which is
important when we're investigating crime
scenes
so keep in mind temperature is kind of
one of the major ones we want to keep
track of because insects
are ectothermic meaning they're cold
blooded their body temperatures are
largely dictated by the outside
temperature so only when the outside
temperature warms an insect's internal
body temperature
to a critical level can the insect
become active
it's becoming active what's allowed to
do is it can eat and grow at that time
so keep in mind that temperature is
something we definitely want to be
making note of
and potential previous temperature for
looking at multiple days going back
in time to try to determine the time of
death now
insects to calculate the postmortem
interval well
insects can be used to estimate the time
between death and discovery of the
corpse which is called the post-mortem
interval
to increase the accuracy temperature
data and identifying
the presence of drugs in a corpse in
addition to if the corpse was wrapped
in a material and the conditions it was
exposed to externally
should also be documented because all
these variables
can be kind of factored in to try to
develop the closest possible
estimation to that original point or
time of death
you can see here definitely how the
incubation temperature and time and
hours
definitely can have an impact so keeping
in mind
knowing the weather conditions we're
talking outside but also knowing
the conditions the corpse was in and the
conditions that the corpse was found and
was
wrapped for example some sort of
external wrapping can also
influence those intervals as well now
drugs can also impact the
presence of insects so any drugs present
in the corpse at the time of death
can be ingested by the insects
themselves and affect the rate of maggot
development
a drug like cocaine speeds up the
development while some poisons such as
arsenic
and glycosides can also slow it down
so important to know and identify what
drugs may have been present
here we see a hinge of a person being
exposed to arsenic poisoning through
contaminated
water over an extended period of time
now all flies keep in mind
are not the same so not all fly species
are found everywhere
identifying and document the species is
important
for example this skipper fly is only
found in urban settings and the house
and blowflies are flesh flies that can
be found in both urban
and rural settings so as a result
knowing not only the general species
but also getting to the scientific name
can also be important
because the flies aren't all the same we
said oh flies were present
this is where entomologists would come
in and specifically identify that
particular fly which has been really
important for the investigative
process