in this debacco University video I'm
going to go over the impact of organic
and mineral-based fertilizers in
relation to cannabis
[Music]
yield all right so I know there's some
great debate between organic and mineral
based fertilizers so let's take a look
at it from a scientific Viewpoint first
off here is the research article if you
want to to dive into the information a
little more detail I provide the proper
uh citation right here I'll give you my
take on it so first off there were two
liquid fertilizer types there was the um
organic and the Mineral Solution both
were prepared in order to contain the
same concentration of macronutrients
based on manufacturer provided
information macronutrients are nitrogen
phosphorus potassium calcium magnesium
were the main focus of the study no
signs or symptoms of micronutrient
deficiencies or toxicities were observed
between the organic and mineral
treatments you want to know all the
details of the f concentrations the PHS
the ECS the um Solutions and the
compositions and ratios of the
fertilizer Solutions it's all provided
here for you to take a look at but again
take a message in order to provide the
same same concentration of
macronutrients despite being organic or
mineral so fertili concentrations and
the general sequence so the
concentrations were 80 uh milligram per
liter 160 Mig per liter and 240
fertilizer treatments were applied in in
liquid solution uh twice per week
starting at day 22 um and you can see
table two which is located right here um
for more details it's days after
planting plants did not receive any
further fertilization during the last
week of cultivation and we can kind of
see the um days here the cultivation
week the fertilizer solution the
accumulative solution amounts and then
the concentrations at 80 160 and 240 so
all broken down right there for you now
plant sampling what was done here in
this study was at two Harvesters during
the stage at 22 and Day 36 days after
planting four Harvest during the
flowering stage at days 54 69 83 and 99
at each Harvest four plants per
treatment one plant per treatment and a
replicant um were cut at the base and
separated into three fa uh factorial
sections stems leaves and in
fluorescence there so this is kind of
the breakdown of basically how the study
was was
conducted uh when we're looking at plant
comparisons at Day 36 and day 99 how did
they actually look so here's our
fertilizer um concentration for organic
on the top row and mineral on the bottom
row here we're looking at Day 36 and
then day 99 which is the Harvest just so
you can see some visual uh comparisons
there so it's the end of the Ved stage
and this is basically the Harvest there
so you can do some visual comparisons if
you want between those now looking at
the the flower comparisons um we're
looking at day 99 of harvest plants were
defoliated to show only the infloresence
just before flower and we can see that
located uh in the image right here we're
looking at the source of variation we're
looking at the concentration of nitrogen
phosphorus pottassium
um uh looking at those different
contents there we could see just kind of
how we're looking at breaking those down
here from a kind of table standpoint but
also from a visual standpoint let's get
into some more what the what this
research actually did show so looking at
the vegetative plant growth well it was
not affected by the type of fertilizer
as indicated by similar values of leaf
area and specific Leaf area so looking
at kind of our data table right over
here when you see um NS basically no
significant uh difference there plant
dry matter which is a increase steadily
over time for both fertilizer types
marginal differences shown between day
22 and day 66 we can kind of see that 69
I'm sorry we can see that from here um
to basically day 69 right here again
plant dry matter we're seeing very
marginal differences but not really
anything too significant we're going to
get to be uh okay down here for um Leaf
area per plant the interaction of
fertilizer type and days after planting
was not significant fertilizer type was
significant with larger Leaf area for
the mineral treatments compared to the
organic treatments Again by a slight
margin here when you see those different
letters
and organic is the green bars and
mineral is the um black and white bars
there's no significant difference
between fertilizer types were found for
a specific Leaf area and that's looking
again at uh letter C here decreasing
trend from day 69 days after planting to
range between uh 282.30
cm squared uh per gram there now the
least squared means and all the little
information here about what's you're
seeing in these graphs is provided right
here just to give you a little bit of
anide idea but we're looking at that
kind of veget to flowering is flipping
between Day 36 and day 54 and we can see
differences in Trends located here
during the vegetative part what the
plants actually look like well this is a
kind of a late harvest leaf sample day
99 leaves from the different canopy
positions it Illustrated for the factors
fertilizer type which is vertical and
then fertilizer concentration which is
horizontal so this is the low end of the
fertilizer the 80 the 160 and the 240
and we see organic in the top row and
mineral here in the bottom row note that
there was some tip ear at the high
higher fertilizer concentrations uh so
just keep note of that that there are
some toxicity Sy uh symptoms as well
looking at the yield difference so final
yield differences a was mainly
attributed to at least 2 weeks before
Harvest when the mineral fation had
significantly higher INF fluoresence dry
matter than organic treatments CBD yield
um differences between fertilizer types
was lower due to lower CBD concentration
with mineral F fertilization indicating
a possible dilution effect during the
last 2 weeks before Harvest influenced
dry matter strongly increased and Canam
were accumulated for part C here
presenting a large sink with high
simulate nutrient demand there again we
see the same coloration difference
between organic and our mineral NS
referring to no significant difference
there now nitrogen forms we need to keep
in mind that one main difference among
nitrogen forms and fertilizer types is
that organic fertilizers contain higher
ratios of the ammonia and the nitrates
than mineral fertilizers so when we're
looking at our comparison you know the
type of nitrogen plays a role those
ammoniums and those um nitrates versus
those nitrites is going to be very
different and how those potentially can
be absorbed by the plant and what the
odds are of them leeching or
denitrifying there uh so just keep that
in mind that the organic fertilizing the
inheritage of the ammonium and the NO3
the nitrate
concentrations now NPK levels uh in the
leaves compared to flowers so kind of an
interesting kind of correlation here
blue representing the lower green the
mid and red the higher fertilization
rates nitrogen is easily Mobile in the
plant tissue which can be observed by
the presence of Curves of accumulation
depletion within nitrogen levels
phosphorus is also a mobile um nutrient
here we can see that right here but
movement in the leaves to flowers was
not clearly as visible as it was for
nitrogen all treatments reached a
plateau for phosphorus around day
69 uh at the final Harvest uh plants of
the 8060 and 240 accumulated 41.9 49.7
and 59 milligrams of phosphorus per
plant in the leaves respectively uh
phosphorus content in infloresence was
up 4.2 times higher than the leaves so
the flowers compared to the leaves where
that's accumulating is a definitely an
interesting Factor there again this is
looking at the leaf column and then the
flowers the of potassium was similar to
phosphorus Only Exception plants for the
lowest fertilizer concentration 80
reached their Plateau earlier um at day
69 so again little nice comparison here
between what's happening in the leaves
compared to what's happening in the
flowers now when we're looking at
phosphorus fertilization um in this
study no significant differences between
fertilizer concentrations were found for
phosphorus concentrations in the
infloresence at the final Harvest PE
concentration in leaves stems and sub
rate were significantly higher for the
highest treatment uh indicating overall
fertilization with phosphorus at the
flowering stage maintaining High
nutrient levels in leaves and substrates
is not relevant at the Harvest point so
this is important for consideration uh
that we really want to be mindful of how
much fertilizer we're adding uh because
it could lead to negative effects or
really just increased cost with no
increased benefit in the end
product now mineral fertilization
generally um has shows higher nutrient
uptake and ergonomic uses efficiencies
compared to organic treatments mainly
because it's immediately available and
it's not really needs to be broken down
um by anything so keep this in mind that
this is an important consideration when
we're comparing these fertilizer types
those organic fertilizers um signally
lower PL infloresence dry matter Leaf
area and finally CBD yield of organic
treatments are supported by the general
lower nitrogen uptake efficiency
especially in the last 2 weeks which is
a major sink stage where that nutrients
are potentially going into that flour
compared to those mineral treatments so
it did kind of Wan or did kind of
struggle those last two weeks there now
if using organic fertilizers uh you
should uh you should be applied earlier
and potentially at higher rates than
mineral components to be available
during those final two weeks of
flowering when the sink demand for
infloresence is very high try to meet
those demands and because minerals are
available so quickly they can meet those
demands and the plant can uptake it
right away because they're need a little
breakdown time to be absorbed by the
plant um applying a little bit more
especially paying attention those final
two weeks right before Harvest could be
important to maintain quality yield Now
The Best of Both Worlds you know a
higher availability of mineral
fertilizers can be important for plant
initial growth while organic fertilizers
can be employed as a more suitable
sustainable nutrient complement during
the flowering stage without major yield
losses it's kind of playing to the
strengths of both using mineral
fertilizers for that quick kind of
available and using organic fertilizers
for that longer more sustained growth
off for the
plant now take home message here we're
looking at fertilizer concentration the
fertilizer concentration of 160 uh
produced 95% of the CBD yield compared
to the highest rate which is 240 while
receiving oneir less nutrients so if you
can get 95% of the yield with a third
less nutrients um that can really help
the profitability standpoint that can
really help you know Max maximizing
yields by minimizing
inputs now organic fertilizer usage if
you're going to be using this Source um
you may have to add more than someone
else using mineral based fertilizers
because of the lower nutrient uptake
efficiency so we had to keep that in
mind and the nutrient acquisition was
lower for organic fertilizer during the
final two weeks before Harvest resulting
in reduced biomass and CBD yield
compared to Mineral fertilizer
treatments now we're looking at
phosphorus fertilizer here nothing
against any of these but be mindful of
the amount of phosphorus that you're
adding uh the fertilizer rate for
phosphorus can be generally reduced
during the end of flowering to avoid
unproductive nutrient accumulation in
the vegetative plant organs so that's
especially mindful if you're using these
very high Bloom based fertilizers that
have 50 55 45% phosphorus plants don't
need as much phosphorus as many Growers
have been led to believe and this study
continues to prove that showing that it
doesn't really help the flowers at all
does accumulate in the stems and the
leaves but those typically are plant
parts that Growers are not really
looking at harvesting or receiving any
benefit from so cut down on your
phosphorous fertilizer you can help
reduce your chance at environmental
contamination reduce your cost and still
maintain the same yields