growers often wonder how plant hormones
can
affect cannabis plants well here we're
going to look at a scientific study
that's the impact of the plant growth
regular naa
on cannabis
[Music]
all right let's get into the study here
so first off the two hormones naa and
bap are the ones that were studied anase
is synthetic meaning it does not occur
naturally plant hormone
in the auxin family so we're going to
see kind of how auxins
impact cannabis plant growth this auxin
family can also be toxic at high
concentrations to plants
concentration and dose is very important
the common ingredient with many plant
plant-rooting natural
horticultural products there so a lot of
them say oh
naturally occurring you know auxins well
this one is a synthetically produced
but it is in the auxin family which is a
naturally occurring
plant hormone now bap is the first
generation synthetic cytokinin another
plant hormone
that causes plant growth in development
responses such as setting blossoms and
stimulating cell division
is an inhibitory of respiratory kinase
implants
and increases post-harvest life in green
vegetables
we can see the examples of those
hormones here both of these were done
in an exact study on cannabis if you're
wondering what that study was and some
of maybe more of the specifics
here's the proper citation here's kind
of that first page there for you're
welcome to go research it
take a look at it and look at it in more
detail however what they basically found
i'm going to provide kind of that
general summary
here we're looking at mean plant height
so we're looking at our two graphs here
the control is the solid line in both
and then the lighter or dashed line is
the different
hormones if you mind a is the auxin
family bep is in the cytokinin family
so in these graphs we're looking at the
mean plant height over all three tested
genotypes
the nas number elephants in graph a up
here and baps
in the graph b down here the means
covered with at least
one identical lowercase letter did not
have a significant difference at a
p-value
of 0.05 the arrows show the period
60-90 days during which applications
took place so we could see the
application made here around day 6
and then another application made here
around day 90.
and we're seeing the changes that occur
over time overall a days after planting
the plant height is going to be taller
in the control which is basically the
non-treated plant
compared to the one that had the auxin
family hormone applied
and here the control also ended up mean
plant height was taller
compared to the one what had the
cytokinins applied to it
again these are all significantly
different and we can see that throughout
the growth cycle here
now the number of internodes so as we're
looking at kind of counting the
internodes
the mean number of internodes per
axillary branch over two tested
genotypes
and you can look at the study for more
information on that means covered with
at least one identical lowercase letter
did not offer significance
again that p value of 0.05
the arrows showed the time at point six
days after planting in
the first application and treated with
the
auxin and the cytokinin respectively
here we're looking at the number of
internets we kind of see a similar
pattern the control having more
internodes
than the oxen family hormone or the
cytokinin family hormone
that's basically true shortly after
pollination i'm sorry certainly after
application
they were both applied and then we see
that separation after that point
then the mean number of axillary
branches we're looking at the branching
point now the cannabis
in centimeters over the three tested
genotypes with our same two hormones
being studied
again same statistics applied p greater
than .05 is the different letters
the error shows the same point six days
after planting for the first application
and again here we see a large difference
of the control compared to the
auxin family our length of axillary
branches
much longer in the control compared to
those with that were applied with dioxin
we see a similar difference in most
cases with the
cytokinin applied but a generally a
similar trend even though it is
reduced in length of axillary branches
with the cytokinin applied one
now pgrs are important for cannabis
sativa so
the results of this study showed that
this extra
these exteriorly applied plant growth
regulators abbreviate pgrs
mainly nan bap had seen the impacts on
the plant architecture
of this cannabis sativa both of these
pgrs led to more complex
compact plant morphology so that might
be advantageous because the plants
didn't grow more
doesn't mean that's necessarily what
growers were looking for the use of na
led to more compact plant architecture
with a consistently high inflorescence
yield for the for
the particular genotype that they
studied a cbd or cannabidiol
content was not affected in these so
again good to see what was affected more
morphologically
but not affected on the cannabinoid
produced
now keep in mind a word of caution here
that there's no approved pgrs so in the
cultivation of medicinal grade cannabis
production there are currently no
approved pgrs to modify plant
architecture
this study was really just showing that
these are pgrs in production under good
manufacturing practice
typically abbreviated gmp or good
agriculture and collection practice
gacp guidelines are not clearly defined
so any products applied to the plants
should be documented
uh for sure there again there's
different rules always
laws and changing but definitely
document it as of right now there's no
approved pgrs for cannabis applications
so if we're looking at kind of our kind
of important for that plant morphology
it is important to note that the use of
pgrs did not reduce the biomass
yield in the content of cannabinoids the
goal is to produce small compact plants
intended for indoor growing environments
the example here i have potentially for
like a grow tent or something that might
be ceiling
in generally size limited the naa
produced a short habit plant reduced the
number of internodes in
sitting in the shortest axillary side
branches so that's the effects of
applying that
auxin family hormone the cytokinin-based
family of hormones bap create that short
shorter habit
reduce the number of internodes and
shorter axillary side branches so just
important to note that both of these
create that more
compact plant which might be
advantageous for some growers
now the degradation so synthetic ias
which are endol
acetic acid are more stable than the
ones applied
and generously which are the ones
produced in the plant
and are degraded at a slower rate so
we're looking at considering plant
hormones
we want to consider the fact that they
are going to be broken down
now is it going to be a really rapid
kind of quick exponential
decay here is it going to be a slower
more linear form
that could be dependent on the exact
hormone depending on the condition
depending on a lot of environmental
factors as well so again
important to take into consideration you
want to know the application
and the concentration so with all
hormones when using synthetic pgrs it's
very important
to know the exact exactly the
appropriate application method
and also the concentrations to avoid
potential negative impact on the final
product
as you mentioned one of these is an
auxin family hormone well
certain oxygen family hormones applied
at the right levels
high levels can actually be herbicides
or basically kill
plants like 2 4-d falls into that
category
it's important though with ias it's a
high concentration or toxic and utilized
as an herbicide and that would be that 2
4-d
so again a little can be good but a lot
could potentially kill the plant so
just good practices for growers to know
the application
know the right concentration look at
scientific studies like the one
presented here in detail
to make sure you're getting all those
correct so you're getting the potential
benefits that you're seeking
without any of the potential negative
side effects