Photography is very important for
crime-scene investigation if you're the
head person responsible for taking
photographs that's extremely important
here's something that's involved being
able to take good photographs is also a
very important skill to have because it
would be very helpful now you do not
need the most expensive of camera gear
or equipment we're gonna go over some of
the key photographs you need to be
considering or taking when investigating
a crime scene so first off the basic
rules never move an object before
photographing it and this doesn't mean
just take one quick picture and move on
you can may want to take it from
multiple angles you might be looking at
multiple zoom in multiple areas you
might be photographing again depending
with that object maybe I think that's
important even if you don't deem it
important to begin with it's very
important to take pictures before you
move it the key thing to remember when
in doubt take a photograph especially
now with the digital age of photographs
it's carry here extra memory cards and
make sure you got plenty of space and
just take a lot of pictures now
photograph advantages the reason why we
take a lot of pictures is it's a quick
method of documentation that's very
accurate generates interest and can be
used as evidence digital images can be
enhanced and also stored want to be
careful on you know how far we enhance
them but the key part is they can be
stored for a long periods of time how
they can be backed up and this is all
important especially if a crime scene
gets reinvestigated later so the age of
digital photography you know could be
the larger cameras or even just phones
as well in some way documenting that
what was seen so some of the
disadvantages though of photography so
it's not all pros they can be altered
that's one to be careful of you know
modifying them a distortion is possible
and perspective can add an influence so
we're not creates a scene that you know
through modifications that didn't really
occur nor do we want to just capture one
thing without maybe taking into account
something else that occurred there so
they're not perfect but they are
definitely a major piece it's expected
of documentation for crime scenes
so perspective is everything so I
mentioned this where are we got to be
careful on how we take pictures you know
looking like the baby is large feet
person holding the plane it's really
just coming in for a landing look quick
here else there's pigs feet and properly
placed flags here off of the swimmer so
perspective is everything we want to be
mindful not just focusing maybe on one
thing gonna be focused on the entire
scene to make sure we're not causing
some sort of false story or false
depiction or what might be going on in
that image so types of photographs will
live establishing photographs mid medium
range of photographs close-up in
macroscopic photographs we're kind of
gonna break those down and kind of roll
represented right here basically we want
to establish the scene we want to get to
an area where maybe something came in
this doorway a close-up look so it may
have occurred it may be more of a
macroscopic view maybe the details of
what's going on there so that
establishing photograph depicts an
overall view of the scene this can
include a broad shot the buildings the
approach to escape routes witnesses and
etc so here we're gonna be focusing on
here justice gives you an idea is looks
like a the high school here a car nearby
you know where to be focusing on the
doorway here but kind of give us an idea
okay maybe someone could pull up here
very easily
there's park benches near the convened
witnesses check the front of the school
so this kind of establishes the area
getting a little bit closer to said
we're focusing on that door in this case
this is the medium range of photograph
shows the relationship between objects
with the concentration on the immediate
scene who shows a relationship of
evidence in a given space so while we're
focused on the door now that we're a
little bit closer you see that there's
some sort of water hose here that could
plate into it out it could be some could
have tripped on it so I'm gonna move
that there could be soil that's left
behind it could be some sort of movement
some sort of trace elements also the
door is propped open so maybe there
could be fingerprints on here I'll look
at the close proximity here to a corner
so this this all gives us ideas and that
relationship of how these objects may
interrelate we need to close up
photography this is depicts a single
item as evidence and oftentimes these
are included from multiple angles so
here we're seeing the door
popped up with this piece of wood could
take it from another angle taking it
we're really focused on just that one
piece of evidence there that maybe this
was added by someone to kind of allow
for easy access in and out there are
macroscopic so they're not microscopic
macroscopic this is an extreme closeup
of very small objects in which the size
of the subject is in in the photograph
is greater than life in size so here
we're looking just as an example of a
fly you can see a lot of great details
that's going on it's great for this
evidence this type of photograph is
evidence for showing that fine detail
defying the subpoenas to find hairs can
really get at something that might be
needed as trace evidence for example so
I'll photographs need include a size
reference to help establish that so now
I'll always do we have this advantage of
having the ruler but we could have the
need for putting a dollar bill that's
six inches long or something of known
size pocket knife or just something a
quarter a penny some that we know the
size of so that it can be determined and
easily measured as we get the size
general idea the perspective of the size
of whatever object we're looking at
hopefully this is helpful looking at our
information about photography and how
important it is for crime scenes