so when many people hear cannabis in the
production of cannabis they're thinking
about the plant
and needing to be a botanist or a
breeder however we can't forget about
the fact that getting into
cannabis and some of the cannabinoids as
well some of the fertilizer
regimens the importance of having a
chemist
involved in the production of cannabis
plants so in this debaco university
video we're going to get into the
importance of a cannabis
chemist
[Music]
so if you're considering getting into
the cannabis industry and you're
interested in chemistry
there may be a job for you let's take a
look at some of those aspects
so first off the job description well
chemistry scientist is responsible
for devising creating and implementing
new product formulations
as well as manufacturing chemists find
ways to increase the efficiency of the
extraction methods used
within the laboratory they send test
samples to third-party companies and use
the information from them
to further improve upon the system in
use
so the chemist of that is trying to
extract those certain cannabis try to
understand how those molecules behave
to be able to increase the overall
efficiency of the extraction
process now the day-to-day activities of
a chemist looking uh that is
specializing the cannabis industry
you want to optimize the recovery of all
extractions
optimize the speed of the restraint
extractions as well
if you can produce the same thing in
shorter period of time well that allows
for increased efficiency and your
responsibility is to oversee the
efficiency as well as the purification
of the processes
now it's responsible for the production
of new formulations as well
they coordinate with third-party
laboratories to send them samples and
get those
results back they maintain strict levels
of accuracy
and they interpret testing results they
track records inventories product
related supplies as well it's very
important to keep track of
that and document all of these processes
and they follow appropriate regulations
which might be changing and updating so
it's important for them to stay current
with those
and they're responsible for laboratory
functions as well as
production now qualities if you're
considering to
pursue this job would mean you're going
to need to have some of these basic
qualities
knowledge in the operations of rotary
evaporator spray dryer
fluid extractor as other cannabis
related lab equipment
particularly involved in the extraction
process standardization and
calibration of the analytical equipment
as well is very important
because you want to make sure you're
getting accurate results you must have a
science
degree as well as some laboratory
experience typically must be at least 21
years old and willingness to
participate with others because often
you're working in a cooperative
environment of a lab
now what's the connection to the chemist
industry specifically at least
uh cannabis chemists are constantly
discovering new methods of extraction
as well as products and information
about how the brain and cannabinoids
work
they can work closely with kind of other
research scientists taking an extract
and seeing how it performs in other
situations
many of the methods used today for
extraction were devised by chemists in
the laboratory setting
well prior to the domestication of
cannabis for medicinal purposes
and have since been adapted to use in
the cannabis industry
then these chemists are taking the next
step further and refining
that process so if this is of interest
to you you may want to consider
to be a cannabis chemist