welcome to this tobacco university video
looking at the importance of keeping
records
as a cannabis grower and while this may
not be the most entertaining or
flashiest of videos
this is a very important one that a lot
of growers will often
overlook and only realize at the end of
a grow or looking back that they wish
they
put a little bit more time into this so
hopefully this video will prevent you
from making that mistake
so first off i said often missed by
growers the floors are not sure why this
seems to be
a consistent problem but more often than
not growers do not document what they do
or keep records in general
now we're looking at record keeping it
could be very simple
or it could be very complex it doesn't
really matter in the sense that
you're getting in the pattern of taking
at least some sort of records
and that could be simply when you water
how much you water
when you're fertilizing what you're
fertilizing with some sort of calendar
system
just some way to be able to look back at
what you did to the plants
so this is applicable to all growers
while there can be different levels of
record keeping depending on growing
situation specifics
all growers must have some method for
documentation and this is true if you're
an indoor grower mainly growing one or
two plants
if you're an indigra growing a large
number hundreds or thousands of plants
or even if you're an outdoor grower all
of these
growers this applies to so a lot of
people think i'm growing one or two
plants doesn't really matter
i definitely want to be documenting and
keeping track
of what you're doing so the reason why
you want to do this is the data is
really
key to overall success because knowing
what you did is important for refining a
growing plan
or to identify what may have gone wrong
with a growth cycle
it also works if something went right
you have a good track record of what you
did to try to
repeat that same success maybe even
refine your tactics even a little bit
more
so again data is key to success in
documenting that data is also important
so a lot of growers ask well what should
i be documenting what should i be
looking
at these are just some basic suggestions
for example
the basics of your growing area the size
of your growing area the number of
plants the type of plants starting
materials
seeds or clones feminized seeds
temperature and humidity levels
as well as the materials you're using
what media containers ventilation lights
are using there's a whole plethora of
more you could add to that key dates
such as when you start or flowering
dates or harvest dates those are like
the key main
three there with cannabis production
water usage the frequency and amount
of related to plant age fertilizers
added and the mixed ratios that you need
to
apply them what fertilizer and what
dilution rate did you do you may be
changing that over
the grow cycle and then also pest
pressures
what uh when and what was seen and
documented and how did you potentially
go about trying to control that
and how effective was that for those
that are breeding
an extra level of detail needs to be
included looking for at morphological
and plant specifics
it's important for tracking traits from
one generation to the next
is it more of a broadly squattier
appearance with short internodes or is
it more of a taller growing plant
with more thinner leaves these are all
important considerations
to be documenting so again regardless of
what's
grower you are what level you're at
everyone should be taking
and collecting data with their grow so
they can continue to improve their
ability
as growers of cannabis in general