okay here we're look at the importance
of documentation cleanliness and
organization are related to growums we
see a nice well-organized area here
where we have documentation not only on
the door we have it well labeled we have
a key card to get in we have a
whiteboard here indicating the plants
that are in there when they were potted
up when they were flipped and when they
are expected to be harvested and we see
track records right here in a bin
located right outside this flower roof
number four great way of having this
documentation climates and organization
all wrapped into one here now
documentation is important because it
should be easy to follow in a logical
format and it would do much thought and
should just kind of hit the main points
here and see a nice organized layout
here a little description initials time
and what was done for all tests and
times there should be an accompanying
initials to know who was responsible for
that great way to hold accountability
information should be posted as we can
see here easy to access going into this
room all people should also be aware of
the location of what's the called the
SDS sheets those are the safety data
sheets for anything that's being applied
good things to consider also if you're
in an area and working to know where
those are located so that you know what
products are being applied and it's
important for Health and Safety images
can also be included as well this can be
another way to go to document things but
also include captions and use that as a
supplement for this written
documentation now calendar it's not only
important to document what you do but
it's also a good idea to know where you
expect or at least hope to be and when
so kind of predicting the future you
could see here when these plants were
potted up when they were turned and
flipped into from veg to flower and
their anticipated harvest state and also
the number of plants of different
varieties publicly posted here also with
documentation and binders here that may
correlate with the room as well this
could be also ideas of you know the
bulbs of the the room how old those are
when they were changed what the
reflectors are looking like a whole host
of things
irrigation events so much information is
good to collect so that you're able to
replica
a successful pattern or just one that is
not successful Clem this is important it
applies to outdoor field grown plants as
well so don't think it's just for indoor
operations cleaners should be continual
not just once a week Oh every Monday we
clean no it should be consistent and
clean does that mean sterile listen we
have to take bleach and bleach the walls
and everything but just going through
and sweeping up collecting everything
and putting in a known location is a
good idea
tools for defined areas is also a great
suggestion but there should be steps to
disinfect and limit cross-contamination
with those tools simple alcohol solution
and keep on hand to be used on a regular
intervals is recommended we see here
kind of a sticky paper so when you walk
through this door this captures
potentially anything that might be on
the shoes or on the soles here of
individuals Footwear so again something
that should be changed freely on a
regular basis so we're not building up
and accumulating a bunch of potential
soil particles I'm here keeping the area
clean as just another step there simple
hygiene mean yes that is me washing
hands before and during a grow area if
you have a larger area with multiple
rooms repeat the process as you change
from room to room always trying to limit
potential for contamination assume every
room you enter is contaminated even if
it's quote not it'll just keep you in a
good pattern of practice consider
yourself a carrier to disease and you
want to limit cross contamination we
want to limit any direct contact between
rooms make sure you haven't washed up in
between if you've - includes Yourself
tools and guests that might be visiting
your facility here wearing a full-body
suit here the booties are the gloves the
hairnet all this just kind of limits the
chance that I if I carry of carrying
anything I infect the plants that I am
visiting and inspecting the environment
in general continually keep an eye on
the environment around your plants have
a designated area where the leaves are
disposed of and also clean this area out
daily to avoid a source of disease in a
grow space don't have a nice bin here
where all the discarded leaves go and
just leave it here to be changed once a
week go through bag this up and remove
that on a regular basis also you could
have again multiple rooms here multiple
areas of disposal go through and clean
this up insurance isn't breeding disease
it gets picked up in the ventilation
system
and spread to the entire room you can
see a nice clean floor here as well
clean and organized I can see the high
pressure sodium lights kind of tint the
color a little bit but you see down this
whole row very clean it's also easy to
spot potential errors it should be easy
for anyone to follow this clean is
coming this in organization so you know
where you may be missing or running
short of something new treats in
particular one plate doesn't look like
the others what might be going on bureau
issued with the emitters or something
going up to watering clean floor also
allows really detection of plant that
may be dropping more leaves than normal
that can just get you to inspect that
plant a little bit more I catch any
potential problems early daily tasked
when it changed Footwear clothing when
entering your grow area to reduce
potential for contamination check all
systems fans lights co2 water so on and
so forth here on there's glasses because
these are high pressure sodium lights
for a grower comfort and also you can
see different sized gloves here to
ensure always changing out gloves with
each room check the plants but also
don't forget to check the undersides of
the leaves as well they'll just kind of
look at all the tops of the leaves and
these mine flowers are going through and
doing inspections to remove any dead or
sick leaves that you notice Prevention's
better than control keeping the area
clean is a key to disease pest
prevention this includes also the blades
of the fan the water tanks the walls the
floor everything we don't want to just
limit it to just checking one thing soil
surface the players to see them the
walls the fans of tools equipment
leaving yourself need to be considered
as far as preventing any potential for
contamination lastly if you do have a
problem room or one that may be
experiencing an issue I just chose this
picture randomly here but if you do have
rooms of various clothing this always
start with the cleanest rooms first and
work your way towards the dirtier rooms
or areas there's a help limit the
spreading of disease to your entire
operation most people want to go the
room that's got all the disease first
take care of that but then that disease
assume is on you and you're transferring
that to your other ones so always start
with the cleanest room and progress to
the dirtiest room soon you're not kind
of adding any infection cross
contaminating those spores that might be
in the dirty room into your clean room
and all this
taking into consideration is that
connection between the importance of
continual documentation clearance an
organization for an efficient Quirrell
operation