and this debaco University video I'm
going to go over the importance of
decarboxylation for canvas I'll go over
a brief introduction of what this
actually is from a chemical standpoint
as well as go over scientific study to
give you some specifics that you can
look for when going through this process
[Music]
so here's the study there's a research
article you can find the screenshot of
the first page right here as well as the
proper citation if you want to look at
the study in more details I'll provide
you with a brief overview here so first
off starting with the very Basics is
just what is decarboxylation well all
cannabinoids that are contained within
the trichomes of raw cannabis flour
consist of canamoids in their acidic
form and have an extra carboxyl ring or
group attached to the chain and from a
chemistry standpoint that's a carbon
with two oxygens and a hydrogen the
decarboxylation are typically called
decarbing is where raw canvas is heated
so that the chemical structure of the
acid cannabinoids changes to a neutral
or non-acid form you can also if you
notice right below me here can also
change invisible appearance we're simply
breaking off that Bond there through the
process of heat
so the acidic to neutral form conversion
and what's going on here well this is
when one states that the climates are in
their acidic form they're referring to
the chemical structure of the compound
itself a cannabinoid that is in its
acidic form has a carboxyl group
attached in the neutral forms where the
carboxyl group simply removed so acid is
the raw plant material and the neutral
form is a decarboxylated compound and
how does that look from a structure
standpoint here we can see THC a and
cbda and their acid form or their how to
be found on the raw plate material when
heat is added we could see they both
convert to their neutral form with the
loss here of carbon dioxide you can see
it also pictured on this side as well
where we see the acidic forms are
considered to be the inactive forms and
then through the Deep carboxyl
carboxylation process with heat and time
you get into the active forms or the
neutral forms
now the chemical structure changes just
to show that in a little bit more detail
here this transforming of the
cannabinoid acids into their neutral
forms needs to Simply remove that
carboxyl group there the weak Bond
holding the carboxyl group can be broken
by a combination of heat as well as time
this describes the process of
decarboxylation because you're removing
our carboxyl group due to high
temperature or combustion the major
difference chemically between the acid
cannabinoids and their neutral
counterparts is that extra Bond there of
that carboxyl group so known as a
carboxyl group again from a scientific
chemistry standpoint which consists of a
carbon oxygen oxygen hydrogen molecule
cluster and that's simply what's being
broken off and removed causing the
conversion from the acidic form to that
neutral form it's also a loss of carbon
dioxide in the process as shown here
now why do we need to go through this
process why is this even important
um why do we need to go through
carboxylation decarboxylation this
process essentially converts the
chemicals to an active form by
increasing the body's ability to absorb
and bind the molecules
essentially the body can use the active
form carboxylation happens naturally
when the plant material is ignited so
through that heating process through
that combustion process that is a
natural way to add heat through time to
convert the acidic form to that neutral
form
so what's the importance of this process
you know converting of thca uh versus
just regular THC so while TTA is
non-psychoactive not decarboxylated form
it's the precursor to THC which is the
which is the decarboxylated form this
does not bind to the CB1 and CB2
receptors just note that thca binds with
other cannabinoid receptors in the
endocannabinoid system so that's why
active is usually like in quotes
although thca poses some therapeutic
effects like anti-inflammatory and
neuroproductive qualities it is not the
most beneficial or is nor is it the
psychoactive form so we're not saying
that thca is you know completely not
able to be utilized by the body but it
doesn't seem like it's as utilized or as
binds as well to the CB1 and CB2
receptors compared to its neutral form
THC
so what this requires um this
decarboxylation does require heat and
time these are two main catalysts to for
this process to occur drying and curing
canvas over time will cause a partial
decarboxylation to occur but the Heat
and time will speed up that process and
make it more efficient heating of the
cannabinoids to a lower temperature over
time allows economics to be
decarboxylated while preserving the
Integrity of the material typically here
we're talking about terpenes this is
used so that it can be incorporated into
what is ultimately going to be consumed
you see this kind of like conversion
here we've noticed that TTA is
decreasing the same time THC would be
increasing
so here's that journal like conversion
graph it's kind of average I have the
picture of the Seesaw here it's kind of
that like inverse relationship here and
this shows the theoretical conversion of
the acidic forms of THC and CBD to the
neutral forms notice the inverse
relationship as the amounts change at
the end THC and CBD remain in high
concentrations so what's basically
happening here this lines representing
TTA and you see when that starts to drop
and go down the presence or
concentration of THC increases and the
same thing can be applied to cbda and
CBD there's that inverse relationship
one's being converted to another
so that's why you're getting kind of
that seesaw-like conversion
now test results before and after
decarboxylation canvas flowers are often
tested for both THC as well as thca note
that THC is often found in small
percentages in fresh flour because it
has not gone through the Heat and the
time to decarboxylate it and we can see
here here's THC and here's THC a we can
see after that decarboxylation process
we can see that conversion here was a
lot more THC compared to THC a so it's
just important note there in a lot of
times Labs do test for both even in
regular dry flour so that grower can
have an understanding as well as a
consumer of that potential conversion to
the amount of desirable cannabinoid
now the best what's the best ecobox and
temperature for CBDs again we're going
to look at CBD as well as THC so there
is some dispute over the exact de
carboxylation temperature for CBD
according to studies however it appears
to be approximately 203 degrees
Fahrenheit or 110 degrees Celsius as for
the time frame neither THC nor CBD will
decarboxylate instantaneously at their
precise decarb temperature so it's not
like you hit that temperature and you
get that automatic conversion there is
still a Time factor to take into
consideration a longer period typically
between 40 and 60 Minutes will be
required for that carboxyl group to
break down into water and carbon dioxide
so it's a little bit of a range there to
give you a general idea but it's not
like instantaneous you hit that
temperature and 100 converts there needs
to be a duration of time also considered
now don't get decarboxylation
temperatures confused with boiling
points because they are not the same now
boiling points for cannabinoids terpenes
flavonoids have been much more
thoroughly studied than decarboxylation
temperatures boiling points for the
compounds are all provided here in
Fahrenheit and Celsius and here's kind
of more of a pictorial graph here I'm
giving you some some more information
but this is what was provided in the
study these boiling points are not the
same as the carboxylation temperatures a
little bit easier to study a little bit
more published but you have to be aware
of what number you're looking at what
that correlates with
because you want to avoid high
temperatures it's important to keep a
tight temperature control applying
cannabis to various technological
applications while heat is needed to
decarboxylate the acids into the active
form of cannabinoids our bodies can use
extreme temperatures can destroy many of
these important plant materials that
contribute to positive Health outcomes
such as terpenes if cannabis is heated
above 300 degrees Fahrenheit need to run
you need to run the risk of denaturing
many important other plant compounds so
it's not just the concept of more heat
is better there we have to be careful
with that because there's also comments
that will validate and evaporate at
higher temperatures and this can result
in unpleasant odor as well as an
unpleasant taste so too much heat too
much and is going to cause a degradation
of that product
so you simply want to use the minimum
temperature basically to try to preserve
those terpenes it is advisable to keep
the decarboxylation temperatures at a
low point to preserve terpenes as well
as other compounds each individual
terpene may have its own therapeutic
benefits so but this also carries its
own sensitivity to heat if terpenes are
to be stored the temperature in the
range of 203 degrees Fahrenheit should
be maintained there we're not looking at
you know heating up too high start
getting above certain theoretical
temperatures and they will break down
and we don't want to lose those terpenes
that we've spent so much time in the
plant growing breaking those down
now maintaining consistent temperature
is important so for this process a
digital oven a safe thermometer is
recommended so that the temperature that
works best for the final product can be
continually monitored now if you're
using an oven limit the number of times
you open the door during the
decarboxylation process so this will
cause temperature fluctuations and
reduce consistency and total yield of
the decarboxylation process if you're
looking at a graph of the temperatures
you don't want to have these that have
these like large swings in it you want
to have very minimal noise data noise
you want to have a graph that looks more
like this because that will ensure a
more consistent temperature and a more
consistent repeatable process
now speeding up the process what a lot
of people want to do kind of we see here
but just as if you drive too fast that
can have negative effects now the key to
faster decarboxylation is known to be
greater heat and this should be a clear
process unfortunately it's not easy also
speeding up the process can result in a
reduction of the quality of the end
product and we don't want to kind of
avoid we want to avoid that
now cannabis trim trim is what is
removed from the final flower after
harvest trim includes sugar leaves bits
of cut off Buds and knocked off tricums
or kief
this portion of the plant is considered
low quality and is usually reserved for
making Edibles hash pre-rolls or simply
just used for extraction the reason why
I mentioned this and Define this is
we're going to see this study uses these
terms so I want you to understand what
this plant material is referring to
now going through the other portion here
the Keith explained when trichomes dry
and break off the plant becomes this
kief product which is kind of what it
looks like it's a popular byproduct of
wheat consumption and is often used for
Edible Creations
has oxidized and lost its freshness when
separated from the plant buds usually
has a darker color than trichomes
ranging from a light gold to kind of a
brown coloration kind of the rendition
you see here in this image it has a
powdery appearance and a texture that is
somewhat sticky often less so than
trichomes on the actual bud keep tends
to decarb faster than an intact flower
so keep that in mind when we're looking
at the temperatures and suggestions for
the decarboxylation process
so here's the temperature in times chart
so suggested times for different
temperatures are provided for the type
of cannabinoid either THC or CBD and the
material being decarboxylated is it
flour or is it Kief and we can see here
the temperature range is here the
heating mode the plant material time or
high THC and high CBD a key for hash
time and in canvas oil time is all
provided here so you can see how there
are fluctuations in time based on
temperature they really didn't do a lot
here with this one with the hot oil bath
focus more on the oven and use the
boiling water bath as well here with the
suggested times below you know here's a
link you can definitely pause the video
or search the primary source as well
now THC content does change over time
exposed to different temperatures so the
highest concentration of THC which in
this case was about 15
milligrams per gram is obtained when the
material is decarboxylate at 122 degrees
Celsius for 27 minutes so we kind of see
the graph provided here and we're
looking at kind of this this one right
here being kind of the ideal for 27
minutes it's kind of lighting up right
here and you'll notice again it doesn't
happen instantaneously it does start to
break down and then it kind of peeks out
and tapers off kind of plateaus we don't
want to run it for too long because we
could get a degradation at that point so
that 20 to 27 minutes 27 minutes being
suggested by the data presented here
now changes in content here in at least
in percentage of the main cannabinoids
before and after the decarboxylation
process now here's the cannabinoids THC
a and THC the acidic form the neutral
form cbda and CBD CBN and then the
moisture and a total cannabinoids and
we're seeing before decarboxylation the
content again in percentages and we can
notice that thca quite high and then we
see THC being relatively low 30 minutes
of decarboxylation compared to 60
minutes we can see that thca almost
degrades to nothing which as we expect
and it's being converted because it's
simply being converted to THC and we see
the same pattern here for cbda being
converted to CBD and then CBN and then
moisture there now it's important just
to remember that the acidic forms are
being converted to their biologically
active neutral forms during this process
note that the longer 60 Minutes in this
case basically right below me time
caused a reduction in total cannabinoids
we see that highlighted right here we
peaked here 30 minutes
at the 30.3 it went down to 27.4 so the
content of cbda before decarboxylation
was 0.6 and an hour after deconvection
decreased 0.3 and we can see that here
whereas the CBD content before was zero
percent we see that right here and after
30 minutes was increased to one percent
so again we're seeing that time we're
seeing that conversion uh process
because of the Heat and the time from
the acidic form to that neutral form
now I just want you to leave you didn't
want to just leave you with that I want
you to understand that there's other
factors of variability
this isn't just a necessarily a set cut
and dry chemical process the variety of
the Cannabis being used the age
refreshness of the product the equipment
being used in the flower uniformity all
play a role in this decarboxylation
process
so the variety of care is being used
let's just touch on that here for a
moment I'm going to go into each of
these a little bit more detail each type
of cannabis contains different amounts
of ratios or different cannabinoids and
terpenes which impact the optimum
decarboxylation time as well as the
temperature this can also be impacted by
the physical structure of the flower so
take that into consideration
see each cannabinoid and terpene
decarboxylates at different temperatures
knowing what the plant naturally
contains will impact the temperature
protocol that should be implemented now
you're focusing on a type 1 a type 2 a
Type 3 What specific terpenes might be
of high presence in your particular
cultivar variety being used
also age and freshness of the product
there will be noticeable differences in
the final product depending on the age
or freshness of the material you start
with this really impacts the amount of
degradation that may occur before
decarboxylation remember the
decarboxylation process only converts
the acidic form from the form to the
bioactive neutral form it does not
create CBD or create the THC molecule
it's a conversion you're taking the A
and you're breaking that the voxel group
off that's what you're left with this is
not a creation of a molecule it's a
conversion of a molecule
now also the equipment being used in
this could be a high source of
variability because you want to reduce
that variability and the ability to
maintain precise temperature will have a
direct impact on the total yield
continually monitoring the temperature
is also important in oven or other
systems such as a cooker slow cooker or
instant cooker is used there will be a
small variability in the cooking
equipment that may affect the final
product and may also affect the
repeatability of your protocol
this is why equipment intended for this
purpose is recommended such as a
decarboxylation jacketed glass reactor
or other professional oven they're going
to have more repeatability they're gonna
have less variability but you are going
to pay more for them
and flower uniformity so this is another
Factor Dickens consideration as this can
refer to the size but also the density
of the final flower the greater the
consistency of the size and density will
allow for the most consistent
decarboxylation process as an extreme
example of fine cannabis or powder kief
will require a much shorter cooking time
to prevent burning and denaturing of the
important compounds in the plant
compared to an intact flower if the
flower consistency varies widely and
grinding up the plant material will help
increase the uniformity of the
decarboxylation process or doing runs or
batches of flowers with the same
uniformity will help increase your
ability to have this repeatable and
consistent end result
now just some general key points never
just keep in mind that you need to have
higher temperatures
um I'm sorry at higher temperatures
Keith and hash 10 to decarboxylate
faster than dried flowers simply because
of the surface area of more surface area
all ground up there gonna have a greater
chance of that heat penetration High CBD
strains tend to have tend to carboxylate
a bit slower than those with high THC
content so just having that knowing what
the You're Expecting from your compounds
can help you plan for that in the
protocol process
three main factors with any
decarboxylation it's important
parameters to perform a good
decarboxylation are the time or duration
the temperature you keep the oven or
heating device at and the quality of
decarboxylation equipment for
consistency as well as repeatability
so lastly if you just want the basic
suggestions here if you've made it this
far into the video suggestions for
decarboxylation your own cannabis from
the review of the published literature
highest concentration of THC which is
about 15 milligrams per gram is obtained
when the material is decarboxylated at
122 degrees Celsius for 27 minutes if
you're looking at converting cbda to CBD
a higher temperature is required about
150 degrees Celsius and is suggested
time for about 30 minutes if you're
looking at decarboxylating key for hash
in an oven I bake it for about 10
minutes at 300 degrees Fahrenheit which
is about 149 degrees Celsius there for
consistency hopefully this gives you a
general idea of a really good starting
point as well as other factors to
consider that you may not have
originally thought of to ensure you're
getting the most quality end product
from your starting material but if you
don't have a good grow or good protocols
to begin with you don't have good flour
this will do the best it can but keep in
mind you need to have it in the plant to
be able to decarboxylate it to get that
final end product result that you desire