here I'm going to go over the importance
of crime at scene sketching so what's
the importance of being a little sketch
ascribes Kane well they're essential
documents in this step within the
processing protocol you need to be able
to sketch a crime scene or what's going
with the objects you may have
photographed what's going in that room
or that area need to be sure you're
including which means you also need to
take these dimensions distance content
in relationship of items of evidence so
all these things must be taken into
account while you're there at the crime
scene so you can generate a quality
sketch that will uphold in court now
sketches versus photographs while many
may think photographs are the most
important item sketches can actually
show more comprehensive view of the
crime scene so you see an example here
of kind of the one level of the house a
photographs women take into account
portion of this this gives us a larger
perspective sketches should be
supplements to photographs in order to
provide a comprehensive description of
the crime scene so while we may be
looking at the table here
this is sketch is going to provide
context to that photograph so they kind
of go hand in hand but keep in mind
sketches are very important this
includes a lot of those essential
elements also including the direction of
north it's also important consideration
so the purpose of the sketch to document
the exact location in relationship of
physical items in the crime scene
provide a permanent record of those
conditions could see here more sketches
of more dimensions we want to relate to
the sequence of events that may have
occurred and in court settings sketches
help prosecutors judges and the jury
understand the crime scene by providing
an overall view of the area keep in mind
is people very likely have never been
there and are reliant on you to supply
them with information these lines here
show doors and it shows the way that
doors open so keep in mind that knowing
which way the doors open can also be
important when looking at angles of
attackers or particularly bullet
trajectory can also something to date
the consideration that sketching
procedure you want to observe the entire
crime scene kind of unbiased ly you want
to outline area dimensions of the room
or rooms if you're sketching more on one
draw objects and
it's measured distances record all
details and add details such as the
legend title scale direction of north is
also very important so I start with the
blank sheet you have to not only know
you're going to be documenting all this
on a sketch but taking all these into
consideration while you're actively
there at the crime scene
general sketching notes kind of see a
nice little example here looking this is
not to scale but do not measure through
space oddly shaped items such as puddles
or liquids are trying related from the
center of mass you do not cross
measurement lines and always have the
sketch verified by someone other than
yourself that was also there we're
looking at you know place by we're not
having any lines crossed here we're
documenting sizes we have the window we
have the door we have to enter and exit
door so and you can there's no other
doors but there's a window here a lot of
information is easily provided here in
addition to all these letters here's the
legend here's the I type block here's
the information here's who it was
sketched by note it's not to scale and
also the direction of north so types of
sketches well there's different types an
example here be a rough sketch is kind
of one you want to just start with
France crime scene it's not a finished
product or polished product but it does
contain measurements and other data as
you can see here now within this rough
sketch we're looking at should show the
proportions with accurate measurements
but does not need to be to scale and
this is speaking particularly to the
rough sketch no changes should be made
once you leave the crime scene and it
requires a legend or a key so this is
something you're actually making while
you're actively there at the crime scene
line to ensure you have all the correct
measurements we have all the basic
information that you need and a legend
to know what you found in where it was
found
I'll brush sketch specifics so we can
see some more of these specifics
indicated here out it should be marked
with the letters evidence marked by a
circle number and those should
correspond with the photographs we've
also taken north is also indicated in
this case we have south east north and
west also indicated typically just need
to indicate north most relevant
materials are documented
typically done with and so you can see
which way the doors are opening here and
this other date marked as well so a
finished sketch was this different than
a finished sketch well finished sketch
shows the proper relationships and
scales the finished sketch is more
presentable for court presentations may
be professionally produced this finished
sketch in addition will emit measurement
lines all items the rough sketch must be
included with no editing myself over
here note scale notations all
measurements should be orient in the
same direction for easy reading and
we're looking at the kitchen countertop
referent points everything's in that
same orientation our head should touch
measurement lines if you are using that
as hidden objects should be indicated by
dotted lines no conclusion should be
noted on the drynesss it isn't image
over just what what was there objects
okay by training triangulation when
possible and the numbers should match
the numbers that are on the photographs
as well and again north is needs to be
indicated you can under case the other
cardinal directions as well be sure
including the legend time person and it
is so here going to look at a picture
picture of two sketches so we have our
finished sketch this is how it would
look and now we have a sketch here we
notice the details a triangulation
measurements included everywhere the
level of detail that's presented here
even though this is a rough sketch is
providing a lot of detail in information
this would be included as the evidence
and would potentially uphold a court
however a lot of times to simplify
things we might take this same image and
simplify it and after we have the image
here a little simplified with the legend
still occurring we sought the couch the
desk but here we're kind of omitting
some details so it's important to maybe
if we're looking at just highlighting
one particular object we can simplify it
but we need to have this also included
as part of evidence because it's to
showing where the door is this is
showing a lot more detail a lot more
measurements a lot more information on
in the one here we do see that it is
instant reports we see that rooms either
buildings see the location who it's
verified by in the cardinal direction
north so again keep in mind that when we
are sketching things it's very important
to
you sketch them well and include the
information needed while we're there at
the crime scene so we can have an
accurate portrayal of that information
that can be upheld in the court of law