on this debaco university video going to
go over the importance of properly
carrying
your cannabis buds because if you've
gotten them through to the very end you
don't want to reduce your quality you
want to maximize your return on
investment
and hopefully this video lecture will
help you do just that
[Music]
all right let's go over the importance
of properly curing cannabis buds
so first off curing in general well
often considered to be a blending of an
art
and a science there are some scientific
bases you should follow but it's kind of
that
properly curing process has a little bit
of an art on this to it
the grower a cure needs to control the
curing environment during this
post-harvest process regardless
of if the original plants were grown
indoors or outdoors so this applies to
both now indoor growers you might have a
little bit more of a visual nisk
that you're looking for outdoor growers
you might have a little bit more volume
to contend with
but still you should go through a curing
process and be mindful
of the importance of the steps presented
here so the
curing room environmental controls that
should be in place
similar to a drying room humidity goal
is around 62 percent and
you want to have a temperature control
as well typically maintaining that
around 60 degrees
fahrenheit now as i said indoor or
outdoors typically
the curing process will cure will occur
indoors
regardless of where the original plant
material was grown
because you want to avoid loss of
degradation so the point of that is to
have it grown indoors because you have
more control
you don't want to have this outdoors
some operations will utilize a
greenhouse or cold frame
then will have at least some protection
from the extremes of the outdoor
environment
so to avoid the loss is the cannabinoids
and terpenes found in the cannabis can
start to degrade soon after harvest
and the curing process helps preserve
the levels originally found in the plant
because you don't want to go through and
have all those kind of high quality
cannabinoids and terpenes and then just
lose them
to to a poor curing process you want to
maintain those levels
and not lose them to simple plant
breakdown
now after proper curing the risk of mold
developing is greatly reduced now i say
greatly reduced because it's not
eliminated
but if you go through a proper curing
process by reducing the humidity by
getting everything set up by drying
everything down evenly
the odds of the buds producing mold
after an efficient carrying process
is greatly reduced so the very last step
here within the
curing is you should involve sending out
a subsample
out for testing in a lab so depending on
how big your harvest is
will depend on the kind of how many buds
you take versus how many
buds you have you want to hold on to the
harvest slot that's represented by the
sample
that is sent to a third party lab only
move the end product to packaging and
shipping once the test results come back
and passing levels are achieved for all
parameters to ensure
a safe product is being sent to
consumers this is also a legal
requirement for labeling
so the reason why you want to hold those
products before you send them to the
packaging and shipping
can process is that if they fail you
want to make sure that you're not
packaging up a product
that may have failed one of the tests
also you want to make sure when you're
labeling
you're able to label the cannabinoid
content label the terpene content
ensure it passed all the microbiology
all the heavy metals all the pesticides
all the testing that needs to occur so
that's a very important
last step that a lot of growers forget
about is that they so focus on the
drying and the curing
which is all very important but also
getting their product
tested so that the consumers looking to
purchase their product
can have the information presented to
them so they can make an educated
decision