this debaco university video is going to
look at the importance of branding
when it comes to growing cannabis and
creating a sustainable
business practice
all right let's look at the importance
of cannabis branding and
growing a quality canvas product
branding it and getting the word out
there is a very important part
of creating a sustainable business so
first off the job description
now we're looking at a job description
looking at a marketing manager
really responsible for branding and
registering products for sale and keeps
the company up to date and relevant
within the current industry and this
relevance
can change so what was popular one year
or one set might change over time
here we're seeing four week moving
average market share of flower
market share of thc looking at data
looking at trends trying to make
predictions
all important considerations for the
description
uh involving the marketing manager of
any cannabis
company now the day-to-day activities
are looking at this creating a principal
display and secondary label
that accurate reports test results
statements
product identification information and
color coding of
for sorting and identification registers
brands with the dcp
files brand registration information
photographs products offer branding
and works with contractors in developing
t-shirts lanyards pens pads
etc and as well as bags a whole bunch of
things and different ways to brand that
particular product
now important part here that says
photographs products for branding this
can be
a very critical part particularly for
cannabis we're looking at dry flour
really showcasing that final product in
the best way possible
can really do a lot for the branding and
selling of that
product going forward so the qualities a
person
must have just in general willingness to
work closely with others
good communication skills knowledge of
the ftc and
fda regulations must be creative
must be at least 21 years or older
degree and experience within the field
is always
welcome as well as pass a background
check so you'll be working in the
cannabis industry
so must be creative in the sense that
coming up with new ways
trying new things realizing when
something may not be working and making
adjustments
from there so what is kind of the
connection to the cannabis industry
well brandon goes a long way we can see
that here with
nutrients with uh t-shirts there's a
whole lot of that within the industry
engineering spreading is a highly
important position within the industry
as they control the company's image
and ensure that the company and its
products have proper labeling and
designs that are appealing
to the customers or the target customers
proper branding builds reputation within
the industry
and a consumer basis all good things
now this could be for the final product
if you're growing as i said cannabis
plants
this could also be with fertilizers but
also with lighting
plant supporting equipment as well so
it's important to keep that in mind keep
that
relevant because the campus industry is
constantly changing
and a good branding person will
recognize those changes
be ahead of those changes make changes
when necessary to keep their company
on the competitive edge