so in this tobacco University video I'm
going to talk about how simple hydrogen
peroxide can be utilized to help
increase seed germination I'll tell you
what percentage to use based on the
research study and how you can achieve
that same concentration with various
products you might be
[Music]
purchasing all right let's look at how
improved cannabis seed germination with
hyen peroxide can be accom lished first
off giving you just a little background
on Growers usage of hydrogen peroxides
some Growers may use it as a simple pour
through it'll cause a lot of bubbling uh
this can be effective for root or
substrate based diseases but this
lecture really we're going to focus on
just the germination rates the some
Growers may already be utilizing this
particular product for other purposes H
peroxide is common uh it's used in most
first aid situations typically a 3%
solution as a mild antiseptic used to
prevent infection of minor cut scrapes
and burn Burns product works by
releasing oxygen when it's applied to
the defected area um and you see this
kind of bubble for foaming that occurs
remove the dead skin basically clean the
area and that's a sign that it's working
I do want to make note that if you are
purchasing concentrated hyen peroxide
typically 25 to
35% and you get that directly on your
skin it will cause it's a a burn uh
basically turns your skin white um as
seen in the image here so that's highly
concentrated that 3 % would just cause
the bubbling effect now with hydren
peroxide remember that light can break
it down so this is why it's typically
found in a light block bottle um because
that can reduce the concentration over
time and there's usually a used by datee
stated on it so keep that in mind if you
are choosing to utilize this particular
product so let's get to the research
article um here that talks about this um
germination um different cannabis seeds
soaked in different concentrations uh of
hydren peroxide
so here's some of the data that they
were looking at so the germination of
six-month-old seeds of blueberry of
cannabis Variety in concentrations of
hydron peroxide solution as well as a
water control so a here the top uh
picture here is represent photographs of
germination seeds and seedlings in H2O2
hyen peroxide for various concentrations
of water in day one day 2 day three and
day four so you can see their actual uh
data here so if we look at water right
AC process is what it looked like after
1 Day 2 days 3 days and 4 days and you
can see that in relation to the other
concentrations of Hy peroxide now down
here uh panel B is a comparison of the
germination percentages with those
different concentrations of hyon
peroxide and we could see here it kind
of puts the visualness of the data here
into actual numbers and we see something
very distinctive happen and that is the
middle bar here the second bar I should
say is the 1% and that has had the
quickest rate of germination compared to
the other concentrations and also the
water
control so then they took this up and
they did a 5-year-old seeds so D of
5-year-old seeds of the Finola and x59
varieties in 1% hyen peroxide solution
compared to the water control and we
could see again the water compared to
the two compared to the other two
varieties in 1% both uh varieties
responded very well to that 1% in that
comparison of germination and this was a
1% peroxide solution media and water
control is shown here in the mean with
five uh seeds being uh tried here each
replicate around 30 seeds were used in
total there give you a little comparison
there and always look at the article if
you want more of the details of
information so growth and survival of H
of hyon peroxide Solutions germinated in
an MS media so this is looking at more
of a um petri dish kind of look look at
but again same basic thing water over
Day from the first day they replaced all
so basically Day Zero to day one to day
three there so Day Zero is just after
transferred to the MS media plates after
they're soaking and then 24 hours after
and 72 hours um after transpl to that uh
medium there and that's just typical
petri dish General multi-purpose uh
media that was utilized there and we're
seeing the results yet again of that 1%
solution uh showing visually that best
rooting so what does the study conclude
what do you kind of like it to the the
bottom of the study here to improve
germination rates of your cannabis seeds
soak the seeds overnight in a 1% Hy
peroxide solution in a dark uh room at
room temperature this is a great for
situations that require stability such
as tissue culture so what the basically
this study concluded however how does
this kind of relate to your germination
rates how can this help uh benefit you
while some Growers May soak their seeds
overnight this is typically not often
advised though shown it can work uh but
this information still can be useful
simply instead of soaking your seeds in
plain water for whatever duration of
time you choose to use you can simply
add hydron peroxide to create a 1%
solution as you're soaking your seeds
and that can help improve your
germination rates so the question now
becomes is how do you get to that 1%
rate so I'm going to use the simple
chemistry here C1 V1 equals C2 V2
concentration of your starting stock
solution with your initial volume will
equal the concentration of your final
dilute solution with your final volume
so if you're using a typical bottle here
that's 3% if you have 16 o of that um
how do you get that 1% solution so in
short starting with your solution
there's three times as strong as you
need so taking 16 ounces of stock
solution adding 32 o of water will
result in 48 o total of a 1% solution
and you can see basically I went through
and calculated that right here basically
solving for v2 now another part here
what if you have that concentrated in
this case 32% food grade hydren peroxide
well if you're using that same 16 o of
the food grade hydren peroxide in short
you're going to be taking 16 ounces of
that stock solution and adding 496 o of
water which result in 512 o 4 gallons of
a 1% solution may be applicable on very
large scales but 4 gallons of a 1%
solution might be more than you need so
if you still have that same concentrated
solution and now you're only going to
use you know 2 ounces of that you know
percentage of water would you need to
add well 2 ounces of your stock solution
here 62 ounces of water would make a 64
probably more reasonable volume there of
a 1% solution that you can utilize to
soak your seeds in to help improve
germination rates so hope this helps if
you have this solution already give it a
try run the trial yourself see how it
helps out but start with that 1%
solution because that's what the data
shows is the most effective