in this debaco university video this is
going to cover the three main options
when looking at
in-row weed management for a cannabis
field and that's looking down our rows
how you're going to best manage the
weeds growing in between your plants
within the row stay tuned here to find
out the three methods
as well as the advantages and
disadvantages of each
[Music]
all right let's get into in-row weed
management in a cannabis field
so first off of our three options
plastic mulch is the first one
the advantages here is that it's very
easy to get it's effective for most
weeds
and there are color options for
different situations some of those color
options may offer some advantages
disadvantages with plastic mulch is the
initial setup process
it can be kind of labor intensive or
require special equipment and also at
the end of the season
the disposal of the plastic mulch can
also present an issue
to those growers another option might be
biodegradable mulches
the advantage is here is that there's
not really an end of the season disposal
issue
at least in most cases also
biodegradable mulches can work on
nutsedge
so if you have a nutsedge problem or
that weed really be presenting an issue
on your particular land
biodegradable mulches can offer a
advantage of being able to prevent that
from growing
however the disadvantages is that
selecting the one that is the best for
your growing conditions because there
are more options can be a challenge
and there's a potential increase in cost
when using
biodegradable mulches definitely at
least compared to the
plastic mulches and then lastly there's
just the
handled manual methods where the
advantage ensures someone will be
walking the fields and doing plant
inspections one of the disadvantages is
the simple the time
and labor that it takes to manually go
through and manage the weeds
now looking at these three different
methods if you
investigate any of them further look at
other videos here
in debaco university