okay here were a look at some in season
care options for squash I never see a
cucumber rubber firm that I visited and
we see these they're not only
suppressing weeds within the row but
also in between the rows where these
vines are about to run to help reduce
soil splashes over the fruit to reduce
cleaning time spent scrubbing so this is
something worth consideration now the
first part we want to consider when
we're looking at squash this almost
happens before the in season part is to
trigger space in your squash properly
depending on the variety they'll hear
terms like vine semi vine contact I and
semi Bush and Bush used and this gives
some suggestions on how far they should
be spaced both in the row and also
between rows this is the first kind of
step to ensuring that all everything may
initially kind of end and run together
they're not having a lot of overlap so
which can create a lot of disease issues
speaking of that weed control growing on
fabric is good for winter squash to
reduce soil splash on the fruit see that
here in particular melon crops also in
row weed suppression if some kind is
recommended seem to hang them down here
but also considering in between that row
weed block there as some benefits can
the cost be justified some growers will
say yes or as well say no but keep in
mind your time in the ease of harvest it
makes it really easy when there's no
weeds in between here also plant cleanup
becomes a lot easier irrigation so
within overall weed suppression
irrigation can also be considered we see
drip irrigation being the most obvious
choice overhead can be used and act as
kind of a panic backup it can also
increase powdery mildew if it's not
timed well you're gonna arrogate with
overhead irrigation actually in the
morning with heavy dew is probably a
good time because the leaves will
already be wet however once established
often the need for irrigation can be
reduced in squash in general
you're looking at this especially that
early on to get those plants and those
roots established well especially if
you're planting successive crops and you
want to have periods of high heat and
want to ensure that they're able to
survive and get established before
they're able to have a sufficient root
system to scavenge for water by
themselves