okay here I'm gonna go over some of the
basic in season care for your tomatoes
to ideally get them to turn from green
color to a nice harvestable red that
your customers will like so in season
care for tomatoes we want to think about
irrigations is usually a high-value crop
so typically it warrants irrigation it
is advised I usually recommend drip
irrigation because it's simple to set up
able to Hill a very long and extensive
rows just watch when you're pounding
them steaks that you know damaged the
lines you're setting up your rows you
could use overhead irrigation but this
is usually recommended as a quick fix
and not a permanent solution because of
the wedding of the leaves and the
increased chance for certain diseases to
occur I want to be using weed block to
suppress the weeds on your tomato Rose
there's many options but in row
protection may help reduce soil splash
as we see here
keep those tomatoes nice and well
positioned you could see the two drip
lines located here under the plastic
eliminating the amount that's lost to
evaporation for ultimate protection
though you might would be considering
in-between real protection we're here
we're noticing that where the harvesters
and caretakers are going to be walking
there's also some fabric laid down to
help reduce weed pressure there and also
eliminate potential for soil splash
there's a staking and weaving system so
here we see some mistakes you can tie
your Tomatoes up directly to those or a
wheat those right in between basket
weaving is advised for field to help
support the plants it needs to be set up
shortly after transplant to prevent wind
damage even in this caterpillar tunnel
situation here we want to be mindful of
wind that's coming through here which is
good for air circulation but we don't
want to damage our plants last summer
pruning everyone has their own method so
it can be personal preference but
typically the 2-litre system is
preferred and it has minimal side shoots
so minimum suppers that come out in high
tunnels some people use Eclipse to help
support the tomato crop others will kind
of wrap the tomatoes around that string
there so again personal preference and
exactly how you take care of them the
key part is in some way to be supporting
them and pruning them for maximum yield