so talk about the importance of drying
candidates properly so if it should take
you inside the drying room
now while drying can occur outdoors it
is definitely not advised because of the
variability that can occur the rain the
humidity the fog not a great area to
allow efficient drying to be done in the
room was controlled conditions I'm going
to go over what those conditions are so
it's very important to have a clean room
with excellent environmental control
want to have tight regulations over the
temperature to look around 65 degrees
Fahrenheit 18 degrees Celsius in
humidity starting at about 45% and
decreasing throughout the process it's
important also this room has very little
light that's at least on other than when
someone's in there inspecting it's also
a good idea to have even air circulation
but do not have a fan directly blood on
the on the drying buds gotta kind of
want to keep the air just moving in the
room but not in any one hot spot they're
monitoring the conditions is definitely
advised because this will have a great
impact on your final product integrating
a monitoring system that can ensure
consistent conditions will improve the
dry room the dry room conditions and
help ensure a consistent product so
having a way of monitoring and checking
and tracking are all systems definitely
well advised for the for the dry room
here now the placement of those buds can
be put on screens that are not
surrounded by leaves to keep the drying
process even inconsistent so that's kind
of the name of the game here whenever
anything I'll pal up in one area you can
see all these different rungs it's all
pretty much one blood thick they're not
really piled on top of one another very
very deep to allow that kind of even
drying process typically these screens
structures are hung from the ceiling to
allow good air circulation you can see
there's multiple in this room here some
growers this is not an example one that
some girls like convertible racks they
can help avoid flat spots we save labor
while increasing the overall air
circulation what these invertible racks
allow them growers to do is they're all
sealed they can learn there's a hanging
here and a hanger on top they can take
this whole rack flip it upside down and
rehang it now from what what does
see the bottom to help increase the
tumbling of those buds at least once to
allow for a better air circulation you
want to be sure to label each harvest
screen with a date variety and person
doing the harvesting as we see here you
expect me to ensure the room conditions
and evidence for even drying and that
person of harvesting is also important
to tell how the buds are trimmed
potentially or how they're drying or how
they were placed and also knowing the
cultivar in the variety and when it was
harvested a way to determine the degree
of dryness or they're ready for the
curing process do something called a
stem test if you take the area and near
the buds and you try to bend the stem
area if it bends then there's still some
dry time required if it snaps you're
ready for the curing process larger
denser buds may take a little longer to
completely dry so double check the
moisture content on these even when the
majority of the other buds may be dry
those may have to just go a little bit
longer now dry thyme freshly harvick
should be dried and ready for packaging
process in about seven to ten days some
can cut it as low as 5 to 7 typically
going over 10 is not advised the goals
of panel moisture content between 12 and
15 percent so if you harvest here on
Friday the 20s you're looking at 7 to 10
days would be your ideal dry time window
to get the max amount of time for profit
producing the highest quality buds now
in the dry run movements and some
conditions you want to have you also
want to avoid some conditions
particularly light UV light in
particular I don't want to have a lot of
that in the room heat above 80 degrees
Fahrenheit or 26 degrees Celsius and
friction which removes all the resins I
mean you don't wanna put the buds on
this kind of screen and then shake it
all around to get them to dry because
that could remove a lot of the resins
and we to see overall quality there of
the buds so this goes over some
conditions that you should have in the
dry room what you should look for in
some conditions you should be avoiding
to allow high quality buds for your
harvest