in this debaco university video we're
going to go over
the post-harvest canvas plant disposal
that goes a little bit more than just
beyond the plants
i want to consider about some of the
supporting equipment that it takes
to grow a plant indoors and how are we
best going to dispose of that
to think about this whole production
process in a sustainable manner
[Music]
all right let's go over indoor
operations post-harvest cannabis plant
disposal
so first off disposal of the actual
plant material
we can see here per the epa caymus waste
must also be made unusable and
unrecognizable before disposal mixed
with at least 50 percent non-cannabis
waste such as non-consumable solids
and stored in a secured waste receptacle
chemist waste can be disposed of
in a permanent landfill or through
composting consideration
or by means of in-vessel digestion there
are
landfill options which most cannabis
growers and processors are
shipping cannabis waste to landfills so
it's under federal scrutiny
composting is a goal to provide optimal
conditions for microbial metabolism to
help kind of
break down that process incineration is
this must occur at temperatures that are
high enough to destroy the toxic organic
components in and in the hazardous waste
as well as reduce the overall
volume note that this is not the same as
burning the leaves in your backyard
incineration is a much more
directed and controlled process then
there's in-vessel digestion which is a
more efficient method of composting
wherein the waste is confined within a
building
container or vesicle in order to
mechanically control airflow
temperature moisture and odors now
with indoor growing we also want to be
mindful and consider it of the
containers
some growers will reuse containers but
this can potentially carry over diseases
from one crop to another so
keep this in mind growers do need to
find a method of disposal of their
containers
depending on the size used in location
they may
be wanted by homeowners or donated to
community garden settings
depending on the size that you're using
and in the sense
that you could buy fresh every time
look at disposal of the substrate so the
substrate that is used will impact the
disposal method
solas mix is the easiest to dispose of
as it has more
universal applications so it can be used
in more secondary situations
and can even be added to compost
operations rockwell's more difficult to
dispose of
and simply typically sadly ends up in a
dumpster
now this soilless mix we're going to
take a quick step outside
so we can see kind of a kind of harvest
that went through
source mix that's left with our that was
grown in our containers for our cannabis
plants
and kind of how that looks on a
relatively small growing operation
so let's take a jump outside and we'll
come back inside and discuss some other
methods
now when setting up an indoor grow
operation you want to take into account
the entire growing season
and what you're going to be doing with
the plants overall so let's just show
some examples here
of some containers that have been
harvested we see
kind of what's left over let's hope will
be composted
out of some other amendments and kind of
reworked potential
for a crop coming in the future all
right welcome back inside hopefully that
just shows you
kind of that looking at that disposal
method when we want to consider the
substrate
we also want to be mindful of in our
indoor operations the
lights that are required so know the
materials that are in the bulbs because
many times they contain mercury in other
hazardous materials
we can see a whole collection of bulbs
here some single-ended dumbbell ended
this means that they cannot simply be
disposed of in the trash
be sure to drop them off at proper house
waste facilities don't just throw them
in the trash
and again on larger operations with a
lot of lights we also want to be
conservative the
ballasts themselves be sure you're
disposing of this properly
a lot of times they fit great and uh
containers can be picked up and
as a whole collection or sometimes
hazardous waste
locations have certain drop off times
that you could bring the lights or
used bulbs and lights to then we have
disposal lastly of the plant support
materials
and regardless of the method used plants
will often need some form of support
some use trellis netting or stakes these
can be reused in some cases
but this is more common with stakes as
they will go through a soak of some kind
of sterilization step before they are
reused
so just keep that in mind you don't want
to be using the same stakes in the sense
you could
carry over insects it could carry over
disease
all threats to your future growing areas
so you won't have a sterile
sterilization step unless you're buying
new
each and every time