welcome to this tobacco university video
where if you're growing plants indoors
and wondering how you can irrigate them
or what options you have
this is the video for you
all right let's get into indoor
irrigation options for cannabis
production
first off you have to determine if the
plant needs water
by lifting the containers usually to
gauge the water weight
this is simply lifting the containers
particularly if you're growing in
containers
it's better to use sometimes than meters
meters can be used as a backup but
getting that literal feel of your plants
yourself
is probably the best method especially
early on to determine
whether or not they should be watering
them
now when to fertilize well fertilized
water should be added each time you
water your plants
with low doses the goal is to have these
low dose and feed
each and every day to allow plants to
maintain consistent growth
some growers will choose to do maybe a
six day in the seventh day they kind of
do a freshwater flush
but the key part here is getting away
from once a week fertilizing
to every day but lower the dose down so
you're just providing that little bit of
a consistent feed
to your plants now irrigation in general
is defined as the process of applying
controlled amounts of water to plants
at needed intervals how the water is
delivered is really up to the grower
ideally the plant's performance will not
differ among different irrigation
systems
if each is performed correctly so that's
why it's important to know the options
because there really isn't necessarily
one
best option that's a reason why there
are options
each method does have its own set of
advantages and disadvantages which is
why growers need to select quote the
best fit
for their operation so one option
would be basically growing
hydroponically and the advantage is it
can really allow for maximum yields and
it's used a lot in the lettuce industry
as we see here
however the disadvantages to this method
is that there's a smaller margin for
error when compared to buffered
substrates swings in ph for example can
occur very rapidly
in hydroponic setups then there is hand
watering
and that's advantage that allows for a
very specific
plant to plant care if one plant needs a
little bit more you can get a little bit
more one needs a little bit less you can
give it a little bit less
however the disadvantage is that this is
very time consuming and plants can be
missed especially if you're growing a
lot of plants
then there's the flood and drain or the
ebb and flow method and the advantage is
that this offers even watering it's
basically a table here that floods and
drains
this allows also for the aeration of the
root zone
however the disadvantages are the
initial cost and setup of equipment
as well as maintaining the equipment and
keeping it clean
from cycle to cycle then we have indoor
drip irrigation and the advantages is
that this is very easy to automate
and offers plant specific watering
because you can add these little
emitters to individual plants
the disadvantage is of course the
initial cost and setup of equipment
and also continually checking to ensure
all tubings
tubes and fittings are all functioning
and working properly
making sure filters aren't getting
clogged then lastly we have aeroponics
and the advantage of aeroponics is that
this allows for
efficient at delivering nutrients to the
roots it also allows for easy visual
inspection of the root structure
the disadvantage is that this is
dependent on electricity
and can become less efficient when dense
roots are
formed as far as depending on the exact
setup that you may have
so hopefully this offers some options
check out this
channel for more details on each of
these options for indoor irrigation
of your cannabis plants