with the potential for co2 to increase
yields there's a lot of products
entering the marketplace that state that
they generate co2 but a lot of the
methods out there that are cheaper it's
going to be a very inefficient co2
generation method so what I cover just a
little bit about what areas you should
be kind of a concern if you're
considering that adding co2 is a great
thing or something you want to add what
are some more efficient methods and what
are some inefficient methods so
inefficient co2 generation methods those
messes that do generate co2 so they are
potentially stating they're generating
co2 and they are however but the amount
can be inconsistent and create variable
conditions typically they're cheaper
because you're not using a pressurized
tank or propane to burn for heat and
that really good way to regulate them
there's high variability to the
conditions that they can create also
there can be a lack of consistency which
could help increase the odds of variable
and the results so even if you have
success with one of these systems
replicating those successful results can
be a quite a challenge you should all be
considered if the gross space is small
for example be a small grow 10 and
you're operating with the idea if
something is better than nothing so I
want you to think that oh if you get one
of these systems typically fermentation
could be an option here on that they're
going to deal kind of consistent results
or they can be used in large operations
they're inefficient but something is
better than nothing they might be worth
consideration some of those methods for
co2 generation include the active
compost fermentation using dry ice which
is solid carbon dioxide mixing baking
soda and vinegar and there's some other
proprietary products out there also
however all these are poorly regulated
and only have a chance to work in very
small spaces dry ice or solid co2 my
think though that's just perfect
however how high in where it's being
released and how much is being released
that can cause some issues active
compost and fermentation yes it is
releasing co2 but based on the sugars
you feed the microbes based on the
release based on the mixing a lot of
these aren't regulated for day and night
cycles this is why I consider all these
to be inefficient methods of generating
co2 because while they do generate some
carbon dioxide
guess something is better than nothing
but if you're really looking at
efficiencies you might want to consider
other options that are more precise and
while they may cost more initially they
will ensure more consistent results