okay here we're gonna look at initiating
an immune response and while we do have
our innate immunity and our adaptive
immunity or a spoken-- focus a little
bit more on the adaptive immunity if you
in mind our innate Metis what we're born
with and includes surface defenses
physical barriers such as our skin and
mucous membranes we're gonna look a
little bit more about the activation of
T in B cells so the first part is the
body needs to be able to identify cells
as friend or as foe it does that with
self MHC markers located on the cell
surface in this case these markers
indicate self and indicate to the immune
system that these cells were naturally
made and are part of the body however in
this case we know assistance of non-self
or a foe marker these antigens are
different or foreign they don't match
the host cell markers as a result this
would initiate an immune response
macrophages are the ones responsible for
inspecting the surface of cells looking
for self MHC proteins the cell displays
the MHC protein antigen self non-self
combination the macrophage will secrete
the protein interleukin 1 and send an
alarm signal to initiate other cells for
this immune response to occur now of our
foreign body and our macrophage
recognizes that as a foreign body the
cd4 proteins required to authenticate
this transaction the interleukin 1
estimates helper T cells to initiate two
things and one end it's initiating a
cellular response resulting which is
responsible by the T cells in the
humoral response which is responsible by
the B cells and we see here now the T
cells in the cellular response once
activated the helper T cells secrete
interleukin 2 which activates cytotoxic
T cells to recognize and destroy cells
with the specific antigen found in the
antigen presenting cell keep in mind
this interaction the cell to cell
communication in binding is very
important we have our MHC 2 here's our
antigen these are t-cell receptor
this is activating the helper t-cells
this is then initiating these cytokines
to be released and is activated
cytotoxic t-cell is going through and
lice in this infected cell here through
this binding occurs now this method that
it chooses to use is very similar to
those of natural killer cells and it
stimulates the proliferation in
activation of these cytotoxic t-cells to
help initiate this cellular response to
help control these infected cells that
might be circulating throughout the body
our t-cells in the cellular response
well cytotoxic t-cells will also attack
transplant tissue and cause graft
rejection so when something it's an
organ transplant
it's the cytotoxic t-cells that may
cause that organ to be rejected the drug
cyclosporine in activates cytotoxic
t-cells this will be given after our
transplant to help reduce the chance of
someone's body rejecting the organ that
they just received now B cells are
responsible for the humoral response the
antigens here in antibodies is the T
part they produce so B cells recognize
nating microbes but do not go on the
attack themselves these cells are
responsible for producing antibodies
that inactivate in mark pathogens for
destruction by nonspecific immune
defenses so here we see B cell producing
a lot of antibodies these antibodies be
very specific ends here to bind to very
specific antigens now the B cells and
humoral response a little bit more
complicated here but we do see our b
cells become inactivated and in
producing antibodies marking this
construction now B cells combined free
and unprocessed Incentive antigens these
antigens are endo settees processed it
presented on the surface with MHC
proteins keep in mind has image c
markers their antigen MHC complex is
indicating a this is an antigen that we
need to be able to recognize and be able
to destroy because we've now marked this
as a foreign invader
the helper T cells recognizes complex
and they will stimulate D cells to
proliferate into memory cells and plasma
cells which are the plasma cells which
are responsible for the production of
the antibodies and here's our memory B
cell for a long-term memory lastly just
a couple last notes here about the
antibody action all antibodies forming
antigen antibody immune complex every
antibody has a very specific binding
site they match a specific antigen
please keep in mind that antibodies
themselves do not destroy the antigen in
D bodies in activate and tag it for
destruction that's their sole purpose
it's this taggle tagging in labeling
component the antibodies themselves are
not doing the destruction they are
merely being able to inactivate it and
tag it for destructions that other cells
can come about and do the work of
actually destruction of the pathogen
it's not specific to D antibodies
antibodies are very important for the
binding and identification but not for
the step of actually lie sink or
destroying the cell