he was going to be a brief overview of
three main classifications of injuries
that may occur on the body so first one
is sprains so the ligaments reinforcing
the joint are stretched or torn in this
case partially torn ligaments slowly
repair themselves completely torn
ligaments require prompt surgical repair
so if you're someone has a sprain you
may be able to ask them if they have a
grade one a grade two or a grade three
spring in this case a higher grade is
not a better thing higher grade number
indicates a more seriousness to the
injury grade one are just stretching or
small tears that may occur grade two is
larger but an incomplete tear grade
three is a complete tear so that's the
worst or most severe case continuing on
with injuries we also have injuries to
the cartilage the snap and pop of
overstressed cartilage common in
aerobics injuries repair with
laparoscopic surgery what laparoscopic
surgery is here is we're basically said
of the doctors taking their actual
instruments in going into the patient
laparoscopically are small holes are
punctured in and it's basically kind of
through the doctors control basically
through robotic arms in they want to TV
screen it allows for fine detailed
movement and allows for the delicate
repair of certain muscles or ligaments
that may occur as a result of aerobics
or potentially sport injuries here
damage to the cartilage in general we
see that here where we have maybe an
impact or the foot got stuck in the turf
here yeah that rotation up here we have
that tearing here of a ligament lastly
if our injuries are dislocations so
occurs when bones are forced out of
alignment
they're usually accompanied by sprains
inflammation and joint immobilization
serious Falls can are common sports
injuries can cause in dislocations so in
relation to this you may hear people say
again kind of like they're
double-jointed and that kind of really
doesn't exist there's no such thing as a
joint that can move kind of in two
different directions with classic
is a different type of joint but it has
to do with people some people can are
able to dislocate certain joints of
their body so if you want to learn more
about this potential kind of
double-jointed or what we may call
double-jointed in dislocation here of
double-jointed medical course and how
these these people with extremely
flexible and ability to dislocate their
shoulders be very painful in some cases
you can learn more about those in these
two videos located here so this again a
brief overview of three different types
of injuries