here we're gonna look at lien neat in
the acquired branches of the immune
system now you might be wondering why I
chose to include these pictures here on
the title slide well included the bird's
nests is kind of to address the word
innate Birds
um hatch out of eggs they come out of
the nest and they fly away I never
taught how to make a nest they have the
innate ability to make an S versus
acquiring being able to acquire and
build something such as engineers here
have to acquire materials and draw it
out and learn out of different symbols
to use and all this relates to the
immune system and you'll see how so the
innate versus the acquired immune system
there's two key differences in the
components so we see here some of the
macrophages the dendritic cells it's in
a fills all are part of the innate
immune system the adaptive which is also
called the acquired immune system
involved mainly b-cells and t-cells in
the production of antibodies cd4 t-cells
and cd8 t-cells to kind of put that into
a flowchart our innate swear immune
system acquired in an eight-hour innate
hears blood-borne kind of phagocytes
such as her neutrophils macrophages or
basophils natural killer cells as semo
fills all those are under the innate
physical barriers are also included
under the innate immune system those
include our skin or mucous membranes so
IVA steers stomach acid all those listed
under the innate now the acquired is
those T in these cells we have some
helper T cells from suppressor T cells
antibodies under the Morel immunity
through the B cells these are much more
specific it needs have to be acquired
over time this is where our body starts
to develop antibodies and help to
remember and carry over some information
from an initial exposure in case that
was to show up again putting this in
more of a pictorial form with comparing
the innate to be acquired the innate is
nonspecific beauty you were born with
its fast-acting occurred within a few
hours as we see here at the time table
down here it includes physical barriers
as well as chemical and immune cells so
some of those physical barriers include
skin hair cilia mucus that just have
enzymes these stomach acid
some internal defenses can be compliment
proteins phagocytic cells and natural
killer cells these are not specific but
very quick acting these might be kind of
the first ones on sight to a potential
source of infection and all of these you
are basically born with getting more
specific are acquired or adaptive
immunity
this is antigen specific this is more
complex however it has a lag time you
know start time table down here is not
ours but days now because it requires
time to process and recognize about
potential invaders it includes a memory
for future infections which is great and
always in part what makes vaccines
effective the adaptive immune system as
antibodies cell mediated immune response
in memory response both of these are
very important components of the immune
system some you're born with and some
you acquire and build up over time