this is going to be a brief overview of
inner gimmick hydroponic production so
there's also some vape taking organics
inorganics the key part is whether using
organics or in organics fertilizing
plants tend to do a lot better than
those that are unfertilized especially
with hydroponic production we're pretty
much growing in a water-based solution
choosing what nutrients to add are very
important and you can use a combination
of both inorganic and organic for a
quality and product specifically though
in organics the advantage is especially
towards newer growers who should start
with this type of idea I want to start
with organics where that adds a lot of
complexity new growers should start with
in organics because it tends to be a
more stable product you're able to look
at measure and see results that are a
little bit more consistent organics can
cause some changes incandescent variable
plant availability aspects so if you're
brand new to growing it's not unwise to
start with in organics because it can
offer you that consistency and it'll be
able to learn the plans and then slowly
incorporate more organics if you would
like to into your operation often in
organic fertilizers or more quickly
plant available so something to keep in
mind if you are switching back and forth
as a result this can allow growers to
correct potential issues fast so even if
you are in organic grower you're having
an issue you may want to grab an
inorganic fertilizer to help speed that
or correct that problem that you're
noticing quickly for both the new and
experienced growers consistency can
offer many benefits this is one of the
advantages to inorganic fertilizers
being able to develop a feeding plan can
help increase the odds of success and
you could run plants on just the right
amount of nutrients keep a-movin dialed
in keeping that kind of everything
focused and very consistent can result
in very high yields