okay here we're looking insect
management for squash because if you're
growing squash you're likely to see one
if not all four of these insects on your
plants first wears cucumber beetles I'm
going to start with they are small
yellow beetles with either black spots
or black stripes and they can start very
early in the season as early as first
week of May insect netting is a good
thing to cover your young seedlings with
to act as a physical barrier organically
they can be controlled with gigantic or
surround or chemically
7.now while they are small there's
rarely just one and they will devastate
leaves and they are very voracious
eaters so important to keep monitoring
your plants especially when they're
small squash bugs is another one to look
out for there are large brown beetles
and have almost an armor plating to them
when they're crushed they so like sour
apple really small reddish tannish eggs
and often laid in clusters how to
prevent these the same thing in set
netting is the only real option they're
very difficult to control organically by
Ganic may have some effectiveness
chemically 7 but it does not really work
that well on adults you want to spray
them at the end in stage because they're
much easier to control at this stage the
products work a little bit better that
armor plating kind of shields them from
some of the chemicals insecticides give
you a size comparison this is a spotted
cucumber beetle so you can see the
relative size comparison of these squash
bugs adult and thence to a spotted
cucumber beetle now their squash vine
borers their large black moths that are
mostly active around the mid part of the
day I prevent them to be a physical
barrier like insect netting or you could
plant butternut squash they have solid
vines and they're immune to squash vine
borers now the moths don't really do the
damage they'll a single eggs throughout
the plant typically on the lower leaf
stocks or the vine itself what happens
from the end of small grub will hatch
and borrow a burrow into the vine and
eat it from the inside out
they like to lay this eggs at the base
of the plant and they're extremely hard
to spot and typically see this orange
kind of frass and that could be an
indication if you have a grub inside
especially if the plant starts to wilt
he feeds another concern with a lack in
size
for in numbers very small black or tan
or white or clear specs is what you're
looking for this kind of shows that very
small how they can look here on the
inner side of leaves if you find
bumblebees in an area and it's devoid of
flowers look closer oftentimes this is a
high site of a fan feeding because
they're releasing plant sugars that the
bumblebees are feeding on you can use
reflective plastic we block to help
repel athens they can be very difficult
to control spring garlic based sprays
can help with pain we can tell them
there's also biological control such as
green lacings which can help actively
kind of insect insect bio control them
but they are very small and they do have
a lot of numbers and they can do severe
damage to your crops