okay here we're a look and review ions
and exactly what this is so when I spend
a little time on this slide right here
we see a neutral hydrogen atom this is
not an ion it's got one proton one
electron one positive charge one
negative charge therefore one proton one
electron it's net charge would be zero
be neutral and this notation just be
hydrogen now if that hydrogen loses an
electron it is going to become positive
there's one positive proton no negative
charges therefore it takes on a positive
one charge being noted as H+ that was
what we would call a cation that's a
positive ion contrast to that we have
our neutral hydrogen atom here and we
add an electron so now we have two
electrons in one proton now we have one
positive charge in two negative charges
the net charge on this would be a
negative one and eh- is how to be noted
that we called in an ion it's a negative
ion there so let's look at this a little
bit more more here's the same slide I
showed you here so in an atom an ion is
an atom or group of atoms that has a net
positive or negative charge so again
that ion referring to something that has
a charge neutral would just be called an
atom atoms can gain or lose electrons to
form ions an ion is an atom of the
charge that's your kind of take home
summary right there recall that atoms
are neutral in charge if electron is
lost the overall charge is positive and
electron is gained in atom becomes
negative so initially this does confuse
students losing an electron becomes
positive when electron keep in mind is a
negative charge for losing a negative
charge the overall charge their port is
positive or so not easier think of the
other way if an electron is gained the
atom is gaining a negative charge its
itself going to become negative we see
that in their example here is the same
thing in the title slide now an ins at
ions and atomic radius so we're looking
at atomic radius here
when electrons are lost their radius
becomes smaller when electrons are
gained the radius becomes larger so we
see that here we see our ions is the
dark grey here and here we're losing an
electron
therefore if we're losing the electron
the radius will become smaller potassium
which is represented by k+ here it's
neutral atom would be this large blue
area when it loses the electron the
electron the erase becomes smaller you
see that here it's smaller radius
contrast to that here our nonmetals
let's take chlorine for example neutral
atom here is that kind of Tanis region
when it gains the Rays becomes larger so
it's gaining an electron that ion
that negative ion it an ion here is
larger than the neutral atom so it's how
our atomic radius changes based on the
ion that these elements may form showing
how that may look here positive cation
formation when an atom loses electrons
radius always becomes smaller because
the loss of a valence electron can leave
an empty outer orbital resulting in a
smaller radius electrostatic repulsion
decreases allowing the electrons to be
pulled closer to the radius so how does
that look here we see here our outer
shell valence electron has one we've
removed that electron creating the +1
charge and we see this visually right
here there's a change in a reduction in
the radius of that particular atom we
see that here for giving a group 1 group
2 group 13 how the ion in red is smaller
than the neutral atom represented in
gray and we see how those trends occur
here in the periodic table
continuing on via and negative ion
Organa information when atoms gain
electrons the radius always increases
which is sometimes contrary and like why
does this occur more electrons mean more
electrostatic repulsion resulting in an
increase in the diameter here we have
more
negative charges out here is a negative
one more electrons out there think of
just more space that they need so
therefore the radius and an anion the
negative charge will increase over the
neutral atom we see that trend that
developed here also on the periodic
table here's the neutral atom and then
here's our ions that are forming in blue
we see overall all those are larger the
in ions are larger radius than their
neutral atom