swallowers no it's important to irrigate
their crops they might not realize the
options that they that do exist to what
are their plants so we're gonna go over
just a couple of those here so first off
irrigation options while there are many
options here to choose from the goal is
to officially deliver water to the
plants that's coming for all of them and
the best fit may depend on the exact
operation whether it's field roan or
indoor Verona container Verona what type
of media you're using you can see here
the athletic field here using pop-up
sprinklers kind of overhead irrigation
is the best for this operation others we
have hand watering against the version
of overhead or drip irrigation are all
options worth considering so first off
hand watering it's only good for small
operations and even in this situation
it's really not advised it's a very
time-consuming and not very efficient
process you should only be used to
supplement other methods to compensate
for potential dry spots so it shouldn't
be the main source it should be kind of
a supplement till one of the other main
sources simply because it's just so
time-consuming
you're really not offering that much
benefits to the plants especially in
areas where you have a very eaten
conditions overhead irrigation outdoor
applications only would be advised for
this I don't want to get a mess and an
indoor especially running lights it
could be a very negative effect there I
should still be used sparingly the
reason why overhead should be used
sparingly is it what's the leaves and
buds and this is why it's not a good
option I can increase mold that could
occur and get all bad things you if you
must use it I have run it early in the
morning when plants are typically
covered in morning dew anyway so you're
not kind of real etic rewetting leaves
you're already kind of getting leaves
and flowers that might be well already
you're kind of just rewetting them
you're not running it at a time that
you're kind of free inducing more
moisture than would be there normally
there's micro sprinklers so these are
kind of like an overhead can hardly get
the size orientation these are smaller
there's specific type of that overhead
irrigation and you're best utilized to
cover areas with low volumes of water
there's inverted for overhead and
there's vertical or pop-ups as we see
here and they spin so they act in a very
similar manner to overhead irrigation
there's also fogging equipment so
typically this is not considered a
source of irrigation
I don't think you're using a fogger for
irrigation using that more for cooling
cuz it's producing the lily that's very
very fine mist and see in the outdoor
operation here for kind of demonstration
purposes but they can be used in indoor
operations we see the lights hanging
here this aqua fog placed right in the
grow facility water is applied is
intended for cooling or humidity
regulation not to hydrate the plants
directly so even though you are using
water don't consider us as a form of
irrigation the goal is to wet the leaf
surface but not to the point of runoff
if we're looking at a true fogging
system some people will say they're
using the fogging system and kind of
like overuse it and what the leaves of
the plants and get it to run off and
kind of use it as a form of irrigation
if you're using a true fighting system
not very efficient for that purpose
better for cooling and humidity
regulation then there's drip irrigation
this is a very efficient way to deliver
water and nutrients as the water Li will
one drip at a time reach the plants we
could see kind of this long run here of
how that drip irrigation operates this
is a low volume low pressure system does
require an initial investment in all
this material but once invested it can
last for several years it can also be
easily automated with timers and
fertilizer injectors for canvassers ease
up coming in very popular these
irrigation rings they're typically uses
a modified drip irrigation system for
even watering of containers and that
could be soured pots or plastic pots
it's specifically marketed for Kansas
production because of the typically the
high demand of water for the plant and
also the ability to cover each
individual plant very efficiently keep
in mind if you are using containers for
indoor operations in particular all
containers need to have a way to catch
the extra water some sort of Basin below
them these catch bins or simple drains
necessary to prevent standing water from
collecting and sitting in the bottom of
the container either way for that
moisture to go to or that water to go to
especially if you're flushing plants and
just a gray to keep an eye on to make
sure that you are getting a sufficient
water in the chosen media that you are
using lastly if your are using storage
tanks as part of your irrigation system
it's important to monitor and clean this
on a regular basis too often if they're
sitting in place people just kind of
fill them and use them they won't worry
about you know any sort of contaminants
especially if they're outdoors they can
build up algae potentially if they're
mobile like this was in sealed still
keep an eye look and inspect it to make
sure there's nothing growing there you
don't want they can be difficult to
clean tanks that if you're used for
gravity systems and are high on a tower
but still worth the extra to quick time
to go check to make sure they are clean
so you don't ruin an entire crop due to
a dirty tank because of the lack of the
grower digging this there's a couple
seconds to kind of monitor it if it is
dirty taking the time then to spend to
clean that to make sure that the water
that irrigating their plants worth is as
clean as pure as possible to reduce the
chance of contamination