okay here we're answering the question
is it easier to hold your breath after
inhalation or after exhalation and then
hold your breath so which one of those
is it easier to hold you breath for a
longer period of time
well actually it's easier to hold your
breath after inhalation and after
exhalation so why is that if you've ever
tried this you can try it yourself try
it in playing and all your breath and
exhale all your breath what's important
there the science behind this is that
your bodies cannot detect a little
oxygen but are sensitive actually to
high carbon dioxide your brain actually
uses blood carbon dioxide as an
indicator for blood oxygen so that when
your co2 levels are too high your signal
to take a breath so your body is only
looking at the carbon dioxide levels
speaking the assumption if carbon exit
is high then oxygen must be low now if
you find this heart believes that low
oxygen is not what makes you breathe
this is clearly a proof of concept and
that's carbon monoxide poisoning what's
happening during carbon monoxide
poisoning is all these negative factors
can also be death sadly or coma reason
why this happens is because you're
breathing air with low oxygen the co2
levels are actually the same in your
body that's what's regulating your
breathing so your breathing is actually
as normal even though because your co2
levels are normal
even though your oxygen levels are
becoming dangerously low you basically
die without ever realizing it because
your oxygen deprived so it's not because
of little oxygen you start breathing
more or start feeling shortness of
breath no your oxygen levels are
decreasing in carbon monoxide poisoning
but because your carbon dioxide levels
remaining normal your body basically
doesn't react as a result that low
oxygen they'll basically black out
without any warning the science behind
the question here is lungs full of a
breath of air have high oxygen
concentration and low carbon dioxide
concentration then your body does so
oxygen flows into your blood and carbon
acid out of your blood even though
you're holding your breath then after a
period of time
empty lungs have lower volume so fewer
carbon dioxide molecules are needed to
get the same concentration in your blood
reverses the process of diffusion thus
covering
they stops leaving your blood faster if
the lumps are empty meaning carbon
dioxide levels in your blood reach
critical levels faster and you need to
breathe sooner looking this in a
graphical standpoint is looking at
divers
here's normal breathing there's no
breathing virgin need to breathe occurs
when high carbon dioxide levels trigger
breathing has nothing to do with your
body perceiving oxygen levels also
notice our pH can influence the
hemoglobin binding portion there keep in
mind hemoglobin is a protein and as a
result pH can influence its shape and
its ability to bind oxygen lastly here
respiratory adjustments at high
altitudes if you've ever been to high
altitude there's basically air is not
quite as dense your body responds to
quick movement to high altitude which is
considered to be above 8,000 feet with
symptoms of acute mountain sickness it
is headache shortness of breath nausea
dizziness all negative things become an
alchemist committed to this area
respiratory and human trophic
adjustments include increasing
ventilation can actually breathe more
are more exchange more air supposedly
also you become more responsive to
carbon dioxide pressure and a
substantial decline in current and
oxygen pressure stimulates this
peripheral chemoreceptors so it's
important if you're going up to high
altitudes to adjust to this to basically
get yourself a climate 'add to this you
want to not go from sea level to 14,000
feet in one day when it worked your way
up to that typically it's suggested that
you start from that you're used to being
at sea level go up to 5,000 feet then go
above 8,000 feet and worked way up to
14,000 feet here at Pikes Peak now
body's going to do some of these
adjustments it's going to breathe a
little heavier you're going to drink a
lot of water these are all ways you can
try to negate some of this mountain
sickness that does occur and simply
occurring with your body's reacting day
simply having less air density at a high
altitude that what's typically used to
at low altitude you see this a lot
sports teams and events that go to
potentially Denver Mile High Stadium or
in Mexico or areas are very high in
elevation they
oh they're up to a week before so they
can get adjusted their body's adjusted
to that lower amount of air density