okay for those playing the home game
here's the question is it easier to hold
your breath after inhalation or is it
easier to hold your breath after
exhalation
see and you can try it out for yourself
and see which method allows you to hold
your breath for longer I think just you
pause the video here I don't want to see
you pass out okay moving on so let's go
with the science on this so why is it
easier to hold your breath hopefully
they found after inhalation you should
be able hold your breath longer than
after you exhale so your body actually
cannot detect low oxygen but it is very
sensitive to high carbon dioxide your
brain actually uses blood carbon dioxide
as an indicator for blood oxygen this
soon so when co2 levels are too high
we are signaled to take a breath it's
assuming when co2 levels are high that
oxygen levels are low this is kind of
the exchange that's going on in the
capillaries of your lungs
so let's proof-of-concept oil if you
think that well I think my body can
sense the oxygen levels that nothing to
come that side consider carbon monoxide
poisoning it happens because you're
breathing air with low oxygen but
believe it or not that carbon dioxide
co2 levels from evarin monoxide is just
Co co2 levels are the same in your body
in which regulates your breathing as
usual so you die without ever realizing
you were oxygen deprived this is what
happens when carbon monoxide poisoning
is so dangerous this real blackout
without any warning you're just
breathing along normally because your
body actually is the same amount of
carbon dioxide which is using the sense
but your oxygen levels are actually
decreasing in a very rapid and
potentially very dangerous rate with
carbon monoxide so the science behind
the question so when your lungs are full
of breath of air you have a high oxygen
concentration and a lower carbon dioxide
concentration then your blood does so
when your inhale the oxygen flows to
your blood and co2 out of the blood
there's still exchange it occurs because
you have a large volume of air
empty lungs have to exhale have a lower
volume so fewer carbon dioxide molecules
are needed to get the same concentration
in your blood that's going to raise that
level that much quicker because of this
carbon exit stops leaving your blood
faster the lungs are empty
meaning the co2 levels in your blood
reach a critical level faster and causes
you to need or feel that burden of
needing to breathe sooner then when you
inhale they're still exchanging that's
occurring here and it's through the
body's ability to monitor the carbon
dioxide levels and has nothing to do
with oxygen levels so we see that here
that kind of urgent need to breathe here
high carbon dioxide levels that burning
feeling as your body wants to try to
reduce that carbon dioxide it's assuming
this increase in carbon dioxide is
leading to a decrease in oxygen it can
only sense and determine the carbon
dioxide levels because it's going to
change the leave amount of the pH of
your blood and that's what your body is
sensing so this gives just a little bit
of background here of is it easier to
hold your breath after breathing in and
breathing out and if you are in a
situation do you have to hold your
breath take the deepest breath you can
possible so fill your lungs with a lot
of air to allow that exchange to occur
for a longer period of time giving you
that ability to not feel that urgent
need to breathe until later then if you
were to exhale that concentration would
increase much quicker