okay here okay isolating mechanisms what
things may keep certain individuals
apart from one another that will
influence the genes that are passed on
to a generation or that are prevented
from intersecting within another species
so reproductive isolated populations
populations whose members do not mate
with each other or cannot produce
fertile offspring reproductive isolating
mechanisms are the barriers that prevent
genetic exchange between species so we
have an original population here and
we're seeing a shift into two different
isolated species here with our examples
of the Flies we have some that like
starch and maltose and then we have a
favoritism for one versus the other and
therefore we have individuals that may
only mate with those that like a certain
food source separating out and causing
subsets of the population to develop
flowers examples here can select for
their pollinators so some flowers have
evolved to attract only certain species
to help them appalling so the white
foxglove flowers adapted for bees and
this long tube shaped flower is better
for hummingbirds so this is an example
of flowers selecting first certain
pollinators to help attract and that is
reproductive isolation because the bees
will not be going through and pauline
these flowers this flower will be trying
to match the habits better of the
hummingbird and the bee there's
pre-psychotic isolating mechanisms and
this prevents the formation of a zygote
so this is a barrier that somehow
prevents the sperm getting to the egg or
the pollen to the egg and there's
postzygotic isolation mechanisms these
prevent popular functioning of as I go
after they formed so this is the zygote
is forming but then there's something
that's preventing it from growing to
have fully developed in normally
functioning individual temporal
isolation occurs when two populations
differ in their periods of activity or
reproductive cycles example so leopard
frogs in the wood frogs they reach
sexual maturity at different times in
the spring and hence do not interbreed
so this is an example of
temporal isolation behavioral isolation
occurs when two populations exhibit
different courtship patterns we have two
crickets here in certain populations
produced different mating songs so a
mate is only going to find the proper
individual that has the right song if an
individual's producing a different tune
or song or ritual they will not be
selected is part of me for that
particular population so the behaviors
that an individual exhibits can result
in its isolation there's geographic
isolation and this occurs when two
populations occupy different habitats or
separate niches within a common region
the example being lions and tigers
occupy different habits habitats and do
not interbreed at least usually they're
in different geographical areas
therefore they're not breeding together
this kind of is a nice summary table of
both pre and post zygotic isolating
mechanisms one over the temporal that's
when they made different times of the
year psychological is when two species
occupy different habits habitats
behavioral when they have different
courtship behaviors and mechanical
occurs when physical differences prevent
pollination for example in this case
different sized dogs simply mechanically
cannot produce offspring because they
can't physically meet postzygotic
isolation isms could be hybrid in in
viability which means the hybrids are
produced but failed developed to
reproductive maturity it's also hybrid
in fertility more hybrids failed to
produce functional gametes in their
sterile example of our mules in hybrid
breakdown where f1 hybrids are fertile
but f2 fails to develop properly so
these are giving you some examples and
these are some more specific examples of
the general pre and post I got it
isolating mechanisms