okay here okay as the title suggests
isotopes and half-life so first off
again defined what an isotope is all
atoms of an element have the same number
of protons which is an important thing
to remember but may have different
number of neutrons isotopes are two
atoms of an element that differ in the
number of neutrons keep in mind the
number of protons will define the
element so you see here our three
examples here are all hydrogen where
hydrogen because they each have one
proton
they each also have one electron here
we're only looking at the change in the
number of neutrons so here there's no
neutrons protium here there's one
Neutron deuterium and here we have two
neutrons
pterygium these are all examples of
isotopes of the element hydrogen now
isotopes
there's also reactive isotopes and
radioactive isotopes at that kind of
dangerous they're unstable indicate
spontaneously they give off particles
and energy not all elements are
radioactive so there's some that are
definitely a lot more likely to be
radioactive and that all elements
necessarily have radioactive isotopes
that at least occur in nature so the
half-life it's the time required for the
amount of radioactive material to
decrease by half again we're looking at
some take a very long time some take a
very short period of time so the
radioactive nuclei our time half-life
the time it takes for half of the
material to decay so the same general
trend will be for all the elements we
see here the time it takes so this time
measurement is going to be different so
this time it takes for half the material
to decay for uranium 238 is 4.5 billion
years so extremely long period of time
for half that material to break down
carbon-14 has that time it takes this
distance would be five thousand seven
hundred and thirty years
and if you get to like some other like
potassium-40 1.25 billion years so I
don't you think they always take a very
long time business to 14 this house life
will only last about 19 point 7 minutes
all the way down is very unstable at
last well well under a second so the
graph will look the same but the time
distance will be very different
depending on the particular isotope that
you're dealing with based on the element
so if you look at here decay of
carbon-14 see our sample in years
percent of carbon-14 atoms we started a
hundred percent half-life of our
carbon-14 universe 5730 years so they
reached 50 percent here would be about
five thousand seven hundred thirty to
decrease 50 percent by half would be
about 25 and we see five thousand seven
thirty plus five hundred five thousand
seven I'm 32 just over or ten thousand
here we notice that that trend continues
we see here the dots that are
disappearing throughout the half-life we
very rarely reached zero get very very
close but we're always dividing by two
that's how we get this general curve
that occurred that occurs when referring
to half-life lastly our applications are
radioactive isotopes through dating
fossils tracing atoms through metabolic
processes in diagnosing medical
disorders these half-life's that we have
rather put in the body that aren't
extremely radioactive or deadly we can
trace and track where things may go
through the body because we know
carbon-14
for example the body or the plant is
going to take that in this regular
carbon some of the more shorter isotopes
or half-life's that we deal with for
isotopes we'll be able to track and see
where those are in the body but it's not
going to recognize it as oh that's an
isotope it's gonna treat it like it just
a normal element and that allows us to
track and see through these radiographs
here these scans this is iodine 123 to
see where that may accumulate in the
body what organs what tissues that may
accumulate in
we're looking specifically at carbon-14
it's very long half-life 5730 years as
we say here that's good for fossil
dating not great for Edo
radiology here because it's so long here
we have to track well how old were those
rocks how old were those fossils our
plans that allows us to give us an idea
based on that decay that occurs when
that first carbon was assimilated
hopefully this helps explain a little
bit about isotopes and half-life for you