hyrum look at the plant hormones osmotic
acid also known as Jasmine aids now this
can be abbreviated GA and since the
1980s details have become better
understood this is one of those plant or
moans it's kind of gone there's some
recent research in some recent findings
is a lipid derived stress hormones that
thrive the picture of the fats here and
that's important because it's found in
the membrane in the phospholipid bilayer
of the chloroplasts and keep in mind
that is the light receding organelle
here that is responsible for the
photosynthetic process jasmine eights
regulate plant annotations to two biotic
stresses they can be activated during
herbivore attack or pathogen infection
so this is an example of something that
can be upregulated in times of stress to
the plant it's also involved with
abrahamic stresses such as those
occurring ozone damage in ultraviolet
radiation so it can be involved also
with biotic herbivores or pathogens are
also a biotics which is wounding
examples there now said increasing the
number of studies have shown that these
GA s also function in plant development
now that plant development conclude
those primary root growth so very
important for root development
reproductive development and also leaf
senescence keep in mind senescence is
kind of the natural aging of the plant
that causes eventually to degrade and
fall off the plant so this is a brief
overview of adjustments or asthmatic
acid