so on this debaco university video we're
going to go over the june nitrate soil
test
it's a great way to evaluate the
nitrogen in your soil which is
constantly changing
but this test is a good job of
evaluating that content
of nitrogen in your soil
[Music]
all right let's get into the june
nitrate soil test well looking at that
june nitrate
test here the june nitrate test also
goes by the name of
presidedress nitrate test or the psnt
it was developed in the mid-1980s and
was the first soil test for nitrogen
in humid regions like new england and we
typically see it associated with corn as
it is here
but it can be used for other crops as
well so keep that in mind that while
you'll see a lot of images or a lot of
correlation with it for corn
yes that was where it developed is from
but it is applicable to many other crops
the june nitrate test is commonly
associated with corn production but can
also be applied to other field-grown
crops so even though the images might
show you here the graphs for corn
again realize it is applicable so the
data generated from this test can be
applied to other crops and field
conditions
here we're seeing the soil nitrate
concentration in parts per million
and the relative corn yield we do see
this kind of like general this kind of
curve here where
if we increase our soil nitrogen
concentration much above that
region here we can see there's really
not that much uh increase in relative
corn yield at least on a percentage
basis so that june
nitrate the test is based on
concentrations of nitrate nitrogen or
no3n
in the soil sample when the soil nitrate
concentration is greater
than 25 parts per million the
probability of increased yield from
n fertilizer applied to the field is
very low
so this is why with that psnt test
depending what the values come back
as estimate nitrogen to apply in pounds
per acre
you could see that there are values and
that's typically above that
uh 25 parts per million range that no
additional nitrogen fertilizer would be
recommended see that here
if it's a net 21-24 about 10
a likely loss so expected yield response
consider side dressing with 20 to 50
pounds of nitrogen per acre
less than 21 we look at here other
specific guidelines that have presented
here but realize about 25 and above
really no need to apply any nitrogen
fertilizer
so what does this test provide well the
test provides an indication of how much
nitrogen will be available to the crop
during the growing season a little bit
more than just a point in time trying to
estimate during the growing season
it measures nitrate in the soil at a
point in time but makes estimations
going forward
sampling is time to match before corn
goes into the higher requirement for
nitrogen which is why it's commonly
referred to as the june nitrate test
and really for other crops as well
sampling in june would also be
recommended
the goal is to minimize the uncertainty
and make for when you're making those
fertilizer recommendations from the lab
however this test can be performed
during other months but typically in
june a lot of the labs offer their
quickest
turnaround time which can be very
important when you're collecting a
sample so it's kind of like a soil
sample
but slightly different because unlike
traditional mineral based
soil tests the june nitrate test soil
sample should be collected from the
surface
foot of soil so from the very top all
the way down instead of six to nine
inches down to 12 inches down
the sample should be placed in a paper
bag and got into the lab as soon as
possible
you do not want to put them in plastic
because that will
cause a nitrogen to react and not give
you a proper field
representative sample results are sent
to growers within 24 hours of being
processed by the lab
typically only during the month of june
and that's why it's simply called
junitrate test
this is because soil samples are
collected when corn is about 6 to 12
inches tall
and it's actively growing so farmers
need to be able to get into equipment
into the field if necessary
to add fertilizer before the plants get
too tall that's why the lab has such a
quick turnaround time when they can
so what is the optimum rate well
excessive would be greater than 30 parts
per million
optum is at 20 to 30 parts per million
and deficient would be under
20 parts per million of that nitrate
nitrogen knowing your field history and
keeping records can help you dial in
your nitrogen and maximize yields
while minimizing potential for
environmental contamination
and increasing your overall costs so
here again another recommendation based
on your soil nitrate level
looking at silage corn again but
applicable to other crops as far as how
much nitrogen should you
add and here we can see that there are
some indications
where you don't want to add any nitrogen
fertilizer because you're just not going
to get any return
on that investment hopefully that
explains a little bit more
about the nitrate test and how you have
to sample the first foot
get the lab as quickly as possible don't
use a plastic bag
and it helps determine your nitrogen and
in some cases you may not need to add
any nitrogen