okay here I'm gonna go over something
that I think it's overlooked by a lot of
growers and it's simple factor of
keeping records now they don't have to
be this larger this extensive but this
is more important than most growers
realize the systems variable not every
farmer takes the records exactly the
same way but the key part is that you
have something that you actually will do
some form or some method actually
documenting what occurred in maintaining
those records so that you can refer back
to them in the future
so obvious question is just well why
should I keep records what's the point
and a good year you want to know what
you did so something worked out really
good and I'd say you kind of want to
have those records so you can repeat
that pattern in future years however in
a bad year you also know will want to
know what you did because you want to
know why didn't it work or why in
hindsight look at a decision I made or
something that occurred I didn't react
to quick enough so it's also beneficial
then so you can see whether you have a
good year or a bad year keeping records
is important and even though a year to
some things you can't control 100% but
you just want to know what happened and
potentially why that occurred so what do
I keep records of well there's no right
or wrong answer to this but why focus on
a few important items or crops soil
testing is an excellent record to keep
and maintain for each field planting
dates that could be started in the field
that could be started in the greenhouse
that could be transplant dates sins like
that and also in general each crop has
its own unique qualities but when it
went into flower one day I noticed fruit
set when I see insects and disease
sightings start to increase what are my
harvest dates for my yields on the field
again a lot of things you can
potentially keep track of you want to
focus on a few that you're actually
going to do and it will provide you
information in the future internet some
disease scouting you know about when a
disease came in one year so you can be
ready for and prepare for the following
year when was fruit set one was
flowering how does it relate to harvest
date how many days after how many weeks
after did that occur it can be important
for your clients or your
csa your people asking when you're gonna
have X Y or Z you can give them a better
idea years to come when you see that
flowering you know oh it's gonna be two
weeks to me three weeks then I should
have something for you how do I keep
records a question I get asked a lot
well you want to label the fields with
the name that's logical to you I don't
care what you call the fields I'll call
them quote whatever you call them you
want to keep the name independent of the
crop so you don't want to call this the
sunflower field because this year you
grew sunflowers and next year will be
tomatoes or corn and you're like oh the
sunflower field yeah they want the corn
on it now try to get away from calling
it with the crop that's grown on it
called the name next to the hillside you
know the level field the rocky field the
next to Grandma's house whatever works
for you it's not a problem as long as
you know what that relates to and you
can break up your fields as small as
possible here a nice level area well
here you have different fields keep the
name independent of the crop and label
it something logical you call it North
one north to north three that works too
you don't to get fancier creative with
their names but get away from calm buy
the crop because ideally he'll be
rotating and that might confuse you in
future years as weather important to
keep track of weather should be
documented I feel in some way individual
weather stations you could have are an
option you can use some public sources
that are probably close enough I want to
find a station that's close to you
whether you're in the hills or the
valley or near the shore or anywhere in
between you want to have an area that's
close to you still be a little
microclimate set develop and just gives
you a general idea and if it rains well
how much rain you could have a simple
rain gauge something like that just so
you have some sort of documentation
temperature fluctuations highs and lows
Weather Channel provides some data some
Weather Underground some other web sites
that are great at just documenting what
the weather is and just have a way to
document and save that for you so a
suggestion do I have what do I use to
keep track records well one
recommendation is use a slideshow format
which makes it easy to import pictures
and the title Connect is the Dayton
stand like a PowerPoint here written
notes work also you can type those right
in there so what system I use I use a
PowerPoint or a slideshow system I find
it really easy for pictures which are
important really to put dates in drop
a couple notes and move on to the next
slide for different fields I could have
different powerpoints it allows me to go
back and dial in and really focus in on
what may have occurred in that that
region again and since that works for me
do you have to use this no I do a lot of
powerpoints what would I like about it
it's really easy to put pictures in
which are important and as I said
pictures are highly recommended because
even though you're taking a picture of X
later you may be more interested in Y so
while you look at this picture if you
see the older woman or the two guys in a
horse something that you may see
originally may get changed
you might be looking at the tomatoes but
later when you look back you might be
looking at Oh what weeds are coming in
or what did the leaves look like or what
does that thing behind it or other
things it's amazing what a picture can
tell you looking back with fresh eyes on
it an example here do you see the older
man's face here there's his nose and
mustache you see the young lady's back
here here's her nose her eyes and this
would be her ear this would be her hair
there so as I said those pictures
because you might see something
initially you might be fur back to them
it might be different should I take
written notes written notes can be quick
and easy field notes quick little thing
all right on your phone real quick
whiteboard works too but be careful
these can get erased and if they get wet
or rain or water they're gonna run good
for quick little notes sometimes if your
workers have something to jot down or
something they see could have a little
board dedicated to that that's great
quick little field notes there's
something quick easy what did you see
what you need to document all good
options in just in some way of taking
notes a last important point determine a
format on that you'll actually do
provide helpful information looking back
and will keep yourself organized however
you want to organize it with a crop or
by field what you see you could do look
at the fruit look at the leaves and
other look at insects you just want to
have some sort of format it'll keep you
better in tuned with did I miss
something or did I make sure I write
down everything they're on that I need
to see and again they don't have to be
long quick little notes
I do want the whole goal is to be able
to have something to refer back to
during the offseasons you can better
plan for the next year