welcome to this tobacco university video
where i'm going to go over key plant
hormones and give you kind of a quick
general summary of many of the hormones
that impact plants
all right let's get into those key plant
hormones here
so first off i want you to understand
that there's many plant hormones there's
not just
one there's not just two and even within
the couple categories
there's multiple that may fall under
that same category
so there's many different plant hormones
some of the main categories of plant
hormones will be covered and provide you
a general overview
but i just want you to realize that just
under gibberellins and that's this one
plant hormone typically abbreviated gas
there's over 120
identified somewhat different um kind of
effects on the plants here and
they're at least kind of commonly named
with ga1 j2 j3 so on and so forth so
realize
that within gibberellins there is 120
just under that one and they can have
everything from enhancing calcium
phosphorus potassium
content to promoting seed germination to
stimulating stem and root growth so a
lot of different studies with a lot of
different hormones
now also the interaction with all these
hormones that can get very confusing
so tried by a little couple summary
charts here where we can see some have
inhibitory effects on others some
block others some also kind of promote
others or work synergistically together
we kind of get all these crazy kind of
interactions that may occur so this can
get confusing
not going to spend a ton of time on all
the complexities once you've realized
that there is a lot at play here
we're going to focus on just the basics
so typically also when we have
our hormones a series of steps and
pathways are involved
so here we see with trichantinol what
does it cause what can cause greater
dry weight and growth wonderful how does
it
kind of accomplish that well we could
see there's secondary messengers there's
enzymes involved there's
metabolism changes in effect there's
this kind of cascading effect that while
we have one thing
that creates one result it goes about it
in many different
pathways and it impacts many different
aspects of the plant so what are some of
these kind of plant hormones you know
what's a general summary
these are the key ones there's auxins
gibberellins cytokines abscisic acid and
ethylene
this would be a great kind of slide to
pause and kind of go through some of
these
however each of these are covered on
separate videos
here on debaco university so good to
kind of
type that name in the search within the
channel find some of these so you can
learn a little bit more
about what the main highlight is for
each of these five main hormones
however there's also more hormones that
will be covered
and we can see a couple listed here and
these are kind of like
also you know plant hormones but a
little less known a little kind of those
secondary uh plant hormones and you can
see their effects
can be very important and everything you
know promote the primary
root growth leaf senescence so they are
definitely important
in pathways of the plant but maybe a
little less understood a little less
kind of commonly
covered but all covered here
specifically with their own video
that you're welcome to check out here on
debaco university