and this debacco University student
series we're going to get to see Kiera's
many jobs in the early season of 2023
where she's progressing become a student
to becoming an employee and learning all
aspects of cannabis production
[Music]
all right if you thought cannabis
growing was just the plants well Kira's
going to walk us through some different
aspects that she is getting exposed to
and it's always nice to see a student
kind of progress to become an employee
she's worked her way up to being a true
play here at Sweet Hill she discusses
The Importance of Being versatile and
flexible since different times of the
year require different tasks to be
completed we're going to see the early
spring time here this indole is working
directly with the plants but she also
has some additional tasks that are
important to make the entire system
company and growing environment work to
everyone's Advantage now she's going to
start us off in the nursery house which
is her main job right now in the
springtime where she's taken a bunch of
clones getting plants established she's
been scouting for pests and being
proactive in defenses against those
pests and of course the daily plant care
checking making sure monitoring
the water making sure everything is
labeled is making sure the plants are
able to show their best work so they can
continue into a good vegetative state
let's hear from Kiera now
when it's Kiara and today I'm back at
Sweet heel or as it's known as Gigi AG
Tech where I took you guys last year for
a few tours of their facilities now I'm
an official employee and I want to tell
you about the different jobs that I have
around here so right now we're in our
Nursery which is where we have all of
our little baby plants just start out
pretty much one of my first stops here
was taking many many many
clones of our mother plants and putting
them into rockwool once they get their
roots in and everything and they're
ready to be transplanted we bring them
into here and plant them based on base
this here is all Miss B all in front of
me all behind me and some of our other
plants in here include sour lifter or
Durban Poison but really these misbees
are my babies
um another job that I typically do while
I'm here is give amendments to these
girls I mean we're pretty much raising
them so we need to make sure that
they're happy and healthy so one of the
Amendments that we add are these
Marigold plants marigolds are great for
deterring pests like aphids and thrifts
from your plant as I guess they don't
really like the smell I'm not sure why
another thing that we do to amend our
plants are add beneficial insects some
of the insects that we do add are
ladybugs and praying mantises our
ladybugs also eat aphids and thrips and
praying mantis really eat anything they
could get their hands on which is good
for us when we're trying to eliminate
the pests that we don't want and it also
helps that they're super cute
this is my first and main job which is
just taking care of the plants making
sure the girls are good and everything
that comes with that but I do have a few
different jobs around here as is
everyone else it's the only way to keep
this entire Greenhouse going I'll show
you some of them
so with cannabis not all jobs are flashy
labeling is very important it's a
critical form of documentation as we'll
see from Kira one of my most important
and arguably most overlooked jobs in
this field is labeling our cannabis
plants I take great pride in making sure
that all of our labels are big legible
and kind of cute for each of our plants
it's kind of hard to tell the difference
between the two if they're different
species or anything based off of the
appearance alone so that's why it is so
important to have big consistent
labeling for all of your plants even if
they are
organized in a way that makes it kind of
easy to guess and figure out what type
of plant you have you never really know
which one it could be this one is sour
lifter while the one right next door
that looks pretty similar to it is
actually cherry wine
so it is very important for all grows of
any scale or no matter the grower to be
efficiently and properly labeling your
plants this is a step you definitely
don't want to overlook or skip in the
interest of time because at the end of
the day if you don't know what the
difference between your plants are
you're going to lose incredible amounts
of profit and be kind of upset that it
you could have just done that in a half
a second
having a good customer connection a good
marketing is very important because
unfortunately customers don't get to see
the actual plants the products get the
most eyes sharing the product is well
presented is critical to keep the
business going it needs that continual
attention it makes a great indoor job
for Kira
another one of my jobs that I kind of
didn't expect going into this field was
dealing with our customers and marketing
now in order for any operation to really
run smoothly everybody kind of needs to
be on board with everything and helping
out where they can I personally have a
big love for editing things on my phone
or making things just look pretty so I
offered to do some of our promo for our
products what you see here is a light
box that I like to use to take photos in
here we have our canagars very pretty
and so we need to make sure that we get
good photos of them I'll go and I'll
take my photos that I take here put them
into some form of editing app and create
Tearaway sheets advertisements posters
informationals about each of our
products I mean it really just depends
on the day and also depending on if we
change our packaging or if the law has
ever changed we pretty much need to
update these all of the time so it is a
very critical part of any business to
make sure that you have somebody working
on marketing and farming your customers
at the end of the day this is what gets
your customers attention and not just
how pretty the plants are in the
greenhouse
right now I'm taking promotional
pictures for our canagars this one is
our sweet Elite Mountain mango and I
want to make it look as appetizing as
possible I don't really have a specific
list that I go through when I'm making
these types of projects but I just kind
of go with what the product really
entails these are very slim pretty so I
could just put as many as I want really
in here next to each other make it look
aesthetically pleasing get my photos
isolate them within an app and it looks
like you hired a professional so this is
why I really enjoy being able to do all
of our advertising and kind of customer
base things since I being a
perfectionist like to see things like
this and so this is my more indoor job
in sweet heel
now potting up plants may seem
repetitive but there's a lot of
preparation checking and double checking
of equipment while the planting process
can get routine the volume in high
standards makes this an all hands on
deck job
required in in order to even think about
having the plants into this Bay I mean
I'm not sure if you could tell by the
camera angle or not but none of these
pots actually have plants in it we've
spent weeks cleaning this greenhouse
sweeping bleaching making sure that
everything's clean getting our compost
together which we make ourselves at
Sweet Hill in order to make sure that
our plants get proper nutrients and a
proper home to stay in I mean we make
our own compost based off of our organic
material that we go through well
doing our basic day-to-day things here
we had to make sure that our drip lines
are all properly working I mean if just
one of those doesn't work then we lose
an entire plant and as meticulous and
tedious as it is we make sure that every
single one of them is up and functioning
before the plant comes in we still have
this entire Bay to cover before we could
say that plants are even allowed to come
in here
when we do finally put the plants in
here I would say it will take about two
weeks maybe more but I hope to show you
it when we're done instead of talking
about all the prep work
in case you thought planting was easy
work I kind of wanted to describe to you
how I go about planting our plants now
here seems pretty simple we have a hemp
plant in a pot but it's actually way
more than that and takes up a lot of my
time especially during this part of our
growth season working here in order to
get this plant to look like this we
first have to take a clone of it from a
mother we then put it into rock wool and
let it root for about two weeks then we
transplant it into a smaller container
and then finally once we think it's
ready there it can go into this
container but that's not it once it's in
this container we make sure that we add
our drip lines for irrigation make sure
that all of our fertilizers are properly
working and of the right amounts and add
rice holes to the top to prevent the
soil layer from being all moist and
encouraging bug growth now imagine this
one plant multiplied by the entirety of
this greenhouse for a few days now my
team and I have been working on this Bay
alone right what you see in front of me
and behind me but everything this
direction has still yet to be potted
completely so you can imagine how much
time it takes us just to get a few
plants into some pots
[Music]