okay here we look at the kingdoms of
life and we're going to use this simple
and basic six kingdom system you'll
notice we have our Eukarya up here and
our prokaryotes down here these are
still classified and each is its own
independent Kingdom and all supports
life in some way
so this kingdoms of life the designation
of kingdoms has changed over the years
we're going to focus on one particular
system originally there were only two
kingdoms as more organisms or obtained
in the numbers of kingdoms increased the
taxonomic level are the higher than a
kingdom has also been recognized we call
that the domain that's a broader
category or way to categories things so
here's some different approaches reduce
this rose example from 1977 this six
kingdom system where you bacterial
architect archaea bacteria protozoa
plants fungi and animals that's what we
do now you'll notice way back if you
watch some of the previous videos talked
about a simple to Kingdom system where
simple plants and animals we have since
learned there's more divisions than that
all the way up to potentially eight
divisions in us that just because we're
choosing this six kingdom system does
not mean there's other six kingdoms
systems that also exist this is going to
fit our purposes for our class but I
want you to realize that there are
different ways to potentially classify
living organisms this has been one we're
going to most widely use definitely in
this class so our phylogenetic tree of
life notes are bacteria or archaea in
our you carry out and what classifies
what classifies as certain categories
right here this is again just an example
we see the branch points and the closer
things are to one another though more
closely they are related and we're gonna
spend a couple videos on different
organizations of these these are more
closely related to each other then
either is to bacteria because if you
notice this branch point here both these
stem from the same area these branch out
earlier indicating these bacteria are
more distantly related
these two are to each other so the k6
kingdom system that Universal ancestor
that common ancestor and then we branch
out and this is a one stick figure way
of presenting it this is kind of bubble
way and this is another way kind of like
this one i use this when you've seen it
in some of the other slides because it
kind of puts a little picture sort of
animal you see the example of literally
an animal like a fish here fungi looks
like a mushroom plants kinda looks like
a leaf and so on and so forth so you can
see our Protista ru bacteria and kind of
this gives a little bit of description a
very brief description of what each is
so how does this look
on the diagram or relationship among the
six kingdom system so here's our
original cell what I'm saying division
points beyond there and whatever is
shares a same division point shares that
common ancestor so these archaea these
three different archaea are very closely
related and very distantly related to
say bacteria well notice here though we
see our mitochondria in our chloroplast
kind of bridging this gap from bacteria
to kind of the kingdom of Eukarya so
these are symbiotic events these are
events that occurred in both our
photosynthetic bacteria and also our
purple bacteria with the mitochondria
remember remember are the theories we
talked about of the endosymbiotic theory
where mitochondria and chloroplasts or
once free-living bacteria
they've been incorporated into
eukaryotes this example here again of
our six kingdom system provides the
domain the kingdom cell type structures
in number of cells the mode of nutrition
and examples of them these are different
ways we can classify them in a ways that
we can see how each is unique so a cell
type remember of prokaryotes versus our
eukaryotes eukaryotes remembering bound
organelles prokaryotes are not this
domain of Eukarya is very broad within a
eukaryote there's protesters funding
there's plants and there's animals those
are domain of bacteria and archaea are
separate and of course we have our pit
of lichen
walls for our bacteria if you remember
when we did we talked about the Gram
stain a unicellular I'll both of these
are unicellular most of these are
multicellular there might be a couple
that are you can say labels in the fungi
Oh for all Eukarya as far as plants and
animals gauss's are all multicellular
and they do some examples so just a nice
little kind of comparison can you be
able to compare or understand a little
bit about what makes the classification
for each of these kingdoms unique and
different