so in this video we're going to look
specifically at the kingdom of archaea
bacteria and you bacteria so there's
distinct differences between the two a
lot of times these get confused or kind
of merged together and they're different
so first the king of arkin bacteria they
inhibit some of the most extreme
environments on earth
some are autotrophic meaning they're
producing food by chemo synthesis some
archaea bacteria genes possess introns
so these are kind of make them kind of
unique individuals the extreme
environments is the hotsprings here this
is kind of what they look like if you
look under the microscope the kingdom of
Arc bacteria they share certain key
characteristics cell walls lacking
peptidoglycan so you'll remember back we
did Graham standing up bacteria we
looked at the pepto peptidoglycan
presence or absence of and where that
might be located they lack those
entirely usually lipids and unique our
RNA sequences remember our RNA is
referring to ribosomal RNA and unique
our RNA sequences indicate that there
can be classified by this as different
and unique and this is how we can start
to divide things into different kingdoms
we look for certain markers in this case
unusual lipid constructions which is our
fats unique ribosomal RNA sequences can
help us determine that this kind of
gives an example some of the membrane
structures that these archaea bacteria
may have and all the numbers are labeled
here I'm not going to get into that much
detail it does show some different lipid
sequences between bacteria and archaea
just so you can have that sense of
comparison we see here a very simple
chain format see here a lot more
branching so when it says unique lipids
this is what it's referring to
okay these are key bacteria are groups
into three general categories and these
are kind of based on the conditions that
they may be able to survive so this
method ends obtain energy by using
hydrogen gas to reduce carbon dioxide to
methane gas so you can see the kind of
word
thing in there and that's kind of what
they're using these extremophiles are
grown under extreme conditions
thermophiles music street heat hey Leo
thousand extreme salt to be why degree
of pH tolerance or pressure tolerance
but the example here of the deep ocean
vents this is an extremely stressful
environment but there's also non extreme
RQ bacteria he's growing the same
environment is bacteria dough needs to
be anaerobic environments such as those
that lack oxygen gas which is very
important for the respiration process
looking at a comparison chart between
the two our archaea bacteria and ru
bacteria or bacteria to me very simple
and living in these extreme conditions
I mean introns are present and there's
those three main types I talked about
moving over now to you bacteria they can
be a little more complex a little more
common than archaea bacteria introns are
absent or spliced out there's two main
types are gram positives or gram
negatives
you'll recognize these as being gram
positive because of their purple color
they're gram negatives it'd be a pinkish
red looking at you bacteria again
classifying these your bacteria are the
most abundant organisms on earth they
play critical roles throughout the
biosphere most Texans recognize 12 to 15
major groups and bacteria are different
from archaea bacteria as they are from
eukaryotes so they are their own unique
classification remember remember the you
bacteria being just bacteria there's
simple structure prokaryotic in nature
through different shapes that we can use
to help identify them and you'll see all
not all taxon is to agree 12 to 15 major
groups that's why there's some variants
there so the team of you bacteria they
reproduce by binary fission and we kind
of see that going on here in this image
this includes disease-causing bacteria
such as tooth decay or food poisoning
and archaea bacteria and new bacteria
contain all of the prokaryotes and
both be produced by this binary fission
this division that's occurring but they
do have some ways to recombine genes
allowing for evolution to occur remember
back to our plasmids those in DNA
sequences can be transferred
also notice the petri dishes here of
Staphylococcus that's an example that
you vector gram-negative bacteria have
this sausage Elam this flagellum are
plural of the flagella is a long slender
projection from the body cell that
rotates like a propeller and this allows
the bacteria to swim so you think of it
kind of going along and swimming right
along Ecoline Salmonella are two
examples of this so hopefully this
clarifies in the difference between our
new bacteria and our archaea bacteria
and are able to tell the difference
between those two and identify certain
characteristics with each