okay this will be a brief overview of
some lab techniques you can see your
plate streaking to get isolated colonies
or bacteria and the whole point of
having good lab techniques is being able
to develop a repeat of that process
again and again so this proper
techniques are important what why are
they important while developing good
habits will help reduce the variability
and results we call that data noise and
we see here where the general trend is
somewhere right around here but the goal
of being well versed in techniques is
that you're eliminating some of the
peaks and the valleys you're reducing
the data noise now the only true way to
really improve your technique is through
practice so keep working with the
equipment keep keep at it and you will
hopefully get better and improve your
technique some common techniques is to
mention a couple there will be separate
videos on these but weighing objects
which might sound easy by pairing
procedures a good one to focus on
filtering the sterile technique and use
of a centrifuge we do see here in this
general lab here the amount of pipettes
that are around this centrifuge and
these techniques are utilized about with
different protocols be familiar with the
equipment that you have so know what
type of we had access to in this case
both of these people are pipetting when
using an automatic one and when you see
more of a manual one you want to
understand the options that each has so
these require smaller tips these require
these large glass tubes there so again
just generally performing the same basic
action but know what options that you
may have and what may be best fit for
the protocol that you're trying to meet
you do also lastly just as you're going
through and practicing wearing gloves is
typically something that's done in the
lab no matter what you're moving so your
dexterity can be affected by that so
when you're practicing again use gloves
and develop that feel and eventually
you'll be able to work just as well with
gloves if you're not used to wearing
them as you would be and have the same
feel as if you weren't wearing