so here we're going to learn about the
loch operon
and also see a simulation on exactly how
it works to get a better understanding
for it
so first off the lac operon lac stands
for lactose
and this is an example of a sequence of
genes so an operon in general is a
sequence of genes
may be found in many bacteria that
encodes for enzymes needed to break down
lactose to glucose and galactose
so sugars can be utilized studies on the
lac operon have been important for
genetic research
the lactose receptor proteins control
the transcription of the lac
operon now this operon again is it is in
uh bacteria so i do show the glass of
milk here anything if you drink galaxy
milk you're activating your own
lac operon not necessarily the case but
this is give a good example here
of taking a lactose and with the lactase
enzyme and breaking down
into galactose and glucose which can be
absorbed by the body and other organisms
so the lac operon the lactose operon
will be the full term here an operon is
a segment of dna
that contains a cluster of genes that
are transcribed as a unit and are
involved
in lactose metabolism lack is short for
lactose
the disaccharide composed of galactose
and glucose that is found in milk and
other products
but as i stressed before note that
operons occur primarily
in prokaryotes keep in mind you are a
eukaryotic organism
so while operons do occur mostly in
prokaryotes
this is a simulation it does provide a
good model for
gene expression so take it for what it's
worth in that regards
now when we're looking at the lac operon
it's repressed when no
lactose is present so the cell doesn't
want to make this enzyme if there's
nothing
to break down so in the absence of
lactose the lac repressor binds to the
operator
that repressor here is going to prevent
that gene from being
made the operator here is kind of like
the light switch that says go or don't
go
so by binding a repressor it's going to
prevent anything from downstream of that
from being expressed so rna polymerase
cannot access the promoter therefore the
lac
operon is shut down in this example it's
important to shut down there's no
lactose present in a high
glucose glucose is a favored energy
source
now in low glucose and lactose not
available again
the lac gene is also not going to be
expressed
now lycopter is activated when lactose
is present so in this case now we have
lactose being available and we have low
amounts of glucose
so in the presence of lactose the
metabolite of
the lactose is called aloe lactose
binds to the repressor and this induces
a change in the shape of the repressor
making it fall off the operator
this now will expose the operator so
that rna polymerase can now bind to the
promoter
and essentially this gene or these genes
now are turned on and these will be made
and it's important for the cell to make
them for the bacteria cell because now
lactose is
available let's give you a couple
scenarios here
we've talked about lactose being
available yes we want to have that gene
strongly expressed in these two
following cases we have lactose not
being available
so therefore they are repressed they're
pressed for different reasons we in this
case we have high glucose
cell still getting energy here's a lot
of energy available regardless but still
not a lot of lactose or lactose being
unavailable
those genes will not be expressed here
we have high glucose and lactose being
available
so there will be some we call it low
basal level gene expression
because as i mentioned glucose is
preferred but in the case where we have
low glucose and lactose being available
it's going to be strongly expressed
this is simply the bacteria cell
producing the genes that ultimately will
produce the proteins that are most
efficient for its current conditions
now this is that operon simulation i
give you a link to it right here
another video you can check take a look
at it but i'm kind of go through the
simulation now
so you get an idea of exactly how this
works
okay so now we're here looking at the
simulation we see our legend here
and we have our ability to add lactose
to the situation
so here we have some breaks in our
genetic code so i want to add that
promoter region so that lac
uh promoter region but if we add just a
promoter region with no
gene this is our rna polymerase binding
to that but it can't make the gene
so here now i have the gene when i
attach the gene there and polymerase
goes through now it has that
specific sequence to replicate that gene
will go through the process
of translation to form what this is
going to be is
the repressor so here's our lac z gene
if i insert the gene it's all well and
good now we have a complete genome
however we don't have an area for
polymerase to start
so it's very important that you add the
promoter we also want to add that very
important operator and you'll notice
that operator fits
the repressor here so we're not making
the lacz gene we're not making the
lactase enzyme why there's no lactose
present
so if i add some lactose you can see our
disaccharide here
when this comes through and binds to the
repressor it changes its shape it
removes
that repressor so i add a little more
lactose
now that repressor is removed now we can
make that lac
z gene which is only going to go through
the process of translation
to form our lacz enzyme this enzyme can
go through and break down the
disaccharide
into galactose and glucose now you'll
notice that i haven't added any more
lactose and we've broken down
almost one more piece here we've broken
down all of the lactose that was present
and now the repressor is bound here and
kind of stuck here it's going to prevent
the enzyme from being made it's this
very efficient way for the cell to go
through and
not waste its energy now if this
bacterial cell goes through and whatever
reason comes into an environment that's
very high in lactose see if i flood the
area with lactose
now what we're having is we need a lot
of these enzymes to be made so
all these repressors are being bound
their shape has changed they can't bind
here
to prevent the making of that enzyme
you're now going to see
a lot of enzymes being made and produced
and it's very important those enzymes
are made and produced because we've got
a lot of this
lactose products we have off the charts
amounts of lactose
but going through the process here we
can see the enzymes doing its job
multiple times breaking down the
the lactose and those lactase enzymes
doing their job going through
breaking everything down still making
more
enzymes because again those repressors
are bound they are a different shape
they can't block that gene which is
important for the cell
high degree of lactose being present we
want a lot of those enzymes
present as well that's helping this
breakdown process
and this will continue until we notice
that there is
basically not a lot of lactose remaining
therefore we have no need to produce the
lactase enzyme
uh the repressors will come back through
eventually bind to the repressor
and reduce the amount of enzymes being
made until the
events change where there will be some
more lactose present you can see now
we're overrun with enzymes but the
repressor is binding
preventing any new ones from being made
however we take this one more step
further
look at lactose in transport we have the
same situation but
here we have the cell membrane so we
have lactose
outside the cell we have insider cell a
repressor being made
let me add our lacz gene let me add our
promoter like we did
in our operator
operator right now then allow that laxi
gene to be made to see every pressure
being bound
uh now that gene that allowed to be made
they didn't have the proper operator
we have some enzyme here even though
there's lactose present
it is separated by the cell membrane
so there's one more gene here involved
with this operator it's called the lac
wise gene what this lacy
gene occurs is allows this kind of inter
membrane protein to be made now you
notice right now it's being blocked
but these repressors can't bind forever
so
eventually it detaches and no one's
going to come in right behind it but now
what's going to happen
is we're now having the lac z gene made
to break down lactose we're also saying
this lac
y gene made this protein is ultimately
going to go
this green protein it's going to
ultimately go to the cell and allow the
passage
of that lactose from the outside of the
cell to the inside so that enzyme can
work
now you'll notice the same thing i add
the enzyme it's going through it's being
transported now it's being broken down
and we're very efficiently using our
enzymes
if i stop adding the lactose
we have no reason to produce any more of
the laxity or the lactase
enzymes we could see that that repressor
is bound but now it's one more time
changed its conformational shape we're
going to make another round of enzymes
to break down these last bit of
lactose that is present inside the cell
now these got in the cell and those
proteins on the outside cell are still
present
if we cause a mutation so for example if
i take the
lac uh i gene and i mutate it and
basically remove it we're no longer
making any repressors
if we no longer make repressors that's
going to cause some issues
because when these finally degrade the
cell is going to keep making these
proteins
even though there is no lactose present
so this is important for gene
regulation that we don't want the cell
to be wasting energy making all these
proteins
we want to make sure it's efficient
producing what it needs to
and hopefully this lac operon gives you
kind of that idea
of just how important gene regulation is
and some of the
hopefully a simplified breakdown of the
complexities of some of the steps
involved
here we have a mutation in the kind of
repressor
protein being made now we have all these
extra enzymes being made when there is
no lactose so the cell right now is
wasting
energy we want to make sure we have all
of our genes properly operating
with functional promoters to allow the
cell
to be efficient with its energy usage
okay having gone through the simulation
now hopefully that was
helpful for you and if you go through i
got a couple questions here so if you
feel
felt like you understood it uh why do
genes require promoters what's the
purpose of an operator
a couple other questions here i try to
carry through the stimulation that i did
and you've got a couple other questions
here to consider you might want to
pause the video take a look at make sure
you can answer so you can determine
your level of understanding when it
comes to operators in regards to
bacteria
being able to break down lactose