here I'm gonna go over lactose
intolerance in the production of lactose
free milk so letõs naturally occurs in
cow's milk and it's found in many milk
and milk related products here this is
what it looks like it's called a
disaccharide you need an enzyme to be
able to break down lactose in our bodies
to be able to use it for energy so many
people actually have problems with the
digestion of milk and milk products this
is what they do drink lots of milk or
consume lactose you can have a lot of
unpleasant side effects across the world
there are certain regions that have
higher chances of having this lactose
intolerance worldwide when 80% of adults
cannot digest milk sugar or let those in
this condition is called lactose
intolerance so it's in ability to have
the enzyme to break down lactose you can
see that represented here on the world
map with the darker colors being the
higher percent and again about 80% of
adults worldwide do not groups lactase
so lack tastes the last three letters
being ASE that suffix ace tends to refer
to an enzyme in here this is the enzyme
lactase which would break down lactose
you see these darker regions again here
are were the higher odds of being
lactose intolerant are these lighter
greens are reduced odds of that so this
is kind of gives you an idea what the
molecule kind of looks like we should
say the enzyme here lactase so left with
some tolerant adults begin their lives
drinking milk from a bottle or
breastfeeding and this is allows them to
digest it completely so early on in life
babies produced this enzyme lactase and
again it's pictured right here in their
small intestine this Ihnen breaks down
lactose remember ace for last and suffix
breaks down lactose therefore if we look
at babies babies are lactose tolerant so
as humans we start our our lives as
lactose tolerant lactase is a pair of
molecules that we need to break apart
here so
the enzyme lactase will snip the
disaccharide disaccharide meaning two
sugars receive two sugars located right
here of lactose into two simple sugars
or monosaccharides here galactose and
glucose here so we see them being broken
apart here with the lactase enzyme and
we see water here so lactose tolerant
individuals produce lactase for life for
them eating and consuming milk is
perfectly fine you know people enjoy
milk chocolate here it's a perfectly
fine experience however for those of
lactose intolerant how the body reacts
to not being able to break down this
disaccharide you see a lot of negative
effects not a vomiting diarrhea blood
feeling stomach cramps to help people
that are lactose intolerant the
undigested lactose in the small large
intestine is what causes the discomforts
so as a result we have ways to kind of
combat this there's lactase tablets
which can be taken with lactose
containing meals to help break it down
you're kind of consuming the enzyme that
your body doesn't naturally produce
lactose free milk products are produced
by breaking down lactose using lactase
so that's supplementing that beforehand
before the product comes to the person
consuming it lastly there's sour milk
products where the lactose it's inverted
to lactic acid using microbes so the
ways we can help people that are lactose
intolerant there's a market for lactose
free products and on the rise such as
ice creams yogurts and puddings cheeses
there's increasing demand for this
because of the high percentage of people
that are lactose intolerant there's an
increasing range of options because of
the different mechanisms we have to
reduce the presence of lactose in
certain products one of those is
large-scale industrial production of
lactose free milk so here we have all
these beads in this beaker and what
happens is we can produce lactase
enzymes even though it's expensive it
can be manufactured by micro organisms
and then purified from these
microorganisms
here we can coat these small beads here
with the lactase enzyme from here we can
run milk through this and be a large
column so we can run milk continuously
pumped through this because enzymes are
not consumed and used up they will go
through and break down the lactose with
the lactase enzymes and this will result
in the end product being a lactose free
milk product there's no residual lactase
in the milk and the enzyme can be reused
frequently so by using this lactase
enzyme and artificially creating it and
running milk products for it we can take
our lactase enzyme that's coated here
and break down the lactose so that
people that lack the lactase enzyme can
consume milk in related products so it
gives you just a little bit of a
background if you know someone or even
yourself is lactose intolerant