okay yes you read that title correctly
lactic acid does not
cause muscle burn so let's go into kind
of the misconception of why it does and
what actually is causing that muscle
burn your feeling
so when you exercise the source of
energy is glucose and it's broken down
to pyruvate
pyruvate is then used in either aerobic
if oxygen is present or
anaerobic fermentation with no oxygen
present process
both yield atp which is the energy
currency of the cell
but very different amounts so when
there's a lack of oxygen you're only
getting about two atps in aerobic you're
generating a lot more
we're also saying this lactic acid being
generated in an anaerobic
environment there we could see the
person here at least training their
muscles there
running through a lot of atp
now aerobic respiration involves a
citric acid or krebs cycle
oxidative phosphorylation which is the
process of generating atp
with no negative byproducts from either
and
high atp production this is why
oxygen or utilizing oxygen is so
efficient because
not a lot of negative products generated
and a very efficient way of generating
lots of atp so what causes the actual
burn to the muscles if it's not this
lactic acid
well it's release of protons during the
atp
breakdown that's increasing the acidity
resulting in the burning
feeling so in short yes it is an acid
it's simply just not lactic acid because
remember the
increasing proton concentration will
create an acidic environment we see here
so as hydrogen ions amount increases
we have this acidic environment that's
being created is
this acid environment that causes the
burning feeling
that reduction in ph so what you're
seeing here is our atp
being broken down and you'll notice
there is that release from atp to adp
density triphosphate
to insulin diphosphate there is a
breaking of that
phosphate group and also this
all-important release of hydrogen ion
causing
a decrease in ph resulting in acidic
environment causing the burn
so lactic acids and lactates roll well
the terms
lactate and lactic acid are often used
interchangeably but
lactate is the component measured in the
blood blood
and is strictly a weak base and lactic
acid is the corresponding acid so it
kind of flips back and forth between
these two
the lactic acid age your muscles as an
energy source can actually help reduce
the acidity
again this kind of binding of these
hydrogen ions to produce again the
lactic acid here can actually be
beneficial at reducing potentially
the burning muscle feeling contrary to
popular belief
you may experience the day after muscle
burn known as delayed onset
muscle soreness this day aft the day
after you exercise you feel kind of that
burning achy feeling in your muscles
it's likely due to microscopic tears in
your muscles inner irritation of pain
receptors during the exercising process
however believe it or not this process
is actually not well understood
so you kind of get up in the morning you
have that kind of soreness it could be
in part due to these torn muscles
but likely not to the lactic acid for
sure
but again that acid that's breaking
those atps
that's your cause so it is an acid
simply put
don't blame lactic acid