and this debaco University video I'm
going to go over whether we should be
using land race or heirlooms when we're
describing cannabis so a lot of times
from Cannabis land race is used and for
tomatoes heirlooms is used but what
should be using for camps what's the
correct term to be using we'll answer
that here in this video
[Music]
all right so properly naming plants
we're looking at land race land races of
crops are most closely aligned with
heirlooms being that they are naturally
occurring they are indigenous to certain
regions and developed their
characteristics in response to the
growing conditions of that area land
race plant species are relatively rare
because many have been supplemented to
breed crops and have died out due to the
changing climate and also through human
intervention
countries where I look at properly
naming heirlooms this had typically done
with are thought of to be done with
tomatoes heirlooms are open pollinated
plants that have been passed down from
generation to generation they are living
artifacts and living history exhibits
and they're considered a reservoir for
genetic diversity
because they're open pollinated these
cultivars mean that the plants grown
from seed will be true to type and will
resemble the plant from which it comes
from some plants however can
cross-pollinate and therefore careful
practices must prevent cross-pollination
to maintain those particular varieties
that's a breakdown between what a true
land race is and what the definition of
an heirloom is now looking at the ear
room classification
so there are some confusion as to how
old a variety must be to be classified
truly as an air room some believe that
any variety grown before 1951 when the
first hybrids became available is an
heirloom however many heirlooms are 100
to 150 years old or even much older than
this in regards to vegetables seed
saving gardeners have kept their
heirloom fries alive
as has the Seed Savers exchange in Iowa
there they're kind of reserving those
seeds and kind of keeping that preserved
for genetic use potentially in the
future as a reservoir
so how do we go about naming a hybrid as
you know just another idea we heard land
race air rooms what about hybrids I
often get asked a hybrid is a result of
pollinating one specific variety of a
class of plants with the pollen of
another genetically different variety of
that same class while the hybrid can
occur by chance within the seed industry
hybrids are result of cross-breeding of
carefully chosen parent plants that
produce Offspring or seeds that will
have special characteristics or
volunteer necks that go behind this in a
lot of looking at kind of different
family trees and kind of looking at what
the goal is to ultimately develop in a
plant by controlling the pollination
process this results in The Offspring
having genetic characteristics from both
parents The Offspring or seeds of this
cross is called an F1 hybrid and F1
stands for first finale the seeds from
this crust will produce plants that are
very uniform in plant habit and carry a
combination of traits from both parent
plants and hopefully those both traits
that are carried over are both
considered to be advantageous in that
resulting offspring
so landless versus heirlooms looking
that's kind of the direct comparison
here land races are wild cannabis
strains that grow throughout the world
free of contact with humans so they
retain their genetics and
characteristics specific for that
environment in which they're growing in
heirlooms are land race is grown in a
non-native environment that's a key
character distinguishing characteristic
there heirloom strains have not been
genetically crossed or pollinated in a
specific way but have been brought from
their place of origin and cultivated by
humans in a new environment so this
implant grown out here in the wild would
be considered a land race we move that
to a different growing location extreme
though in an indoor environment that
would then classify that then
technically as an heirloom
so why does heirloom need to be used
more particularly in regards to cannabis
production if you're growing a plant
outside of the postulated domestic area
you are growing in heirloom or hybrid
and not a land race it's only a land
race if it's being grown in its native
Geographic environment so if you're
moving that plant from wherever it was
naturally grown to any other location
you're really not growing in land race
you're technically growing an heirloom
again it's why that needs to be used a
little bit more kind of defined by
Growers the Cannabis industry in
particular
so the land race seed uh kind of
misconception while Growers want to have
the original land race variety if you're
growing it out of the native area then
you're growing an heirloom land race
requires both the seed or the Clone or
plant material and location
heirlooms just need the seed or the
Clone replacement material so you see
the best land-raised seeds in land race
cannabis strains of Asia well you're
taking them out of Asia or even out of
the area within Asia that they're being
grown well we need to be using the term
heirloom which I know is going to be a
change for a lot of people but that's
the true scientific
reasoning for that change and I know
it's a hard concept to get across but
here at tobacco University the goal here
is to provide you with the true
scientific answer even though it may not
be what's popular or currently accepted
in the industry