so i'm going to go over a little bit of
how we learn and think to give you some
insight into this
[Music]
well first off we may recognize patterns
or think a pattern
exists is kind of one way we think we
can recognize patterns
which is can be very beneficial when we
start a car for example
a certain pattern or sequence we want to
become familiar with
so we know when something goes wrong
patterns can also be essential for
survival knowing that
goes from green to yellow to red lights
can be very important for safety of us
and others however sometimes we run into
issues where we may try to find a
pattern
in one that does not exist or we can run
the problem where we
may fail to see a pattern that does
exist
so these are important considerations
when we're looking at patterns and
trouble we can get into
in addition storytelling can help fill
in gaps for individuals but often
stories can go unchecked you want to
make sure we're fact checking and be
able to back some information
up the scientific method is a
kind of ongoing process that requires
observations hypotheses
and theory testing to develop
conclusions now how do you relate this
well studying three hours
uh once is not as effective at setting
20 minutes
three times a day for long-term memory
retention
which is very important when you're
taking notes during your studying
you should rephrase and rework the
material this will help you know
be able to remember it for a longer term
and also develop
connections with that material you want
to review your notes and write
questions when and where did you have
them now yes there can be moments of
frustration
and this is just part of the learning
process keep
at it trust me it'll work out in the
long run
now there's null and alternate
hypothesis so in scientists i mentioned
the scientific method
what about these null and alternative
hypotheses how do we test these
well the null hypothesis is a statement
of the hypothesis simply not being true
and the alternative is the opposite of
that the example here fertilizer will
not make the plants grow better or
fertilizer will make the plants grow
better
we see that listed out here we see the
grass being fed fertilizer
will that help it grow or will it not
when we're looking at
the running a trial we also want to
observe the results
and document those results but when
we're documenting
and making observations for results it's
very important that those results are
only valid if there's a comparable we
call a control group
to make sure the same results would not
occur without the test intervention
for example we had the fertilizer when
the plants grow well anyway well it
wasn't the fertilizer that made the
difference
look here how scientists think they have
two main
forms of reasoning the first form of
reasoning is looking at what we call
deductive reasoning this accepts a
general principle based on observations
so if all humans are mortal and albert
einstein is a human therefore he is
mortal inductive reasoning is looking at
an observation
and going to a broader generalization
the poll shows 75
of students at school x takes the bus to
school aaron goes to school x
therefore aaron probably takes the bus
to school it's a deductive reasoning the
premise is true the conclusion must be
true
inductive the premise is true the
conclusion is probably true
keep in mind these distinctions