in the artificial lighting market led
lighting is getting a lot of popularity
so we're going to go through some of the
options related to cannabis production
here on tobacco university
all right let's get into some of the led
lighting options for cannabis production
so first off led light is a high powered
light emitting diode
this kind of shows the kind of the inter
mechanics of
what is involved in those little tiny
diodes not going to spend a ton of time
on the mechanics
but realize that there is a lot going on
in each of those little led chips there
so led color mixing so to get certain
colors
types of white leds are produced with
the
red green and blue color mixing so you
get a lot of kind of mixture of those
colors this is how they're able to get
kind of that pure kind of white light
by mixing the leds that they're adding
to get that color mixing
to get potentially certain wavelengths
or a combination of wavelengths
for those plants to be exposed to now
the advantages here
so led advantages on plant growth and
development compared to conventional
lighting sources
so for some lights growers can select
specific wavelengths for customized
plant growth and development
the versatile control of the flux
emissions and light spectrum
high luminous efficiency small size and
directional light emissions down towards
the plants which is great
they have a long life expectancy
essentially up to 50
000 plus hours reduced heat emissions
but that does not mean no heat emissions
it does not get dim with age economical
in terms of space and power at least for
wattage requirements more robust
structures and easier to handle
and easy to dispose of without any
environmental hazards
that might be contaminants in other bulb
or lighting options
so with this it sounds like almost too
good to be true it's just a win-win
however features to look for when we're
looking specifically at led lights
you want an led light that does not have
fans to help cool it
fans have a tendency to fail sooner than
the actual bulbs or diodes will
so if the fans start to fail it'll
overheat and potentially
damage your lighting structure also full
spectrum you want to go beyond the just
the par reading as we can see here to be
a full spectrum light
if they're dimmable that's another great
option particular ceiling height limited
light intensity that matches the
environment so if you're enriching with
carbon dioxide
higher light outputs can be utilized by
the plants compared to non-enriched
environments
so make sure you're getting the proper
fixture that matches your growing
conditions
now there's the great debate between the
high par and the full spectrum led
lights
the high park look like this and the
full spectrum look like this hyper is
that kind of purpley light
the pros is that they're very efficient
at producing high par values
however the cons are they're hard to
diagnose plant abnormalities
in general i would not recommend the
high par lights simply because
plant production can utilize more than
only the par spectrum
and potential plant issues can easily be
missed so not only is it harder for the
grower
to identify potential issues with their
plants plant services for learning more
about them particularly cannabis plants
might be able to utilize more than just
the par reading
so yes it's great and plants can be
grown well with these lights but really
i'd recommend more the full spectrum
lights
produces wavelengths outside of just the
par spectrum which canvas plants can
utilize and potentially can get better
yield
a better quality as well however they
can be more expensive
but they're highly recommended for plant
production in general especially
cannabis that has high light intensity
demands
and growers are also interested in plant
compounds
not to mention the added benefit of
being able to diagnose potential disease
or nutrient deficiencies very early on
lastly just looking at one example here
of
one of these led lights the gavita pro
1700e led just to give you kind of an
example of one
and kind of what they may look like and
they come in very different forms i like
this one because it simply gives you
that nice little chart there to see as
well what it's producing
and they can reduce the hvac needs
because they're not producing as much
heat
they have a nice even design here very
spread out amount of light
so again a lot of advantages but again
this is just one comparison i'll do
another video on exactly comparing
some specific brands of led lights here
on tobacco
university that you're welcome to go
search the channel for and check out