okay we're gonna get into some basics of
Lewis dot structures now that name
exactly how it looks we see a bunch of
dots these dots are referring to or
representing the valence electrons of
individual atoms we're looking at
bonding between atoms when those we use
these lines to indicate that but let's
get this in a little more detail also
run through some examples so start with
Lewis dot structures these are often
used to show how bonding between atoms
occurs here are some basics to show
individual atoms and also some simple
atomic bonds we see that represented
here these bonds these lines indicate
his hands are bound together so for
developing a lewis dot structure our
step one is is to determine the total
number of valence electrons we want to
look at the periodic table to determine
this keeping in mind family one has one
valence electron family two is two
valence electrons family 13 has three
down four times 14 is four males so on
and so forth just be aware that family
eighteen the noble gases typically have
eight except for helium now lose that
step to one determine the total number
of electrons needed to fill each atoms
outer shell remember the octet rule
every atoms like they have eight valence
electrons as its shared or transferred
so here's oxygen represent by the red
you see one two three four five six
valence electrons what it typically has
but because it's covalently bonded with
carbon and kind of can share two more
therefore they count as part of oxygen
that will have eight same thing goes for
this oxygen because those electrons are
being shared carbon typically has four
its borrowing two electrons are sharing
two electrons from this oxygen atom be
sharing two from this oxygen atom so it
has also eight long that octet rule now
step three is to draw the elements on
your paper
typically the oven with the least number
of particles goes into the center and
there should be some that symmetry to
your layout so in this example we don't
have all these oxygens at the bottom are
all clustered over in one area
you're typically gonna be fairly evenly
spaced out is that's what the generally
the most stable structure is for
different molecules
step four two electrons shared between
two atoms form a bond and draw two
elements between atoms to form a
chemical bond so we see here
bonds are hydrogens bound to our
nitrogen and we see that evident here
with these lines representing two
electrons there's two what we call
unshared pairs of electrons and those
are located here and those are left as
two dots these electrons that are being
shared I represent by unlocking now put
in the steps together our step one is
well we have two fluorine atoms here
here's our two elements step two I'm
gonna bond them together you see these
two are forming bonds and the name
shared between these two and that will
then be transferred in to O line these
are individual atoms forming molecules
in this case so want to go through some
simple examples to go through and see if
you can develop a lewis dot structure
for these individual atoms and also the
molecule of carbon dioxide so take a
moment here pause the video hopefully
you will and try it for yourself before
I reveal the answers hopefully now
you've paused the video now she has to
try to send your own and hopefully you
come up with answers that look like this
remember calcium with F 2 oxygen there's
1 2 3 4 5 6
boron would have 3 potassium ok would
have one remember it's in Group one
sulfur here 2 3 4 5 6 and then the X's
are representing the electrons with the
carbon and the red ones with oxygen we
see here as the example I showed
previously this is following the octet
rule for this very simple molecule of
carbon dioxide oh that helps explain a
little bit about Lewis dot structures