okay here we're looking at a nice lineup
of lighting options that we can use
during the vegetative growth phase so
starting with a nice picture here
there's no one set light for vegetative
propagation or really any stage of the
growth per se many options can still be
successful in the vegetative state
probably offers the most opportunities
for different types of lights the key
that won't in the vegetative state is a
duration of lighting that you're using
how long or what's the photo period the
plants are being exposed to in general
lights can cover slightly more during
the vegetative phase than the flowering
state so just keep that in mind that if
you're looking at the square footage of
lights covered in the vegetative look at
transferring that over to the flower
maybe the cover slightly more area at
the vegetative state fluorescent lights
while these may be beneficial for
propagation overall the power readings
of these are not able to meet the
demands of a growing plant since these
eyes must be kept very close to the
leaves it can limit the coverage area
and also the penetration of light sorry
this was great for propagation or early
on and you can see some other lights
here in the background for more the true
growing phases when the plants get
bigger HPS are high pressure sodium czar
commonly used throughout the flowering
phase light but can also be used edge of
educated light as we see the plants here
if used as a vegetative phase keep an
eye on the distance your plants are from
the light you may want actually try to
keep it around at least that two feet
distance to ensure maximum power to the
plants does help reduce the tendency of
stretch so some people put them very far
away because of the natural spectrum
HBS's produce it can induce a little bit
more stretching so if you keep them a
little bit closer or right kind of at
that minimum distance you can help
reduce the chance of those straps as a
result I suggest you put them on those
ratchet hinders or strongly advised to
ally to keep kind of changing the
distance that the lights are from the
ceiling maintaining that two feet from
the planet CMA chasers from ceramic
metal halides a great choice for the veg
phase this is 215 here and this is a
double-ended bulb here so there's over
600 watts just in this one light it's
close to the spectrum of natural
sunlight and this also produces UV light
it's a very efficient partout watt ratio
these are both very efficient lights in
this category they run cooler compared
to other HID lights the both has a
relatively long a lifespan about 20,000
hours and still producing 80% of its
original out-of-the-box rating you
should purchase everything though as a
unit even if it cost a little bit more
because these can have very specific
requirements the bulbs may not get along
with different ballasts so a lot of
companies now are selling them all as
one unit and that would be advised to
purchase everything together so you're
ensuring that everything works with one
another
LEDs are light emitting plasmas while
they do produce a quality spectrum do
the cost of these in the competition of
ceramic metal halides and during the
market there's slight advantages but
overall it's overshadowed by the overall
cost of these compared to ceramic metal
halides as a result most growers are
shifting over to the use of more ceramic
metal halides and phasing out LEDs
lastly LED is a great option for all
phases of growth all LD lights though
are not the same there's currently great
variance within this category quality
LED lights that have all the benefits
are often cost prohibitive so the better
ones can be more expensive and the
cheaper ones to not to be quite as good
as we thought should be considered as an
option look compared currently to
ceramic metal halides for grow operation
do they offers many of the same benefits
but they can be at reduced cost to run
reduced heat but that upfront cost may
make them out of reach for some growers