well this importance of selected proper
light to use also how you place that
light in relation to your plants is of
equal person and even greater importance
to ensure maximum yield without doing
excessive plant damage so when we're
mounting our lights use of quality
ratchet a nurses advise for ease of
installation an added advantage of being
able to adjust the height of the light
be sure to the attachment Rings are
fully encapsulated and not open s-curves
these are fully uncap slates sometimes
you'll see some of these how they can
add some they just kind of hook on to
different areas that advise because
those could easily slip or if you bump
the light could cause the light to fall
of damage you and/or the plants and then
within 1/8 inch but quarter inch is
preferred when you're going to buy these
with each being able to support about a
hundred and fifty pounds or sell for the
pair in this example so you can always
up it a little bit more always worth
going a little bit higher rating than a
little bit less of a rating and here's
the example here's if you pull on the
ratchet strap that will help increase on
the height of this light and that can be
utilized well as the plants grow to
maintaining equal distance that distance
off of those lights to the plants the
light should be kept a constant distance
from the plants but remember that plants
grow so if you fix the light in a
certain area it could be a challenge
using this ratchet straps will allow you
to raise the light as the plants are
growing which makes for a great
consistent conditions this is important
because the distance can vastly reduced
the light intensity which could cause
plants to stretch so you just found a
light really high and say oh they can
use diffuse light if they're not getting
enough light they hit stretch and that
could cause all sorts of issues as you
get later in the grow cycle this is
because there's an exponential decay of
light follow the inverse square law for
light as you increase the distance this
is the relationship between light source
and the distance the light needs to
travel and as we get further away in
distance we have an exponentially
decreasing amount of light intensity
intensity equals the output divided by
the distance squared because this is
square that's the key term here you can
let's compare two plants of the same
light so plant is one foot away from
that light source plant B is two feet
away it's double the distance however
because it's the inverse square law and
distance is squared plant B is not
receiving half the light we see the only
25% of the light that plant a is that's
that in the first square law also it's
very important that that distance be
maintained consistently because if it's
allowed to get a little bit too far you
could see here how the amount of light
is exponentially smaller because that
distance of term is squared
lastly closer to the light source isn't
always better
sometimes a plant is close to the light
source it will burn this needs to be
taken into consideration especially for
high intense lights plasmas also are
advised or LEP s are advised to be at
least 2 feet away to be to burn so again
just because we're closer the light
sources and always been the case for
fluorescence definitely want those
closer so keep in mind that closer is
not always better
depends on the type of light you're
using in the stage of plant growth