okay here we give a brief overview of
light emitting plasmas or lights or LEP
grow lights we see one right here a
small little jelly bean or peanut area
is where the light comes from and while
that is a very small initial starting
point it can easily cover a sufficient
we're like competitive with most
high-intensity to discharge lights now
plasma girl a chair it's a near full
spectrum light and they are incredibly
energy efficient they have low wattage
solid-state bulbs that are in the full
spectrum of light from ultraviolet
infrared and all with no moving parts or
electrodes and here is the LEP light
there's similar to ceramic metal halides
that we see here just kind of on a quick
visual comparison and we can clearly see
the difference between these due to a
high pressure sodium light in the
background of this image now the
advantages of plasma lights is they have
no basically minimal moving parts
they're very quiet operation however
they're fixed they can't dim them at all
they're very expensive in comparison to
ceramic metal halides and the emitter
which can which can fail over time is
often not replaced so because of these
reasons probably certificate of Hines
there tend to be more popular than all
the benefits associated with LDP lights