so looking at light wattages and
voltages is important we've ever been
looking at lighting I might see things
they're offering in different voltages
and you know and maybe you got the wrong
one shipped to you also wattages might
be wondering what that is wouldn't help
explain that a little bit here so we're
talking about what it is in this case
and volts I think these are the same
volts in the same 120 volts or this one
has a crowning plug has nothing to do
with the waters or the volts but is
advised that you buy something that does
have the grounding plug attached to it
so first off Watts this might be what
you're most familiar with if you're at
to change light bulbs because it's the
amount of energy it takes to produce a
certain amount of light so these are you
know 60 watt light bulbs indicated here
the higher the wattage the more power
the fixture uses and ideally the
brighter the light it will produce this
preferred white is so for full sized
vegetative plants and flowering plants
focus on four six hundred or thousand
watt lights most growers are focusing on
the six hundred of the thousand watts of
particular anythings small and this is
not gonna allow for maximum yields it's
better used for clones or seedlings
thousand watt bulbs we see here this
could be the pro 1000 double-ended watt
bulbs are considered to be the stands
for North America by most growers other
person world or other growers will use
600 as kind of their standards typically
we're seeing the thousand Watts being
the general standard here now the other
terms for my be familiar with in the
sense of electricity this diagram shows
a perfect example we have amps which is
the amount of charge or current flowing
through the circuit over a period of
time we have the volts which is like the
pressure in line causing the current to
flow through the wire it's the push and
we have ohms of measurement indicating
the amount resistance applied to a
current so we want to keep the ohms as
small as possible because we don't want
to restrict this flow this is kind of
what caused excessive heating and
potentially lead to fire now we might
hear 120 volt system versa to turn a 40
volt system all the plugs do look vastly
different it's more than that then just
what the outer plug is 120 volts with
most appliances run on so if you have
something requires a high amount of
energy such as a dryer let's up leaving
run on 220 or 240 volts Watts is equal
to volts times
amps so it's just an example here we're
looking at changing the volts and how it
relates to amps we have in this case a
1200 watt appliance or required motor or
a light or something to that nature so
we're keeping that the same however in
one case we're going to buy 120 volt
supporting light and application by 240
volt light well the 120 volts going to
draw 10 amps well the two Coreys only
going to draw 5 amps so what does this
mean
other than the outlets look differently
so the 240 volt requires less current or
amps and a smaller conductor can be used
smaller wire can be used which can be
advantageous the 240 is the world
standards while the United States still
use the 120 volt is its standard so then
keep in mind if in parts of the world
where that be located you could see why
in some cases the 240 volt is
advantageous so because of the less amps
requiring a smaller conductor that can
be used to transfer that energy