okay heroic the looming factors in
photosynthesis we've looked at
biological systems and there's always
some sort of limiting factor that's
involved we're a look at that as more of
a micro scale here specifically we're
look at light intensity Kerman acid
concentration and also temperature and
how this impacts the rate of horses
synthesis strong with limiting factor in
the general sense a lumen fit factor
these can be resources in environmental
conditions that restrict growth
abundance or distribution of an organism
or a population of organisms in an
ecosystem we've talked about predators
before physical barriers particular
biomes speed limits all these impacts
are limiting factors to an individual
we're now going to take this and look at
more of a micro scale here so late
intensity so light energy is necessary
for photosynthesis and as it applies in
the name flow to meeting light but the
intensity of light can vary due to
weather for example is it a cloudy day
is it a sunny day is it a foggy morning
how is that impact impacting the light
intensity the location of the plant is
it in a large open field is it near some
rocks is it under large trees different
areas is it on the north side of the
building the south side this could
impact the intensity that that was light
that that plant may have received also
the season spring summer winter or fall
it can impact the light intensity based
on the angle of the Sun relative season
of nearby plants what this means is if
your plant living under a deciduous tree
they drop their leaves in the fall
meaning in the winter and early spring
that plant will we serve a greater
intensity looking at our light intensity
to a photosynthetic rate graph unless as
light intensity increases from A to B
the rate of opposed synthesis will also
increase however this is not continuous
and forever
when we reach here our maximum rate even
if the light becomes brighter from B to
C the light is brighter the rate of
photosynthesis will remain the same we
reach that plateau or that maximum rate
now light intensity follows this
particular inverse square law and what
this is the inverse square law is a
specified intensity is inversely
proportional to the square of the
distance from the source what does this
mean kind of a little easier terms here
energy twice as far from the source it's
right out over four times the area so
we'll notice here with our light and as
we get further away take an exponential
decrease in the intensity of light you
can see that here with our candle in our
book on our clock and getting as we get
further away the intensive that light
drops off significantly and we see that
here the little mathematical here the
inverse square of the sphere we've got
our area and it's being spread out over
that four times the area as the distance
becomes twice as far so this is part of
the reason why light decreases so
quickly because it's an inverse square
law now lights met readings in the
called power PA are I'm flow
synthetically active radiation and it
says made for the spectral range or
waveband
of solar radiation from 400 to 700
nanometers that photosynthetic organisms
are able to use and process of
photosynthesis
now this 408 to 700 nanometers be from
specific wavelengths the 400 you can see
here verses 7 and 800 and we notice on
our graph over here that or the
wavelengths are not all used by the same
pigments in a plant's CR chlorophyll b
chlorophyll a carotenoids are all using
different wavelengths this is helping
the plant be able to use a greater
portion of this spectrum with this image
shows here we have our light intensity
at the center point and as we get
further away from that light intensity
you notice how quick the power may drop
off so consumed being very limited or
very low intensity to the parameters a
very high intensity in the center point
here so important for considering and
lighting a plant you won't have that
plant directly under that light because
the further we keep that light away the
less intensity of light that it will
receive
ComNet save concentration is another
consideration it can help limit or
potentially limit plant growth
so Kerman oxide is a common limiting
factor assuming all other factors
example water and lighting are not
limiting so all these limiting factors
assume that they're the most limiting
amongst all the other factors keep in
mind that the atmospheric percentage of
carbon acid is only about point zero
four percent the more carbon accident
plant is given the faster it can put
synthesize but this only occurs up to a
certain rate as we see here again
increasing the carbon dioxide
concentration these brackets and
concentration will not increase the rate
of post synthesis beyond that point so
here's our normal atmospheric air it's a
mixture we get some water vapor here's
our carbon dioxide these are oxygen lots
of nitrogen we're increasing our carbon
dioxide concentration from A to B listen
that a great is also increasing have
them get to see we're in that plateau
phase increase in carbon dioxide here at
this point is not yielding any greater
photosynthesis how this may look
elevated carbon dioxide concentrations
can increase plant growth assume
sunlight and nutrients are not limiting
factors keep in mind the average
atmospheric carbon dioxide expressed in
parts per million is approximately 410
so here's our ambient here these images
show growth with additional carbon
dioxide expressed in parts per million
so ambient to be about 410 for
increasing it by additional 150 so this
would be about 500 in 60 parts per
million
notice that plants grown a little bit
better we releasing 300 parts per
million from ambient better growth and
450 parts were almost doubling the
amount of carbon dioxide present in the
natural atmosphere we noticed a gross
difference that does occur same thing
here is 196 this is about half of the
normal carbon oxide in the atmosphere
and here's 752 a study done on average
growth response to 300 parts per minute
of additional carbon dioxide you can
look at all the some of the data
provided here and pretty much it all
comes through an increase in some
average
anywhere from an average of 32.8% to as
high as 70% for trees increasing the
ambient carbon dioxide levels so this is
one way assuming again water nutrients
and lights are all not limiting factors
to help increase yields of plants
temperatures the last one chemical
reactions office photosynthesis are
impacted by temperature the rate in
temperature are directly proportional
meaning as temperature increases so does
the photosynthetic rate however since
this is a biological system there's an
optimum temperature pretty much for most
plants any rate above or any temperature
above 86 degrees Fahrenheit it's going
to be the maximum rate of photosynthesis
anything above or below that it's going
to be below maximum now if we get too
high we notice that our rate does drop
off significantly proteins are starting
denature and there's other issues below
86 there's just not enough energy to
move those molecules fast enough 86 is
considered the optimum temperature
anything above that again we see a
dramatic decrease and below that we're
noticing an increase up to that point so
the general summary here just to put it
in graphical form how does light carbon
oxide and temperature impact the rate of
photosynthesis we can see how light
impacts it in carbon dioxide have very
similar graphs and temperature has that
optimum again around 86 degrees
Fahrenheit
and post and dedicated be lower at
temperatures greater than 86 or less
than 86 degrees