here we're gonna look at linkage maps in
relation to genes located on the same
chromosome let's go through an example
here so first off this should make basic
sense looking at a linkage map it
estimates the distance between genes
more closely linked genes would be
closer together and less closely linked
genes will be further apart so we're
looking at a linkage map to try to
determine the location of certain genes
in relation to whether one another and
how close how far they may be so as an
example how can linkage maps be made
from observations of traits well our
recombination frequencies the inserted
gene terms given gene X Gen Y and gene z
gene X and Gen Y we kind of a about 8%
of time meaning about eight units away
from one another X and Z though are 12%
so here's our X we're wondering at 12%
whether the Z is 12 units away to the
left or from x 12 units away to the
right so this is a kind of a quandary
here looking at we know it's 12%
becoming frequency so it's 12 base pairs
away or 12 units away I should say so
we're not sure though if it's gonna go
basically 12 units this way or 12 units
the other way so we need some more
information
knowing that Y in Z are four percent so
Z is four units away from Y we then can
make the conclusion that Z's over in
this way so see initially here without
this information we know here we're
exits we know Z is 12 units away we
don't know if it's the left or right now
but by getting that information that is
also four units away from Y 8 plus 4 is
and there's our X there's our Y and
that's where her Z would be located with
this information we're able to eliminate
the possibility that Z is located
let's look another example so crossover
frequencies can be converted to again
these map
yeah so take for example a 5% crossover
frequency equals 5 map units since easy
enough gene a and gene B cross over 6
percent of the time so how many map
units would that be 6 map units gene B
and gene C cross over 12 and a half
percent of time we can convert that to
12.5 map units gene a and gene states of
taking the information from here here
crossover eighteen and a half percent of
the time so again this being six map
units away this being twelve and a half
map units away six plus twelve and a
half would give us detune half
indicating a to B and then C is located
over here you could see because this
follows everything here aim B 6 units
away yep B and C are 12 units away
indicating that a to C is 18 and a half
that makes it simply though ABC won't be
all it will always be the case but
hopefully you can kind of follow and
understand how we got to the order and
the distance between these two see once
you Hale it's actually it's pretty easy
to go over so let's check HERE based on
the above linkage map one located here
what's the frequency of gene a and gene
be crossing over together Virge engaging
in G and C could also draw on leakage
map based on the fine crossover
percentages for the three gene pairs a
if a.m. these 8% B and C is 10 percent
and C is 2 percent what would that
physically look like so then get the
first one here based on the above
linkage map or if you go here can pause
it I'm gonna give you the answers so for
the first one here based on the above
linkage map since case to be the below
linkage map what are the frequencies of
a and B crossing over here's a here's B
40% minus 25% but gives you the distance
here that would be 15% and then D to C
so here's D and C we want to figure out
what this distance is we take a and D we
subtract a 2 C 20
percent minus 30% this distance is 5%
please realize that this map may not be
drawn to scale by simply calculating
these figures out you can tell this
distance based on the math is 5% and the
distance between B and a or a and B here
would be 15% the other part of that
question trial linkage math base and the
slide crossover percentages if Amy's 8%
and B and C is 10% a and C its 2% and
what order these are in so I start we're
just drawing simple two ends I connect
them together and I start to label and
you go with the first information you've
got here and a 2 B would be 8% so it's
just a longer distance here B 2 C would
be 10% so B and C is 10% and C is 2%
we know that that C is located here not
over here because 8 plus 2 is that 10%
the distance between B and C so I know
initially this might sound a little
confusing and it does take a little
guess in chapters no set quick easy way
to determine that but if you look at the
numbers and put one down one place and
start with unknown we know a and B is 8
units away all right now we gotta go the
next one B and C's 10 units we don't
know if that's to the left or the right
but with a and C only being two units
away 8 plus 2 is 10 and that perfectly
solves our linkage now hopefully if you
review these a little bit they'll start
to make a little bit more sense
initially I know it is a little bit
foreign to look at but hopefully we're
doing it a couple times we'll make it
quick and easy and it makes for a great
quiz question