here we're a look at a very short and
brief overview of lipids as you can see
in the image here lipids are a form of
basically fats is how we may associate
with this type of macromolecule so the
street forms of lipids fats is one of
them which may be the focus here there's
also going to be a video on
phospholipids and steroids if you want
to check that out on the channel here so
looking specifically at fats as one of
the forms of lipids again typically
lipids and fats can sometimes be
considered an exchangeable terms but
lipids is the correct broad macro
molecule fats are used for long-term
energy storage usually use the term
triglycerides which as we see here which
means they have 3 3 fatty acids with a
Cristal bat though the composed of these
fatty acid chains and are linked
together so these are not independent
fatty acids so it looks like they're
kind of separate here they would be
linked to this literal backbone and this
is our definition of fats and then being
insoluble in water means that the
hydrophobic in nature so this is just a
very brief overview of lipids and as I
said if you're interested in
phospholipids or steroids there'll be
separate videos on those