yeah I'm gonna discuss some of the very
important functions of the liver and
also feel need to mention the
gallbladder agency located here because
it is in such close proximity to the
liver so strong with deliver in general
liver is the largest internal organ of
the body it's about 3.3 pounds it's
divided into lobes it's the main
exocrine sufficient is bile and it aids
in the digestion of fats in the duodenum
now chemically modify substances and
absorbed in the GI tract and it converts
poisons into less toxic forms so it's a
very important function of the liver
this is why it's so large kind of like
the main filter it's a detoxifying of
r-tard some of the toxins that the body
takes in it's also one of the only
tissues that can regenerate itself
indicating its importance this tries to
show a little bit of its orientation in
the body and produces most of the
proteins found in the plasma of the
blood so it's okay right they're kind of
tucked up under your rib cage if you
feel under your rib cage you can
actually feel your liver now some very
important functions the liver is three
main ones all blood leaving the
absorbent surfaces of the digestive
tract so we have entering the Phanatic
portal system flows into the liver then
we have the liver cells extract
nutrients or toxins from the blood and
this is before they reach the systemic
circulatory system through the in patek
veins you see here this is kind of like
intermediate filter going through lastly
on the liver removes and stores excess
nutrients corrects nutrient deficiencies
by mobilizing stored reserves performing
synthetic activities so it's kind of not
only filtering things it's sensing and
regulating and changing so that our body
can do its best to Kent and maintain
homeostasis continuing on to give you a
little bit of that complexity the liver
regulates the composition of circulating
blood waste product removal nutrient
balance and nutrients can be
carbohydrates lipids and amino acids
vitamins storage 18 E and K vitamins
nutrients urge for iron drug
inactivation and these are some of the
crazy pathways that go on
arose from defeat that occurs in these
lines here means that could block that
let's have some unknowns here indicating
some of the pathways here now they need
to know all the kind of complexities
here the cemetery inhibitory Tex now I
want you to understand some of the many
functions that deliver performs in
particular here's just six very
important regulations that it does the
the HEPA sites here the liver cells how
they function well they produce bile C a
bile duct right here on this processing
of blood-borne
nutrients and a storage of fat soluble
vitamins they're also important for that
detoxification step as you see here a
very good amount of surface area
allowing this to occur continuing on
what does the liver do I love that
question because there's about 500 vital
functions of the liver very hard to kind
of summarize them kind of only a couple
but I try to put like eight kind of
major ones here phagocytosis an antigen
presentation it removes damaged or old
red blood cells it synthesizes plasma
proteins such as albumin reabsorbs
hormone removes antibodies and converts
to amino acids traps um look at Seibel
toxins removes in stores certain toxins
so it's keeping the body clean and it
also synthesizes it secretes bile now
I'm inferring - toxins isn't like oh you
drink something toxic there's a lot of
potential harmful things that could
occur in the body especially at high
amounts it's helping clean some of that
up a lot of drugs that may be taking
prescription drugs usually go through
and are processed in the liver
since why a lot of times doctors will
check for liver they watch there's blood
liver levels and how that's kind of
operating that can be an indication of
some of the stresses that might be put
on it or some of the particular products
it might be putting into the blood
system as a reaction to something this
bile have been mentioning the functions
of IELTS dietary lipids are not water
soluble
the causal processing in the stomach
creates a large drop
it's containing lipids so removal of
bilirubin also results from the
breakdown of red blood cells breakdown
cholesterol pancreatic lipase is not
lipid soluble interacts only with the
surface droplet of the lipid so one
who's kind of like we call this
emulsifier or break that apart
increasing that surface area allowing
the by the better absorb or breakdown
these particular products
lastly bile salts break apart or
emulsify as I said the increases surface
area to allow enzymes to work a little
bit better these tiny droplets are
coated with bile salts and that's what
helps only those enzymes to be able to
perform their function la sites have
mentioned the gallbladder and that's is
kind of it's uh green and these images
here so okay to kind of that right
behind the liver there that's
pear-shaped it's a muscular sac it's
stores some concentrates bile prior to
excretion into the duodenum of the small
intestine via this bile duct so you can
see here's our pancreas again here's our
gallbladder and here's our piled up
entering the duodenum does the first
beginning part in the small intestine
and dealing with the time as it
immediately enters or exits I should say
the stomach on the syste extension the
gallbladder and this is allowing this
bile to be immediately released into the
beginning part of the small intestine