okay if you've ever taken a forensic
science class you've probably heard of a
cards exchange principle this is a key
kind of component of the forensic
science and what forensic scientists do
so I figured I should include the quote
from the professor himself while the
current exchange principle states that
wherever he steps or ever he touches
wherever he leaves he unconsciously will
serve as a salient witness against him
not only his fingerprints or his foot
prints but his hair the fibers from his
clothes the glass that he breaks the
tool-mark he leaves the paint that he
scratches the blood or semen he
deposited or collects all of these and
more beer mute witness against him this
is evidence that does not forget this is
not confused by the excitement of the
moment it is not absent because human
witnesses are it is factual evidence
physical evidence cannot be wrong it
cannot be prejudiced itself it cannot be
fully absent only human failure to find
it study and understand it will dismiss
its value professor and would look hard
this is that key principle here for
forensic scientists are always looking
for that physical evidence because it
isn't press it is there we just need to
find it and it could be in a variety of
forms so this kind of summarized a the
general summary of that would be
whenever two objects come in contact
with each other
traces of each are exchanged every
contact leaves a trace whether it's a
small whether it was something large
with something very obvious every
contact will leave some sort of trace
this is why it's important when going
and investigating a crime scene is that
to have any of your own material
anything that you come in contact with
as the scientist evaluating the scene to
have anything exchanged or kind of
contaminate the crime scene so this fact
is that there is a salient witness that
those investing in the crime scene need
to find and interpret them correctly for
the significance so initially might look
at this and you see it's wood some older
wood but we could see there's some
footprints so there might be also some
fibers left behind there could be some
fingerprints there could be potential
blood splatter there's a whole different
on a sort of things we want to consider
and not dismiss as scientists so every
contact leaves a trace this applies to
both the people involved in the crime
scene originally and also as I said the
investigators as in the investigator you
want to limit your traces left you want
to go into scene undisturbed and be able
to collect the evidence without kind of
adding any of your own having things
prepared ahead of time and knowing what
to look for have an idea what to look
for can it be helpful so finding the
trace it's not as easy as in your face
per se type of evidence and may be
limited to investigators abilities and
or access to equipment or technology so
might see this kind of this blink
blackboard here well if you dust it you
could find fingerprints or you know
trace elements with fiber there's a lot
of things in trace elements is very key
and important so it's being mindful of
what to look for in knowing how to look
for it how to find it and how to
eliminate any potential contact that
you're adding because remember every
contact leaves a trace so it's your your
ability and hopefully you can find that
in a crime scene and that can really be
in very important part of the diagnosis
and evaluation of that crime scene