in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over the lollipop
pruning method to maximize the
light exposure to your plant's leaves
let's get into the lollipop pruning
method for cannabis production
so first off what are we doing with the
ipod method well we're enhancing the top
buds
visually the lollipop plants have bare
stems with no foliage towards the bottom
similar to a lollipop stick we can see
that evident right here
lollipopping is a pruning technique that
enhances the buds at the top
this works well with growers also
planning on the screen of green pruning
method
helps really train those branches and
eliminate any lower leaves to help air
circulation
and also just plant efficiency the
result is to maximize
the bud size of those apical buds
this can be done also with autoflowers
as well so
not just sativa or indica dominant
strains can also be done with
autoflowers
now what's happening is as i said we're
trying to maximize that kind of
light use live popping allows for the
greatest light intensity to be utilized
by the plant
is accomplished by removing growth up to
a certain point now that certain point
is determined by the grower
here we can see all these leaves kind of
clean removed
maximizing the light exposure of the
leaves up here
we also see that evident in the plants
here
all the lower leaves kind of cleared out
here they though they went a couple
fewer nodes up the plant before they
started not removing leaves here they
went a little higher
again that's grower choice this pruning
method though will focus the light
energy being efficiently captured and
stored by the apical buds
and simply the goal is to maximize the
bud size and also the quality of the
buds produced
now how do you go about doing this
method well the lipoprinting method
should be initiated
initially kind of completed two to three
days before the plants are flipped into
a flowering photo period
or it can even be done a little bit
before that because you want to start by
removing unnecessary lower
foliage that is heavily shaded simply
it's not getting enough light
how to determine if it's not getting
enough light will you check with a
parameter
this ensures growers can know the light
intensity that actually is within the
canopy
typically the entire branches are not
removed unless there are some
they are short and not reaching the main
light intensity to begin with
so typically the branches are kept it's
the leaves that are removed
in general growers should focus their
timing
their trimming efforts and their timing
and for five or more nodes below the top
or apricon meristem of the plant we
don't want to prune them way up to just
a very tippity top
and we do want to allow some portion of
canopy there
again trimming there about five or more
notes below the top
is a good starting point for you now
lollipopping is not
the same as defoliation so yes both do
involving moving leaves so that is true
but lollipopping focuses
on the bottom part of the plant with a
focus on removing growth that receives
minimal light
specifically light popping favors the
apical or top buds
while defoliation really does not
prioritize defilations just removing
leaves
not really in an organized format per
say lollipopping is really focusing on
those that are not getting the light
intensity
taking those out it's a very directed
form
now common method here is lollipopping
is completely done as part of a complete
pruning or training program
for example lollipopping and the screen
of green tend to go hand in hand
why because you're trying to maximize
all those branches out on the screen
as a result that lower portion is not
getting very much light
and you want to improve your air
circulation so you're maximizing your
light
here you're also increasing your air
circulation this is why lollipopping and
screen of ring
typically are done together even though
each can kind of be done independently