welcome to this debaco University video
where we're going to be looking at
lollipop pruning options for cannabis
whether you're keeping or removing the
side branches we could see here showing
in a comparison of two plants I'm going
to walk you through some of the details
and we'll go out to the greenhouse and
Care will show us the comparison of
those two plants she's sitting next to
[Music]
so first off lollipop pruning's
definition is that live hopscreen
really's goal is to focus the plant's
energy on the top part by removing the
lower branches resulting in a lollipop
appearance so you can see with a kind of
a plant would look like initially remove
these lower branches you're kind of
focusing that energy towards the top
portion now it says removing the lower
branches these are typically referring
to the ones closest to the container or
ground level there are some more
aggressive versions of that as we'll see
a comparison here
now there is a Botanical support for
this method and it's why it's
implemented quite a bit of the plant
portions that simply receive less light
intensity are typically poor
contributors to the plant so by removing
the lower branches and leaves of the
cannabis plants this increases the
overall plant efficiency but looking at
these six Buds here these would be more
towards the top receiving more light
typically in these popcorn or smaller
size buds B grade buds will be more
towards the sides simply receiving less
light on those side branches
now the benefit of the lollipop method
is that with the lower portions of the
plant removed this can help increase air
flow and help reduce the potential for
disease pressure so not only does it
benefit what more plant materials
getting more of the light it can also
help increase your airflow Under The
Canopy
now the general lollipopping process
this is well the best time it really
depends on the cultivar you're choosing
to grow in the environment typically
this is done in the late vegetative
stage or early flowering stage in
generally about 15 days before and 15
days after flowering is the critical
window and you want to be really
implementing this method or committing
to this method if you are going with the
screen of green or scrog method as we
can see implemented right here you're
likely doing a form of lollipopping
already just kind of keeping everything
on that same level there with the screen
method in particular
now indoor or outdoor growing where
would you implement this it can be used
in both situations but since the sun
travels across the sky it's less benefit
this is a less beneficial printing
method indoor applications or others
that have less degrees of light that
travel tend to benefit more from this
method because you're kind of focusing
more in a particular region
now two different takes on basically
this same method here traditionally
Growers like to Simply remove the leaves
and keep most of the side branches and
the exact amount really is up to the
grower in unconventional method kind of
more shown here is where the side
branches are completely removed which
will result in a plant that represents
more of a palm tree this does result in
a thicker Central stock but still
requires staking if the plant is topped
and then cut down the apical meristem is
removed it can have a similar number of
growing tips compared to the traditional
method
now the traditional method is I'm kind
of using here is again this maximizes
the branch meristems which should in
theory result in many buds however the
bud size may be reduced if all branches
are kept for the full plant cycle
keeping four main branches will probably
give you the highest amount of a quality
buds more you keep you are going to
start to see a reduction in size because
the plate can only produce so much
energy
this is an easy method to employ
intensity best when implemented with
some form of screen of green method
where you're keeping all of these
branches
now the unconventional methods that kind
of shown here in tight plant spacing
this does allow for improved airflow
under the plants trimming can also be a
little bit more difficult and this does
require more frequent prunings of the
side branches because you are going
through and removing all of those side
branches you can see even at this small
stage the importance of plant staking
because the plants will be top heavy but
the main stem that you will notice will
thicken to help support the structure
compared to if you were keeping all of
those side branches
now just to kind of a recommendation
here if you're going with the
traditional method use this in most
cases especially if utilizing the screen
of green method where you're keeping all
those branches the unconventional method
here where you're really removing a lot
of those side branches best Implement if
you're looking to clone a plant because
you can take those side branches off and
clone those remove the side shoots with
the timing of plant growth and also be
careful when you're choosing to top that
plant remove that apical meristem and
you will get a consistent number of
clones and be able to harvest the mother
plant even though the yield will most
likely be lower than the traditional
method depending how aggressive you are
with the side shoots and branches you're
removing and limiting the plant too
so here we're going to go out to the
greenhouse there and here's going to
show us in the greenhouse in comparison
to two lollipopping methods with plants
nearing the end of the vegetative cycle
this allows you to see both and make an
informed decision on what method you
would like to implement in your
operation and keep in mind this is in
the greenhouse these are fairly large
plants but we'll go out to Kiera and
hear her comparison of these two methods
hi So today we're back at DG AG Tech
comparing two different forms of
Lollipop pruning on my right we have a
much more intensive form of this
lollipop grooming as you can see many of
the branches are missing in comparison
to this other one and we have just a
much wider and larger bigger stock here
in comparison to this one now this one
just has the leaves taken off of all of
the branches as opposed to taking all of
the branches off like this one we can
see this has a little bit of a thinner
branch in the middle but more branches
coming out the side more yield up on the
top which will need eventually more
support than if you were to just do it
this way but the con with this way is
that after a while you can see that it
starts getting pretty top heavy so
you're going to need support using
netting either way our yield at the top
is pretty similar as you can see we
don't have big differences just based on
this pruning method so at the end of the
day it is really up to you as a grower
to decide what best fits your operation
when it comes to pruning each of your
plants