okay here we're looking at the lower
limbs here you see here with the Wicked
Witch of the West lower limbs bone
structure may not be matching what we're
going to be discussing here but here's
what we are going to be looking at
basically what we need to call the leg
bones so for the lower limbs this
classic thanks kind of a listing of some
of the major bones here the consists of
the thigh the leg and the foot so the
bones of lower limb are the femur the
patella the tibia and fibula the tarsals
metatarsals and phalanges
now those might be terms you might be
familiar with or may not be the femur is
basically your thigh bone patellas your
kneecap tibia and fibula are the bones
of the lower leg here tarsals are the
bones of the ankle and metatarsals
phalanges are bones of the actual foot
so let's start with that femur that
largest bone there it's in the upper leg
and it's the largest bone in the human
body and also one of the strongest has a
lot of pressure to kind of deal with the
femoral head articulates with the pelvis
to form the hip joint this shaft ascends
in a slightly medial direction and it's
designed to bring the knees closer to
the body center of gravity this helps
increase your stability so a lot of
these bones while they may look
perfectly straight are not that way on
purpose to help with the basic geometry
for maintaining stability or increase in
strength distally the femur exhibits two
rounded regions so that's the FAR's
point down here and they articulate with
the tibia in the most anterior
projection of the patella that's getting
into that knee region so that patella
region because you just left the femur
here at the bottom that patella but tell
us basically the knee or the kneecap and
it's the bone between the fibula and the
femur two main functions is to protect
the knee from physical trauma and it
acts as also kind of a leverage at the
quadriceps in tendon can exert on the
femur thereby increasing the muscle
efficiency so again we see another bone
being placed and we protect portions of
the body that delicate joint but also
increasing muscle efficiency the tibia
and fibula of the leg hairs were kind in
that lower leg region the tibia is this
small is
the smaller fibula bones comprised the
lower leg and articulate with the knee
so the tibia is the thicker bone we can
kind of think of it in that way a lot of
people confuse the tibia and fibula the
fibula is the smaller one so that tibia
if you think T and thicker that can help
you remember that in a quick and visual
comparison it spans the lower leg
articulates with the proximal e with the
femur and patella the knee joint and
distally with the tarsals bones at the
ankle joint that's down here it's a
major weight-bearing bone of the leg
because is the thicker one the fibula
you can think about being fragile it's
the thinner one it also spans the lower
leg and although approximately does not
articulate with the femur or the patella
that's been located right here serves
more as an attachment point for muscles
rather than a weight-bearing bone and
that's why it tends to be more fragile
the thicker tibia is doing most of the
weight bearing we have the tarsals and
metatarsals and the phalanges
so in humans the ankle and foot bones
include the tarsals that's your actual
ankle metatarsals are kind of your
middle bones and the phalanges are the
actual toes kind of like very similar to
analogous kind of being in your hand we
see those seem terms the phalanges
fingers and toes being given here so
it's important to make that distinction
of where you are talking about when
you're using that particular term