so here we're a look at how different
types of macromolecules are formed it's
important to realize there's four main
classifications to macromolecules and
they are DNA and RNA also known as
nucleic acids proteins carbohydrates and
lipids which also you may know as fats
so a what is a macro molecule well
they're carbon-based so they consist of
a carbon-based core with specialized
groups attached I'll go over some of the
specialized groups but because we're
talking here about macromolecules it's
an organic molecule and here the organic
is meaning that there is carbon-based
core to the molecule these groups have
specialized properties and I referred to
as functional groups so it's a currently
score as I mentioned here because it's
in special groups attached what those
special groups are are functional groups
and here's a couple main ones located
right here functional group with a
hydroxyl group the methyl group the
carboxyl amino the phosphate these are
different types of groups and you can
see they have very distinctive
structures now it's important that these
structures are defined because these
particular structures will define the
various properties so hydroxyl group
this Oh H attached to R is kind of that
a variable group here for example methyl
group this variable chain is attached to
a ch3 this gives you just some examples
of some of the functional groups related
to macromolecules so macromolecules can
be formed or they can be broke down
macromolecules are made by the process
called dehydration synthesis is
important remember dehydration is the
loss of water when we're losing water we
see in O H and H also known as h2o
leaving and here we now have two
monomers to single a monomer one one or
two are now linked together by a
covalent bond so here we have two single
monomers that are now being linked
together here this is dehydration
synthesis we're synthesizing or putting
these two monomers together the opposite
of that with a break down our
macromolecules are broken by a process
called hydrolysis here we have our two
monomers linked together if we're adding
water
now creating or breaking into two
monomers so you can kind of break this
word apart into hydro lysis hydro
meaning we're taking in water lysis
means to lyse or to cut or to break both
of these processes both hydration
dehydration synthesis or removing water
to join two monomers together and
hydrolysis where we're adding water to
kind of break apart this in these
monomers that are linked together
breaking apart that linkage into our
individual monomers both of these
require enzymes and we'll have other
lectures to talk about those but key
part here dehydration synthesis
dehydration removal of water to put
things together to synthesize them and
hydrolysis taking in water here to
separate out into two individual
monomers organisms are primarily made of
four kinds all of macromolecules it's
important to be able to identify these
carbohydrates lipids proteins and
nucleic acids room in a clique as it
includes both DNA and RNA these are
termed macromolecules and they're the
basic building materials in machinery
for a cell so we're working our way up
from small atoms to molecules to have
macromolecules and working our way into
these are the primary molecules that are
used for both the machinery and also the
building blocks for the cell