okay here we look at magnesium
deficiency in cannabis plants so
magnesium is a vital nutrient something
some growers may not initially think
about but when they see a problem
something that may come up on the list
and be sure to check out some other
videos on looking at other deficiency
symptoms in cannabis so it's going on
with magnesium in particular in this
case so magnesium well why does a plant
even need magnesium is often you know
the question growers may ask keep in
mind that magnesium is a mobile nutrient
meaning it can move through the plant it
has a dominant role with the
photosynthetic process so it's
associated processing the chloroplasts
that green color that real nice green
color we typically associate with plants
as part of the responsibility of
magnesium or that 35% of the leaf
magnesium is actually located within
those chloroplasts the magnesium is
involved with the verbiski enzyme
activation activity and that is very
important to initiate that carbon
binding with the photosynthetic process
there now the magnesium does impact the
chloroplast structure and the synthesis
so it is involved on a micro level but
we can see macro effects in the plant
the deficiency leads to reduction in the
plant's ability to utilize carbon
dioxide assimilation rates and reduces
rates of biomass formation and that can
reduce the yield in the end result and
also in the simple plant biomass both
negative aspects of growers want to
avoid now a trial is done so kind of a
unique thing here with cannabis
now the cultivars wife the police plants
are you're gonna see about 80 days old
it's grown in a greenhouse to help
maintain consistent conditions
you never see a control plant that was
fed a balanced fertilizer and then a
test plant was fed all the nutrients at
optimum levels except the one being
studied in this case it would be a
magnesium deficient plant
so specifically here's the cannabis
plant that we can see see it's a little
hard to tell
zoomed in there's another image that I
found this is kind of what you're
looking for that slight yelling of the
lower leaves here
is kind of what you're looking for the
veins of the plant will remain that
typical consistent dark green color
which we're looking as in between those
veins you have the yellowing so you have
this kind of dark green veins but then
you have that yellow and that is
occurring that yellowing on lower leaves
in particular is characteristic of a
magnesium deficiency so in cannabis
there can also be some stippling some
brown spots that you kind of see going
on here at least a little bit here in
the lower leaves they may not turn
completely yellow so this is a great
example of how sometimes the plants
don't follow the textbook exactly
because this is actual cannabis plant
that was particularly fed magnesium
deficient fertilizer ich Ihnen so you
kind of get to see firsthand what what
may occur or how the plant may react may
not always be that textbook here you're
noticing they have those brown spots
that are kind of developing it's another
kind indication of a potential magnesium
deficiency I tend to be first seen in
those lower leaves so if you're seeing
right at the top that might be something
else here we're looking at that older
leaves those lower leaves can progress
up the plant if the problem is not
corrected so it's important to recognize
it's occurring the lower leaves could be
magnesium
let me start to feed some magnesium
fertilizer so a lot of growers asked
well what may that look like we have
some different options so applications
it should be made repeatedly and on
regular intervals until the problem
stops progressing because it might take
a little while that the buildup in the
plant don't expect a one-time
application to kind of fix the problem
I've read some suggested fertilizers in
suggested application rates for a two by
two foot area but followed the
recommendations on the package that you
may be purchasing epsom salts is one and
that's kind of quick and easy one to two
tablespoons per gallon and it can be
applied as a soil drench or can also be
applied to the leaves directly the
advantage is it's very easy to get
drugstores have it just go out grab it
you can apply it the same day it only
supplies magnesium and there's some
sulfur also added there there's a
cal-mag product this one's by patina
care but you want to start at about an
ounce to a gallon and the advantage of
that is it
a magnesium but also that supplies the
plant with some calcium that could be an
issue especially for growing in cocoa
qua the Kansa of the options prevented
here that is the most expensive but it
does have the ability to help correct
that deficiency and especially if you
have a calcium issue can up correct that
as well
the last one I cut included here is
dolomitic lime so if you're growing in
an outdoor application or you need a pH
correction anyway if your soil tends to
be a little bit on the acidic side need
to add lime you can add adult dolomitic
lime this is calcium lime this has that
plate as much on 90s and with it but
dolomitic would be a great option there
it's free I say with the line because
that line naturally is high in magnesium
but it could only use for soil
applications that you're trying to raise
the pH so you kind of got to balance
your options in what particular growing
situations you're looking at
so hopefully this provides a little bit
of that kind of that real-world kind of
example of how plants may not always
follow the textbook but gives you
something to look at or helps you
identify the potential deficiency that
you may be having