here we're gonna look at a little more
detail how your body goes about
maintaining homeostasis if I have this
picture here of someone balancing on the
railing here that's exactly what your
body's trying to do trying to maintain
this balancing act that's occurring
despite changes that are happening in
your body on a daily hourly
minute-by-minute basis so starting first
with the basics of homeostasis well we
have our homeostasis we want to be nice
and level with an imbalance that's
occurring well that imbalance needs to
go through a receptor to detect that
change it needs to go to a control
center of some sorts that then will send
out an effector which will respond to
that change and help correct that
potential imbalance that did occur now
it's important to realize that
homeostasis does not involve keeping
conditions static there can be changes
that occur what's important to remember
is that involves keeping conditions
within a tightly regulated limits so
because you can change all we wanted
here but if we went to go outside of
this range this is where we have issues
that occur so as homeostasis is keeping
this very tight range so slight changes
are occurring but it's occurring within
a very tight range is very tight
balancing at go back to our person
balancing on the railing you can wave
her a little bit if you waver too far
you're gonna fall one way or the other
keep calm and maintain the stasis so
let's now look at some examples so
there's a negative feedback model it's
called so we have a specific body
condition we have something increasing a
gland releasing a hormone up causing the
lowering of that condition now if we
have a way if something's getting too
high to lower that condition locally if
the body overcorrects and over lowers
the condition it needs to typically be
another hormone that will then raise
that condition that's how our body is
able to try to maintain that homeostasis
is to maintain its raising it's trying
to bring it down it's too low it's
trying to bring it up so let's take this
as an example particularly at the
nervous system tied in with body
temperature so if our body temperature
for increasing their body temperature we
have nerve signals that respond to that
that will cause our body to sweat and
dilate our
blood vessels that will hopefully cool
our body temperature however if our body
temperature gets too cold right then we
will need a way we have different nerve
signals that would cause us to shiver
you constrict our blood vessels that
will then hopefully cause their body
temperature to raise you're able to
maintain that nice consistent body
temperature in our brain we have the
hypothalamus which is involved in
regulating body temperature so as a way
of both lowering our body temperature or
raising our body temperature connecting
this with the endocrine system we can
look at the blood sugar so our blood
sugar level if it gets too high we have
insulin that will be secreted by the
pancreas body cells take up sugar from
the blood and reduce our appetite then
if I it overshoots we put too much sugar
into our cells our blood sugar level
gets too low glucagon will be released
and this triggers hunger and this
deliver will release glucose from the
cells increasing blood sugar levels and
that will hopefully through this system
of insulin and glucagon it will be able
to maintain a consistent level or a
consistent range of blood sugar in the
body system