on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over main nutrient
categories which important when we're
looking at fertilizing our
[Music]
plants right let's get into the main
nutrient categories so you can be able
to understand each of these three
important categories
so the first category is going to be
macronutrients so they are needed in
large amounts and that's why i have the
picture of the elephant here they also
might be referred to as primary
nutrients these are typically the
nutrients that plants show sign of
lacking first as
they are needed in large or macro
amounts these are also the big three
numbers that are printed you'll see on
fertilizer labels and those three
numbers that you always see
are referring to nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium the npk ratio there and all
three of these are actually mobile
nutrients which is important when we
might be looking at diagnosing potential
deficiencies or issues these are mobile
nutrients within the plant that's our
first category the macronutrients
proceeding on from macronutrients we
then go to secondary nutrients and these
are needed to of extent from fertilizers
in most cases and for most plants
they're often added in other products
such as lime or organic matter so keep
that in mind that these secondary
nutrients
we might be wondering what these
secondary nutrients are well they're
typically magnesium calcium and sulfur
are those secondary needed but to a
lesser extent than those macronutrients
that leads us also to our micronutrients
and micronutrients are essential for
plant survival so i want you to realize
that they are essential but they're only
needed in small micro quantities so it
can sometimes be referred to as trace
elements and these are immobile except
chlorine is the only exception to this
so boron copper iron chlorine manganese
mn molybdenum as well as zinc are
nutrients that fall into the
micronutrient category they're needed
but needed in small amounts
then we get to lastly here talking about
the micronutrients common deficiencies
include zinc iron manganese and copper
however be aware that it's also easy to
get to toxic levels if you are to add
these can often be worse situation
compared to if you had a deficiency so
just remember that that we don't want to
necessarily be fertilizing for our
micronutrients we are seeing a potential
for micronutrient deficiency by all
means yes but keep in mind that they're
needed in such small amounts you are
going to be measuring them in very small
it should be dosing in very small
amounts i see a lot of growers often
over add micronutrients and that can
lead to toxic levels in the plants which
can cause more harm than good so this
understands the major categories of your
nutrients