so when we look at plants were PI very
familiar with the stems and the roots
and the leaves but we also have to
consider and also remember the major
plant cell components so of those plant
cells what does each one of those
individual cells what are they made out
of what do they contain well they
contain a nucleus on this controls the
cells actions is often refer to as the
command center of the cell contains most
of the DNA you know the mitochondria and
chloroplasts to have some of their own
unique DNA this would be the vast
majority of the DNA inside we or on the
outside I should say of the nucleus we
have the nuclear envelope there's
nuclear pores here that regulate what
can come in welcome come out because
this is the command center it's very
important the cell keeps this
information protected the mitochondria
this is the site where food is converted
into energy through the process of
cellular respiration it does contain
some of its own unique DNA and it's the
site specifically what we call ATP
synthesis then assume triphosphates the
energy currency of the cell this is the
main site where it is synthesized or
made to say it's the powerhouse of the
cell is where they students will tell me
it is it's not really a proper reference
to its function the synthesis of ATP is
a much more accurate description of what
this organelle does the chloroplasts
contain the green pigment that's it's
called the chlorophyll that capture
light for photosynthesis also contains
some of its own unique DNA there's a
high concentration of chloroplasts give
the plants this green color we may
notice here in New England in the fall
plants lose their some trees lose their
green color and will start to turn
different colors and that's as a result
the breakdown of the chlorophyll which
is located in the chloroplast there's
also some other pigments but chlorophyll
is the most dominant the vacuoles see
here has a large shaft it contains water
stored food salts pigments and other
waste products it can take up the
majority of the volume of the cell so it
can vary but it can take almost up to
about 90% of the cell ribosomes are the
site of protein synthesis it's where
amino acids are linked together
is ribosomes are these complex here we
can see one indicated here we're not
going into two mentions in the protein
synthesis pathway but it's where all the
amino acids are linked together to form
polypeptides also known as proteins
specific types of proteins that would be
an example being enzyme the endoplasmic
reticulum or er contains these
interconnected network of membrane
includes two black structures there's
rough ER which has a rebus odin's kind
of put on top here kind of studded on
top and we have smooth ER which is more
the site of lipid or fat synthesis Golgi
bodies are the site of protein
processing storage and modification you
can see here's our nucleus here's our
rough ER and then we would go to the
Golgi apparatus
this tends to be one of the more
finishing bodies where kind of were
modifying those proteins that may have
been produced from the rough ER and is
tweaking them before they may be
released outside the cell or put into
the cell membrane the cell memory
specifically is also known as a plasma
membrane it's what's called a
phospholipid bilayer there is a
phospholipid there is a bilayer English
two layers this together helps the cell
regulate what can enter and exit the
cell causing on this semi permeable
layer it's present in both plant and
animal cells the cell wall is only
present in plant cells so the cell
membrane platon animal cell well only
plant cells we see here onion cells and
the root tips in particular cell walls
are composed mainly of cellulose steel
this is a complex sugar molecule giving
a lot of strength and rigidity after the
cell stops growing this the wall will
thicken and become rigid and it's not
present in animal cells so that kind of
gives these kind of this until almost
blocks like look appearance it's the
formation of that thick and rigid cell
wall when a plant cell reaches the point
of maturation