okay here we look at the MHC proteins
which stands for major
histocompatibility proteins but the note
here of know thyself this is how cells
are able to interact and recognize one
another these MHC proteins are very
important so class 1 in a class 2 and
we'll look at those in more detail so
starting with that know thyself here
quote know the enemy and know yourself
in a hundred battles you'll never be
defeated so this is part of the immune
system it needs to be able to identify
the enemy but it also needs to know
itself be able to recognize what self
cells are so it doesn't attack those so
the first step is I get to find the
enemy so what's our first kind of
process here well we've been recognized
our own cells and every cell in the body
carries the surface markers the surface
markers are called MHC proteins
specifically they're called major
histocompatibility proteins these MHC
proteins are different for each
individual they acted self markers so
class one has basically one binding site
here to the cell in class two has two
binding sites we can see an example here
of our class twos and class ones these
are class 2-z these are class ones these
are ones and these are twos this
indicates even further which ones came
from a maternal line Fortunes came from
a maternal line and a paternal line from
mom and from dad so didn't find the
enemy's number one so we have inter gene
presenting cells sometimes abbreviated a
ap C cells they ingest off foreign
particles or partially digest them in
this case here we have a macrophage it's
in copes capsulated this bacterium in a
vacuole they then combine pieces of
foreign particles with MHC proteins and
move them to the surface
so our lysosomes here are digestive
enzymes are fusing with this bacterium
contant to break down and then here's
our antigen news our MHC class 2
receptors move the digested bacterium
and presenting it on the cell surface
t-cell receptors can only interact with
cells that have a combination of MHC and
antigen so this is why it's important to
have these MHC proteins incorporating
that that's helping identify as self and
not destroying the entire cell here this
image here has been a little time on
ions the antigen processing and
presenting steps so here we notice we
have a pathogen in this case it's being
ingested here and this pathogen or
extracellular antigen as indicated here
two different pathways are being taken
in by the cell being engulfed by the
cell phagocytized would be the proper
term to use in this indigent presenting
cell does aid in dendritic cell is
placed into a vesicle so received both
of these different pathways of antigen
being acquired from either inside the
din dendritic cell here were required
from outside the environment here being
placed into a vacuole this ingested
pathogens are digested by but the
digestive enzymes in the lysosome and
interacting with the antigens
now this lysosomes releasing these
enzymes these enzymes are breaking this
bacterium down maintaining the antigen
from the digested pathogen these
antigens bind with MHC proteins that
enter the the vesicle here so we notice
it's occurring with the bacterium and
also in the case here where we have our
extracellular antigen being going
through that same process it's important
that these able are able to bind with
the MHC class 2 protein so that they can
be presented on the cell as we
progressed further i mean c proteins are
now carrying the antigens that are
released from the vesicle and travel to
the outer surface of the cell membrane
if they never reach the outer surface
our T cells won't be able to bind with
them meaning if our image c proteins
found at the antigen and were stayed
inside the cell there'd be no point our
T cells can only bind with receptors on
the cell surface so
it's very important this dendritic cell
is now presenting antigens on the cell
surface so that it's able to activate
t-cells that bind with the MHC proteins
this is helping the immune system be
able to recognize these foreign invaders
are these antigens require these antigen
processing cells APC cells to go through
this process to then display these on
the surface with the appropriate MHC
protein so our T cells can recognize
this itself American this is a formed
antigen and then initiate a potential
immune response so hopefully going
through and understanding this very
complex process was a little bit easier
welcome to pause the video and take a
look at this image here so you can
better understand the antigen processing
and presenting process