on this debaco university video we're
going to explore
manual canvas plant takedown for harvest
something you might be familiar with
i'll give you some tips and tricks and
to explain it a little bit more in
detail
here on this video lecture
[Music]
all right let's get into the manual
cannabis plant takedown
harvest regarding cannabis so first off
physical labor
is required so this is the kind of pro
and con to this method
is that as the name implies this
requires physically cutting down the
plant by hand and transporting it to the
next location
typically your drying location however
this process can be incorporated into an
operation that's also looking to do
selective harvesting
as a first step so this manual harvest
is made will take down you can also go
through do selective harvest first
and take larger plants a little bit
later so it does afford you that option
you can do a slightly
staggered harvest that manual harvesting
for indoor growing is likely the only
option but it is
easier when plants are being grown in
containers if you're growing outdoors
well
then if you're an outdoor grower it's
kind of like harvesting christmas trees
from the field which requires energy and
willingness to get a little
dirty as you're kind of going through
close to that soil line cutting that
plant down
picking it up and transporting it to its
next location there
so all part of the kind of fun of the
manual harvesting
process now this is a very common
procedure so
this is nothing kind of really new
typically the plant will be cut down at
ground level with
heavy duty loppers and this allows the
entire plant to be easily handled and
limits the need for unnecessary cuts
which can take more time and also more
labor we are seeing someone going
through here and try doing a little bit
more of a selective harvest maybe taking
some of the
larger buds putting them into a separate
container for a separate drying process
there this also helps hold the entire
plant together for easy transport when
you cut the entire plant down
in here if you're taking a couple off
that's perfectly fine and then the rest
of the plant can be dried together
great at keeping everything kind of
collected together
easy for transport you don't kind of
have a lot of little parts kind of
missing
i also want to have forward thinking so
if you know you're going to be mainly
harvesting your crop at the end of the
season this may influence the variety
you select the plant
typically selecting smaller plants would
be preferred to allow you to actually be
able to handle them
you have to go through and do multiple
maybe cut it in half and cut that in
half again to be able to handle the
plant
excessively large plants may have higher
yields at least on paper
but manually harvesting process will be
difficult to increase
a chance of plant damage and this could
reduce the total end product or at least
the quality of the end product
so it's always good to have an idea of
what how you'll be harvesting in the
end because that may be a contributing
factor to influencing
exactly what you plant what variety
cultivar you plant
so that you can ensure that your when it
comes to harvest
you're not going to have any incidental
loss to physical damage
simply because the plants got too high
and only because you saw your reddit on
the paper oh it's going to produce this
much per plant
we want to make sure you can handle
those in efficient manner and you don't
have
a lot of physical damage reducing your
overall yield
cutting down on your total efficiency