have you considered adding manure tea to
your canvas plants
well this tobacco university video will
provide you with some information and
some data
to look at how applicable this may be
[Music]
let's get into using manure tea for
cannabis production
so first off here's the research article
and i would invite you to kind of go
through
find the article look at in more detail
because there's a lot presented here
i'm just going to provide you again with
a brief overview
so the study specifics as far as
overview of kind of what they went
through and looked at
they evaluated the individual and
combined effects of commercial synthetic
fertilizer humic acids
manure tea and bio inoculants such as
inorganic
organic and biological resources
respectively
on cannabis growth and physiological
parameters
and here's some pictures of plants from
their study
so what were the treatments and this
kind of is
shows some of the data table that they
provided
so one of the two biological fertilizers
was micro grow
which is a brazilian patented product
categorized as manure tea
so micro geo is this manure tea
specifically that was looked at in this
study
this bio fertilizer is composed of
organic components
active in dormant cells from various
microorganisms
and metabolites and organomineral
chelates that are produced through
continuous anaerobic fermentation
in a liquid medium so when we're looking
at kind of what's presented here we can
kind of see some of the
sighting of sources as well we see that
bio fertilizer category which will be
focused on
the micro geo and micro uh geo supreme
bio inoculant and what is this here this
is a water soluble powder containing
several strains of bacteria and fungi
including 11 different mycorrhizal
species and microbial foods is well
included in the mix so you can kind of
follow these through
the study now what are the effects of
these biological stimulants on
cannabis well the microgeoproducts did
increase you in root biomass as
this was generally not different from
the control
and this may have been due to the
reduced stress and not the overall
improvement of the plant it's an
important note to make there
however there is still change for
improved cbd content even though this
data was not
collected in the study so what this is
showing here is the different
groups and different treatments and the
shoot biomass
the root biomass and then the total and
keep in mind means within
a column followed by the same letter are
not significantly different at the 0.5
probability level of statistics
so you could pause the video here and
take a look at some more detail but
there's definitely some consistencies
here sadly
not showing a whole lot of differences
so what were the researchers general
conclusions
well their general conclusion was the
combination of the combined application
of humic acid
and bio fertilizer resulted in additive
but not synergistic increase in the
measured parameter what their core ideas
was that cannabis height chlorophyll and
photosynthesis were affected by vital
fertilizer and umic acid
can con cannabis biomass was rarely
affected by the application of
biofertilizer and or humic acid
now clear evidence found in the
additional benefits from the combination
of biofertilizer and humic acid
therefore bio stimulants may contribute
to cannabis stress
mitigation and naturally about it so
keep in mind if you are growing plants
and hopefully maintaining their
environment so there is not a lot of
stress on the plants
then the really effectiveness of adding
some of these biostimulants such as
manure teas
may be significantly reduced good if
they're in a stressful situation
but in this case or this study if you're
keeping the environment
well keeping the growing environment
very supportive the effectiveness of
these bio students may be greatly
reduced
to the point it's not worth the extra
labor
time and money to add them to your
growing operation