all right in this tobacco university
video we're going to be investigating
marijuana and the history
of the og kush a very famous variety
you might have heard of before so while
marijuana is high
in thc content that is important to know
and while this channel does focus
more on the hemp it's important to
understand that while marijuana
is associated with that recreational use
in general following and understanding
the history of the famous og
kush strain can provide great insight
into the marijuana culture in general
and a lot of the information is spread
through oral
history and kind of explanations of
things so this just kind of serves as an
example of that
also the og kush has become a worldwide
staple used for numerous famous trains
like girl scout cookies and there's
also many different phenotypes of the og
kush
that exist the following that i'm going
to present here is the history of the og
kush is based on an
interview with matt bubba berger who
found a bag of seed in florida that
would later become known as the og
kush the original interview came on the
adam dunn show
as you can see right over here adam dunn
right there and i was
been very fortunate to meet him both in
denver
colorado and also on the east coast if
you want to
hear the interview for yourself i have a
link to the
youtube uh description there as far as
how to look it up and the link to
provide if you want to look at the
original interview but here i'm going to
provide a
kind of summarized version so the
history of the og kush just in general
looking at its original this originated
in
orlando florida and the seed came from
an unknown bag of wheat in miami in
1991.
we just was called crippy which was
really just a generic term for good weed
and it's the start of the generation
that started naming
and breeding around this time frame only
one plant was kept and propagated from
the limited amount of seeds that were
present
in the once original weed and it was
just called kush
since the first batch was said to look
like cushberries that's an important
note to make that
there's really no such thing as a
cushberry but they like the name
so it stuck and it became a popular
popular in the cannabis
industry in 1996 it's made its way to
los angeles so while a lot of people
think the og kush is a
west coast california-based strain the
original seed did come from orlando
florida in 1991.
now become how would become the og kush
here
well in 1988 star to actually be called
the og
kush in an attempt to identify it as the
original strain grown in
los angeles ground in la there in
general it tends to be a
viny morphology and can have homogenic
tendencies as well originally to prevent
the strain from being
lost seeds were the main form of
distribution and this is how the og kush
got spread across
the united states now looking at the og
kush it's a quality over
quantity example here so the cush is
generally a poor yielder in quantity
it's not going to give you like an
example of the tomatoes over here it's
not going to be a ton of tomatoes but
it's going to give you
high quality um end results there
so the quality was above average in
shops in amsterdam
i did not want to pay any more for
originally since it was not well known
it's hard to get a premium price even
though the quality was higher in
amsterdam
however during 1997 to 1999
in los angeles california it was getting
top dollar for the cush
due to the great demand and limited
supply
to give you an idea of what the price is
going for around that time frame you're
looking at 500 plus dollars per ounce
and it was sold even before it was grown
that's his
shows you how high in demand it was now
cush is very much a west coast strain
sour diesel was dominant on the east
coast so these kind of develop the
west coast as more og kush east coast
more that sour
diesel strain now limited starting
materials mentioned so the kush strain
can be traced back to an original
literally few seeds that were found in
an
ounce of weed way back in the early 90s
very rare for this limited starting
material to become such
a successful strain but remember it is
possible if you think about developing
your own
there are some people who have feminized
it and generated their own versions of
it
but original uh has been kept for these
special unique terpene profile that it
does um
possess here to find that true and
original
og kush now past the present and i gave
you that kind of like just quick summary
matt bubba berger has been growing the
same plant propagated via clones for
about 18 years
up to this up to the publication of this
video overall the end product
is unchanged but the leaf morphal
morphology has gone from more of the
traditional kind of
five-fingered leaves to more funky
random
morphology over that many years of
propagation
yield has dropped a little bit but over
this time
however the chemical profiles remain
like the original
so that's the importance of kind of
clones or maintaining a strain over a
long period of time
at the point of he interviewed here he
was growing up for 18 continuous years
and like i said it's a slight difference
in plant morphology but the key part is
that chemical
and terpene profile remain the same
giving that og
kush the reason for why it's still
around to this day is it's for its
unique terpene profile
and uniqueness to the market and that's
why it's still respected and known
to the present day