hopefully you've made it through a
successful growing operation
you've had a good drying process you've
cured all your cannabis buds
now you're looking for storage and now
you're realizing there's a lot of
material options for properly storing
your cannabis buds
well here at tobacco university we're
going to give you some advantages and
disadvantages of some common materials
so you can make an informed decision
so you can have the best long-term
storage for what you've worked so hard
to grow and produce
[Music]
all right let's get into material
options for storing cannabis
so first off you want to keep the
environmental conditions optimum
regardless of what material you're
actually choosing
regardless of area jews environment is
still important and those environmental
conditions are important to monitor
to help maximize the storing of your
cannabis while
also maintaining a high quality now it
can be a very
high-end regulated kind of canadore
product here or it can be just the
environmental conditions that's being
stored and does not have to be
super high-end can be large scale but
keeping it monitored and regulated is
very important now there are different
material options you can think of it
like
different material options for water
bottles cannabis can be properly stored
in a number of different materials
not just one correct material each
material does have its own advantages as
well as disadvantages
that a grower must recognize to
determine the best fit for their given
situation
and here in this video i am going to
provide you with a host of options
as well as the advantages and
disadvantages to allow you to make that
informed decision
so first off storing canvas in glass
these are typically easy to acquire
and commonly used for display as well as
storage
mason jars are the industry standard but
there are other options that can be
larger or smaller but the ball mason
jars is probably the gold standard we
can get the
lids uh you can buy new lids so they can
steel up really nice it's really easy to
acquire these
this is probably considered to be
probably one of the more common options
now why is it more common option well
the glass itself is inert
it's very hard it's not biodegradable so
it makes the
glass material advantageous however most
are clear which would require a dark
environment for storage so just keep
that in mind
there are different colors but also
present similar challenges as clears are
still letting
light in so while the material itself
has a great advantages
because it is clear they should be
stored in a dark environment not
necessarily hard to do but something to
keep in mind if you're selecting this as
your option
so others will look at what's called a
violet glass to basically store the
cannabis buds and violence glass blocks
visible light
with the exception of the color violet
so we can see here let's some light in
but a lot of visible light is reflected
it's semiprimal depends on the specific
glass type as well as the thickness
to uva and infrared light allowing about
40 to 60 percent to penetrate
and so keep that in mind that you are
getting some degree of penetration
but it is a lot less than clear glass
for example
so the advantages of selecting this type
would be it does limit to light
penetration
can help protect bud quality over clear
materials the downfalls wavelengths
filtered
may be low exposure to buds anyway and
this can be
also difficult material to acquire
so at least this is storing in stainless
steel as we can see right here
many cooking safe containers can easily
be used for storing buds these
containers offer great storage
conditions
this material is less likely to become
damaged compared to glass
so there's again some of the benefits
and pretty easy to acquire and easy to
seal up as well
so reason why someone would use the
stainless steel
was it it is an inert material seals the
bud environment from the outside
and offers the ability to block light
the downfall is it can be heavy
and they come in limited sizes and
shapes which could impact
storage depending on how much room you
have for adequate storage
then that leads us to storing in plastic
so cannabis can degrade in plastic
containers
can often allow for easy stacking though
plastic materials can have great degree
of variability meaning you can have
plastic bags
or you can have plastic buckets or
containers
now storing cannabis in plastic the
advantage is that it's really easy to
acquire very easy to get
um as bags or buckets or bins it's not
likely to become damaged because it is
rigid however the disadvantages it can
lead to degradation of the buds
particularly for really long-term
storage
which is why a lot of growers choose not
to use plastic
it can be good to be used in a pinch can
be good for short-term operations as
well
so keep these in mind when looking at
selecting your material so you can
select material that's the best fit for
your situation
to allow the longest storage uh of your
buds
and keep in mind that the environment is
also important as well as materials
you select actually store your buds in