thank you for checking out another video
here on tobacco university
this video we're going to look at
measuring bones to estimate height which
can be applicable for a skeleton that's
found
or you can also try this yourself to see
how well the
math or measurements come out so here
we're looking at a single bone
to individual height so by measuring a
single bone the estimated height of the
angel can be calculated
it's important to be able to properly
identify the bone to know the formula
in the or i should say the correct
formula to use because you can't just
pick
any bone there are certain key ones that
a formula has been developed
so you can get a closer estimation of
the height of the individual
so you want to select a long bone to
measure and have a couple listed here if
you remember from
long bones the humerus radius the ulna
the femur the tibia or the fibula would
be
bones typically that are used in this
measurement process
now looking at race and sex or the
gender of the individual
knowing the race and sex of the
individual of the bone will help
increase the accuracy of the calculation
because there's different formulas to
apply at a crime scene with an unknown
individual it's important to know that
some of the identifying characteristics
to aid
in the classification the trained eye
can spot some of these details
and other slideshows will go into detail
on this to try to be able to determine
an unknown individual to try to classify
them
as to allow for a greater formula to be
applied with greater accuracy
so as i said you can measure yourself
you can try this out for yourself here
when i stick to one of the long bones
that you mentioned you want to measure
the bone
length in centimeters and then you want
to use the following
reference table on the following slide
so once you choose one of those bones
you take a measurement
here is kind of an initial kind of
reference table to be able to use
and how you're going to use this well
you want to identify the bone you
measured the humerus the radius
the ulna the femur the tibia or the
fibula when defined one of those bones
measured
you use the measured length in
centimeters the eraser gender is known
if you're looking at a
skeletal remains and the gender are
known the most
accurate estimation can be calculated so
here you can just see some of the
equations whether it's
caucasian african-american asian or
unknown
and whether it's male or female they are
different
equations to apply there and this will
help provide you with an estimation
of the height of that individual based
on only using
one bone now you can calculate and
measure your height once you calculate
your height and compare it to the actual
height you can see how close it comes
remember this is only an estimate some
bones
might give you a closer uh or more
accurate
answer but they are all just to give an
estimate to give you a range or an
expected
approximate height of the individual you
want
questions to consider how does your
calculated height compare to your actual
height
and how may this be applied to a unknown
skeletal remains so you may want to use
different bones and find out which one
provides you
the more and less accurate results
you know some bones provide a closer to
the actual
but they're all just an estimation so
which bone for you provided the most
accurate results