he went about measuring light and some
of the units that you may see stated and
what does kind of mean there's just one
example here I can help our meter to
measure light also I included a link to
the fundamentals of a light kind of
Summit lecture I located on youtube if
you want to take a look at that also so
first off you may hear the term lumens
used the lumens a measure of the total
quality visible light emitted by a
source however this has greater ties to
the human visible spectrum so kind of a
cliche term mirrors lumens are for
humans so something that may look bright
to our eye may not necessarily be bright
or produce something that is also
beneficial to plants in the same way so
par or photosynthetic active radiation
this is a measure of the amount of light
in the 400 to 700 nanometers which is
where a plant needs to grow there's four
hundred seven or Navis kind of that full
visible light spectrum the higher the
power rating the more efficient the
plant will be since it measures the type
of light needed for this photosynthetic
process that's important to keep in mind
this par is a better measurement than
lumens now PFF or photosynthetic photon
flux is how many photons are being
released from a light source every
second the eight typically uses micro
moles per second color this is limiting
it doesn't tell you how much of the
measure light actually lands in the
plants but it's important metric if you
want to calculate the efficiency of
lighting system is that creating par so
that the example here we can see how
this light is scattered now I'm a plant
under this light a lot of this scattered
light will be part of the PF at the
photosynthetic photon flux being
released the photons released from this
light what's that going to be taken up
by the plant here a lot of this for
example will be wasted
there's ppfd photosynthetic photon flux
density and this is how many photons are
hitting your plant so this is a very
important measure and the one you should
look for if you're looking at comparing
lights or trying to get information from
a manufacturer this is a spot
measurement so it's important to take an
average of several PFDs measurements the
defined height that are taken micro
moles per meter squared per second is
the often
limitations this can overstate the true
light intensities of the fixture you
want to see published average ptsds
over a growing area one does a spot
measurement when I see it over an area
because I'll tell you again the photon
flux density the amount of light
actually hitting your plant so it
actually can be absorbed and used by the
leaves for photosynthesis measuring
light with par meters sensors are
primary instruments used to qualify
these light intensities well if you're
going to test your light allow it to
warm up for at least 5 minutes or so
before doing any intensity of the light
readings signature you're getting an
accurate reading these sensors work by
an optical filter to create your uniform
sensitivity for car light the light
meter measures instantaneous light
intensities or data loggers to measure a
cumulative light intensity also be
careful what like meteor you may be
using
make sure it's best match for your light
source that you're using some have
choices between artificial sources some
of the ways to measure the Sun on some
are best for or limited for LED lights
some are better for high pressure sodium
so again just be mindful of which one
that you're using and realize its
limitations and what it's best for