on this debaco university student series
video we're going to look at both the
pros and cons and compare a mechanical
timer to a digital timer now many of you
may make the decision of using one
versus another but this is going to
provide you with that information so you
can make an educated decision on which
one is the best for your growing
operation
[Music]
these are both timers that you could use
for your grow this one is a digital
timer and this one is a mechanical timer
they both have their pros and cons which
we will be going over in this video so
that you can determine which is best for
your operation now we're going to go
over the pros and cons of a mechanical
timer
so as you can see a mechanical timer is
a bit more straightforward and simple
than a digital timer there's a lot less
going on right here for you to work with
really you only have to press down some
buttons and move
some things left and right for it to be
set up
a con would be that you have to set it
up through 15 minute increments the most
precise that you could be on this is by
15 minutes which isn't usually a problem
but some people would like to have it be
a little bit more precise
another con is on the side we have a
switch that goes from timer to
indefinite this means that the light
will be on indefinitely and it's very
easy to sometimes switch this into the
indefinite meaning that your light will
not switch off when you have it
scheduled to meaning that your photo
period may be
interrupted so now we're going to be
talking about the pros and cons of a
digital timer some of the pros are that
it's just more precise in general you
can see the exact time and we have a
bunch more buttons to work with we see
we could just the day of the week the
hour the minute even the second
another pro is that it has a battery
backup so just in case something was to
happen where you lose power this will
actually remember what time it is it
will retain the exact time so that
nothing is really changed within your
schedule for when the lights turn back
on or off
a con would be that it's just a little
more complicated than a mechanical timer
if you're used to a mechanical timer
then all of these buttons may be a
little overwhelming at first i mean you
may be confused as to why you need
seconds when before you were adjusting
by the 15 minute increments
another con is that it's kind of just
the buttons are tiny and close together
so if you had big fingers you have the
risk of pressing multiple buttons or if
somebody was being careless they could
accidentally hit one of these buttons
which could change your timing from
being auto to just on all the time or
off all the time which would impact your
photo period
another con is that unlike a mechanical
timer you can't really see the logistics
of what's happening inside this timer
you just kind of have to hope that
everything's going on properly within
the timer
and just keep checking to see if
anything looks off just by this little
screen here rather than being able to
see everything that's going on with your
timer
so now that we've gone through the pros
and cons of both the mechanical and
digital timer is that for you as a
grower to decide which one you would
like to implement in your grow operation
now a tip from debacle himself would to
be would be to use the digital timer for
your
pumps because when you feed your plants
is very important down to the exact
second and to use the mechanical timer
for your lights because a 15 minute
difference isn't going to drastically
affect your photo period so in the end
it is up to you whether you will decide
to use a digital or a mechanical timer
either way it'll be one step closer to
fully automating your grow and making
your life a step easier
you