so in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over mechanically harvesting
cannabis plants
more commonly done with industrial hemp
but to give you some details
about exactly how this process occurs
[Music]
all right let's get into mechanical
canvas plant takedown options
regarding for harvest so first off using
harvesting equipment
it is advised for large scale operations
doing whole plant harvesting because it
just makes the process a whole lot
easier
while the basic concept and idea are the
same there are different mechanical
options to growers
and you should be aware of them so
you're making sure you select the proper
one
to fit your particular growing
environment so as we said there's
different types of equipment we see a
couple pictured here
there are different options so be sure
you select the one that's a good fit for
your particular operation
remember that canvas has a more
wood-like kind of fibers in a tobacco
plant
so the same equipment is not advised
just because you've got a lot of tobacco
equipment don't think you can just go
right down your cannabis field and
harvest it in the same way
a lot of growers sadly learned the hard
way that the
a lot of damage can be done to their
tobacco harvesting equipment so make
sure it's specialized or
at least tested on specifically cannabis
growers who have tried to use the same
equipment because plants are similar as
i said have
cut severe damage to their tobacco
equipment avoid this frustration and
added cost
make sure you're spending time with the
actual crop you intend on harvesting
just because it looks the same doesn't
mean you can be harvested in exactly the
same way
with the exact same equipment the basic
process though is the same the goal
of the machine is to cut down remove and
temporarily store the canvas plant
um on the way to the trim or drying
process whatever the grower's
choosing hemp harvesters utilize a
tractor with an implement mounted in the
front
side or even back the tractor many
different options
but utilizing mainly a tractor some
maintain the entire plant others will
chop the plant into small pieces and
others will mow the plant at different
heights
as we saw in kind of the last slide
there the method you select should be
based on your intended drying process
and end product that you intend to
produce because depending on
where that product is going to end up
what kind of you need to produce in the
end
may choose how you choose only choose
how you go about selecting
the harvest process that's the best fit
for your situation
plan the end at the beginning as i say
if you're utilizing mechanical
harvesting at the end of the season
keep this in mind when you're planting
having plants in straight rows and
equally spaced apart
will really help the process in the end
of the season when the plants are quite
large
so this is just again paying a little
extra attention to detail that planting
process that springtime
can really save you a lot of frustration
at the end of the season
so if you're going through mechanically
hard saying just make sure extra sure
you're kind of in straight pros
to allow the ease of the equipment to
actually benefit you in helping the
process
instead of becoming more of a
frustration and hindering the efficiency
of your operation