so just as the name implies these medium
moisture meters are simply meters that
will measure or assess the moisture
level in a given media net could be soil
at B soilless media they give you a
reading or an assessment and number to
go on as far as what that moisture
content is these moisture meters just
it's like there are water monitors for
nutrients we get it's important to
concealing monitor the soil moisture
level at the root zone so keep in mind I
should have this picture here because
you want to think the roots are in kind
of a 3d image when I think about it and
not just kind of a flat oh it cut the
soil in half and here's our roots it's a
3d have structure going on there so how
that moisture level isn't that media is
important for us as growers to know and
understand so motion rays are great
tools but they need to be calibrated and
installed properly only as good as the
operator so this is we have here for the
post rate I'm calculating the weight
there of a letter we want to show that's
calibrated
want to make sure also our moisture
meters are calibrated and depending on
which one you select or use will have
different calibration procedures the key
partisans is some way I realize they do
need to be calibrated to get accurate
and consistent readings for you so you
want to watch three units that they use
some low numbers indicate low moisture
and this makes more sense to people
others have low numbers meaning high
moisture so keep this in mind when
you're going through and purchasing one
be aware of the units that it chooses to
use just like we have Fahrenheit to
Celsius here we're looking at the you
know the same temperature here but very
different numbers they're just important
to know that and also if you're
comparing to other friends or other
people that are using moisture meters
being mindful what unit they're using
and what their numbers equate to just to
give you can that a nice quick general
summary provide a table here the water
scout the watermark and tensiometer you
have a picture of them all three here
again the all their pros and cons the
water scale is the most expensive but
does have the greatest accuracy
these have a slower response time the
water marks they're affordable and offer
a good level of accuracy intense
diameters they're lower-cost not as
useful and really dry conditions because
they only go
is Santa bars here that's the unit this
also measures incentive ours here so
again just look at the options it
depends on what operation you have with
media you might be using as far as which
one might be the best fit for your
operation personally I've seen in no
growers who have used all of these I've
chosen use the water scout I do feel it
is highly accurate when it's set up
properly so again that stresses the
point there that the moisture sensor is
only as good as the way to mount it and
if you mounted in accurately place it
wrong in the grow operation that will
give you false results but that's I'm
you know so take take some time actually
read the instruction manual make sure
they installed properly calibrated some
require are soaked ahead of time follow
those procedures and they will give you
accurate readings they'll provide you
with good data to allow you to know
what's going on in the root zone of your
plants