ok this video lectures in meiosis I
suggest you watch the other one that I
have on mitosis first because a lot of
these same steps repeat and use the same
terms so starting with meiosis here now
we're talking about meiosis we want to
be mindful of comparing it to mitosis
and we're gonna see these comparisons
done quite a bit mitosis is starting
with this diploid cell which is a normal
cell in your body and it's making two
identical copies meiosis here we're
taking that same initial start to the
cell we're going to end up with actually
four cells in the end that each have
half of the total genetic material do
another comparison here where we see our
parent cell we have this replication
phase and from that replication phase we
can go to mitosis which you could see
here is forming two identical copies of
the parent cell or meiosis here were
forming four total cells each with half
of the total genetic material so some of
the terms sister chromatids is one this
refers to e to either of the two
identical copies chromatids formed by
replication from a single chromosome
with both copies joined together with
his centromere so here's our chromosome
here here's our centromeres at center
location also represented here our
sister chromatids are those two things
two chromosomes joined together here in
that centromere together these make the
sister chromatid now there's also
something called daughter chromosomes
now these are appeard chromatids or
sister chromatids eventually separate
fewer dear separate and become daughter
chromosomes at the end of mitosis
daughter chromosomes are properly spaced
out in allocated to the different two
daughter cells together their sister
chromatids or from Anna chromosome
that's represented here or separated
their daughter chromosomes so I know
this is just sounds a little confusing
the difference between daughter
chromosomes and sister chromatids the
key part here the sister chromatids
actually joined the data chromosomes are
separated so getting into what's the
purpose of meiosis well for sexual
reproduction and for plants that seed
formation is basically to get to the
next generation spreading out the the
genes to then produce either in this
case it be pollen grains it could be on
forming in church seeds to be able to
make a new plant or a new person in this
case so first we have to understand two
key terms here first one is somatic
cells these are any cell a living
organism that is not a reproductive cell
here we have and endoderm lima mesoderm
and ectoderm i and all the somatic cells
they go through and they confirm these
stem cells and they're forming lung
tissue the pancreas the heart or red
blood cells skin or neurons all these
are somatic cells they are also diploid
meaning they contain two sets of
chromosomes one from each parent
so one from mom one from dad these were
plant cells it could be leaves in roots
and shoots and stems and they would also
have one chromosome from the male plant
and one chromosome from the female plant
we talk about gametes this is these are
single cells produced by adult organisms
that are specialized for meaning and
only at half the number of chromosomes
and thus we call them haploids
they're the single set of unpaired
chromosomes so the former site oh we
need a sperm cell in an egg cell to come
together and this is the first cell the
new individual this zygote here you will
see the ovules in a plant you receive
pollen grains if these two come together
that's from the fruit here these are an
example would be Tomatoes looking a
little bit closer at comparing the two
how ployed is usually represented with
just a letter n and diploid is 2n help
haploid sperm fertilizes a haploid egg
the resulting diploid zygote yourself up
here diploid zygote receives one copy of
each gene from mother and one from
father so here we see the example here
how ployed eggs in a haploid sperm
come together to from the diploid zygote
this is me the start of the new
individual same thing here
how boy sperm haploid egg forming a new
individual also and this is diploid one
copy from mom one copy from dad so a two
divisions of meiosis one cell divides
into two and then each of those divide
again resulting in four total cells so
unlike mitosis where we were forming two
identical copies here performing four
unique cells through very similar phases
prophase metaphase anaphase and
telophase one and then the same thing
repeats prophase metaphase anaphase and
telophase all represented to will go
into these a little bit more detail
sorry with prophase one chromosomes coil
becomes shorter and thicker nuclear
envelope in nucleolus dissociate apart
chromatids can be seen centromere is
performing at microtubules attach kind
of later prophase in mitosis seeing that
condensing here of the chromosomes we
could see our centrioles developing the
chromosomes are condensing the nucleus
breaking down and this is term crossing
over is important during prophase one
crossing over can occur this is a very
important thinking that happens in
prophase one it's a process where
homologous chromosomes pair up with each
other in exchange different segments of
their genetic material to form
recombinant chromosomes what does this
mean when we have longest chromosomes
and these urges could be the same
chromosome one for example and they line
up next to one another what's crossing
over is because these are homologous
meaningly essentially encodes in the
same thing one could be from mom one
could be from dad crossing over meaning
a section could break off this chromatid
and rejoining here and this is what's
causing or what we call crossing over
because a piece is crossing over here we
have a white and a black chromosome here
we get crossing over and we see to get a
kind of a stripe to a parents gonna wait
in the black the white and a black of
the white in a black this is crossing
over mean these were unique genetics
separated out now they're kind of joined
together this isn't
for example on metaphase the chromosomes
align at the equator and spindle fibers
become apparent meditation over the line
at metaphase plate the equator of this
cell here is lined up
remember this is metaphase 1 so what it
looks like on a real world image here I
could see everything all lined up
distinctly through the dye anaphase 1
his chromosomes migrate to the poles
again we're getting the pulling part of
our chromosomes now the centromeres are
not broken here that's an important
aspect to keep in mind they are still
attached the centuries are still
attached but now if we got this one for
Mom this one from dad is very pulled
part here we notice a little crossing
over did occur so anaphase looks like
that pole in the part of those
chromosomes telophase 1 and cytokinesis
this is a weak formation of the nucleus
because remember they're gonna divide
again you see initially we're starting
to have a nucleus starting to form but
that's gonna slowly divide and break
apart more here so division 2 similar
but not the exact same process repeats
so be careful in mind flow was different
so here in prophase 2 chromosomes become
shorter they never really completely
dissociated but they become shorter more
condensed spindle fibers are forming
here in metaphase 2 they're lining up
again an important part here between
metaphase 1 and metaphase 2 if you look
at these images there's three here this
one and this would look very similar
this one looks distinctly different we
notice here we're gonna hit separation
at the centromere here we're just gonna
migrate the chromosomes who knows this
is evident in metaphase - same with this
one
this is metaphase 1 that century will
not be broken in metaphase 1 again
metaphase 2 here a little bit harder to
see and some of these stained images
will get the sense for what that looks
like everything kind of lined up on the
equator region anaphase 2 same thing
happens or chromatids separate aligned
chromosomes to migrate to the poles
important for interphase - were actually
breaking those centromeres and those are
actually migrating to the poles here
teyla phase 2 and cytokinesis
chromosomes become longer new nuclear
envelope develops into the ol Ivy appear
new cell walls develop between each of
the four groups of chromosomes nuclear
envelope forms around each set of
chromosomes in the cytoplasm divides you
could see we're getting a distinct four
distinct cells that are forming meiosis
stage 1 unless is stage 2 could see kind
of the comparison here the key part here
with minuses or ending up with four
cells in the end each with half the
total genetic information so to kind of
give you a little bit of an animation of
what's what's generally occurring most
everything lines up we are just pulling
them apart nothing was broken getting
our formation and this is for a single
egg cell so we'll talk about we get to
human development egg cells or le
technically one total mature true egg
well you can kind of see and replay this
again what's going on how things are
migrating what is these are just moving
across no centromere is broken and then
when they do get broken polar bodies
will talk about that we do human
reproduction so you hear the centromeres
are actually being broken and for the
formation of eggs a single egg there's
only one true egg that's formed then
important in a good quiz question
between mitosis and meiosis here's a
great comparison between the two so
mitosis again forming those two total
cells meiosis forming those four and
being able to compare and contrast these
two ORS important aspects to show
understanding and if you want a couple
more links to some videos here is a
couple that I've provided to