here I'm gonna go over a basic overview
of memory processing that occurs as we
see in this image you can kind of think
of the brain here is exactly motherboard
of a computer in the sense of the
processing of events and storing them
for recall later that occurs so this
memory processing involves kind of three
main principles it's in general memories
that storage and retrieval of
information so it's important to memory
just don't store it we also need to find
a way to be able to retrieve that
so in general storage have here
Kirstin state is that continually change
so we have for example our disk our
memory card our tape recorder back one
is a magnetic strip or memory stick all
of these different storage ways when
relating it to the electronic kind of
things then there's a primary processing
portion occurs this is accomplished by
the hippocampus and surrounding
structures and that is the actual
processing chip here in a computer so
again while relating it to computers we
want to think about that from the human
aspect that the same process and overall
process is occurring within our own body
the third one is memory traces these are
chemicals or structural changes that
encode new memory they're broken into
two parts we have short-term memory
which appears to be stored electrically
in the form of transient neural
excitation and then we have long-term
memory so short-term memory we're
talking a couple seconds to maybe a
couple minutes maybe an hour or not much
longer than that and this shows the
depth of memory so we see there's a
quick spike and then it drops down
ultimately short-term memory this
overlap would be transferred into
long-term memory which appears to
involve structural changes in certain
neural connections so as we see here
within our short-term memory our
parental lobe here in the areas of
expectation as we start to transfer
further down into longer-term memory
will notice the cerebellum here becomes
more active initially very little
activity there as we're approaching long
to remember we start to see a couple
dots
see a little increase in intensity
ultimately leading to more memory
processing and storage here in the
cerebellum in relation to long-term
memory now way to kind of relate that is
a retrieval memory memory is not a
snapshot stored in the brain actually
must be put together from information
stored in various parts of the brain so
it's just kind of like a bunch of puzzle
pieces that come together because we
always want to store it we also need to
be able to access that into the future
so that just a snapshot there's a bunch
of pictures stored in there it's
actually kind of put together as like
puzzle pieces so they can easily be
retrieved and accessed at a later date