okay here we're looking at a memory
challenge or just memory in general so
this is important to kind of recognize
your own limitations as well if you're
interviewing someone there are potential
limitations that they may have to
recount the scene or remember an event
also remember the duration of time that
the event may have occurred or other
conditions whether it was during the day
or at night that can also impact
people's ability of remember things or
just what they can see in general so
looking at memory there's different
types of memory so the sensory memory is
one type this is the shortest term
element of memory and its ability to
maintain impressions of sensory
information after the original stimuli
have ended this is why it's important if
you see something you try to write down
as many details as you can as soon after
it occurs as possible so you're able to
kind of recount what happened what
occurred if you can add timestamps to it
that's all the better but just kind of
this is that first shortest term element
of memory what was going on around it
and that leads us to working memory
which has a limited capacity that is
concerned with the immediate conscious
person perceptual and linguistic
processing working memory is important
for reasoning and guidance of
decision-making in behavior this can
kind of be sometimes considered to be
kind of in the moment we're looking at
making the decision do you go left you
go right do you FLE do you stay what do
you do is kind of part of that working
memory so limited capacity you can sort
of think of immediate conscious of
what's going in in a round of the
individual unless I'm going to cover
here is long-term memories it kind of
would apply it's a short-term it's a
long-term memory compared to our
short-term memory which kind of just
discussed previously here long-term
memories the types of memory responsible
for the storage of information for an
extended period of time this might be
more limiting on the total amount of
detail that can be provided but the
extended period of time this is
something that if a crime occurred a
long time ago this is kind of what
should be depending on that witness to
be able to provide or recount it for you
so tips for improving memory just in
general get active and be creative to
kind of help keep the brain working try
to teach someone something kind of like
what I'm doing
right now test yourself on multiple
occasions in multiple ways and it's
going to be you know just challenging
yourself in general practice and repeat
processes and get enough sleep so all
these things kind of can go through and
improve your memory if you think your
memories you know pretty good as it is
just a question for you can remember
anything about the image on the title
slide into there were two children do
you know anything or you describe
anything about what's going on in the
picture or for example can you describe
the shirts that they were wearing if not
go back to the title slide take a look
and keep working on improving your
memory