so based on the Lee experiments Mendell
developed and did he came up with some
laws and some theories look at some of
those right here again studying just a
simple garden pea in his monastery in
Austria so again he's the first one to
come up with the idea heredity and
considered the father of modern genetics
they worked with garden peas in his
monastery in Austria one of the first
things he came up with Holmes first
theories he came up with is the
fundamental theory of heredity parents
do not transmit traits directly to their
offspring they do so via factors called
genes and this is we're tracking in our
punnett squares remember our genes are a
segment of DNA that encodes for a very
specific amino acid sequence or a
specific protein how genes influence
traits well this should look familiar
the central dogma here going from our
DNA to RNA to our proteins the amino
acid sequence determines the shape and
activity of the proteins proteins
determined in large measure or what the
body looks like and how it functions
potentially its color and this its
structure mutations in the gene result
in alleles and this ultimately leads to
a change in the amino acid sequence and
also the activity of the protein natural
selection may favor one allele over
another so it's important to remember a
mutation does not necessarily
automatically mean a bad thing mutation
it simply means that there's been a
change in the gene whether it's a good
change or a bad change will result from
the environment or the natural selection
that occurs so if it's advantageous to
have blue eyes or brown eyes that's
going to be softened by the environment
other mutations will be again determined
whether or not they're beneficial based
on the environment that they're in if
you have webbing on your hands you're
going through and doing a lot of quick
typing that may not be advantageous but
if you're in duck swimming in the water
and you lose the webbing that would not
be a good thing
so again depends on the environment
other law law of segregation during
reproduction the alleles that determine
traits are separated into reproductive
cells by a process called meiosis and
randomly unites during fertilization the
two
alleles of a gene separate when forming
gametes in the game it's combined rarely
to common offsprings this is our
segregation here see randomly segregated
randomly placed in two different cells
that will then merge together with an
egg and a sperm or egg and a pollen
grain when you're forming the actual
Zygo this segregation is just that
separating out or segregating where
those alleles go
since help me look getting since the
males the female form in our seeds so we
have our pollen grain here in our egg
merging together form seed a or in this
case seed B if you have different
segregation that's occurring how this
may look in looking color if it was as
simple as being simply orange or green
if you took a pure orange and it was a
capital o capital o and a pure green to
lowercase G's you bred these together
ideally we would have all orange
offspring but all these would be
heterozygous because they would all have
the green gene also there if you were to
breed these together you'd get opponent
squared like this in 25% of the green
the other 75% that would be orange and
again it's phenotypic way of speaking
Geno typically speaking only one would
be double dominant orange the other to
be heterozygous as Olaf was in the law
of independent assortment so here genes
located on different chromosomes will be
inherited independently from one another
that means if you have a gene on
chromosome 1 chromosome 9 they're gonna
be inherited independently of one
another this is their independent
assortment all the genes of hidden
chromosome wanna be moved over
chromosome 9 removes separately this is
independent assortment of sorting things
and basically an independent in often
random way this is how it looks
independent from one in segregation is
were filming our dihybrid cross here if
M is the symbol for female in male and
you can see our segregation image
independent assortment image here
something else that adds to genetic
variability is crossing over and we
looked at this during meiosis 1 longest
chromosomes basically come into contact
one another and a little part of one can
we can combine with another part of
another meaning one can break off and
train
for over it's an exchange in the
positions of the chromosomes to make
information is exchanged between
homologous chromosomes from other
basically getting lined up and we have
one kind of flipping positions with the
other that's what this shows right here
the to become a chromosomes are then
formed so this adds the genetic
variability of an osprey now random
fertilization occurs a single egg
fertilized by a single sperm it's
important remember you're a very unique
individual considering independent
Cermak in a random fertilization and
offspring represents one out of 72
trillion
yes--that's trillion Saigo possibilities
there's about eight and a half million
different ways to make individual
different sperm and eighty-five million
different ways to make an egg so eight
point five million times the 8.5 million
excuse me eight point five million times
eight point five million will give you
72 trillion zygote possibilities so you
may ask initially the question what
about identical twins
well after fertilization after the
zygotes made if that saigo then is to
divide after the fact they would have
two identical twins this is the odds one
in swimming two trillion that a
genetically identical sperm will be
identically identical eggs so you're
very unique there's a multiple traits
we're gonna look at this we do dihybrid
crosses here remember at it's like a
pupil MS inheriting white or purple
flowers might be parroting things
together and that's the point of this
dihybrid cross which we'll go over first
a little vocabulary here each parent
contains two copies of a factor
governing each trait if the two copies
are the same they're called homozygous
as we see here capital B capital B this
is homozygous if two copies are
differently recalled heterozygous in
this case would be heterozygous it may
be a little B little B in a big B here
are two little bees is also homozygous
this be homozygous recessive speak
homozygous dominant our alleles are
forms of factors that lead to different
traits alternate forms are called
alleles so hearing here at one from
parent one and parent two in this case
allele for both tall genes
here from parent one it's getting a
wrinkled Peapod and here it's hitting
his smooth again different alleles the
Penguins dominant or recessive will
determine is expressed gives you the
alleles being transmitted through an
inbred pedigree again that family tree
we can trace things through this that's
why it's important to understand these
and recognize some of these this is a
very basic one phenotype and genotype
you've heard you mention phenotype is
how an individual may look genotype is
the actual genetics so here's our
genotypes represented here by our
capital and lowercase w's and our
phenotypes normal wings in this case
wrinkled wings is our phenotype most of
wrinkled wings is a homozygous recessive
genotype and the dominant is for normal
wings again there's dominant recessive
alleles the two alleles and individual
possesses do not affect one another
again endowment versus recessive Davin's
going to be expressed the excessive will
only be expressed in the homozygous
recessive state devil is represented by
uppercase letters recessive by lowercase
letters is dominant alleles expressed
the phenotype on at least one of those
alleles is present they can be the
heterozygous or the homozygous recessive
is only expressed as a phenotype when
both copies both from both parents are
represented in this case two little arse
therefore the pewdie wrinkled because
it's a recessive trait versus two round
tray
we don't know if this one is almost I
guess dominant or heterozygous we do
know there's at least one allele though
that is in the dominant or round
genes are homologous chromosomes
there's same size the same shape that
carry genes for the same trait but
they're not necessarily identical in
this case here's a heterozygous here
different genes might be located can
just be one from dad one from mom it's Y
or 2n organisms diploid and in this case
we have a lot of homo sinus dominance
has to be the same in this case they're
not identical these chromosomes one
allele from mom one allele from dad each
trait is determined by adherence of
those two alleles the alleles present in
the chromosome are distributed to Kami's
during meiosis this why we have so many
different possibilities because there's
so many different genes that can
recombination in many different ways
doubt recessive inheritance then there's
something called carriers I want to draw
your attention to in our punnett squares
here a carrier would be represented a
heterozygous those be a carrier here
meaning it's not recessive genes not
going to be expressed it's carried its
present there and it may show up in the
offspring it will not show up in that
particular individual some traits of
current arranged as a possibility and I
wanted instance always clear cut and dry
with pea plants though it is pretty
clear cut and dry I color for one in
particular is when it varies a lot so in
the case of how can two people with
brown ions have someone with blue eyes
gets into a little bit of the
complexities of genetics here the odds
are definitely for brown eyes but
because it's a dominant there's many
different traits that can occur creating
genotypes that can represent that same
phenotype those different genotypes can
result in different offspring however
you have two people with blue eyes
because that's a recessive trait the
eyes are very much in the favor of the
offspring to also have blue eyes
recessive traits again that carrier
aspects the presence of an allele does
not ensure the trait will be expressed
individual individual as an example of
recessive trait so here we have two
carriers yes they can produce 25% of
offspring and homozygous dominant but
25% make homozygous recessive the other
50% will be carriers of that particular
trait not expressing it carrying that
recessive allele again recessive does
not necessary mean that autosomal
dominant is one possible way for a trait
or a disorder in some cases to be
inherited as we see here and also down
disease if the abnormal genes inherited
only from one parent disease will be
present so in this case if it's a
dominant disorder or disease it's going
to be expressed even if only one allele
is there the recessive though means an
organism needs two copies of that gene
in order to express that if only one
copy is present expression will not
occur
personally considered a carrier and that
person being a carrier will not be
infected themselves but can still pass
that on to their offspring and if an
offspring of an autosomal recessive
basically combination of alleles
typically the parents are carriers so if
the offspring represents it but the
parents do not the parents are likely to
be carriers hopefully this is helpful in
explaining a little bit about heredity
and genetics