okay so here we're looking at
micronutrients sometimes called trace
elements given by micronutrients are
essential for plant growth but just
needed in small amounts so starting with
the first one here boron represented by
letter B this helps in the use of
nutrients and regulates other nutrients
also an example would be calcium so
calcium and boron levels are often
compared to one another because they can
burn can influence the amount of
availability of calcium it's essential
for seed and fruit development
deficiencies are encouraged if plants
are water stressed in the admit II is
very low also if sole or media calcium
levels are low for X or boric acid are
common sources of boron if you're
looking at supplementing them to your
plants chloride is often considered to
be a soil contaminant levels this is
true Gloria though is needed by plants
it's kind of considered a soil
contaminants it's a negative ion they
kind of influence some of the
availability of some cations but it is
needed at least in these kind of
micronutrient amounts because it's
important to help regulate the stomata
which are areas below the leaves that
help air come in and out and also
regulate water and it helps the plant
balance its interaction with the
environment it's also necessary for the
photosynthetic process to allow that to
function properly so again in these high
amounts not the best thing but is needed
in some amounts by the planet
copper's another one it's required for
many enzymatic activities and plants and
for chlorophyll and seed production all
very vital tasks at the plant most
common cause for a Division sees at pH
imbalance and not a lack of copper in
the media this is again why I stress
that it's important to be monitoring and
knowing what your pH is because this is
one micronutrient particular that can be
drastically affected by swings in pH
when it's they pay a special attention
to the leaves around the buds or tips
from that are turning yellow and lower
parts of the leaves getting a darker
than normal green color this can be
evidence of a copper deficiency that's
of concern for cannabis in particular
because it can stunt blood formation if
you stunt blood formation that's kind of
where all the main driving cannabinoid
production is and if that gets stunted
because of low copper that can really
impact your final harvest
to iron he represented by Effie it's
involving the formation of enzymes and
chlorophyll leaves will yellow if
deficient but will typically be the
upper leaves not the lower ones like
nitrogen or a magnesium deficiency this
is kind of a citrus plant kind of get
the idea that's the upper leaves that
are yellowing iron typically used you
know a lot in greenhouses and for
structural support but it is also a
nutrient it's a common problem with
cocoa cars simply because of some of the
properties of this particular media
manganese again not to being confused
with mag in the magnesium this is
manganese represent by M and punctured
with enzyme systems involved with
breakdown of carbohydrates nitrogen
metabolism and post services see here's
eye fertilizer here Crick's the Frizzle
leaf in palms so commonly a palm tree
fertilizer for whatever reason but it is
manganese is needed by all plants here
molybdenum is needed in such small
amounts it's very unlikely to be the
case of a deficiency in most instances
if growing in purely hydroponic
situation there may be a chance of this
occurring but many fertilizer contains
some level of molybdenum and it's not in
large amounts I have the picture here of
a thimble because it's like to grow an
acre of corn need like a thimble full
amount of melindam for the entire acre
so again when I say small wants very
small amounts well this is what the
actual element looks like the fertilizer
form is not the pure element it'd be in
a molecule complex so last one we look
at here is zinc it's not a common
occurrence in cannabis
but where does occur it can be a major
issue it's not very mobile so you're
likely to find the symptoms show up in
newer growth doesn't really translocate
through the plant very well because of
this give me an issue if you're cloning
a plant since the cutting is taken
towards the end the plant may this zinc
may have a hard time getting there so if
you take a recent clones and they all
turn yellow fairly quickly there's a
chance you could be zinc deficient in
the plant and I mentioned this just
because if you're looking at kind of
feeding the picky mother plants you want
to make sure that they're healthy
if dink is an issue in the media you've
been growing in something to keep in
mind especially if you're looking to
clone that
here you'll be removing that tip and you
want to make sure that it maintains a
nice green coloration so they can absorb
light and produce quality roots and
allow you to have the next generation
so again when it's not a major concern
but we haven't problems with your clones
one you may want to investigate