see here we look at different types of
microscopes there's a couple general
categories that they all fit into and
we're going to investigate some of them
in class we mainly work with one type
but there are different ones for
different purposes like people have
different jobs there's different ones
for different substances a scientist may
want to look at students where you think
they need a microscope to look at their
small tiny grades but in this case we're
gonna be looking mainly at cells and
different sizes so starting with the
first one the compound lights is the one
you're probably most familiar with looks
very similar to this in many cases there
might be some variations depending on
the manufacturer looking at compound
light so there's a light source at the
bottom there's these IQ their lenses
here it's basically using a
magnification with the light these are
focused glass lenses and the image is
really being formed in the back of your
eye as you look through and it's
basically we use Elven images about 500
times better than what the human eye can
see if you were just to look at
something in general there all the parts
are labeled here to here the ocular lens
in particular or the eyepieces of
located up here these are the objective
lenses
down here and those gave different
magnifications when you're looking at
magnification you're actually taking
images or looking at pictures you want
to be sure you're taking into account
the objective lens and also any
magnification that the ocular lens may
add to that sometimes it's a factor of
10 so if this was times 100 you'd be x
my additional 10 I'd be actually a
thousand times more strong and objective
lenses you have to fine focus you have
the course focus the light source to die
for him to allow more or less light
through so you having trouble finding
the slide something on a slide that
looks like it's on there oh you always
want to start at low power and you want
to adjust the light if you put too much
light it may shine right through and
basically make it possible to see the
specimen these are some images taken
with a compound light microscope
these are cheek cells chloroplasts eat
muscle cells here
are really nice to find and here looking
at different cell stages and these are
all taken with a compound light
microscope should be familiar with what
microscope images that they produce
I'm sorry able to identify that okay
getting a little bit more unique
something you may not be familiar with
the transmission electron microscope the
TEM this is allows electrons to pass
through this specimen this is max
mastication is very strong about a
hundred thousand times better than the
human eye very complex very expensive
piece of equipment here and what it's
good reason why it has an electron gun
essentially it's a passing this electron
through the specimen how those images
look ins typically for very small items
such as viruses that the polio virus
looks like taken through a TEM or
transmission electron microscope
smallpox tissue section and it's
bacillus bacterium
all taken with transmission electron
microscopes another type is called
scanning electron s a.m. this is where
the specimens code with a very thin coat
of metal the electron beam is passed
across the specimen it's like a slit
like a scan that occurs anybody copier
machine and it's viewed on a large
screen TV screen again you don't have to
know the complexities of everything here
but again I'm using electrons the key
part here is it's coated with a thin
metal there's one what transmission went
through this is just a scanning of the
actual surface as a result we get some
very detailed very unique images the
pollen grains look like this is the
adhesive on a post-it note let's see if
I always think it's like kind of sticky
and flat this is it actually looks very
zoomed in now because we're scanning and
we're getting bounced back from the
electrons typically images come back as
black and white however through modern
days tools were able to colorize some of
those images to give them a bit more of
a vivid appeal make it easier to spot
certain things for example here the
yellow structures
almost look a little blended in you
might not even notice that they're there
and this black and white image here
they're very vibrant very easy to tell
this is a little bit more complicated
the immunofluorescence light microscope
what this
uses and this is an example of it it's
using antibodies developed against a
specific protein and have a special dye
attached to them
what's happening is the antibodies are
binding to something in particular with
this fluorescent dye allowing it to be
illuminated with an ultraviolet or a
blacklight light source and this allows
mapping indicate in the distribution of
specific proteins within a cell so how
does this look this might be a little
confusing a little bit different than
what you're used to so I think this is a
great summary and these are both kind of
showing very similar the same thing we
have our antigen and we're trying to
identify this little green circle here
so in the first case here with a primary
antibody with the tag on it well
basically we were putting this antibody
in solution we're bouncing around it's
fighting this one little green circle
and it's binding specifically only to
that green circle that boots bound that
only that green circle that is the only
spot this actual floor for this
basically light meaning or substance
will be attached now this allows us to
identify this the secondary
immunofluorescence is kind of very
similar to the first one where we're
still identifying the green circle here
however we're first using a primary
antibody to bind that that and then
we're using our secondary antibody
actually is labeled or tagged to bind to
that antibody so what this allows for is
you can see here multiple bindings here
one one green circle one antibodies
finding my Bruce a weaker signal here
we're allowed our secondary antibody
combined multiple times to that original
or that single primary antibody because
of that we're able to get maybe a
stronger signal so both of these are
accomplishing the same thing we're
identifying a very specific component of
the cell so this shows a good example
antibodies are extremely specific as a
result we can label them to look at
different things so this first image
we're defining this particular DNA and
that's blue here wheezing from green to
enough eye a different structure
and here using red to divide another
structure so when we just add that
single antibody we just get the blue we
just get the green we just get the red
if we combine all those antibodies were
able to now see a better picture of the
cell of where specifically different
components might be located and that's
the power of the immunofluorescence
light microscope image is that we're
able to determine or hash out where
different things might be located based
on their color because we're using
specific antibodies to bind to specific
antigens or specific proteins in certain
cases so um
fair questions on quizzes or tests might
be showing an image and you have to
identify what microscope was used so if
you're playing along in our home game I
have a series of images and the last
site will have the answer so I'm simply
not going to go through and answer the
ends of the questions you can play along
and say what microscope made this image
this is image one what image two looking
at the microscopes that we learned ahead
of time what image looking at this what
microscope may have made this image for
this continuing number three again what
microscope was used here and the last
one before again don't let the colors
fool you as we learned before so I'm
going to colorize an apical eyes look
actually I added two more so another
prime example into the microscopes maybe
used more than once and this is our last
one here won't microscopy this image so
for those looking for the answers played
along in our home game here's our six
answers to the six different images
you'll notice the compound light
microscope was not used in any of these
you're probably very familiar with that
one so I included these but please
realize that the compound light
microscope image is fair game for tests
or quizzes hope this was helpful