you maybe remember wild app talking
about mitochondria and the fact that
they do contain some of their own DNA so
if we're talking about inheritance in
inheriting genes which is DNA we've kind
of touched on the mitochondria we can't
forget about them
well it may not be a large portion of
DNA that we get from mitochondria it is
still a portion and then that must be
taken into consideration so extra
chromosome or mitochondrial inheritance
some genes are actually in the
mitochondria all mitochondrial genes are
transmitted only by the mother meaning
all of the mitochondria that you've
received come from the your mother come
from the female side unusual muscle
disorders and neurological problems have
been linked these particular genes so
this means if the mother's affected all
of the children will be affected if the
father's affected all the children will
be unaffected because you get your
mitochondria from your mother so because
of this if the mother country come from
mom even though you get all your
mitochondria from your mom you may not
always get a mutated mitochondria well
how this is possible kind of involves
the dice here what kind of roll the dice
depends on what percentage of
mitochondria mom hasn't mutated so look
at this is kind of a good summary here
so we have our mitochondria in our
mother the mother with no symptoms but
we have some mutated mitochondria well
the number of mitochondria well some of
those are transferred to the mature egg
so if you're unlucky then you get a high
percentage of the mutated ones we have
up to 80% of mutated mitochondria in the
egg which will result in the offspring
having that percentage or if you're a
little luckier you get half-and-half or
even a little bit more lucky you only
get kind of 20% let mutated and the
sperm contributes no mitochondria only
comes from the mother so child with
severe disease potentially if there's
80% mutated
try to get a mild disease if it's 50%
which I have no disease or very little
signs of disease if only 20% are mutated
so this is how 20% mitochondria for mom
I like
your odds meaning depends on which ones
you get all those 20% you could get some
they're all 100% clean or in this case
you get 80% of the mutated ones so this
is where a luck or unlock the draw comes
into play but all of your mitochondria
good better and different you can blame
your mother for that