in this video as the title suggests I'm
gonna go over mitosis but I'm also gonna
be mentioning interphase and cytokinesis
a good summary slide provided here a
couple more of those will occur
throughout the video presentation so
starting with mitosis it is involved
with cell replication it cells making
more identical copies of cells and
identicals the key word here if we're
not having identical copies we have
mutations good to give it simply the
copy machine we want to produce as close
to the original as possible that way we
can ensure the same functions of
ourselves the cell cycle or two main
components interphase in mitosis so
mitosis is actually the courses of cell
division interphase those a little
slightly different phase there are
subdivisions of interphase those being
the g0 which is just a resting phase g1
is the growth in metabolism s DNA
replication g2 is growth of structural
elements and n is actually the mitosis
phase this gives a little bit of
approximation of time even idea of the
eukaryotic replication cycle that does
occur mitosis here broken dinh these
phases at prophase prometaphase
metaphase anaphase telophase and then
cytokinesis interphase here is that g2
phase is occurring in the interphase is
the stage where living cells are when
they're not dividing it's indicated by
chromosomes not being visible with a
light microscope here is our interface
to the gray region here mitosis is
occurring this darker region
you can see again those terms do one s
and g2 interphase is g1 is referring to
when the cell increases in size s is
again that DNA replication portion in g2
is the mitochondrion other organelles
begin to divide before the cell actually
enters officially mitosis you could see
here mitosis is basically cell division
and there's four main steps plus the
last step of cytokinesis kind of broken
out in different than the four main
steps of mitosis there
Kherson the meristems which are stem
tips or there's a lot of actively
dividing cells and root tips there's a
lot of athlete's dividing cells can
occur to other parts throughout the
plant but these are areas where you're
likely to find a high rate of cell
division Starla's prophase chromosomes
form into chromatids so we have our
chromosomes forming into our sister
chromatids with their replication phase
and ever going into mitosis where we're
basically separating those out to form
two identical cells this shows a little
bit an example here our sister
chromatids located in the nucleus
prophase chromatin condenses into
chromosomes the nucleolus disappears so
nuclear envelope fragments and nucleolus
disintegrates remember the nucleolus
from our organelles is where the our RNA
is made we're looking at that nuclear
envelope and loping into fragment
chromatids are condensing making them
more visible prophase our polar
microtubules shown in green kind of in
this image here are strands that
established a matrix around the
currently intact nucleus this will break
down and we'll fragment but right now
it's still intact what we're seeing this
webbing being I'm starting to occur the
condensing chromosomes are in blue here
the red dots kind of pinkish dots we see
here are the centromeres and that's
involved with DNA Pro metaphase is kind
of in-between prophase in metaphase so
we have our spindle fibers anchoring at
the poles goes here and here the nuclear
membrane fully breaks down and our could
be the core microtubules invade the
nuclear space these Kaneda cores are now
starting to attach to the chromosomes
and are starting to get some level of
organization now that the nucleus is
broken down we see a little bit the
change here I'm prometaphase the nuclear
membrane has just basically broken apart
the microtubules quickly interact with
the heater cores which assemble the
centromeres to condense
chromosomes so what's this mean well
because our nucleus is breaking apart
we now need these fibers to grab on to
these chromosomes to be able to hold on
to them and get them in alignment as
we're going through the process of cell
division metaphase here chromosomes line
up along the metaphase plate now we call
the metaphase plate on lining up on the
equator that we have on the globe here
but remember this is an imaginary plane
both on the globe and also in the cell
there's no true plate that they're all
kind of lining up and pressing on
it's just lining up in that middle and
imaginary kind of line but they do form
this line just like the equator on the
globe metaphase spindle favell's
attached to the centromeres is right
here centromere is that red region and
that's kind of where these two join
together and that is a point of
attachment that will then allow these
two then be separated and broken apart
to form the two identical cells we kind
of see that forming here middle
fluorescence microscope will tip this
image our centromeres have moved to the
poles in the cell have established any
of the metallic spindle the chromosomes
have condensed anna metaphase plate kind
of see a little bit of a line up here in
that central imaginary region Anna fades
this is the shortest time to complete of
all the phases centrioles are broken
apart the two sister chromatids into
debtor chromosomes basically we see that
we're all initially lined up on the
plate and now they're being broken apart
and pulled to the poles here
this happens in unison you can see
they're all kind of in alignment it
happens in the least amount of time is
any of the phases of mitosis anaphase
the chromosomes break at the centromeres
and sister chromatids move to opposite
ends of the cell again those daughter
chromosomes are then moving towards the
poles remember this all happened
basically at the same time in unison
anaphase could see that example here I
get the idea that pulling here are
kinetochore microtubules are pulling the
two sets towards the poles here this is
creating two halves and dividing cell
further apart
well the chromosomes are condemned
it's either centromeres here there's
little red regions telophase and
cytokinesis is where the nuclear
membrane reforms in La reappear
chromosomes unwind into chromatin myosin
one and a pin filament rings and check
to cleave the cell into two that Cluj
furs were in that contracting ring is
where the cells basically starting to
kind of pinch where it's ultimately in a
brick part there so - telophase due to a
phase is reverse reversal prophase and
from benefits events thus completing the
cell cycle and you can see that here
we're now even visually seen basically
two separate and distinct cells that
mitosis phase could be that again that
kind of refresher of what interphase is
you could see the DNA is very hard to
see it's very thin here we're condensing
it down then you need to envelope is
starting to kind of break down a little
bit
metaphase is very distinctive if they
land on the plate
anaphase very quick time words are
separating out and here until the phase
we're starting at that cleavage furrow
so I don't get that pinch point in the
middle action path because there's five
main events occurring in Tooele phase so
well like they simplify it the hair
they're actually five things going on
during this one pays the daughter
chromosomes are becoming surrounding a
nuclear envelope see that here we're
starting to form that protective nucleus
over the DNA structure also during
telophase daughter chromosomes become
longer and thinner and become invisible
become invisible because they're
becoming from my condensed state to a
very relaxed state the reason why
they're getting into a relaxed state is
it makes it easier for DNA replication
of certain genes that may be needed by
the cell if everything was all condensed
and pack together be really hard to get
it DNA so that's why it becomes
invisible because it's becoming thinner
it's becoming more single-stranded and
it is a dense coil during telophase also
nucleoli become visible again a little
hard to see here it's the kind of the
nucleus within the nucleus and it's that
typically a little darker region very
evident in this cell here also
many of the spindle fibers beginning to
break apart they were needed for
separating out the chromosomes here but
they're starting to disintegrate and
basically fall apart because they're no
longer needed at this particular phase
lastly for talking about plant cells the
cell plate will form this is only for a
plant cell because they have a cell wall
so we're getting into that cell plate or
that cell wall that's forming and that's
kind of what it looks like in a real
life cell that is the cell plate and
that's ultimately a joint appearing form
a cell wall between these two newly
formed identical cells cytokinesis is
the actual separation to two independent
cells here it's very end of the mitotic
phase it's actually considered its own
separate phase that's when the two cells
actually are separating out completely
this is a very simple summary so
hopefully you can follow along with this
here with some of the what's going on in
the different phases interphase early
prophase late prophase metaphase is very
distinctive with them all being lined up
on the plate and then anaphase we have
here and in telophase this would be
followed by cytokinesis you're looking
for a wonderful summary slide of
everything this is the entire process
here with nice bullet points for each
also gives a wonderful images of the
cell how it looks with the stain and die
here of the immunofluorescence
microscope to get you an idea of how it
looks on a cartoon image showing the
things in detail gives you those
descriptions and in the real world image
with the bar here indicating the same
size for each so great slide to review
from tester quizzes
another review slide the cell cycle here
it specifically points out animal cells
because it won't have that cell plate
forming inside a thesis just another way
to kind of review and make sure
understanding and knowing all of the
steps here's a slide here showing cells
actively growing in a root tip wears a
lot of mitosis going on
I could easily point to one of these you
should be able to identify what stages
is based on digital observations so
let's go through some of that remember
in the description there
a link to all these slides and he had
the answers you're welcome to pause them
all I'm gonna run through these slides
here and go over the answers so this is
the first one linked to the second one
Oh Ted is put into two different cells
here the third one in two different
cells and again this is in a plant cell
the fourth one what phase of mitosis are
these two it so if you want to pause and
go back or look at the description for
the links to the slides you can look at
those more now we get to the answers so
the first one was metaphase gainer all
kind of lined up on that plate may not
be 100% perfect but we do see a
distinctive line form interphase in
anaphase here they're not lined up on
the plate they're getting pulled apart
and see that and interphase we see the
distinct nucleus and nucleolus prophase
we're starting to do that condensing and
anaphase again being pulled apart a
little bit more distant here Teela phase
for seeing that cell plate kind of
starting to form a little bit to cells
almost complete with their division
process and then prophase here we're
seeing the DNA being condensed here link
to some videos that might be helpful and
looking at the descriptions here and
you're also welcome to go back and
review the sides here thank you