so in this debaco university video i'm
going to look at monitoring systems for
indoor cannabis production
we talk about monitoring systems there's
a lot of things to monitor in an indoor
cannabis production
area we're going to focus more on the
growing environment
and not necessarily the security of the
site but i'm sure you'll find this
information
useful
[Music]
all right let's look at some of the
monitoring systems for an indoor canvas
production environmental area
so first off data is important so you do
not want to estimate conditions having
some
form of monitoring and or ideally
documenting conditions
is important there are many options to
consider when it comes to monitoring but
two main categories involve
digital data collection and analog
sensors some growers will use the
digital systems as their primary while
still having an analog as a backup or a
fail safe
because there's some benefits to both
systems which we're going to discuss
here
so first off the digital and that's
probably what most growers might be most
familiar with
and the advantage is why is it so
popular well because it offers precise
readouts
can be preset with minimums and maximums
for levels of alarms
it's also very easy to read it's very
easy for a multitude of workers coming
through an area to be able to read the
data
collect that data and be very precise
about that inconsistent
however the disadvantages of that
digital monitoring system is it can fail
unexpectedly
more than just the batteries running out
of a ph meter it can provide sometimes
too much information or just get lost in
the data
and often digital monitoring systems are
more expensive than their analog
counterparts
so some of the advantages though to an
analog system is that it's very
simplified mechanics they can last for a
very long period of time
they're also reliable and less prone to
failure keep in mind in growing space to
be high humidity high heat
the analogs tend to be a little more
resilient to some of those
overall analog monitoring systems are
less expensive
compared to the digital monitoring
systems so why aren't analogs always
used the disadvantages
require manual readings and
documentation so has to go through and
write down those numbers
they may not provide exact conditions if
someone may look at that and kind of
like determine oh is that
54 55 you know what am i looking at oh
it's 53 53 and a half two and a quarter
may not be precise as some may want to
be
they also may need calibration to ensure
that they're operating properly
so as a reason these is again some pros
and cons to each as i said analogues can
be used as back up to the digital ones
but make a decision on which one would
you want to have
in your grow space