now with any growing setup you want to
be able to monitor your conditions you
want to be monitoring your condition
there's a variety of ways you can do
that but keep in mind that when you're
monitoring conditions you'll also be a
lis concerned with the unit's that
you're using be familiar with the unit's
you're using while you're using them and
what they tell you what the expected
range is for the given unit so we're
gonna go over some common ones here EC
TDS CF and ppm this is EC referring to
electrical connectivity total dissolved
solids conductive factor in parts per
million some of these are
interchangeable terms like from inches
to centimeters so be again mindful of
what you're using and what it measures
so if a monitor or an example of one is
called a bluelab guardian monitor and
this is an easy monitor to look at three
critical conditions all at once it's
very useful for hydroponics and for
those using easy cloners you can see the
connectivity you can switch between in
parts-per-million as this is set here I
can also go to TDS or EC or CF because
those are interchangeable terms
temperature you can measure in
Fahrenheit and Celsius and pH is a nice
six point five here so these nutrient
concentrations is that's basically what
we're going to be keeping an eye on in
monitoring our nutrients or salts which
can be measured based on the ability to
conduct electricity through a solution
the higher the concentration the more
conductivity they'll more diluted the
less conductivity so starting with
electrical conductivity EC pure water
such as reverse osmosis as an EC of zero
however the mineral ions added the more
readily the water will conduct that's
again kind of sending a pulse to the
electricity through to see what how
quickly it passes through the solution
the sieve your nutrient solution is
fairly reliable measure and how much
general nutrients are dissolved in your
water
ec is the most widely accepted
measurement for the strength of nutrient
solutions and is the standard in Europe
in many other parts of the world but
typically for whatever reason North
America tends to like TDS total
dissolved solids but there's a couple
more issues with that one when compared
to EC the total dissolved solids I think
it's easy to understand at least the
initial name it's the amount of solids
dissolved
solution ETS qualifies the concentration
of these diluted salads in a given
aqueous solution the problem though with
TDS is that accurately measuring the
nutrient solution you really need to
evaporate all the liquid and measure the
residue which kind of goes against
having a nutrient solution in the first
place there's also conversion factors
and it can get messy
so even though this is typically widely
used by a lot of growers may not
necessarily be the best CF or condone
factor is basically the same as EC
because it tells you the exact same then
it's how stronger or how concentrated
your feed solution is then they both
measure the rate of electrical
connectivity in your solution the higher
the mineral content higher the
conductivity rating so that's why if you
notice back on the lat I'm the blue lab
Guardian EC / CF it's that easy / CF
it's easy or CF both kind of
interchangeable terms in this case
lastly we have parts-per-million and
press vermilion is referring the
concentration of solution or minerals in
the water to put parts per million to
perspective a 1% solution or one out of
100 solution is the same solution
containing 10,000 parts per million so
we had 1 out of 100 is the same as
10,000 out of a million kind of it's
here 1 million black dots or pixels each
tile with white or gray background
contains a thousand dots it's going to
be the concept or the idea of exactly
what a million may look like