here we're going to go over the
difference between monocots and dicots
pictured here I have a represented of
each of these two categories monocots
are here they look like grasses or small
corn plants and dicots here is
represented by the bean plant
specifically what monocot and dicot is
referring to are short for us and say is
cotyledons
so monocotyledons or dicotyledons and
cotyledons is translated into meaning
seed leaves so an interest perm see and
the sperm is fully used but by the time
the seeds mature food reserves are
stored by the embryo and swollen fleshy
leaves called these cotyledons or see
leaves dicots have two cotyledons an
example this would be squash and that's
just the seedling I have represented
here and over here I have monocots and
these have one cuddly and these are corn
plants they look like grasses they come
up with that one single blade where
dicots have basically two seed leaves
when they emerge now there's many
differences between the models and
dicots more than just their seed leaves
there's differences in the number of
seed leaves as I mentioned but there's
also differences within those leaves of
the way that the veins are organized for
monocots are looking at parallel veins
dicots looking at broad leaf network of
veins the vascular bundles are more
scattered in monocots and there's more
of a distinctive ring in dicots and the
flower parts are in multiples of 3 for
monocots and multiples of 5 or sometimes
4 in monocots also the root system is
very different in monocots it's more
fibrous and in dicots it's more of a tap
root system now I'll have some of these
same comparisons throughout this
presentation good to try to learn the
differences or distinguishing factors
between these two and here's another
representative image you see the
monocots here the die-cuts here showing
the leaf venation
the number of multiples in their flower
the root type when we look at the
microscope it microscopic images we're
looking at the scattered that's their
bundles and monocots a little more
organized in a ring structure for dicots
and of course once you leave verses 2
bringing some of the real world images
could see again how those leaves may
look dicots can be much more varied
shows in the microscopic image of the
scattered vascular bundles indicative of
monocots in the distinctive rings that
are evident for dicots and the floral
parts that might be four or five
multiples for dicots or typically three
cuts that stem that I was talking about
the kind of organized in the ring here
is the dicot this is what I mean by
scattered see the other it might be a
little bit more concentration to the
perimeter here but overall relatively
scattered throughout this tab bringing
that to a real-world root comparison now
the dicots here of this kind of central
key portion kind of almost looks like a
tee or an X and monocots have this kind
of internal ring structure to their root
system remember the monocots can be more
fibrous and the dicots can be more of a
central tap root system bring that to
the larger scale which I might be more
familiar with here's a dicot stem I
should say root system here and it's
kind of that one central tap root the in
lines are a prime example of this you
ever tried to pull roots up from a grass
species or pull it up the grass in the
lawn
then those it's much more fibrous root
system a lot more intertwined here
above-ground the monocots will click
those single blades and those dicots
have that kind of broad leaf appearance
here and the different de nations in the
game then in alliance and example the
daikon and grass species are examples of
monocots zooming in a little bit more
comparing the leaves and it'll be other
videos to help explain a little bit more
about the leaves monocots that parallel
venation
you could see dicots a little bit more
complex network of veins and blue the
same image here but bringing in now the
seedlings as we can see the monocots are
that single kind of blade that comes up
and dicots
are those two seed leaves that emerge
and this could be a pea plant this could
be I could say the squash plant
watermelon many many different things
fall into these categories this is an
engine concept if you've ever seen this
roundup for lawns kills weeds would not
belong so just what we learned about
here with monocots and dicots without
getting into the specifics of the
chemistry that works in this particular
brand of herbicide this is targeting the
dicots so it says kill the weeds most of
the weed species such as dandelions in
this case clovers viewed as a weed as an
example of dicots so this chemistry is
working on something specific to dicots
where it says not my lawn the lawn is a
monocot certain chemistry's certain
plant behaviors are not going to be
evident in monocots and this particular
chemical will only attack dicots
so that's how you can apply this to the
lawn and will kill the weeds but not the
lawn