okay a term commonly used in the
cannabis industry is concept of mother
plants these plants are also considered
stock plants and there are plants that
are unique genetics that are going to be
the source of many offspring in the
sense of many clones and that's why
they're called the mother plants so the
mother room is where these plants will
be kept so mother plants is one that we
used to generate many clones this can be
referred to as a stock plant since it is
the main source of propagation material
for future plans and typically around
two months old so they're kind of that
one plant and going to have all these
identical offspring that are going to
come from that one stock plant they want
to ensure that the mother plants in good
health and has desired traits it's
critical for the success of any grow
operation any female plant that can
become a mother plant and the original
plant material can be a seed or a clone
so you want to make sure they're in peak
of health want to make sure they're
getting all the nutrients that they need
now over fed now under fed and proper
moisture conditions they're not going
under any biotic or abiotic stresses
maximize a cannabinoid production for
example a six-month-old plant will
produce more cannabinoids in a
one-month-old plant and one-month-old
clone can actually behave more like a
four-month-old plant and can be
encouraged to flower in a shorter
interval by photo period adjustment so
this can also help maximize production
if we're looking especially at a large
scale operation where days and weeks
difference can make a large end product
difference so reducing that time as much
as possible through the use of mother
plants and clones is one way to
accomplish that to maintain that mother
plant the goal is to keep the mother
plant in a vegetative phase with just
enough nitrogen to allow for ease
including process and then by a short
duration to route if you overfeed them
with nitrogen the time to root will be
greatly increased and that can offset
schedules and also make a difficult
following process with a weak root
system this is why you want to keep them
healthy and properly fed but not overly
fed