you ever wonder what conditions you
should keep your mother or stock
cannabis plants in
well here we're going to go over the
details on how to maximize
uh the conditions for your mother or
stock plant here on debaco
[Music]
university
all right let's get into the ideal
conditions for your mother or stock
cannabis plant
so first off the goals keep the material
healthy and this is paramount
you're not necessarily looking for yield
instead the goal is to produce plant
biomass in a form
of active shoot tips if you're looking
at cloning that mother or stock plant
and keeping them healthy is very
important a growing plant is good but
the real goal of a stock plant is to be
a source of more plant material
so as a result we do some things
slightly different than we would in the
vegetative
growing phase now while the vegetative
environment in general is a good
representation
of what you should have for a stock or
mother plant i'm going to make some
slight tweaks to those general
recommendations
so what do those slight adjustments look
like well i've provided them here in an
organized list
first off we want approximately an
18-hour photo period want to make sure
we're keeping that plant in the
vegetative state
the temperature for day night should be
maintained was around that 70 or 20
degrees celsius
and keeping that relatively warm
conditions but not excessively
hot conditions relative humidity around
that 63 percent is advised
to help keep the chance for disease down
and help reduce water stress on the
plant
now if you're growing that mother stock
plant it's carbon accident
enrichment can be at a concentration
level of about 650 parts per million
a lot of growers will look at that and
say well why even add carbon dioxide at
all
you don't necessarily have to or why
don't you bump that up to like a
thousand or eleven hundred parts per
million
well keep in mind we're looking at
growing the plant but we're not looking
at necessarily
speed growing the plant per say you
could always increase that to help
increase you know biomass and yield a
little bit but remember our goal here
is really to produce more actively
growing shoot tips to produce more
asexual
vegetative propagation points mother
plants typically grown in five to ten
plus gallon containers i've seen some in
very large containers
and that depends on the grower's area or
the age that they want to keep that
plant
stock plants of about 10 months old
should have between 20 and 25 nodes on
their main stem just to give you kind of
a general kind of target there
if you have a 10 month old plant
approximately how big it should be if
not you might want to look at your
conditions to see if they match these
and see if you want to make any
adjustments to those conditions to keep
the mother and stock plant in
so not only do you have a healthy plant
a plant that will produce many
clones but this can help improve the
efficiency of your operation overall