okay this is gonna go over muscle fiber
contraction and relaxation so we have a
contraction is what's going on here
we're bringing all our muscles together
and relaxation is kind of the opposite
effect of that now while this is gonna
focus on what happens for the muscle
fiber they're gonna be if you haven't
had exposure a little bit of an
introductory to the nervous system and
how neurons interact so I'm going to go
through this process and I'm gonna kind
of build on the images here so you're
welcome to pause the video and read
what's here I'm gonna try to help
explain this so starting with a muscle
fiber contraction sequence it's a series
of steps here looking at step one here
the neurotransmitter ACH which is
acetylcholine is released from the axon
terminal binds to receptors on the
sarcolemma
now what's going on here so our axon
which is our nervous system is releasing
a neurotransmitter and it's binding so
keep in mind our proteins it be very
specific binding that's occurring and
that's what what's worth noticing here
you may remember if you can err system
before this gap here is called a synapse
so we have our neurotransmitter being
released and binding here so as see the
Cullens being released and binding to
the receptors here since so far this is
what's occurring building on from that
the action potential is generated and
travels down the t-tubule so this
binding that occurs is now during an
action potential and it's traveling
along this structure called a t2 beulah
so again here's our axon we're going
through we're releasing our
neurotransmitter binding to the proteins
here and now this signal this action
potential signal is being transmitted to
a structure called the t-tubule
calcium ions now are very important in
this process so calcium ions here are
released from storage in the
sarcoplasmic reticulum predated sr in
response to the change in voltage so we
said that action potential comes here
down the t-tubule
well now that we have that voltage
change calcium is being
the calcium is typically related with
this +2 charge that's the charge that it
takes on and that's being released here
we see the same thing going on in this
image where we have the binding of the
neurotransmitter we have the change in
voltage and now we have a release of
calcium so the calcium binds to troponin
this cross bridge is formed between
actin and myosin resulting in a muscle
contraction so here's our actin thin
filaments and here's our myosin as long
as calcium ions remain in the sarcoplasm
to bind to troponin as long as ATP is
available long as these two conditions
in do exist the muscle fiber will
continue to shorten and what that is is
that slight filament we have our muscle
contracting a muscle can stop
contracting though when it either runs
out of ATP and/or becomes fatigued now
the video on the sliding filament theory
which we'll go over some more of this in
greater detail but that calcium ion
release we notice that release is
causing the sarcoplasm to bind to
troponin as ATP is available our muscle
fiber will go from this stage and it
will shorten to the sliding filaments
and it will result in this on the shape
here cause a contraction to occur now
keep in mind that was contraction let's
look at the relaxation phase this acetyl
co cool Lister race sorry
acetylcholinesterase hthe
is a protein and it removes
acetylcholine from the synaptic cleft
this is kind of like the opposite here
here's our acetylcholine little red dots
and here's our acetyl choline histories
a cynical Lin histories is the protein
represented by the blue molecule here
what's happening is that's binding
that's removing the see the coin from
the synaptic cleft that removal of that
is stopping this signal from occurring
calcium ions are transported back into
the sarcoplasmic reticulum
no sir returning back here to be stored
because they're no longer having the
voltage change down the t-tubule so
they're going back lastly triple myosin
binds
binds to active sites on the actin
causing the cross bridge to detach so
you notice we now have a lath of a cross
bridge because they have a lack of
calcium which is because of our binding
up of acetylcholine so this is kind of
the opposite effect here and this is
that relaxation phase very different
than the contraction phase so I know
this does involve a little bit of
neurotransmitters and a little bit
introduction to the nervous system but
it is very important when we're looking
at the contraction of muscles how they
recommend you watch my sliding filament
theory video lecture also to understand
a little bit more about what's going on
with the contraction process