okay here I'm going to provide a brief
overview of the muscular system paying
particular attention to these different
types of muscle tissue and also the
sliding filament theory in a general
sense so first off muscle tissue lets
the body move well distinguishing
characteristics of muscle cells is the
abundance of contractile protein fibers
these are called microfilaments that are
made up of actin and myosin when a
muscle contracts and we pull in our
muscles what's happening is that actin
and myosin are sliding past one another
and this is that part of the sliding
filament theory there's three different
kinds of muscle cells
there's skeletal smooth and cardiac
skeletal is we call striated tubular
multinucleated fibers and they're
typically attached to the skeleton
examples would be the bicep and they are
voluntary muscles mean we have control
over them we can choose when to move
them and those are our skeletal muscles
smooth muscle is a spindle shaped non
striated unicellular fibers each fabric
contains only one cell and one nucleus
it's found in the walls of internal
organs such as your intestines and this
is involuntary mean this moves on its
own without conscious control last part
here is cardiac and striated branched
Union occluded fibers and found in the
walls of the heart and involuntary
cardiac winning of heart this is a
zoomed in view of how each of them look
this is what they would look like a
skeletal muscle on a microscope slide
and this kind of gives you a cartoon
kind of rendition of how that looks
highlighting some of the certain
features here's smooth muscle here's a
zoomed in version with that and then
cardiac being able to distinguish the
characteristics of all three and also
visually identify them would be advised
now I'm gonna go over a little a detail
of each of them and I have a video that
goes into each and even more detail so
first off skeletal muscle the quick
summary well they're long to their cells
with striations do these kind of lines
here number three here corresponds with
they're multi multiple nuclei meaning
there's multiple nuclei per cell here
the nuclei are embedded in the cell
membrane notice where they're located
and this is so they're just inside the
cell this type of tissue occurs in the
muscles that are attached to the
skeleton and skeletal muscles function
and voluntary movements of the body they
say their skeletal muscles are attached
to our skeleton the ones that were
choosing to control here another type is
smooth muscle their spindle shapes we
notice a definite shape change each cell
has a single nucleus and there are no
striations so see how they appear to be
smooth those striations those lines we
saw in the skeletal muscle are not
present here in the smooth muscle smooth
muscle acts and voluntary and
assumptions in the movement of
substances and illumines they are
primarily found in blood vessels walls
and walls of the digestive tract areas
that we don't consciously think about
moving what they move on their own and
they contract on their own in an
involuntary basis cardiac muscle these
branch off from each other rather than
remaining along each like the other
cells and the skeletal and smooth muscle
tissues they have striations as you see
here as we also saw in the skeletal
muscle there are junctions between
adjacent cells
that's this area's here each cell has a
single nucleus another characteristic of
cardiac muscles here striations single
nucleus in these connections this type
of tissue occurs in the walls of the
heart and the primary function is for
pumping blood this is also it in
voluntary action we don't think about
our heart beating we just can kind of
feel it the sliding filament model of
contraction again I have another video
it goes into this in more detail but
this is the basic overview here during
contractions myosin ratchets along actin
filaments compressing the I and H bands
what does that mean we have all these
bands and these lines and it's thick and
thin filaments well kind of you want to
think about is what's happening is we
have our filaments now neither of them
are thick or thin filaments are actin
our myosin are changing what's happening
is they're sliding so when we have a
contraction we're having
sliding the Z lines you think of my
areas here being Z lines they're being
pulled closer to one another and that's
what's happening here
during stretching this tension is
released in the IH bands expand so we
see here our relaxed phase it's our
muscle in the most relaxed phase you can
think about it like this where it's very
far as very too spaced out quite a bit
then in our contracted phase what
happens is they slide past one another
and they pull closer and that's our
contracted phase the AVN remains
constant throughout the length of the
myosin filaments does not change so if
you notice we compare our relaxed in our
contracted model we notice that the
length of the athlete didn't change the
length of the myosin didn't change but
the space between them our H band here
shrunk up considerably and that is
because we have those things sliding
together so we have our thick filaments
and our thin filaments again the thick
filaments correspond with myosin and our
thin films correspond with actin this is
how it would look in the real world here
and this kind of gives you a little bit
better of a picture of what's going on
this h zone here as it's being reduced
compressed when we have these two
filaments sliding against one another
hopefull is it's helpful and we view it
a little bit for this sliding filament
model contraction in a basic overview of
the muscular tissue types