this debaco university video will be
explaining the basics of muscles we'll
get into some of the slight into the
details but hopefully give you a good
overview of understanding
[Music]
all right let's get into muscle basics
explained here well first off why do we
see striations in our skeletal muscles
well this is because the microfibrils
are densely packed in their rod-like
contractile elements called myocytes you
can see that kind of right here in the
image they make up most of the muscle
volume and myofibrils are perfectly
aligned within the fiber they do create
this repeating series of a bands and i
bands so this i band is a way to
remember it light
i is in light so you have that i for the
i bands and then the dark or the a bands
right here so dark has the letter a in
its second letter and that's
can help you remember that dark a bands
light i bands on there
so sarcomere is in this banding pattern
well there's thin filaments that don't
overlap the thick filaments in the
lighter h zone
the m lines appear darker due to the
presence of the protein desmond the
smallest contractile unit of the muscle
is a sarcomere as we can see right here
the region of the myofibril between the
two successive z discs
so we have a z line here and a z line
right here that is your sarcomere right
in that defined region the regular
organization of these sarcomeres gives
skeletal and cardiac muscles their
distinctive striated appearance remember
smooth muscle does not have these
striations and these are composed of
myofibrils made up of the contractile
proteins the fibrins are the two types
there's thick myosin and those thin
actin filaments
now sarcomere is sliding filament theory
so there will be another video on that
specifically but during contraction
medicine ratchets along the actin
myo filaments compressing the eye in the
h bands so i think of it is basically
there's a sliding that's occurring if
you have your fingers here and you're
sliding even though we have a thick and
thin filament we have this sliding
that's how you get the term sliding
filament theory the ab hand remains
consistent throughout as the length of
the myosin myofibrils does not change
we're having this if you can kind of see
here the h band is very spread out here
and here it is contracted because we've
slid over there more information on the
sliding filament theory video
so this myofibrils this banding pattern
that we see those thick filaments extend
the entire length of the a band whereas
the thin filaments extend across the i
band and part way into that a band
region you can see that right here the z
disc are queen-shaped sheets of proteins
basic connections anchor the thin
filaments and connects the myofibrils to
one another you need an anchoring point
because you're going to be pulling
things together so that anchoring point
so it's allowing that to go through and
contract
now if you've heard of tendons and
ligaments and use those interchangeable
terms that's in misnomer because
technically a tendon is a flexible but
an elastic cord of strong fibrous
collagen fiber attaching muscle directly
to bone
so tendon is muscle to bone
in contrast that a ligament is a short
range of touch flexible fibrous
connective tissue that connects two
bones or two cartilages together and
holds together a joint so we have heard
the acl well that l portion is referring
to the ligament because that is
physically linking those two bones
together where a tendon is going to
attach that muscle in this case the
hamstring here to the bone region
so how do muscles work in a very basic
sense well skeletal muscles are attached
to bones by straps of connective tissue
again called as tenants i mentioned
bones pivot about the flexible joints
pulled back and forth
by attached muscles keep in mind an
important point is that muscles can only
pull never push they can only pull
things together they don't push in the
other direction antennas allow for the
movement in the opposite direction so
whichever a muscle or group of muscles
does another muscle or group of muscles
undoes this so if one is pulling in one
way you're going to have another group
that's going to pull in the opposite
direction because the other side muscles
will relax causing that joint to be able
to
rotate amongst that fulcrum
so how do muscles work we need a point
of origin and we need a point of
insertion so origin is the muscles the
end attached to antenna by a stationary
bone it's in a fixed position that
origin the insertion is the end it's
attached to the bone that moves during
the muscle contraction so if we're using
my arm as an example this would be your
you know origin up here the insertion
will be down at the elbow joint here
because that would be allowing those
bones to move
now antagonists as i mentioned before
muscles in a movable joints are attached
in opposing pairs it's the antagonist
flexor retracts the limb and extenders
will extend the limb so if we look kind
of right here we have our movement here
flexors are retracting the limb pulling
pulling this up in this direction
extenders are extending that limb and we
see that here with the hamstring
compared to the quadriceps so having the
kicking motion here like for soccer
flexors are the hamstring pulling the
leg
back and then the extenders or
quadriceps would be extending that
forward allowing the individual to kick
the ball
now two types of muscle contraction or
two main categories i should say we have
the isotonic which is the muscle
shortens
thus moving bones you know the isometric
which is muscles that not shorten but
exerts a force so think of this if you
had a pail of water if you're picking up
that pail of water and lifting it up
well that muscle is shortening there
we're lifting that three kilogram weight
isometric as if we just kind of hung our
arms straight and we have stood up and
our mouth and our arms were still
straight but we're still exerting a
force to support the weight of that
bucket of water in this case the six
kilogram weight
so normal versus atrophy muscles if you
sadly have any add any accident and put
you know an arm in a cast or a leg in a
cast that can lead to an atrophied
muscle and that's muscle mass that's
reduced
simply because of not being used or
disused although atrophy due to disuse
can often be reversed with exercise and
physical therapy
muscle atrophy with age referred to as
sarcopenia is irreversible so as you get
older your muscles overall will simply
atrophy as a product of age
so muscle metabolism energy for a
contraction here respiration is release
of energy from sugar to make atp
remember there are two pathways
aerobic uh and anaerobic so anaerobic is
without oxygen aerobic requires oxygen
aerobic is preferred because there's a
great much greater amount of atp
adenosine triphosphate that's generated
however when you work out when oxygen
gets low aggressive workout you're going
through your body will generate lactic
acid fermentation pathway would be
favored to generate some atp however
keep in mind that when your body does
use atp protons hydrogen ions are
produced resulting in an acidic
environment it's an acidic environment
that causes your muscles to burn lactic
acid is slowly converted to pyruvate in
the in the liver so you'll have that
breakdown process but that burning
muscle feeling is really not directly a
derivative of lactic acid but it is a
derivative of the simple acid form there
other videos on this channel on lactic
acid fermentation more detailed but that
burning feeling is really just protons
that acidic feeling not because directly
because of lactic acid
if you ever had your eye kind of
twitches a little bit here where we kind
of get that little twitchiness of the
eye this can be cause of stress limited
sleep or high caffeine consumption
probably might be uh factors
contributing to you while you're
watching this particular video
uh at thanksgiving if you want to have
good uh table conversation you might
notice there's white meat and dark meat
looking our chickens and turkeys
uh we're looking at this
myoglobin which is muscle hemoglobin so
white meat is fast twitch muscle fiber
short energy burst
but it does tire quickly it does have
lower fat content but slightly higher
protein content this would be the turkey
breast if you're looking at the bird
dark meat if you prefer dark meat that's
your slow twitch muscle it can work for
very long periods of time it does have
high oxygen requirement and therefore a
high myoglobin content higher fat
content but is also mono and
polyunsaturated fats slightly higher
cholesterol this would be found in the
turkey legs wings or thighs so if you're
having that thanksgiving conversation
remember white meat would be the breast
of the turkey and that's going to be
your fast twitch muscle short burst of
energy for the um turkey dark meat if
you prefer that was your slower twitch
muscle for the turkey and that's going
to be the legs wings and thighs
if you have an interest there hopefully
this provides you a very basic overview
of muscles and develops a greater
understanding