okay here we're going to look at naming
and identifying some muscles and I
thought this was a very appropriate
image to put as the title slide so going
on in naming of skeletal muscles will do
some important factors that go into the
naming process is not just our random
name the location of the muscle the bone
or body region associate with that
muscle can affect the name the shape of
the muscle can be part of the reason
where it gets its name
for example the deltoid muscle deltoid
means triangles it's a triangular shaped
muscle the relative size whether it's
maximus being large minimus being small
or long as being long direction of the
fibers rectus or fibers that run
straight transverse and oblique fibers
that run in angles the number of origins
biceps has two origins triceps have
three origins location of attachments
it's named according to the point of
origin or insertion and also the action
of flexor or extender as they named the
muscles that flex are extend
respectively in addition to how these
muscles get their name well a lot of
it's derived from the Latin so we could
look at our Latin roots and be able to
derive the meaning muscle that moves
things away so this is what I want to
highlight an abductor moves muscles away
so if you remember from the other
lectures that I did or we talked about
angles and movement abductor moves
things away in contrast that adaptor is
a muscle that moves towards typically
towards the midline and these are just
some examples here that you're welcome
to look at and comparing these two that
may sound initially very similar how
they differ and how they're Latin Brut
can help describe the motion that they
did not the overview of muscles I tried
to highlight some in green that I'm
going to have you responsible for
doesn't mean the others are any less
important just trying to provide with a
little direction as far as what to
expect potentially and one of my quizzes
we have our deltoids here remember
that's a triangle-shaped triceps we're
three points of origin who is maximus
big muscles just able to
go through and identify some of these
key muscles here adductors how did those
move you can see all the other ones that
for right now I'm leaving out as far as
knowing for identification quiz
sphincter is one I do want you to be
able to recognize it's a little hard to
show it's an internal muscle it's
actually a ring of muscles surrounding
and serving the to guard or closing
opening of a tube such as the openings
on the stomach this is our lower
esophageal sphincter and this is what's
sealing opposites close version is as
it's opened version here it's open as we
want food to pass into the stomach but
it's closed we don't want the stomach
acid to get into our esophagus if you've
suffered from heartburn you may having
improperly closing esophageal sphincter
that's could lead acid to getting into
the esophagus creating that burning
sensation muscles that create facial
expression this occipital front Alice
there's a one right in the front here
you can see how it kind of relates to
some of the names of the bones so again
excuse many more that create facial
expressions is hiding that one here keep
in mind the terms anterior and lateral
don't go away and that helps us be able
to determine the view of the angle that
we're getting on these images muscles of
the eye now I didn't highlight any of
these particular but I want you to be it
or realize again lateral versus medial
what's that superior going up inferior
going down medial going towards the
middle region this is the right eye in
the anterior view versus the right the
right I hear what the lateral view so
remember anterior or lateral superior
medial inferior all terms that you still
need to be reviewing and familiar with
prostrate lateral views of the neck
there's our trapezius this same muscle
if you want to be able to recognize it
in two different orientations some of
our external obliques were looking down
at the muscles of the abdomen region try
to focus on a few this one does kind of
zoom in a little bit but please realize
the external obliques are here they're
also here instance a zoomed in version
and our pectoralis major major being our
large muscles muscles that position the
pectoral girdle so we're looking at
again that our scapula here and we have
our sternum we have our part of our
scapula here and some of the muscles
that attach to that I did go over
already deltoids and trapezius but again
those come back and here you're able to
appreciate the orientation that they are
in the body now if it says cut this is
the Delta that's been cut in this region
to expose some of the other attachment
points in bones please realize that that
Delta it does cover this entire region
upper arm muscles our biceps and our
triceps biceps having two points of
origin triceps having three be able to
recognize where each of these are
located fuming main our anterior view is
here on the left and our prosti riyer
here your right let's say our hip and
thigh muscles again that gonna make you
learn a lot of these but the quadricycle
it is maxis and the adductor group all
should be familiar as far as what they
do in the relative size comparison
hopefully it's helpful to give you a
brief overview of some of the muscles
you should be able to identify an
appreciation for all the muscles that we
do have in our bodies and all the
corresponding names