welcome to this debaco university video
we're going to go over the natural
cannabis seed breeding process here
uh kind of walk you through some of the
basic steps if you're not familiar with
seed reading in general
just to kind of give you a general
healing on how it naturally occurs here
on tobacco university
[Music]
all right let's get into the video here
well first off to have a proper breeding
process you need to have
male and female plants so growing both
male and female plants at the same time
can allow for the production of seeds
and keep in mind female plants are going
to look like the ones down
over in this area and the male plants
are going to look like the kind of
flowers there so it's important to be
able to identify a male in the female
plant as well
and keep them generally isolated and we
want to be careful with the male plants
particularly for growing for
cannabinoids and terpenes
because they can pollinate plants we may
not want to be pollinated vastly
reducing our cannabinoids and terpenes
produced
so focusing first on those male plants
well male plants typically mature before
female plants to help ensure that pollen
will be ready
as the female matures pollen is wind
transferred so often there can be a lot
of pollen produced and it's very fine
pollen at that for indoor operations the
pond can get into ventilation systems so
be mindful of that
and for outdoor locations the pond can
travel from one field to another
so you want to keep that in mind with
your indoor outdoor growing if you are
producing male plants or neighbors
producing male plants
be aware of the distance that pollen can
travel
now for female plants pollinating them
will cause
a shift in the plant's energy from
cannabinoids to seeds
and as a result that shift that will
reduce that production of the cannabis
and terpenes
that we may be seeking or may have grown
that plant for
so keep that in mind you can't get the
ink at everything
you can't get seeds and high
cannabinoids you can get one or the
other
now this comes down a lot in breeding it
comes down to timing
so ensuring both the male and female
plants need to be at the same stage of
development to increase the odds of a
successful pollination
for indoor applications this can be
potentially achieved by a photo period
adjustment
and for outdoor grows this can be just a
timing when you're seeding
those plants when the natural photo
period will change as well to ensure you
have a plan of large enough structure
to be able to support and produce high
quality and high
qual quantity and quality seeds
so keep in mind also that when we're
looking at seeds there are often
different strains that we bred together
to create a hybrid
with the intention to get the best of
both original plants
in one this result in offsprings that
will have
increased variability so this may be
different traits
for example desired plant morphology and
preferred chemical profile could be a
great combination
auto flying a preferred chemical profile
is another thing that a lot of
growers are trying to breed for in the
sense that they're selecting certain
pollen isolating certain females growing
certain strains
to kind of get this best of both worlds
into
one plant they can call their own
ideally now
remember that the theoretical does not
always equal
the observed so just because you make a
cross and are expecting something and
theoretically that should happen
that doesn't always mean that's what's
going to happen sometimes you get what
you want
other times it just simply doesn't work
out if you have a tall plant with a
great chemical profile and a plant
that's short with poor chemical profile
and you cross the two you might get a
short short plant with great chemical
profile which would be excellent for
indoor growing operations particularly
grow tents
but keep in mind you could also get a
tall plant with poor chemical profile
which isn't going to make anyone happy
the key is growing as many many plants
and then selecting the ones with the
desired traits
that you as a grower deem desirable
hopefully that gives you a quick little
overview here of how to breed cannabis
natural cannabis breeding in general