so here when investigate natural killer
cells or NK cells and how they relate to
the human immune system I can tell you
right now they are very appropriately
named related to the function that they
perform now natural killer cells they go
through and they're looking for infected
cells so we could see here in the first
case our natural killer cells recognize
an MHC class 1 major histone
complementary complex here and it
doesn't kill this cell it's able to
recognize these surface proteins as self
and a healthy cell as a result or
natural killer cell does not destroy
that cell this is because it's
recognized as self or host it's
displaying the right
identifying proteins on the outside
however in this case in the below here
we have an infected cell we notice the
proteins recognitions are not being
expressed as a result our natural killer
cell will go about lice in that cell
keep in mind till lice means to kill or
destroy or break up that cell so because
this one is infected with a virus it's
not displaying the proper recognition
proteins on the outside and a natural
killer cell will go through the process
of destroying that cell it's important
that our natural killer cells don't go
around destroying every cell only the
ones that are infected or need to be
eliminated and those are determined by
not displaying the proper coat proteins
on the outside the natural killer cells
can lice and kill cancer cells and virus
infected cells making them a very
important component of the immune system
they're the most aggressive of dooming
cells and they're the only phagocyte
that destroys other human cells they
react not specifically and eliminate
cancerous and virus infected cells they
kill their target cells by releasing
these toxin proteins here foreign
proteins and other cytolytic chemicals
they secrete these potent chemicals that
enhance the inflammatory response so
while these might sound like a bad thing
initially that creating inflammation in
certain instances particularly sites of
injury they are important and as a
result they go through
and they are able to go through the body
and kill target cells through these
through this process hopefully this is
giving you a little bit more background
and exactly what natural killer cells do
and how they're able to recognize
healthy cells from one that is a virus
infected