this is intended to be a short
comparison between natural selection and
genetic engineering so natural selection
here we have our two moths and
engineering we're modifying the genes of
an organism so start off here natural
selection over time selecting from one
particular trait typically based on the
phenotype so here we have the birds
eating the green bugs here that stand
out against the brown tree the brown
bugs are able to survive and they're the
ones that are gonna pass on the genes
there and there are more or less
surviving through the process of natural
selection they're naturally being
selected for another example here pretty
complex but over time selecting for one
particular trait again typically based
on phenotype modern corn comes from
something called teosinte teosinte here
we see compared to 1/4 I save corn plant
but it is a highly branched corn plant
that produces very small almost single
you know rose seed ears through the
process of natural selection people have
cultivated corn to grow one main central
stock and produce large ears of corn you
can see here the comparison of our
modern corn versus our teosinte the
ancestor of corn this was through
cultivation and through being able to
feed people and being more efficient at
food production the modern corn
essentially was developed we've then
gone to the next step in genetically
engineered it which is the corn in
general that we're modifying is the
result of many many generations of
natural selection
specifically genetic engineering it's a
deliberate modification of an organism
by manipulating the genetic material
based on the genotype of an organism so
since all the genes in DNA is a you know
a universal code we're able to take
those genes and modify them here we're
taking the genes for a red pigment
pigment we can make bacterial bananas
clovers and frogs all red by simply
inserting the red pigment gene here's
the mice with glowing eyes were
genetically modifying this particular
mice
want to see what one looks like kind of
in real life we have a green glowing
mouse a YouTube video link provided here
hopefully this clarifies a little bit
about natural selection versus genetic
engineering and what each individually
does