here we're going to be looking at some
of the details behind natural selection
natural selection here might be familiar
with the finches and the birds beaks and
also with these two different colored
moths and how they're able to survive in
different environments so first off well
how does a biological evolution happen
well there's two main ideas on how
traits or genes can be passed on to the
next generation one theory is that
individuals evolve where inherence
acquired characteristics are somehow
passed on to the offspring or the
concept that with these leaves being at
the highest point on these trees because
giraffes stretch their necks to
constantly eat those individuals evolved
to have kind of longer necks that then
go on to the next generation that ends
up being the case what doesn't have
happening is a theory of populations
evolving and this is a selection of
genes already within a population
changes within those genes frequencies
in a population leads to that change
over time in this example we just have
some giraffes that are just naturally
born taller because they're able to
acquire food easier they're able to
survive or more likely to survive
therefore they pass their genes on to
the next generation in that way so we
can also see this with human directed
selection through domestication of
animals and plants Shifa is an example
of domesticating animals we could see
wheat or corn would be an example of
domesticating plants we also have
breeding for extreme variations compete
for very small pumpkins or I breed for
very large pumpkins we also have dog
sizes the Great Dane being a very large
dog and the Chihuahua being a very small
dog there's extremes of the variation
now within our evidence for the
selection theory of change natural
selection same process however there is
no human direction in this case we could
have ecological equivalents through an
analogous Anatomy so we're looking at
the fin of a shark penguin and of a
dolphin we have a fish a bird in a
mammal both developing these structures
to aid them in being able to swim within
the water environment also we have the
same process without human
selection looking at natural selection
with homologous Anatomy this is where
there's a common ancestor where if we
look at the human arm the cat the whale
in the bat well they may all perform at
very different functions
grabbing walking swimming flying they
all have the same basic structure or
Anatomy this again evidence for natural
selection theory of change within this
theory of change if drug and pesticide
resistance as becomes an issue if we
have a collection of bugs that are
eating a crop reading a plant we have
this first generation then a pesticide
application is applied and what reason
the red bugs have our natural resistance
to that particular chemical and a couple
other of the other color you're able to
survive just based on their location
maybe when the spray occurs the next
generation we see bugs have the same
number so in same chemicals applied well
now we have that selection process for
those red bugs being able to survive in
greater numbers meaning this chemical
spray it has these bugs have a
resistance to this pesticide of this
chemical application now Charles Darwin
came up with the idea of natural
selection here in 1831 Charles Darwin
took a role of natural sand ship HMS
Beagle and he sailed on a five-year
navigational trip around the world could
kind of see his track here we stayed a
wide variety of plants and animals
across the globe but of particular
importance he was known for his studies
he did in the Galapagos Islands and
they're located right here here's a
little image here of what they actually
look like different sizes in a small
cluster pretty far off any large
mainland
this allows some very unique things to
develop here now his observations
convinced him that evolution took place
fossils of extinct species resembled
living species in the same area the
Galapagos finches
differed slightly in their appearance
but resembled those in South American
mainland so even though they're
separated by quite the distance there's
some strong resemblance they may have
migrated or traveled from there in 1859
he publishes book the Origin of Species
and he proposed that evolution occurs
through the process of it
natural selection here's a copy of that
top book here so Charles Darwin he
observe ations that eventually convinced
him that evolution took place fossils
from extinct species resembled living
species in the same area an example of
this was his Galapagos finches that he
studied differed slightly in appearance
but resembled those in South American
mainland the kiddin that there may be
some connection there in 1859 he
published his book the Origin of Species
located right here where he proposed
that this evolution occurs for the
process of natural selection now even
though we may know it that is his most
quote famous work he was most proud of
his work that he did on earthworms he
was fascinated by their behavior he
conducted 40 years of earthworm
experiments that occurred both in the
lab and in the field so when you
struggle with a lab experiment just
think he spent 40 years just looking at
earthworms and amongst other things that
he studied he published his findings in
1881 in the book that we see pictured
here the book sold 6,000 copies in its
first year selling faster than the
Origin of Species when it was first
published if I an Amazon in hardcover
for $45 there's also some soft cover
options available for a reduced cost now
the theory of natural selection so he
came up with the idea about what is that
theory of natural selection well he
observed 14 different infinite species
they differed and mainly in the beaks
and feeding habits he concluded that the
results were descendants with
modifications from a common ancestor or
as we now term at evolution meaning
there was an original common ancestor
and that ate seeds for example those
that ate leaves at insects tool-using
and grubs and and buds or fruit had to
develop different beaks to be able to
best and match or fit the modifications
for their particular in the environment
that they were living in in this case
the food item that they were eating here
the insect eating bird is a very small
and pointed beak able to grab maybe
small insects those eating buds or large
fruit as developed a very strong beak to
maybe break shell of a nut for example
now the theory of natural selection we
kind of see evident here Darla's from
there with artificial selection used by
breeders to produce animals and plants
with particular traits if you're
familiar with maybe broccoli or kale or
even cabbage or cauliflower they all
kind of go back to wild mustard plant
through artificial selection through
breeding and selective breeding I should
say growers have been able to take the
wild mustard and produce kale broccoli
Brussels sprouts cabbage and cauliflower
with modifications to certain traits
whether it's the stem where the leaves
with a terminal bud or the flower buds
able to get all these different strains
that were maybe familiar with but they
all can be traced back to a common
ancestor dog breeding is another example
here dog Ridge shown enormous amount of
variability due to the target selection
of particular traits by man if wolf is
the common ancestor Europe America China
and India have all bred for different
subsets of that selection process but
they all can be traced back to the
common wolf ancestor the process of
natural selection
these trait selection can occur in
nature which he termed again that
natural selective process and it's
occurs in response to a number of
conditions there could be simple
variation in color within a population
that's inherited could be bright yellow
or dark brown there could be competition
over a production of offspring leads to
competition for survival who's a best
fit for their environment these leads to
adaptations for individuals with
beneficial adaptations or mildew to
survive and pass on their genes here we
see the brightly colored one easily
sticking out easily getting eaten versus
the ones that blend in or camouflage a
little bit better and this ultimately
leads to a selection process over many
generations there is a change in allele
frequency this is leading to the concept
of evolution now this theory of natural
selection here also applies to kind of
food so Darwin was influenced by Malta's
si the principle of population this is
back in 1798 where populations increased
exponentially while food supplies
increase only in kind of a linear scale
thus food supply will limit population
growth so here we have in
example our population growth in this
case our population is below the kind of
food threshold so there's a food surplus
then over time if population grows will
be a food shortage and this will lead to
competition
and who's the best fit for the
environment lastly our four fundamentals
of natural selection proposed by Charles
Darwin and Alfred Wallace he proposed
that there are heritable traits to be
able to come in to be passed on limiting
factors exist in all environments
overpopulation of offspring lead to
those that best fit and reproduction by
those who are that best fit they're able
to fit that environment we kind of see
here our initial little frequency of all
the colors is equal but then there's a
selection for for whatever reason this
case the red circles and over time that
allele frequency of the red becomes much
greater and we see that the pink here is
basically selected against as does the
yellow adaptation of populations is the
result of this natural selection process
so hopefully this kind of gives you some
appreciation for the natural selection
process and kind of what Darwin kind of
came up with and was able to theorize
based on his observations