okay here okay t-cells classified as
either cd4 or cd8 you may have seen
these images before depending on or
order your watch some of the videos I
have posted under this channel but we're
gonna explore these a little bit more
detail in this lecture series so looking
for cd4 and cd8 cells these molecules
are important because it regulates how
the t-cell will interact with and
respond to an antigen presenting cell so
that's abbreviated a PC a PC engine
presenting cell we notice in this case
in particular where cell to cell
recognition is very important to
populations of T cells have different
mechanisms for immune protection both
buying with MHC molecules via their
antigen receptors called t-cell
receptors typically abbreviated TCR s so
in this case the TCR the t-cell
receptors are the kind of the purple
molecule here our antigen presenting
cell or the green molecules here and
here's our antigens being presented on
this cell this is going to lead us down
either the cd4 pathway or the cd8
pathway and we'll talk about each of
those coming up here so first off the
cd4 pathway so these cd4 cells are bind
with a PCS antigen presenting cells via
their antigen and benning MHC 2
molecules and are stimulated to become
helper T cells so these cells that go
into and simulate B cells or cytotoxic T
cells directly or secrete set up ends to
inform more in various target cells
about the pathogenic threat so what does
this kind of block of text kind of look
like in an image well here we have our
cd4 catfights what we're looking at we
have our t-cell receptors here we have
our cd4 what this is allowing is an
activated helper T cell so when their
cd4 helper T cell binds at the image to
complex in antigen presenting cell the
antigen presenting cell and T cells now
release our cytokines in response the
cytokines T cell clones
so so in response to this we're noticing
one cell basically cloning itself going
into to these cloned T cells are
produced different cytokines and
activate either B cells and cd8 cells
and these can go about as being an
integral part of the immune system so
what is our cd4 do well there's binding
that's very important in the immune
system they're then releasing the
compound causing T cells to clone itself
and from there T cells are able to
differentiate into the cd8 pathway and B
cells we're going to investigate in this
selector the cd8 next up we're going to
follow this cell along so looking at the
cd8 now what that does is that engages
an antigen embedded MHC one molecules on
the APCs and antigen presenting cells
are still need to become cytotoxic T
cells these are responsible for directly
killing infected cells by apoptosis and
emitting cytokines to amplify the immune
response so here's our cd8 binding and
our cytotoxic T cell when this interacts
with the mh1 complex the epitope complex
infected cell it produces these
molecules here these molecules are very
important these molecules go on now and
our infected cell because this cell
basically has now either virus particles
in it or is in some way compromised its
expression is going to be slightly
different and the peripheral foreigns
form the pores in the membrane so we're
looking at breaking apart this cell by
adding these kind of pores to the cell
we're able to break the cell down licen
the cell so remember the cytotoxic T
cells are responsible for destroying
this affected cell we don't want this
Olivia to go on and spread these virus
particles throughout the entire body as
a result the cytotoxic T cell is
responsible for licen or destroying that
cell now the cd4 and cd8 cells both are
surface molecules and different
different
whether teacr will engage in MHC - all
right seeing one molecule so here's our
one and here's our two as you may
suspect the two molecule has two here
embedded in the image class one only has
one bonded here because they assist in
bindings with specificity the cd4 and
cd8 molecules are described as
co-receptors so very important in our
binding that occurs these are an
integral part of the binding and
recognition process of the immune system