okay here we're looking at nematodes are
nematodes you can see here both
pronunciations are fine they are not as
segmented worms meaning that these are
in fact animals so while they are very
small these are animals that can infect
plants now they're often overlooked and
they can affect the roots as well as the
leaves of plants the most commonly found
in the soil without and compete on the
roots that's probably their most notable
for root-knot nematode being worn that's
often talked about but they can there
are some that can infect the leaves as
well
now the identification you see here
these small worm-like structures they
are very simple organisms most are small
but can be a wide range from zero point
three millimeters to up to eight meters
long so keep in mind that size isn't
necessarily a way to positively identify
these because the range is so wide they
are non segmented worms they said these
are animals we're talking about there's
only about 20,000 species with some
actually being beneficial so what do you
think that all nematodes are negative
impacts on plants there's actually some
beneficial ones and they can be used to
help control other organisms for example
white grubs in lawns now we're to look
for these other typically found in soils
and can affect the roots you do the
first area people look for microscope is
often needed for positive identification
due to the fact that they are so small
for the most part and there are some I
get quite large but many of the
parasitic ones and ones that feed on the
plants are on the smaller end of that
scale they can also have a delayed
almost a three-week delay impact on
plants so when we finally start to see
some negative effects
well that initial infection could have
occurred up to three weeks ago and this
is in part why keeping records and
documentation is so important how to
prevent them while management is a
challenge so sanitation is highly
recommended invitations can reduce by
following soil for outdoor operations in
media solarization what this
solarization refers to is we're kind of
covering the area in this clear plastic
heating this soil up to extreme
temperatures causing the nematodes here
which are again animals to die
essentially
keep in mind that these will reduce the
nematodes mainly only in the upper six
to twelve inches of soil and do not
provide a long-term solution so this is
good for areas where you may have
increased pressure you may want to go
through and do this once I'll pull the
plastic up or take the media out kind of
remix it and do it again to ensure
you're getting an even kill throughout
the entire profile there otherwise those
become the very surface if they are
living below that where your roots tend
to go you just simply have infection
occur again how to control them well
because these are animals the products
usually used to control them are harmful
to humans and many as a result of
restricted use requires a license to be
able to use them there's strict
protocols involved few against target
the soil it need to be applied and are
then covered in seal to allow liquid
vapors to infiltrate the soil particles
again pretty harsh environment here
we're in a previous slide just to go
back for one moment we're saying this is
simply covering this and causing the
heat of the Sun to kind of surface
sterilize and Solarize the soil here
we're covering the soil but also adding
a fumigant a pesticide there if you're
an outdoor operation rotating broccoli
cauliflower grain sorghum or millet came
the lower root-knot nematodes if that's
your particular issue but keep in mind
that that's recommend these are grown
for two consecutive seasons so this
isn't grow broccoli for one year and
then go back and plant it looking at
maybe growing broccoli and cauliflower
and then back to your host crop
sometimes isn't an option of her some
growers but if it is this can be a way
to help try to reduce those numbers
biologically without adding any
pesticides or fumigants to the soil
because again these are animals and they
can those pesticides typically have a
lot of harmful effects to humans are in
the environment in general so it gives
you a little bit of that brief overview
of nematodes and hopefully it's to
understand a little bit more about these
animals now they can impact plants but
also the fact that they can be
beneficial in some regards