so here we're going to look at the
distinctive structure and function of
the nephron which is located in the
kidney and there are many over a million
nephrons for each kidney which is
important for the filtration of blood so
looking at that blood in the kidney well
how's it going through only this intense
network of capillaries and we have our
veins in our arteries here surrounding
our nephron these nephrons here outlets
allowing a lot of nutrients and water
and ions to be exchanged and that's how
we see Sunnis blood vessels surrounding
each one of these each nephron has this
very distinctive structure I'm going to
go over the details of that so look at
the nephrons are the functional units of
the kidney
they cleanse the blood and balance the
constitutes for circulation they're
constantly filtering out the blood they
take simple filtrate of blood and modify
ultimately into forming urine and they
say there's 1.3 million nephrons per
each TD that you have so that blood flow
through these intense capillary beds we
have our arteries and our veins going
through our venules we see all these
little blood vessels surrounding kind of
this kind of looks like a bunch of tubes
kind of folding on one another this is
important we have a lot of exchanges
occurring at these distinct exceptions
ultimately we're producing urine at the
very end and that will be excreted from
the body the anatomy of the nephron here
giving a nice quick summary the globe
Eris's filters on small solute sweet
blood that then leads to the proximal
convoluted tubule the PCT
where ions may be absorbed water can be
reabsorbed but also nutrients toxins
will be removed and we'll adjust the
filtrate pH to maintain our proper
homeostasis continuing on you see it
kind of bends around the corner comes
around here we have the descending loop
of Henle aquaporins allow water to pass
from the filtrate into the interstitial
fluid in contrast we do 180-degree
hairpin turn coming back up the ACE in
the loop where were absorbing sodium
ions and chloride ions from the filtrate
to the interstitial fluid that's leading
to the distal tubular which is
selectively secreting and absorbing
different ions Symington
electric balance this is part of that
homeostasis so we don't know if we're
secreting or absorbing it depending on
the constraints or the stresses on the
body ultimately the collecting duct
which reabsorb solutes in water to form
the filtrate now the physiology of the
nephron are saying this arterioles when
we see these veins we see this
filtration that's occurring in the
Bowman's capsule
lemare's capillaries located here we
have filtration reabsorption secretion
ultimately excretion in the form of
urine in the body this gives you a
little bit of an idea of the complexity
of what's going on each neuron nephron
I'm sorry
and we noticed that there's different
ions that's occurring here now these
ions are either coming in they can be
going out this is helping the body
maintain homeostasis so these nephrons
need to be in direct contact with the
blood now this might seem a little
complex right now that will admit that
the easiest to follow is to initially
but I provide this with you at the end
but I want to draw your attention to at
this point is we have these distinctive
sections here the filtration step we
have the PCT the proximal cuddler to
build and lay the distal in the
collecting duct we're gonna go over
these each in detail in image it's
probably a little less scary here
showing you the same region stretching
out that nephron a little bit so we have
that filtration that selective
reabsorption the osmoregulation insult
radiance selective reabsorption and then
water retention at the very end it's a
little stretched out to kind of give you
the idea of what it looks like it is
much more condensed as you're trying to
fit 1.3 million in each kidney so start
with the clematis the only place where
actually the filtration occurs blood
pressure is used to push plasma through
the capillary walls to the Bowman's
capsule here this is our actual put of
filtration the blue mass is in red and
the Bowman's capsule here in hand we're
forcing that blood plasma across causing
that kind of physical type of filtration
to occur that then leads to the PCT or
proximal convoluted tubule where our
nutrients and our salts some vitamins
and water can
moved out of the tubule through active
transport so this does require energy
however from water right using that
through active transport that occurs by
osmosis
we can also reabsorb seven sodium's
nutrients urea lipid soluble silence and
small proteins now proximal tubules
continuing on we have our loop of Henle
remember there's two parts to this
consist of was the descending which is
important for water flow and in a
setting which is a transfer of ions we
see that here here's our sodium and
chloride ions tissue surround loop of
Henle is salty from active transport and
diffusion of these chloride ions the
salty conditions allow water to diffuse
out of the loop so this is we're
creating that water and that ions into
the process of osmosis and regulation
this is how we're having that water to
move across active transport since
moving the ions and as Moses is moving
the water continuing under the distal
tubule here it's a selectively secretes
or absorbs ions to maintain blood pH in
the electrolyte balance these are that
homeostasis coming in so we can kind of
absorb or secrete them depending what
the body needs active transport is used
to move these nutrients out of the
concentrated urine that are slowly
getting very close to producing our end
product which is earrings some ions
drugs and toxins are actively pumped
into the tubule for excretion out of the
body you see this active transport
pictured here again that's requiring ATP
continuing on that collecting duct more
water leaves it to be las voces since
the tube is around eyes salty tissue so
that salty tissue is driving that moving
water and that water is going to move in
that direction Cimmeria also leads by
diffusion but it may be cycled through
the system Maria it's less toxic than
ammonia so again here's that kind of
simple structure of the nephron looking
at the Bozeman's castle the proximal to
build a loop of Henle the distal tubules
and the collecting duct lastly they end
with that a little bit more complex
image hopefully you can kind of get an
appreciation for all the different
things occurring at the different steps
and where things might be moving in or
moving out to help the body maintain
homeostasis and ultimately produce urine
and kind
waste products so they'll be excreted
from the body