okay we're looking at niche or niche
iearned competition so niche is
referring to the pattern of living and
these organisms and species are all
interacting and have different patterns
of living are all in competition for a
limited amount of resources how these
kind of interrelate is very important to
an ecosystem so looking at communities
let's first to find a community well all
organisms that live together in an area
are defined as a community if you might
be a little hard to define because like
what type of area or what size or scale
of area are we talking about
but for communities the different
species compete and cooperate with each
other to make a community stable a
community is often identified by the
presence of a dominant species the
distribution of other organisms may
greatly differ however the ranges of all
organisms overlap we see that here with
our trees and our shrubs in our ferns
and salamanders all kind of overlap at
one another as part of this these
communities now this niche and
competition will a niche is a particular
biological role of an organism in a
community this is not to be confused
with habitats so habitats a place a
niche is it referred to as a pattern of
living so we see all these different
birds beaks have different niches
different patterns of living that can
help them consume unique food items so
habitat versus niche a good comparison
between the two
well habitat is a portion of an
ecosystem occupied by a particular
organism it's a physical place and it
reflects the living place of an organism
a niche on the other hand is the role of
an organism in that ecosystem so the
role is a function or activity and it
reflects the biotic and abiotic
associations with the environment so
comparing habitats to niche communities
like the physical place and this is a
function or activity so we're kind of
looking at environment now habitat in
niche you kind of see this stacking doll
effect here so the environment is the
overarching thing and that's everything
surrounding an organism that's the air
the rocks the water all of that is the
environment a little bit smaller than
that a little bit more specifically the
habitats motifs is a physical place its
area in the environment where organisms
grow and survive this could be the ocean
habitat the forest habitat the Arctic
that's a portion of the total
environment within the habitat there's a
smaller portion here where we're over
here when we're looking at the portion
of the habitat where the living organism
makes its home so this is referring to
that living it's a part of that habitat
part of that physical place and it's how
that interaction is occurring so
competition is a struggle of two organiz
to use the same resources where
resources are limited here we see
individuals competing for mates and
competition there's a limited number of
amount of food water and mates as is
resulting in often competition that
occurs on most animal species now
there's two different types of
competition there's intra specific
competition which occurs between
individuals of the same species here so
intra is between the same species same
signal species interspecific competition
occurs between individuals of different
species so here receive a line in the
hyena these are different species here
this is interspecific competition here
we see two flamingos competing this is
intra sniffing competition now there's a
fundamental versus realized niche
because of competition organisms may not
be able to occupy their fundamental or
theoretical niche this is where an
organism can live so a fundamental niche
is referring to where an organism can
live we see this rock here you see these
barnacles and organisms living on this
rock well the fundamental niche is where
Northam might be able to survive however
this is often not the case
just because an origin can live there
doesn't mean it does live there instead
organisms often occupy what's called
their realized or their actual niche
this is where the organism actually
lives so some of these organisms for
example sink the light brown one here
kind of the blue one the light brown may
be able to live on this entire
intertidal zones this is the high tide
mark and then as the tide goes out this
is the low tide mark so this brown
organism maybe it'll live
the entire Rock however it gets out
competed from this white to gray and
this blue one so therefore it's realized
niche or it's active actual niche where
it lives is on the just below the high
tide line the fundamental niche could be
for the entire intertidal zone here but
it's realized or its actual image here
is just near the high tide line
countries to that the blue and green
kind of some of the Pink's they also may
be to live over this entire Rock but
they be out competed here maybe need to
have a little bit more moisture a little
bit more water therefore they're
realized niche is here very close to the
low tide mark so this in interspecific
competition with only one winner we see
the example here of blue and red we have
two different species competing so we
see initially they all start off and
then slowly at species one the red
species starts out compete species two
and we see over time the blue species
actually gets pushed out entirely and
only the red species one survives also
in that picture here we see the brown
living with the white walls for whatever
reason the white can out-compete the
brand and it gets pushed out and
therefore there's only one winner in
this interspecific competition
competitive exclusion can partly explain
this no two species with the same niche
can coexist so we see what is called
blue species here and we have a tan
orange of species here when they're
grown separately we see one that's here
one less here different carrying
capacity that's okay but both living in
able to survive they all grew alone in
different culture tubes
this is them just how they grow normally
all isolated now though we add something
different so this is competitive
exclusion we're now taking these or
mixing the populations so we're mixing
the blue species here with the tan
orange species so we notice that there's
a decline or extinction here of the tan
or orange species when they're to share
the same culture too so because it to
have different realized niches thus they
avoid competition when they're able to
coexist but when they're mixed together
here we see that one species can outlive
the other can out-compete the other
for food or resources do that
competition the overall Karen capacity
is reducing if it's just grown alone but
we see that that mixed population very
closely resembles the Luthor species
compared to the tan or orange pieces
here hopefully this helps explain a
little bit of niche and competition that
occurs in ecosystems all over the world