welcome to this debacco University video
we're going to be going over nitrogen
fertilizer impact on CBD and THC
concentrations in cannabis giving you an
indication of how much nitrogen
fertilizer you should be giving and what
might be too much and what are the
negative effects by giving too much
nitrogen
[Music]
fertilizer all right let's get into the
video here now the this is the research
article so if you want to find out some
more information about this or look at
some more of materials and methods
you're more than welcome to Via the link
provided here but I'm going to give you
a general summary and kind of give you a
grower Viewpoint of this so uh kind of
most important here is the actual
research trials uh that they did and the
results that they got so looking at the
uh graphs that we see over here note
that the total biomass and total
cannaboid concentrations in percent dry
weight are on the Y AIS the vertical
axis and this is versus the measured
nitrogen concentrations in percent dry
weight that'll be on the xaxis here it's
kind of what you're looking at they have
some correlation lines now the
Triangular points you see kind of here
and here identify plants in the north
and west facing edge of the glass house
and that's where these plants were grown
as part of this study uh we're
considered above the regression line as
we can see here the regression line is
here uh an average had higher values
than the dot points and the dot points
are those little circles and those dot
points in the same grass were indicated
plants not on the edges so the triangle
plants uh here uh give you the idea that
those were on the sun Edge and the
circles were not on the sun Edge so this
also speaks to the importance of light
and concentration of light the intensity
of light your plants are getting how
that can influence things as well they
took that into consideration here now
looking at the general Trend we could
see that biomass in grams here is
increasing uh which is you know everyone
thinks that'd be better bigger quote
better plants however we'll notice as
the biomass increase we see all these
other regression lines going the
opposite direction and those are looking
at total uh CBC total CBD and total THC
there's a negative correlation there
they also a little study on pruning I'm
going to focus more here on the nitrogen
uh treatments as
well now as I say it's an inverse
relationship here so the increase in
biomass is nitrogen concentration
increased from 3 to 6 was approximately
100% in this is why you want to be
careful of the scales so if you look at
the y-axis just to go back for a second
here we could see biomass in grams is
100 to 200 this is like doubling in size
here just to give you a little bit of
idea what those numbers actually
mean however the corresponding decrease
as I pointed out in the cannaboid
concentration was approximately
67% this entails a net decline in yields
in terms of grams as nitrogen
concentration increases so as you get
excessive in nitrogen and that comes
higher and higher your cannabic content
is canabo concentration is decreasing
that's the little brackets mean here and
I saw example of the Seesaw here because
as nitrogen's going up it's an inverse
relationship the canab concentration is
decreasing which of course Growers don't
want to have so kind of your general key
points is that biomass was strongly and
positively related to nitrogen
fertilizer canab concentrations were
strongly negative related to nitrogen uh
and plants in the sun Edge tended to
have higher biomass levels in
cannabinoid cont concentrations compared
to those grown in the row now those High
nitrogen levels those High nitrogen
those nutrients raised in those High
nitrogen um levels in both the
inflorescence the flower and also the
leaf plant matter for very high levels
of nitrogen nutrition which is defined
as 500 milligrams per milliliter
influence in cannabid concentrations
decrease significantly with little
change in total biomass and leaf biomass
also increased quite a bit with higher
nitrogen supplied stem diameter also
increased this is a sign of kind of a
nitrogen bloat Growers may say to their
plant and the net effect of increasing
nitrogen nutrition on the total yield of
canids was negative because of the
increase in biomass which was also which
was only significant in the leaves kind
of that extra giant growth you might
have on the leaves this was not enough
though to offset the conent decrease in
cannaboid concentrations so again we're
getting a little to these excessive
levels getting a bigger plant but
decreasing our total yields which is
what are not should should not be our
goal now looking at our canab
concentration as well as canid yield per
plant or decreased with the increased
Supply so how do we kind of explain this
and this is kind of looking at a general
fertilizer curve so as we get our
nutrient Supply as we go from left to
right we're getting more fertilizer and
on the y- axis here we looking get crop
yield higher yield being better well
there a certain point that if you are
growing in soil and don't add any
fertilizer you're going to get a certain
yield uh but of course is probably going
to be below what Growers are aiming for
so they add fertilizer now you can add
fertilizer and you have this kind of
initially almost a linear increase but
then it kind of like levels off it kind
of like reaches this kind of peak and
there's this maximum yield point now if
you keep adding fertilizer beyond that
maximum yield Point what ends up
happening is that you start to get a
decrease in return now you're increasing
your cost but you're going to decrease
on return that's what we're seeing here
the correlation with the nitrogen
fertilizer numbers
so very high concentrations of
fertilizer are not advised because of
lower cannaboid concentration in yield
and then the optimum nitrogen nutrition
is likely between 60 and 120 milligrams
per liter I also did it here in ounces
per gallon and this is a range so it's a
pretty big range uh but it is a range so
you want to make sure you're definitely
not outside that range because you'll
try to get over to where that yield
curve is going down now pruning impact I
just wanted to mention it here that they
did a double spem pruning was applied as
an additional treatment to investigate
efficiency and biomass increase pruning
treatment did not increase cannaboid
concentration or affect biomass when
measured at the final Harvest so I just
wanted to make note of that it was on
the graphs that we saw earlier now study
also evaluated the sun Edge uh plants I
wanted to just touch on that because
across all treatments as an artifact of
this trial Sun Edge plants were the most
directly exposed to sunlight showed a
trend towards more biomass and higher
cannaboid concentrations according to
the model that they did statistics wise
self- shading of plants can limit the
production of cannaboids so it's
important to consider plant density and
light intensity and also the Spectrum
your plants are receiving for those
growing indoors however these results
can only be considered preliminary
because in it warrants further research
but just showing you for those growing
maybe indoors how can we relate this
study that we want to really make sure
we're getting high par to our plants uh
and across all areas as we saw a
dramatic effect here with the sun Edge
plants versus those growing in row how
that can affect things so it's more than
just nitrogen but that is important
consideration you don't want to over add
it because you'll Simply Be reducing
your yields and increasing your costs so
hopefully that's helpful there's other
videos on this channel about nitrogen
fertilizer but this gives you another
study to investigate