here again of the unique opportunity to
see nitrogen deficiency and toxicity in
a cannabis plant there's a trial that
was conducted where a plant was fed too
much nitrogen that's we see the toxicity
and then underfed nitrogen after you'll
see the deficiency however the image
here this is the goal of what we're
trying to achieve here so nitrogen we'll
just start with the basics why do plants
need it what do they use it for well
it's a mobile nutrient and that's
important when we look at where we start
to look at we're on the plant where we
might be seeing toxicity or deficiency
symptoms its sa four amino acids nucleic
acids chlorophyll coenzymes a whole
bunch of other things associated with
the components of plant production
nitrogen gives the plants that lush
green color while promoting succulent
growth in hastens maturity so that's
kind of giving that plant that nice what
we've determined as growers as a healthy
green color deficient plants exhibit
what we call chlorosis which is loss of
normal green color or yellowing of the
leaves excessive nitrogen can cause
delayed maturity higher disease kind of
issues lower tolerance for environmental
stresses reduce carbon carbohydrate
reserves poor root development and
difficulty to clone eyes another
negative effect of overfeeding nitrogen
not to mention costs so this is the
trial that was conducted this is kind of
a setup here the cultivars users wife
it's a high in CBD plant age is about 80
days old it's grown in a greenhouse to
help maintain consistent conditions
control plants were fed a balanced
fertilizer and the test plant was either
fed a deficient amount of nitrogen or a
toxic and that's like super toxic to
kill the plant but a bloated appearance
as you're gonna see with the nitrogen I
was over applied to those plants so
starting with these deficient plants so
it's important when we see leaves that
are yellowing we notice where they're
located and over here in kind of those
red circle we see that lower portion of
the lead of the leaves is showing that
yellow in color lack of robust growth a
thin overall appearance to the plant
poor green color even throughout the
plant but especially
those lower leaves in slow growth so if
you're looking at just this image it's
very hard to do that comparison so let's
take a look at this plant compared to
what be a normal plant we could see that
control plant over on this side here
that's how a plant should look if it was
fed of balanced fertilizer now you can
really see that lack of vigor in that
test plant of suspense also has a really
yellowing leaves of the on the older
portions of the plant or that lower
portion of the plant so again it's
really now shows a nitrogen deficient
plant when you compare it to a normal
plant the same age now look to look for
specifically as I said those yelling of
the leaves notice how the upper leaves
here as a normal green color on the
older leaves are yellowing this is a
plant that's exhibiting it kind of a
more advanced form of nitrogen
deficiency and we can see that here that
the green color is being pushed to that
newer growth because nitrogen is a
mobile nutrient it's moving from the
older and being translocated through the
plant to the newer growth that we see
here now if you're growing tomatoes
they'd kind of do the same thing yelling
with those older leaves same symptoms as
cannabis this was an extreme case where
only the very top of the leaves the
plant have much green color to them at
all and it plays a very spindling look
to it in general as well seedlings can
have early symptoms of low nitrogen we
can see that here there's a yelling of
those older leaves in that greening of
the upper leaves here this problem
should be corrected now to avoid stress
during the transplant in field
conditions this can be more common if
after prolonged heavy rains particularly
in sandy soil that will flush out a lot
of that nitrogen here we see a heme
field here the bud regions the upper
portions green but those lower regions
definitely that yellow coloration
if notice only near harvest time near
the end of the season not necessarily a
bad thing because you want that last bit
of nitrogen to push through the plant
and it's a sign that you do not over
feed those plants with nitrogen now how
to correct a problem
well whole host of fertilizers are out
there I've just kind of mentioned a
couple here with the advantage of just
about all nitrogen fertilizers is
they're very
acting so typically the ones added
wanted into the root zone you should see
a plant change in as little as three
days so all the rates suggested here for
about a two by two growing area we have
blown a blood meal urea calcium nitrate
and ammonium sulfate are the most common
ones blood meal one tablespoon per area
corporate into the soil and water Danis
ki it's organic the downfall is it is
kind of costly but in three days you'll
see the plants green up if you did have
a nitrogen deficiency urea
three-quarters of a teaspoon per gallon
of water it's a very potent this is 46%
nitrogen compared to blood meal that's
only 12
that's very concentrated source you can
volatize or you can lose a lot of that
nitrogen to the air if not incorporated
into the soil and keep in mind if you
are making the soil applications of urea
the soil should be warm about 50 degrees
Fahrenheit + or 10 degrees Celsius or
greater calcium nitrate is 15 and a half
percent nitrogen one tablespoon per
gallon of water highly water soluble but
it can increase the soil pH if used at
high rates or over an extended period of
time so just be mindful of that unless
they have a Mon iam sulfate here 21% in
nitrogen half a tablespoon per gallon of
water reduces leaching and authorization
but it can acidify the soil so this had
a corrected deficiency but what does a
Texas City symptoms look what happens if
you over apply your calculations here
well looking at the over applications
this is what a toxic level of nitrogen
can look like you have excessive growth
a very dark green color to the leaves
and brittle stems plants can also be
very difficult to clone so again here we
see that very dark lush green growth now
how does that look compared to the
control plant that same control plant
from before you can now see that
comparison how much darker that green
color is there's a green door and a
white wall in the background kind of to
kind of color balance things a little
bit we can definitely see that darker
green color with this excessive nitrogen
a very dense canopy as well and that
just excessive growth there now
the toxicity how to correct that well
simply how to correct it is to know what
fertilizers you're adding and how
to add and as growers not to over adder
if it says a tablespoon and don't do one
and then a little bit more they want to
calculate what you're adding and learn
what the normal plant and color looks
like so that you know if you're over
adding or under adding they mentioned
before nitrogen is very quick acting
which is great because you do have a
deficiency you can easily correct that
so hopefully this helps you kind of
understand the nitrogen problems on
toxicity or on the divisions end you can
check out other videos out in this
channel to help you understand potential
deficiencies in your plants