often when growing cannabis you can feel
like pushing the stone up a hill it can
be quite the battle us in particular
non-disease challenges facing cannabis
growers can be an area that trips a lot
of people up so I'm going to cover some
of those here so hopefully you can
identify it won't be a major problem for
you so looking at some of the challenges
here girls often think a plant does not
look normal
it is disease they immediately go to the
disease aspect but really it could be
something that's not disease oriented
being able to identify that early is
beneficial well the disease can often be
the case non disease issues that's
causing the problem even though it may
appear to be a disease so it's kind of
like figuring out a chess game here
where there's always a different
challenge something being presented it
can be either kind of looks by that look
through that and identify it properly
whether it is disease or something that
is not disease related they don't
realize your power as a grower in what
conditions you have control over and
what you do not have control over with
Inter operations there's very few
conditions of our does not have control
over however you need to recognize what
conditions you deem ideal and how you're
going to meet those and how you going to
monitor those targets if you're growing
outdoors you have a lot less control so
it can be a little bit more of a
challenge indoors you can see the
picture of the cat and the lion in the
shadow a lot more control but you got to
know what you want your growing area to
be and hanging a monitor and meet those
goals so knowing those targets is kind
of the first thing now what areas can
you control what areas should you be
targeting well in no particular order
what temperature you're gonna run the
room at what humidity level do you want
to be the air circulation the irrigation
nutrients use and throughout the growth
cycle and carbon dioxide concentration
all these things come together to make a
successful grow room any one of these
gets way out of control it can
significantly reduce yields and cause
the others to be of less importance so
you're only as strong as your weakest
target condition here in the environment
temperature again and these humidity can
vary depending on the growth stage so be
mindful of that so just know what your
targets are
the clear stage of claim that you have
you wanna have a check system so alarms
are alerts great and you also yourself
want to check the place at a consistent
time so you know if something is off
either checking it right after a pump
comes on right after a pump comes off
after a light comes on our light should
go off is just a good way to kind of
have that kind of is everything okay or
should there be something I should be
concerned about having alarms or alerts
of temperatures get too high or too low
is another way you can kind of add that
24-hour monitoring another things should
be able to know when something is
abnormal as a result you know what the
normal should be it'll be easy they'll
be easy for you to identify the abnormal
now in this case here we see the cameras
plants of you know not quite green color
it could be that the cultivar so that's
not to say a bad thing or if we're
supposed to have that green plant we see
these clovers here well this one kind of
looks a little off-color so this would
kind of be an abnormal one so by knowing
the normal knowing what should expect we
can tell whether we have something
pushing on various extremes from that
normal either really to dark green or to
light green or what color should we
expect so just having that idea as a
grower so you can identify something as
abnormal and the sooner you can identify
it the quicker you can go about
correcting that potential issue