okay this video is going to look at some
of the nonspecific cell their responses
of the immune system now they're all
listed here such as physical barriers
besides extracellular killing
inflammatory response fever
interferons in the complement system and
a focus mainly on fever and some of the
brief overviews a lot of these can also
be found in other videos they're what
they all have in common is nonspecific
cell response it's kind of like the
spider putting the web out here or
casting out the cast net nonspecific
just kind of catching whatever comes
through here the lot of these systems
just kind of kill or prevent sources of
infection
none of them are very specific so this
is what we're talking with nonspecific
cell responses they are still providing
very important functions but they're non
specific here can be classified
sometimes that part of that innate
immune system when we're born with so
this second line defense mobilized and
quickly is inflammatory responses also
kind of falls into this category the
body uses non specific cellular chemical
devices to protect itself they can be
phagocytes and natural killer cells
there'll be a whole separate deal on
those antimicrobial proteins in blood
and tissue fluid inflammatory response
can be macrophages mast cells white
blood cells and chemicals it's important
to keep in mind that harmful substances
are identified by surface carbohydrates
unique to infectious organisms as we see
here are cell phospholipid bilayer has
many things it's not just a phospholipid
bilayer there are many surface
carbohydrates here so a lot going on in
the surface and that's very important
for cell to cell communication in part
that is how certain cells are able to
determine cells that ourself and
shouldn't be destroyed or foreign
invaders that do not belong in the body
one we're to focus on here is a fever
again a nonspecific response here well
abnormally high body temperature in
response to invading organisms it's kind
of the definition of a fever here
the body's thermostat is reset upwards
so normal body temperature it's about 37
degrees Celsius or 98.6 degrees
Fahrenheit in pyrogens are chemical
secreted by leukocytes and macrophages
when exposed to bacteria and other
foreign substances part the hypothalamus
located here in the brain regulates body
temperature when your body is inducing a
fever it's up regulating that
temperature it's getting at above ninety
eight point six degrees on average now
as we notice our as we know certain
proteins can denature at very high
temperatures so we're saying raising the
body temperature well we may feel
extremely hot it's not necessarily gonna
move all that much reason being for our
fever if we have a high fever they're
extremely dangerous because they can
denature our own enzymes so here's our
normal body temperature and see a
medical emergency to get too hot also
hypothermic we get too cold fevers are
not used to directly kill the invaders
because fever is greater than forty
point six degrees Celsius or 105 degrees
Fahrenheit are often fatal so we don't
want to elevate our temperature much
above that was will denature our own
enzymes however what our body does is
with a moderate feeder can be beneficial
we were moderate not high the primary
benefit is an increase in the metabolic
rate which speeds up tissue repair
although every degree in temperature
equals ten times
metabolic increase also by increasing
the temperature in the metabolic rate
can also cause the liver and spleen to
sequester iron and zinc which are needed
by Moke microorganisms when it means
sequester it means can it bind up in use
this may help slow infectious growth so
as much as we think a hot fever is
destroying all the invaders by just keep
killing them and denaturing all their
enzymes may not be 100% the case because
if we get too hot we will delete her our
own enzymes what's really helping with
is increasing the metabolic rate yes
some enzymes may be denatured or at
least are reduced in their effectiveness
but we're really looking at the
metabolic rate speeding up repair and
helping slow the growth of infectious
organisms by sequestering I
music