in this video we're going to be
investigating non vascular plants
putting parentheses bryophytes this is a
classification of plants that might
commonly refer to as mosses there are
more scientifically called bryophytes
they're considered very early or
primitive plants we're going to talk
about why that is so to start with the
reason why we say they're primitive is
they're not too far away from clean
algae and our cladogram here they are
considered to be the first successful
land plants and have no vascular system
as a result the maximum size of the
plant is greatly limited because all
materials have to be transported by
diffusion and osmosis even under ideal
growing conditions you'll see mosses are
very short they don't get very tall
because they don't have this vascular
system and everything has to go through
the process of diffusion and osmosis and
this limits their overall height that
they can get
so remember diffusion is a net movement
of molecules from an area of high
concentration to an area of low
concentration see here with the food dye
in the bottle
its diffusing throughout if we came back
a couple days later this would all
hopefully be a consistent blue color
when everything diffused through the
water in this case in the bottle to give
you another example of that here's high
concentration we see it going to low
concentration over time to the point
that the molecules on the top and bottom
side will equal one another and it's in
the process of diffusion as most it's a
little different as most this is the
process by which two molecules of the
solvent and that pass through a
semipermeable membrane from a less
concentrated solution into a more
concentrated one resulting in equal
concentrations on both sides of the
membrane we see that here is our water
here's our solvent molecules our solid
molecules can't pass through this
semipermeable membrane but the water can
and that will result in a change in the
water height here water molecules travel
through this membrane trying to even out
on both sides trying to make even
concentrations on both sides
osmosis as we saw in red blood cells we
could see them causing the shrivel
isotonic is when equal waters moving in
and out
hypotonic is when more water's coming in
and going out in red blood cells that
they could lyse or break apart and in
hypertonic think of it like making a
pickle you get that kind of shriveled
look to it in the sea now we're talking
about plants kind of the translation of
that hypertonic situation called plasma
sized implants isotonic is called
flaccid and hypotonic is detergent
there's a lot of water here a lot of
water pressure this can be important to
hold plants upright talk about
nondescript plants or bryophytes there's
actually some other classifications
liverworts hornworts and mosses is that
a liver or norton loss looks like I
chose mosses you're probably most
familiar with that but all of these
pretty much lack of vascular system
mosses has a very simple conducting
tissue soft strands but for the most
part these are all considered non
vascular the lifecycle of a moss not to
get into too much detail key part is
because they are so low growing and then
transporting all their nutrients through
diffusion as Moses they need water
transport so if a Moss dries out they
are unable to reproduce need that sperm
being to swim to the egg this is why we
typically see them in shaded regions or
areas that tend to hold a lot of
moisture in that case fertilization
process is the same sperm eating egg
producing an embryo sporophytes
developed we see a female gametophyte
and male gametophyte these need to have
a union between the two need to merge
with one another with water present and
that will then form the fertilization
process that forms the embryo that goes
around this is Ulta also involves a
little bit of alternation of generations
that can occur which is in another video
there the key part with mosses being
solo and nonvascular they typically are
found in areas with high water content