so this channel focuses a lot on
different pruning methods and you can
research a lot of options
but ever wonder what happens if you
really chose not to prune your cannabis
plants
this video here at tobacco university
will help give you some information on
that
[Music]
all right let's get into not pruning
chemist plants and see what impact that
has
on production so first off you have the
untouched growth habit we can see
image right here unpruned or untrained
chemist plants grow like
a christmas tree basically kind of that
nice triangular shape
at the time of flowering this will
typically mean the plants will have a
dense leaf canopy
with minimal light penetration into the
plant to the inner portions
this results in smaller and typically
weaker branches and buds
lower and deeper in the plant canopy
because they're simply not getting a lot
of light
these small buds that may be called
popcorn due to their small and minimal
density characteristics
so this gets into the great debate of
are you looking for quantity are you
looking for
quality so while it is possible for buds
to develop with less light
it can come down to quantity versus
quality there is not a simple x amount
of light equals x amount of ripening
partially shaded buds can still produce
quality buds just may not be the highest
quality
however this style of growing will
increase the amount of popcorn buds
which are smaller sized and typically
have lower densities we see in this
image
compared to what's determined to be a
higher quality bud located right here
now if we're not going to be pruning
that's that's one option for growers
but even if you don't plan on that
pruning method growers should still be
going through removing
yellow leaves to reduce the chance of
disease or insect
and have them kind of placed to
initially become established
so what we're trying to do is remove
some leaves
even if we're not pruning simply because
some of the leaves could create a
starting point for disease to start or
insects to start which would affect not
only the entire plant
but any neighboring plants so even if
you're not going to go through and prune
selective defoliation is still advised
and it helps you kind of
inspect the plants individually catch
any problems that might arise
very early on so you can implement
corrective measures that will have the
maximum chance
of effectiveness