okay here we're look at nucleotides so
for those playing the home game we'll
recognize these as a monomeric unit or
the building block for our nucleic acids
we see them listed right here are we're
going to define our primitives and our
purines are your cells timing cytosine
adenine and guanine we'll make up our
nucleotides so looking specifically our
nucleic acids a nucleotide is composed
of three parts one is a nitrogenous base
and this is a nitrogen base containing a
carbon nitrogen ring so we see the
nitrogen is located here carbon would be
located here here here this indicates a
double bond between these two carbons so
one of the components of our nucleic
acids is our nitrogen containing base
that is linked to a five carbon sugar
we'll just call the pentose sugar and
this is ribose in RNA which stands for
ribonucleic acid and it's sugar would be
a deoxyribose in DNA you'll see it as
comparison between those two in a moment
then we have a phosphate group here
appeal for molecule you'll notice the
oxygens have negative charges to them
this is what gives
nucleic acids their negative charge on
their backbone because here we have the
oxygens creating that negative charge
this is kind of that base see located
here again and that's it's causing it to
have a negative charge so we do
electrophoresis
they'll be pulled towards a positive
charge so I said here can we spot the
difference between deoxyribose and
ribose looking specifically at that and
touch sugar there well if you look at a
little bit I mean you know deoxy means
without an oxygen you know so this is
missing something and we see that
indicated right here
our rainbows has an oxygen and the deoxy
is means without oxygen so therefore
that does not have oxygen bound to it
sugar now looking over here we have our
purines located up here the appearance
are a double ring and nitrogen base they
are classified as adenine and guanine
have these double ring structures
now on this side children over here
there were primitives and these are a
single ring nitrogen base and cytosine
which be present in both DNA and RNA
diamine will only be present in DNA and
uracil will only be present in RNA so
when we look at our nucleotides if that
can help us identify what particular
nucleic acid we are looking at lastly
here are pairing of nucleotides
nucleotides bond between DNA strands
what we call complementary strands they
are not identical there's always a
pureeing linked with a pyrimidine by way
of hydrogen bonds as we see here a vines
with T T binds with a G binds with C and
C binds of J's are complementary not
identical strands we look down one side
of the DNA adenine a by DT gives me a
complementary thymine on the other side
same thing here we see a guanine there
will be a complementary cytosine on the
other side when we're looking at
particular DNA because we see thymine
here hopefully that helps describes the
monomeric units nucleic acids