you may be familiar with the deter my
path assess but there's actually two
different types there's a null and
alternative hypothesis we're going to
explore what the difference is between
these two here so starting with the null
hypothesis no hypothesis is valid if it
cannot be tested no test is valid if it
results cannot disprove the hypothesis
niece is related to the null hypothesis
the null hypothesis is the formal
statement of the hypothesis not being
true in the tested results that will
support the null hypothesis so you know
right now you probably going through and
reading this and like the Terminator
like this doesn't really make a whole
lot of sense
we're gonna use an example in the next
slide that I think will help help this
process out the alternate hypothesis
though expects a difference or an effect
so the null hypothesis kind of like
saying nothing happened
and they alternate they're saying oh
look there was a difference what the
researcher seeks to prove through
testing is what the alternate hypothesis
involves is it's the opposite of the
null in this case something did happen
there wasn't output there was a result
so how does this look kind of in an
example well took an example here we're
looking at the effect of fertilizer X
and Plumpton growth so our alternate
hypothesis this is what the researcher
attempts to prove so this alternate
hypothesis here was the researcher
trying to prove application of
fertilizer x increases pumpkin growth
the null hypothesis keep in mind is the
opposite of that we're still looking at
the effect of fertilizer X and pumpkin
growth so the null hypothesis would be
application of fertilizer X does not
increase pumpkin growth this null
hypothesis what the visitor attempts to
disprove so in an example here
tend to disprove the fact that there is
no effect that is trying to show that
this will increase pumpkin growth here
that's the alternate Knolls like nothing
happens there when we're running our
tests though we look at these two
hypotheses we want to minimize results
based on chance as a result when I have
something called a control group
checking to make sure the same results
will not occur without test
intervention you see the control group
here with mice looking at non obese mice
and obese mice and comparing awesome
factors here and things that were
measured particularly fat group and
control group and calories from fat and
so on and so forth so this idea of the
control group what is this well let's go
back to our previous example so in here
would be our control group our control
group would make the pumpkin plants
grown with no foot fertilizer it could
be our control group in the sense that
maybe just the soil they're growing and
naturally makes them grow a little bit
better or worse so our control group
just sometimes the group that we poke do
nothing to and they might just get water
where we could have an example here
getting smaller doses of fertilizer or
greater just as a fertilizer the control
group in this case would be those that
got no fertilizer I don't want you
always to think that the control group
does something that you don't do
anything to an alternate kind of example
for our pumpkin plants again would be if
we gave plants fertilizer that the bag
recommended so if we look at a bag that
recommends a tablespoon per gallon of
fertilizer X that could also be our
control group that control group is
getting the labeled or the recommended
rate of fertilizer so again that control
group in summary is just something that
you want to be able to compare to and to
make sure you're not getting the same
results that occur without the
modifications that you're making to the
test group
lastly minimizing the results based on
chance there's all sorts of stats that
can be done here checking to see if the
same result could be caused by chance
example how likely to get four heads in
a row and flipping coins randomly versus
always starting with the coin on tails
be something that you could do your goal
is to develop an observed data point
that is consistently beyond the control
or in this case the average here and
this would be the typical average you
could look at average height thinness in
a grade there's two be the average
height and looking for something here
very unlikely these really very tall
kids a very short edge here we're using
stats and statistical analysis to
determine that hey there's results that
we're seeing may not be based on chance
but might be influenced by the test
program
that were instituting so it's kind of
just a general overview of our null and
alternate hypothesis and hopefully the
example here I'm looking at fertilizer
on plant growth is a way to kind of be
able to better understand the comparison
between these two