here we look at managing nutrients for
tomatoes and helispot particular
deficiencies so starting with calcium
what to look for a calcium deficiency a
rot spot that starts at the blossom end
of the tomato this is more common in
longer Tomatoes simply because the
calcium has longer to travel typically
runs out before it gets to the very end
how to prevent this will soil testing to
know if you're naturally low in calcium
and also make applications just before
fruit set of a calcium product if
there's known to be an issue of a paste
tomato choses blossom end rot that
you're seeing here in here may be
advantageous to start a calcium regimen
for your other varieties because there's
a longer Tomatoes they typically will
show it first and it can be a senator
others may be getting exposed to this so
treat as soon as you see it starting to
develop to prevent it from getting on to
the other crops they're how to control
well
cal-mag plus from botanic air or a
Bioman calcium if you're under organic
restrictions magnesium deficiency well
the lower leaves will start develop a
mottled look to them and progress to
brown lesions this is kind of how they
look I can see the brown lesions
starting to develop here monitor plants
and make applications if problems are
noticed before fruit set typically the
application would be any epsom salts
starting about a rate of about one
tablespoon per gallon this is in part
why cal-mag is advised because you get
both calcium and magnesium so you're not
getting blossom end rot and hopefully
not getting too much of this lower leaf
yellowing there's also potassium this is
browning of the leaf margins which is
the edges of the leaves here on the
other shoulders can be another
indication but so can some skulls so be
careful on your Sun scald areas how to
prevent you want to add a potassium
product with your irrigation water
especially if you're getting heavily
during the plant growth phase of
development as a result you have pushed
out or flushed out some of that natural
potassium does in your soil
sulfate potassium applications are
recommending a kelp can also add
potassium it's often not in quantities
needed especially during a heavy fruit
set of a plan
the nitrogen what to look for on our
nature and efficient which is not always
the case maybe early in the season I'll
be yelling branches and typically the
lower branches when a feed nitrogen
fertilizer especially early when the
salt on the cool side they may not be
greatly plant-available all the
nutrients in this is the easiest one to
fix so of all the things to be low in
choose to be low in nitrogen it's a
quick and easy fix if you apply nitrogen
fertilizer to a plant and ji6 best is
low in nitrogen wait about three days or
so if you water it in immediately and it
doesn't change in three to four days if
not nitrogen that's the problem it's
something else last thing we talked
about deficiency they want type of
excessive nutrients so over feeding of
one nutrient can block other nutrients
this is most common with nitrogen
doesn't benefit the plant it can cause a
reduction in yield
Griese is very healthy put in quotes
looking plants that look just huge but
they don't really produce much in the
way of fruit you're shifting that plant
to grow more leaves than actually set
fruit it could also mean you over
fertilize potentially contaminate ground
water and you're also wasting time and
money so apply fertilizers at
recommended rates and with a soil test
to know if you should be adding that
nutrient in the first place