so this is gonna go over explaining what
a nutrient solution is and things to
look for when you're creating one now
put the picture here because this is not
a nutrient solution this is this regular
bag fertilizer now this might be able to
be mixed and made into a nutrient
solution but keep in mind this and it's
kind of raw solid form is not considered
a solution we need to in some way have a
solution the aqueous or dissolved in
water so since we're looking at us water
we need to start with target so what
what are we going to use so typically
what you want to start with is some
basic testing pH and EC or two easy
tests you can keep complete your targets
are starting with water in that six to
six and a half pH range in EC under one
hundred and fifty parts-per-million
reason why I want a low e seen this is
why ro or reverse osmosis water so
revered in for many growers in the sense
that the lower the EC is when you're
adding that allows you to add more
fertilizer and not have kind of waste or
background parts-per-million kind of
clogging up the availability of sites in
that water that you're using to irrigate
so pH is important as you remember that
peaches determines the availability of
nutrients in your plants if the pH
drifts this will negatively impact your
plants and we see that slightly acidic
range typically being where we wanted
want to keep our pH simply because most
of the nutrients are at the greatest
availability in this pH range you notice
for example calcium we get much more
acidic and we kind of lose that we start
getting into the basic range we see can
kind of iron will really drop out in
soil manganese that's why we want to
shoot for that slightly acidic pH and
want to monitor these so measure the
salts or nutrients in the solution we
want to start with a low ppm because
that provides you with more control over
what salts there were nutrients or salts
that are present in that solution having
a continual running meter is important
to help ensure you maintain levels at
the acceptable range typically you're
looking for around 300 to 700 parts per
million in EC of about half to 1.3 see
the bluelab guardian monitor here not
only managing measuring our parts per
million but our temperature and also our
pH this gives a quite a nice quick look
to see where you are and this is
slightly on the highest
I just kind of have it here I'm just
kind of waiting for it to balance out
maybe he's over at it just a little bit
but temperature looks real good and pH
is right in that general slightly acidic
range in that nutrient solution remember
that pH may be a Civic or basic
depending on what the main nutrient is
and that can be depending also on what
you're feeding so monitoring the page is
important with the ideal target for
cameras being again around that
six-and-a-half hour range it's good to
shoot for so depending on what nutrient
you might be feeding how you're making
that nutrient solution it can affect
whether it might be favoring more the
acidic range or more the basic arrange
so in hydroponics settings there are
minimal buffering factors which can lead
to drastic swings in pH it can stress
plants that's why I stressed the idea of
having continual monitoring because
without a buffer factor that pH can make
large swings when you're adding or
mixing nutrients whereas roots develop
there could be a lack of buffer in that
water depending on so solution you're
using so just keep it extra attention on
that if you're growing hydroponically
growing in media or the piece oilless
media or soil here these situations
there's more buffer factors and this can
help stabilize the pH and reduce large
swings from occurring even in heavy
feeding programs so it's one of the
benefits of growing in media it does
allow some of that buffer factor to
occur if you're going for example in
like a rock wall well there's a media
that really offers no buffering factor
so keep that in mind as far as what
meeting you're growing in soil is our
soil here there's a greater buffer
factor but you can still have swings in
pH so again watch the nutrient solution
that you're adding to your plants lastly
flushing plants so letting some solution
drain out of the growing container is
advised to help reduce excessive salt
accumulation in the root zone on this is
called flushing this is where you're
adding a lot of water and we have holes
hopefully in the bottom of your
containers if the catch basin here so
it's not making a mess anywhere and you
can kind of regulate and monitor how
much water is actually being flushed
through the media that you're using for
your plants so this helps explain a
little bit of nutrient solutions and how
they're utilized and what to look for to
maximize the efficiency of your grow