okay here we're look at some of the
basics of nutrient management for squash
and it can be whether you're managing
organic nutrients or chemical
fertilizers we want to start with a soil
test and to our Mendes our soils so that
we are in the optimum conditions to
start with now nutrient deficiencies in
squash we have nitrogen what I look for
is yellowing of older leaves done to
divine growth and overall this kind of
limey green color you want to fertilize
with nitrogen-based fertilizer
especially early in the season when the
soil is cold didn't have a chance to
warm up quite yet continue regular but
small doses and nitrogen fertilizer
until we get to kind of fruit set
anything back off the picture I want to
show you here that I've taken of a field
really shows nitrogen deficiencies and
how they can change you can see the
plants in the back here are stunted in
yellow compared to the ones here this is
a very small area two three four or five
only about six seven plants long and we
could see that the nitrogen shifts
between here here particular knowing the
background of this field personally this
was a wetter area and as a result this
leached out more of the nitrogen and
this held more than nitrogen so it can
be even in this small plot of an area
you can have different requirements for
nitrogen so just something to keep in
mind there potassium deficiencies this
is leaf browning typically at the
margins which typically coincide with
fruit set or occurs shortly after fruits
begins to swell how to prevent this well
if you're known to be low in this you
can by adding you start adding some
potassium what about the flowers start
to open so you don't get into this
deficiency standpoint if caught early
can be corrected if it's caught late
yields may suffer high potassium
fertilizer like potassium sulfate is
recommended and we see that here at I
spotted here in this field this the
Martins are starting to burn this was
late in the season so not a major issue
but assign that this field in future is
probably low in potassium and we have
the low inside we also have the high
inside high nitrogen improves plant
growth but can actually impact and
reduced yield watch folio applications
as large and thin leaves of squash can
burn very easily
they can also get thin and crack they
can get this really aged look that's
picture of me here with some really tall
leaves here here's a typical gardeners
globe giant leaf this is all indication
of excessive nutrients which we want to
avoid because not only wasting the time
and the money of applying them also
could be contributing to soil
contaminants