okay here I'll look at the nutrient film
technique which is involved with
hydroponics typically abbreviated n ft
you can see in this diagram we have a
nutrient solution with an airstone and
keep it aerated nutrient pump pumping
that nutrient solution here at the top
level of a trough the water then through
gravity flows down passing over the
roots allowing plants uptake vital
nutrients and then exiting out the
bottom here back into our reservoir
sometimes timers can be used to run this
other times this will be run for a
continuous to 24 hours now this NFD
technique allows for high degree of
detail and can maximize performance we
see the very same setup here this
supplies aerated nutrient solution to
the roots of the plant and the plants
with a strong root system are
established with a capillary mat and are
fed a continually aerated nutrient
solution in a channel system this allows
for the recirculation of that nutrient
solution with a holding reservoir the
size of that reservoir will depend on
the amount or area that you'll be kind
of running the nutrient solution through
irrigation is typically done for a
continued 24 hours some will have timers
that will turn off for a short period of
time but may times is run off for 24
hours plants are commonly grown in rows
that are tightly covered to allow for a
high humidity within the root zone again
we see the same basic setup here hoping
that water through and allowed to drain
back if the roots dry out they will die
and this is why it's important to
maintain a high degree of humidity
there's also concern about the pumps and
the spread of disease and this is why
these inners should be covered and
should be monitored so that we're not
spreading disease throughout the entire
operation here now because of this a
variety of reasons this technique is
actually lost popularity and it's
typically used with hobby growers or
those that are growing lettuce
there's lots popular in a large scale
for the fear of quick spreading of
disease in a recirculating solution and
this is why it's been shied away from
now an urban media like Rockwell is the
preferred source for large-scale
operations provide plants with the
continual access to water but it can be
more beneficial to have specific
irrigation events for fruiting crops
this is another reason why it's been
lost its popularity on large-scale
production this if a crop is looking at
producing the fruit are a heavy
carbohydrate load it might be beneficial
to actually have some dry down events
and have some re irrigation events here
with this 24-hour system with continual
flow of nutrients might be best for the
consistency of leafy greens but not so
much for those looking at high fruit
load stress