so if you're involved with cannabis
production you may want to be
considering some form of odor control
depending
who your neighbors are who's in your
vicinity as a result debaco university
here will provide you some ideas and
suggestions
for odor control
[Music]
all right if you're looking for ways to
reduce the odor of your cannabis plants
you've come to the right place
so first off keep in mind that filters
make a good addition
in general whether we're looking at
removing odors or not
it's good to kind of have those in place
but utilizing intake filters
in particular can help control air
that's being brought into the grow area
this can involve removal of insects and
also
particles from the air but these will
not impact the odor around the plants
so here we're specifically going to be
targeting the smell generated by the
cannabis
plants so if we've grown canvas plants
there is that distinctive odor
that they do produce every early on
plants will have a minimal amount of
odor so you might think oh we're getting
bite is fine
however in the three to five weeks old
odor will start to become
apparent and odor will start in the
vegetative stage but will really become
much more apparent during the flowering
stage
so if odor is an issue early keep in
mind that it'll become a much bigger
issue
later in the growing cycle so you want
to plan for that ahead of time
there's not when the plants are small
it's only going to get quote worse
or more prevalent so you want to be
considering an odor
control option now you want to consider
your neighbors meaning
while odor control has little impact on
the actual plant's productivity
it can be the difference between growing
or not growing your plants again
depending on who your neighbors are
or particularly where you're located
hard to do it in an outdoor situation
but for indoor situations
we have greater control and we'll go
over some of those options for you
so odor control and ventilation
hopefully you're having some form of
ventilation regardless
but the growing area because that
typically is required by the growing
area
so when it comes to odor control this
often requires some simple modifications
or additions
if you're moving air through and
ventilating your area like you should
anyway
adding one of these odor control options
should be fairly easy
once you've gone through the initial
investment so you want to consider the
different options you have available to
you there's not just one option
you want to evaluate the options and you
should take into account the size of the
area in the operation
and the degree of order control you want
to achieve or just looking at reducing a
little bit
or looking at really making it
non-existent so i want to present some
options here give you the advantage and
disadvantages
of all the options presented here you're
welcome to search tobacco university
here for more detail
on each of these starting with the first
one here looking at carbon filters
the advantages is that it allows for
high airflow volumes
very easy to install and comes in a
variety of sizes
however the disadvantage with carbon
filters is they cannot be used
in highly humid conditions you start
getting above 75
plus percent humidity their
effectiveness really decreases
they also do not need to be changed out
after after a period of time so
keep in mind that you do need to change
these you just can't put them in there
and like up they're all set it's all my
carbon filter
and if you notice after a couple grow
cycles it may not be working as
effectively
because they do need to be changed over
a period of time
don't just set it and forget it forever
they will need to be replaced at a
certain point
there's also ozone generators so the
advantage is no chemicals or residues
easy to use and operate however the
disadvantages is they cannot be used in
high traffic areas where people will be
present
and regulation ozone limits may limit
their effectiveness meaning the
degree of ozone that's needed for odor
control
kind of may conflict with certain limits
set by
certain governing agencies sprays and
absorbing gels as our last one the
advantages are very easy to add to a
ventilation system
the disadvantages they do not eliminate
they really only mask the odors
unlike some of the others that we have
talked about previously they will kind
of
these ones just kind of mask the odors
they also need frequent replacement
and need to be purchased in a timely
manner to when they're
planned to be used so if any of these
sounded of interest to you
welcome to search the channel to get
some more details