I hear me looking at odor control for
cannabis now I want to keep in mind that
there's an odor control the final
product this is gonna focus on odor
control during the actual grow phases
through the plant odor controls more
important later in the stages early on
cannabis wall does have a distinct odor
will not necessarily be as pungent early
on but as it progresses and ages
typically around week six or so the odor
will become more prevalent so canvass an
order control well the air circulation
is needed it is not advised to be
directly exhausted air from your grow
facility due to this negative odor that
can be produced there's no harm in this
but the reason why you may want to
consider this odor control is if you're
in an area it could increase odds of
complaints that everyone enjoys the
smell of growing cannabis plants I think
that charcoal filter will drastically
reduce the pungent odor the cannabis
odor while you're exhausting air out so
you don't want to have a fan this scent
air directly out especially if in the
area where you could have a complaint so
that could arise there's an ozone
generator this converts oxygen ozone
which is o3 by exposing it to UV light
this could help reduce odors it changes
the charges of things it binds and
neutralizes with those odor molecules
and this reduction now does take up some
time for this ozone to come in contact
with these smelly cannabis particles
this can be prohibitive in areas that
have high areas of volume exchanges also
UV light is dangerous and so it's ozone
for both you and the plants so cautious
caution is advised if you're
implementing this type of system also
the oh three molecules are unstable only
lasts for about half an hour or so about
30 minutes and if you are using ozone
and it does somehow come in contact with
the plants and high doses that can
damage the plants or if it comes in kind
with the grower that can be another
caution because it couldn't damage
humans lung tissue as well so just be
cautious if you are looking at
implementing an ozone generator type
system for odor control what is more
advised is carbon filter for odor
reduction there should be installed for
operations through the entire grow they
said is most important for that week six
or on
so that's when odors tend to become more
of an issue be sure to size your system
accurately don't know something it's too
small you can favor going slightly
larger if you need to but be sure that
you have an idea of what size would be
recommended if you're not enriching with
co2 then you can easily increase the
power of the exhaust fan to compensate
for potential for reduced airflow when
you're running something through a
filter there will be reduced to airflow
and this not injecting with co2 you can
afford to kind of increase the rate
exhaustion of air and ventilation
without worrying about exhausting out
your precious carbon dioxide so this
activate chart charcoal filter we see
pictured here our surface areas
increased with oxygen open pores
increase the absorbing mists of the odor
and they typically can be covered here
so the carbon is on the inside
this as an extra filter here to ensure
clean air is being evacuated out of the
grow tent is mounted very high so I'm
exhaust in the hottest air as well and
represent virgin activated carbon this
was recommended to due to its very high
surface area and potential for the
longest life possible to maximize the
effectiveness of a activated charcoal
filter you want to keep the baby below
55% 65 to 72 will reduce performance and
80% plus stops performance what this
means is simply if you're running this
in an area with very high humidity such
as for a cloning area again they don't
have the pungent odor to begin with but
if you are looking at run that in area
with high humidity those high humidity
those moisture will kind of clog up and
eliminate some of the surface area there
for that carbon to act as they remove
the odors what I have the air moves
slowly through it and one of the over
sizing this fan and pulling it right
through and right out because you there
needs to be some contact time between
the odor and the activated carbon if you
use a pre-filter and that's what you see
here to remove particulate and change on
a regular basis about every 60 days
depending on the quality of air that
you're dealing with so again this is a
pre-filter
easily removed and will help protect and
extend the life of your activated carbon
on the inside so as you can see this is
for odor control your indicators plan to
help reduce
potential for complaints size is
important in life and that you're using
and exhausting dosing or not dosing
enriching with co2 is important so all
these factors come together but this is
just another thing to consider if you're
looking at trying to reduce the chance
of having complaints if you're growing
cannabis here with neighbors or people
nearby