all right here we're gonna look at oil
in sweat glands and hopefully by the end
of this we'll be able to provide a
comparison between oil-producing glands
and sweat producing glands now let's say
oil this is actually vegetable oil but
just trying to give you that visual
comparison between the tail mostly is
gonna be located you see here in the
dermal region of the skin so starting
with our sebaceous glands or oil glands
they occur over the entire body except
the palms and soles
they're simple Abiola glands and the
hollow crown secretions they basically
the entire cell will break up to form
the secretion we're going to see a
comparison between oil and sweat glands
later in this video these oil glands
secrete this oily substance called sebum
and are mostly associated with the hair
follicles we see here so here's our
sebum and associated with that hair
follicle again that image of the skin
comes back and hopefully it's starting
to make more sense with each video that
you watch so the sebaceous clear that
oil producing glands what does the sebum
actually do you could see it kind of it
here it's providing a lubrication to the
hair and also the surrounding skin it's
also softening both of these regions now
it is an oil so it's hydrophobic and it
also provides some waterproofing some
resistance to water of both the hair and
skin it's being secreted and covering
all this region it can also collect dirt
to help maintain cleanliness of the skin
and overall health of the individual for
example you see again located here is
our sebaceous gland here's our hair
follicle there just seem super releasing
to the surface of the skin now sweat
glands just to take a step here of sweat
glands so we're gonna do a little
comparison there's two main types they
occur over the entire skin surface
except nipples and parts of external
genitalia and they prevent overheating
they can produce a total up to 500 CCS
cubic centimeters can also think about
as milliliters to 12 liters of sweat per
day and that is gonna be mostly water
and they are could be activated or
produce these secretions
due to heat or also stress is another
way that these sweat glands can be
activated they're just an example of
when located here within the dermal
layer of the skin
now sweat glands are pseudo risk Lambs
the American or a cocoon glands most
abundant sweat gland they produce what
we call true sweat about 99 percent
water with some salts they contain some
traces of metabolic waste up to 2% urea
not really any more than that staying at
the 99 verse and they open through pores
and their role is thermal regulation so
that can cool the body they're widely
present in the skin the 500 can be
located in just a single square
centimeter on the body I see an image
here that secretion again this is
occurring through pores and you're going
to notice a comparison between the other
two how it's very different so American
here also epic rating the kind of
interchangeable terms these sweat glands
are being secreted in this case now
another type of sweat glands they apple
crying are the apex or top of the cell
breaks off so if you think of that had
an apex a peer into apex at top of the
cell contain organic molecules that
decompose over time resulting in this
odorous secretion so because the cells
breaking off we're putting this we have
a lot more than this water being kind of
released here ducts open into the hair
follicles absent before puberty this
occurs only after puberty do these
particular glands develop the president
in the armpit genitalia areas and they
release proteins lipids and form of
steroids and so because we're getting
proteins and lipids being released in
parts of the cell this is what's
reducing that odor it's a lot more than
just water with so little salt in it
this is actual portions of the cell the
last one here going back to oil glands
there's produced in these are so you may
add a little bit of a comparison between
all three of them hello crying the
entire cells break me down he's
releasing the sebum was in an oil
lipid-based remember that's hydrophobic
it's lubricating the skin and retards
bacterial growth both benefits to the
body and skin found on the face chest
and back regions so mature cell dies and
becomes a secretory product so how do
all these kind of three compare
well here's a nice summary slide showing
the secretion versus is helping pinched
off kind of that producing that odor and
here we have an entire cell basically
being broken down producing that sebum
which is that oily substance lastly for
comparison our sebaceous or oil glands
versus our a book written in our attic
Rhine glands well we have to look here
at our images so some are separated out
from the hair follicle and here's our
sweat gland located with the hair
follicle and again our oil gland also
associated with that hair follicle are
eco cryin glans or apocrine glands
located here one is independent the
zuzia Ukraine we see here in the blue
and our apocrine glands here are
associated with the hair follicle keep
in mind don't forget these sebaceous or
oil glands are also associated with the
hair follicle as we see here so again
what's inserted with the hair pockets it
out great for identification purposes
and can also help you remember where
they may or may not be found within the
body