this debacco University video I'm going
to go over optimizing magnesium
fertilizer rates for cannabis
[Music]
production okay our goal is not to over
fertilize plants so how do we go about
optimizing and avoiding plants that look
like this here we're going to look at
magnesium uh in particular and its
importance so here's the research study
and the citation that goes along with it
if you want to look at the original
study in more detail
so first off what's the importance of
magnesium why should we be concerned
about magnesium it is an essential
macronutrient for plant growth and
Metabolism which may be disrupted under
magnesium deficiency or toxicity
conditions it involves the in
photosynthesis by activation of the
ribos biphosphate carbas oxye enzyme
typically referred to as rabisco and as
a central component of the chlorophyll
molecule and we can see that located
right here as magnesium molecule being
right in the center of that chlorophyll
molecule and then here's rabisco
important for the photosynthetic process
it's also important for cell division
involved in the activation of several
enzymes acts as a phosphorous carrier in
plants is essential for plant
respiration and essential component
again of the chlorophyll MC as we saw
here um so many many roles that
magnesium plays now what are this
deficiency symptoms well inter vinal
yelling of the leaves typically first
seen in the lower leaves or the older
leaves um on the plant of course this is
an extreme case but did that interanal
meaning if you're looking at the veins
of the um plant it's going to be in
between those veins inter vinal is what
that's referring to um and typically
it's first seen on those lower or older
portion leaves
first now looking at the study here 30
days after the initiation of the
magnesium treatment visual appearance of
the plants under 2 20 3540 and 140 U mg
per liter of magnesium Supply the very
top here we're looking at the plants
themselves from kind of a zoomed out
macroscop look and again magnesium
concentration here so the lowest here is
on the left and the highest is on the
right then we get to the um next row
here we're looking at the uh youngest
mature leaves in the second row and then
the older leaves uh from the bottom of
the plant again this be your third row
and we could see definitely those older
leaves definitely showing it here in
that very low treatment and we've got
the roots also in comparison there which
visually may not have very Stark
differences uh but again we're looking
at the whole plant here so what's the
effect of U magnesium Supply there well
the effect of magnesium Supply on macro
and micronutrient concentrations in the
leaves stems and roots of medicinal
cannabis plants so leaves are
represented by the green circles stems
by the uh red triangle and Roots by the
dark blue squares and we can see again
here's our nitrogen here is our
potassium here is our um calcium here's
our zinc iron manganese magnesium as
well and then phosphorus so this is a
presented data and we can see as those
magnesium concentrations change some
things remain relatively stable uh and
other things have uh changes not always
greater so we could see that definitely
at the low concentration of magnesium uh
to them there's this immediately
leveling off here of nitrogen in the uh
leaves uh the stems and also um The
Roots so leaves here Roots here and then
stems here others you know correlate
differently here for potassium we see an
overall increase in our root amount of
magnesium but a decrease in the leaves
and also the stems so just kind of an
interesting correlation or a look at and
as again we increase magnesium we would
expect magesium concentration overall to
increase in all parts of the plant so
what does this kind of mean what's this
kind of uh relate to and why is this you
know why should we be concerned about
this
well because magnesium interacts
particularly with calcium as well as
potassium so increased magnesium Supply
impaired the uptake of calcium potassium
in their root to shoot translocation
demonstrating a compe a competitive
cation inhibition what does that mean
well calcium and potassium are both
positive or cat I as well as magnesium
we've got a lot of magnesiums here
globbing onto the negative soil
particles you're going to impair the
root hair's ability to absorb those
other cat ions s it's going to kind of
block or suppress the ability for plants
to absorb the very important potassium
as well as calcium ions so having two
high of one nutrient can block or
suppress others now what's the possible
effects on that soil Aggregates as well
excessive fertilizer applications may
have more impact than just nutrient
levels possible effects of calcium and
magnesium cats and soil aggregation more
calcium attracts clay particles together
to form Aggregates or form uh basically
a well- defined structure there versus
more magnesium repels clay particles and
break aparts breaks apart those
Aggregates the Aggregates are important
because we do want them to have that
cation exchange capacity and interact
with the roots and if we over add our
magnesium we're causing repelling or
breaking apart of that basic soil
structure now min max um levels here
it's definitely a minimum level
magnesium deficiency symptoms develop
first on those older leaves it was shown
at 2 Mig per liter and progressed
towards um young mature leaves
demonstrating the ability for magnesium
in plant storage and also remobilization
it can move magnesium toxicity symptoms
appear in older Leaves From the Bottom
of the plants under 140 milligram per
liter of magnesium so what's the general
uh target range and what could we add to
correct this if we're below Optimum well
the findings suggest that 35 to 70 U
milligrams per liter of magnesium is the
optimum concentration again it is a
range uh for canis plant development and
function at the vegetative growth phase
this can be converted here to parts per
million or ounces per gallon and this is
again looking at pure mag magnesium
we'll talk about some fertilizers I just
want to draw your attention to he that
below Optimum again is the red there's
an Optimum range and then there's above
Optimum so if you get a soil test back
you want to be in that Optimum range now
and this shows the above Optimum kind of
remaining level but a lot of times if
you get too excessive you can actually
have a decrease in yield toxicity
symptoms can lead to a decrease in yield
so staying in that Optimum range is
really the target of any grower so what
are if we're low in magnesium what could
we add well dolomitic lime if we need to
adjust our soils or substrates uh pH
would be a great addition that contains
about 99.5% uh magnesium Epsom salts if
we need to have something water soluble
to water in uh it contains a little bit
more magnesium slightly
99.87% and for something continuous
feeding wise and typically plants need
calcium anyways a Cal Mag fertilizer
here which may only have 1 2% magnesium
but continually being fed can slowly
build those levels up or really maintain
those levels within that Optimum range
again don't want to get too excessive
because then negative things can happen
don't want to be under we don't have
reduction in yield want to stay right in
that Optimum range and hopefully this
study gives you that Target of what that
Optimum range actually is