okay here we're gonna learn a little bit
more about the oral cavity looking at
some of the details that occur in our
mouth in relation to the digestive
system starting with functions of the
oral cavity
well there's sensory analysis of natira
before swallowing recognition kind of
determining texture mechanical
processing which occurs through the
teeth and the surfaces in the oral
cavity lubrication is occurring with
mucus and salary' gland secretions and
there's some digestion it's limited but
mainly carbohydrates and some lipids
salivary amylase is one of the key
enzymes it's produced and that is
starting the breakdown of carbohydrates
you ever had a cracker I'm just kind of
kept it in your mouth eventually it kind
of break down turn into mush and
ultimately liquid we did the same thing
with like a piece of gum or something
high in fats that same process will not
happen because you only have enzymes
specific to carbohydrates and some
minimal on lipids now breaking down the
food in the mouth many variants have
teeth that allow for chewing
massification of the food now we're
going to see a carnivore or herbivore in
an omnivore looking at incisors canines
premolars and molars all color-coded
appropriately here in the carnivore
there's a only eat meat see the
noticeable designers and the canines are
very pronounced here at the example of
our Tiger timers a pointed teeth they're
adapted for cutting and shearing
herbivores those plant eaters such as
the deer those have flat teeth here's
your molars and our premolars wilson for
grinding of plant cellulose help to kind
of mechanically break down the very
complex elyes also notice their incisors
and canines are in very small amount
here it's actually kind of a gap here in
their teeth so you have a lot of the
premolars and molars for that break down
then are omnivores these have kind of
the teeth of the carnivores in the front
and kind of also the teeth of the
herbivores in the back to allow them to
eat both meat and plant materials and be
able to efficiently break them down from
the mechanical process continuing on to
the tongue on the superior surface of
the tongue actually bears three
different types of Hawaii we have the
Philly form which is to give the tongue
the roughness and provide
friction kind of what friction in the
tongue so you can be able to move that
food around thumb the form is scattered
widely over the tongue and give it that
reddish kind of hue as we see here
circum of the left is the v-shape row in
the back of the tongue and it's kind of
waiting towards the back section there
and then our sulcus terminalis is the
groove here that separates the tongue
into two areas we see the anterior 2/3
residing in the oral cavity and the
prostitute here residing in the oral
Phoenix
farik's which is important when we're
starting to ingest our food as it begins
its way or its path through the
digestive system in the mouth the tongue
mixes the food and solution called
saliva the saliva license and lubricates
the food contains amylase which remember
is an enzyme it's important for the
breakdown of starch starch is a
collection here of glucose molecules all
them together hey Lois here's considered
like that starts clipper breaking down a
disaccharide apply polysaccharide
Astellas could be maltose and the
monosaccharide of maltose would be
glucose disaccharide leading to glucose
is learned together
- decorating one here see you again Paul
II died and monosaccharides amylase
breaking down our starch multi is
breaking down our maltose
so remember ASE at the end important for
identifying potential enzymes in the
mouth our celery glands are controlled
by the nervous system to see where
they're located right here continuous
secretion of about 0.5 milliliters per
minute keeps the mouth moist and in the
presence of food this triggers an
increase in the secretion rate the
reason why I might want to increase in
secretion rate Maivia to lubricate the
food as it starts to enter the digestive
system we also want an increased number
of enzymes that start breaking down some
of those carbohydrates
lastly the bolus as a bollock mixture of
food and saliva that forms in the mouth
during the process of chewing we have
that bolus forming if that's gonna be
turned ultimately into time and that
time will be broken down into nutrients
which will be absorbed and all the
leftover material will be excreted from
the body in the form of feces once the
bullet roots of the stomach and mixed
with the gastric juices becomes kind so
keep in mind it's kind of the same
collection of food but depending where
it's located what it's mixed with that
will change its name so if you're
looking for identifying certain areas
that same thing that was called a bolus
up here we call kind once it reaches the
stomach and mixes of gastric juices
further digestion and absorption and
eventually will be discharged again as
feces