on this tobacco university video we're
going to look at oral drops derived from
cannabis and provide you a little bit
more of a detailed and description
so you can have an understanding of just
what these are
all right let's get into oral drops
derived from cannabis well first off i
want to thank
ct pharma because they provide publicly
available you know
local reports and labels uh the
descriptions
options and uses here are intended to
provide an understanding of some
end products of the cannabis plant ct
farm does a great job of making that
publicly available
and has a model for many other companies
and manufacturers
so first off description of what oral
drops are well typically
an example here a marijuana extract
blended together
in a solution with natural flavors and
medium chain
triglycerides and cts for
a convenient discrete easy to use drop
form
now the oral drop options that exist
there are two different oil drop options
there's
standard drops of marijuana extract
those natural flavors and those mcts i
talked about
there's also nano drops which are amino
marijuana extract blended
in water soluble based for precision
micro dosing
so again you have the regular and then
the nano for that precise micro dosing
these drops are available in high cbd
varieties as well
high thc varieties and a mix of both thc
and cbd so again be
mindful of what you're seeking and make
sure you're getting that particular
product
oil sprays are also available as these
are lower dose flavored solutions
they can be sprayed directly into the
mouth now the use of oral drops
well they're highly convenient way to
ingest marijuana or cannabis in general
as there's no smell no need for any
combustion they also come in many
different dosage forms
the drops can also be combined with food
or drink to allow for an easier
consumption
these drops are highly effective for
patients with respiratory problems as
there is no inhalation requirement
to consume these are some of the
benefits that they offer
now what those benefits well anything
you're looking at purchasing
always go back to make sure you can get
a certificate of analysis report
want to make sure that it's dated and
the lot numbers match up
many people will be looking of course at
the terpenes and cannabinoids and that's
all and good but we want to also be
looking at the
microbial analysis heavy metals
microtoxin pesticides to make sure our
products are passing those
a lot of times the numbers provided here
will hopefully appear also on the label
and that's great that they have this
label and make it really easy to read
but make sure you're also able to access
the original documents we see here
to encourage that there it's a current
test the lot numbers match up
just so you can be a well-informed
consumer more so just looking at the
label
making sure you know where to access
that information that supports
the numbers presented there on the label