okay me here the term organic compost
teas tossed around a lot it's iffy I
should provide you with a little
background and exactly what these are
and teases you we see here as we think
about may have in the morning or you
know with that brunch a very similar
concept here at organic compost teas but
I'm getting compost teas probably want
to drink those so they're a liquid
extract of a solid based compost that's
the basic term organic teas here so
putting me the teabag layer that allows
water to come in we're kind of
developing a liquid extract of what
normally would be solid the event
benefits are said to be able to add to
supercharged liquid of microbes to your
soil and I'm taking the idea of what's a
solid form and creating a purified
liquid form which opens up your
opportunities for application now while
there already many microbes in the soil
in organic tea increases the rate of
replication kind of being the ideal
environment for them however there's
little control of the exact microbes
that are being produced or replicated in
many cases they were going to keep the
limitation is important to realize this
process doesn't create anything new it
only provides an environment to allow
the naturally occurring microbes in the
compost to multiply so you're not really
developing anything brand new you're
just kind of multiple increasing what's
already there in developing it into a
form it can be applied in many different
ways
the organic tea studies they're
scientific studies showing effectiveness
are limited for organic compost teas
while dr. Elaine Ingraham is considered
to be the gold standard there are a few
replicated studies that support many of
the claims
so again just because you find one
article you want to go through and find
it from multiple sources so if you have
a good not only a good understanding but
multiple sources to support that
particular common view so that was a
brief overview hopefully that gives you
just that basic background and of
exactly what an organic tea is