here we take a brief look at organic
hydroponic production - producing a
hydroponic grow with organic based
nutrients now growing hydroponically and
organically can present some challenges
organic nutrients can take longer to
become plant available so in hydroponics
where fruits may be only exposed to
nutrient solutions for very short
periods of time this is something to
keep in mind
organic based products can be less
stable in solution resulting in a
greater chance for a potential shift in
pH or EC electrical conductivity changes
that could occur so just keep these two
things in mind especially when growing
hydroponically organic nutrients can
also have more particulate than other
nutrients which can clog systems and
lead to more frequent operation
cleanings so again this is necessarily a
bad thing but just keep in mind that if
you are switching to more organic based
nutrient solutions there's a chance that
they might contain more particulate so
according to change filters more often
or to keep make sure that the spray
nozzles are clean I make sure that it
may have more of a muddy or water or
look to that and this made custom routes
to potentially not look pure white they
could have a slight teeth kind of color
to them now it could be a sign of
disease but often times if you're using
organic production as a very strong deep
coloration to the water that's going to
tinge the color of the roots yeah and
not necessary a bad thing just something
to keep in mind lastly we also want to
be mindful that just because you're
growing organically doesn't mean you
can't pollute it's the same as chemical
fertilizers if you're not careful so
still keeping an eye on the nutrients
that you're adding and knowing how much
it you're adding in eliminating runoff
can also keep your plants healthy keep
your plants doing well but also not
contributing to environmental
contaminations especially with
hydroponically with a lot of water based
solutions we want to be mindful for
changing their solutions out to not just
dump them down the drain I'm gonna try
to get the maximum we want for
efficiency at the plant but also so
we're not wasting anything in
contributing to groundwater
contamination especially with phosphorus
that's true for both organic and
inorganic operations but our gimmicks
can also pollute so again
run those numbers double-check
just to make sure you're operating in a
sustainable way