here on debaco university we're going to
be investigating some organic forms of
nitrogen
which are important for plant growth and
[Music]
production
all right let's get into organic and
nitrogen fertilizer options for cannabis
production
so first off options for organic growers
uh there
are nitrogen only others and nitrogen
dominant ratio ones
so some of these contain only nitrogen
some contain blends of other
nutrients as well which is important to
take into consideration
recover blood meal fish fertilizers bat
guano as well as manure
in this video so let's start with the
blood meal first
well blood meal is a byproduct of the
slaughter house industry
waste basically it's one of the highest
concentrations of nitrogen
in any non-synthetic source even though
it is organic
it can be over applied so keep that in
mind and it can burn
plants due to the excessive ammonia that
would be produced
now for the fertilizers here i've tried
to provide kind of
there's a link in the description to
where i got the source from but the
typical npk analysis
the time to release the pros cons as
well as application rate that's
recommended
now blood meal is uh 12 0 0 i've also
seen it's 13 sometimes zero zero
but it's basically all nitrogen with
little or no
amount of phosphorous or potassium so
again that's a great thing
it can be on the more expensive side as
you're looking for
a pound of nitrogen to dollar amount
just keep that in mind
then we get into different types of fish
fertilizer
so there's fish emulsion there's
hydraulicized liquid fish there's fish
meal there's fish powder there's a whole
bunch of different ones here and i'll
kind of break these
down so you can understand that while
fish fertilizer is one general category
there's a couple other more specifics so
start with the first one fish emulsion
well what fish emulsion is is kind of
the infamous for its foul smell
emulsions are soluble liquid fertilizers
that have been heat and acid processed
basically from fished waste and we can
see again all the same information
provided here
you can see typical as is these are five
one one this listed typically is five
two two
so again when you're looking at
applications be mindful of what
particular fertilizer you might have be
purchased
yourself then the liquid fish or an
enzymatically digested fish and probably
of this of all the enzymatically
digested liquid fish products
neptune's harvest is probably the most
name most people would recognize
and this is a digest of the nutrients
from fish wastes instead of using heat
and acids
so enzymes are using to kind of break
break this process down
it retains more of the proteins enzymes
vitamins and micronutrients
than emulsions do this is why this is
typically so commonly used within
growers and you can see the typical
ratio compared to these a little
different so again
just mindful the product you're using do
a fish meal which is fish meal is
basically ground and heat dried fish
waste
a little more variable a little bit
harder sometimes to kind of
mix with water though it is water
soluble may take a little warm water a
little more agitation to get that into
solution
so you can be utilized and given to your
plants
doing it to fish powder which fish
powder is
dried with heat and turned into water
soluble powdered form
its high source of nitrogen can be mixed
into solution and injected to an
irrigation system however while fish
powder is supposedly able to be injected
into the irrigation system if you are
going to be utilizing that
make sure you have a filter because some
fish powders are
more soluble than others and some may be
too
large of particles and may clog drip
emitter lines for example
so be sure you have that filter to
protect yourself so your fish powder
doesn't go through and clog
all your potential irrigation lines then
we get into bat guano
so baguano or feces harvested from caves
and is a
kind of a power powerful powdered
product
the powder can be applied directly to
the soil or mixed with water so it can
be applied in irrigation water
for delivery to the plants again make
sure you have a filter there
so you're preventing any clogging of any
drip lines and again also looking at you
know the past fertilizer with
the fish here fish meal keep in mind
there are potassium
and phosphorous numbers as well we see
that also with the
bat wanna keep mine there is cost
associated with background can be on the
more expensive side
you also have to think about the carbon
footprint it took to get that fertilizer
to you and then lastly we have manure
so for manure i can come from cows sheep
poultry
horses typically used as a soil
amendment contains more nitrogen
and because of this it's often used as
the main reason for adding manure to
soil
however manure's nutrient content is
small compared to other chemical
fertilizers
it can also help with soil structure
keep in mind though the nutrient values
will depend on the source of the animal
the bedding used
and the amount included so coarse
minerals a little different from cow
from sheep and poultry typically chicken
manure will be your most nutrient and
dense
for comparison so keep that in mind also
with manures if you are adding it's a
soil amendment that may require
higher amounts first year you'll get a
lot of nitrogen boost which would be
great
but the phosphorus and potassium can
reside in that soil for a number of
years
may cause you in years to come to switch
to a pure nitrogen source
because the phosphorus and nitrogen
sticking in that soil and getting the
benefits of the soil properties
don't keep adding manure every year
because your phosphorus numbers will
likely become in the excessive and
potentially toxic
range which could contaminate fresh
groundwater