if you're looking at organic soil
amendment options such as compost manure
peat moss and coconut fiber that's
important to mention we are focused on
soil here these are gonna be amendments
these are things we're going to be
adding to that soil to change or modify
its particular properties kind of
amending here we're not be growing in
pure compost or pure manure now I'd use
the term organic and for this purpose
it's going to mean to contains carbon so
organic here is relating to or
containing carbon compounds charcoal
diamonds and graphite all are carbon
compounds but the method or way that
they those carbon atoms are organized
gives these three materials there are
different properties
so compost it's a term that does not
define one single amendment but rather a
broad classification of amendments it's
important ask what questions to ask if
someone has compost our one is what is
the base material so some of those
compost that's a broad term you have to
keep that in mind Campos does that
always mean the exact same thing so
manure and leaves are a common with the
compost being preferred to reduce the
likelihood of developing excessive
phosphorus in soil conditions some
people use food scraps leaves straw
grass clippings all great compounds to
use manure can also be composted but if
you are worried about being high in
phosphorus these would be manure based
compost will raise phosphorus levels
another question asked if someone as
compost is how old or is it aged
typically older is better with about
three plus years being the target for
material that has not been
professionally managed but to picture
the trimmings here to kind of give the
idea of time that needs to occur the old
books here I need that manure or in
compost in general needs time to age
needs times to break down to make those
nutrients plant available another
question asked well how it's been
prepared it's been a static pile that's
the easiest but takes the longest time
to produce quality compost where was it
actively managed this is where piles are
turned and this is a preferred choice if
you have the option when new or as I
mentioned before this can be a great
soil amendment when used in moderation
over adding can lead to water
contamination and poor crop yields
almond or contains be aware of this and
how much you're actually adding Sosua
Posterous actually looks like if you
over or add areas have had excessive
phosphorous and freshwater we can get
this kind of algae bloom as we see here
if you think about it it only occurs on
a small scale well it can actually these
algae blooms occur in a large scales we
see here with the Great Lakes areas here
from image from space in the amount of
algae blooms again indicative of high
levels of phosphorous runoff going into
this freshwater system they have horse
manure it's very common to be easy to
get manure there's many types while
composting process is advantageous type
of animal influence the end product so
in particularly horse manure here this
tends to have more weed seeds and it's
often not fully composted and broken
down material also be careful not only
it's knew where you want to consider but
also the bedding horse stables ten days
a lot of sawdust bedding which actually
bind up a lot of the nitrogen and could
cause plants to be nitrogen deficient
even though the manure itself may
contain some levels of nitrogen chicken
manure is the hottest which means it has
the most nutrient dense newer in a
general sense a little goes a long way
with chicken manure be careful because
it can have a very strong odor that is
very unpleasant so if you're used to
getting for example cow manure and apply
in a yard a cubic yard to a certain area
you will not want to also apply a cubic
yard of chicken manure because this is
more nutrient dense and this is what's
called hotter manure
cow manure as often regard is the number
one choice to the well balanced end
product can be as you gotten in large
quantities spreads pretty easy so this
is one that is very sought-after by
growers for modifying their field
applications
clay pellets are another kind of
amendment you can add to soil clay is
cooked under high pressure causing it to
expand it drains well holds roots the
combination of air and nutrient
solutions can be reused but should be
sterilized between usage so you can see
here is a plant grown in just pure clay
pellets may be used to help aerate
certain soil conditions here typically
not used on the large scale but one that
is commonly used so I figured I should
mention it for some of its advantages
peat moss is very commonly found in
media mixes it maintains water well and
some ability absorbed 15 to 30 times
it's only in water all the material
itself contains no nutrients for the
crop it can affect the nutrient
availability and also be a soil
acidifier typically lime is incorporated
and we need to added in high peat moss
base growing media due to its tendency
to lower the pH or make it a more acidic
environment this is the bogs and kind of
what they look like here this is what
the end product is coconut fiber is a
product of the chocolate industry many
Brewers really like coconut base
materials however quality cal-mag
supplement is needed for if grown in
coconut fibers it is cal-mag here it's
the typically the fiber that's used got
the actual shells but it's separated out
and provides this kind of growing media
base
there's a peat moss debate so we're
talking about peat moss coconut fiber
some believe well should he must be
harvested 80% of the peat moss used the
United States comes from Canada it's
approximately 0.2 percent of this 270
million acres of cane Canadian peat bogs
being used for peat mining their efforts
made to kind of restore this peat bogs
after their kind of harvested but some
are believing that the result may not be
as it once was in its natural state how
many Pekinese are aware of this and it's
a hotly debated topic and they're
looking at you know maintaining
sustainability of that you can see this
compressed Bale here and it is product
of Canada did provide this link down
here for some more information if you
want to look at Pete versus Coco qua
we're looking at those two there's no
clear winner between one being is say
better than the other Tomas is a more
consistent product and also has existing
microbiology Coco can be highly variable
making it hard to plan a know which are
you working with from delivery to
delivery so again Brewers have grown in
both just fine as amendments but you
want to be mindful that Coco car can be
highly variable one batch to another