so in this lecture series we're gonna be
looking at osmoregulation
in fish now this is something you may
have to pause the video at certain times
to get a review and look at what some of
the images have I think if you once you
look at the whole thing it might make
more sense but initially I know this
section can be a little confusing so
we're looking at salmon here and striped
bass both of these fish are involved in
osmoregulation so it's a balancing act
the physiological system of fish operate
in an internal fluid environment that
may not match their external fluid
environment meaning the water inside the
cells of the fish may not match the
concentrations of salts on the water
outside the fish relative concentrations
of water and solids internally must be
maintained with very narrow limits this
is part of homeostasis so we can't
change the fish we can only change how
the fish is reacting to the environment
the internal environment is influenced
by the external environment the sense of
what the fish has to do this is a clown
fish living in salt water and this is a
sunfish living in freshwater we
understand what stress is most of these
fish are under so starting just in
general osmoregulation it's regulating
solute concentrations and balances the
gain or loss of water cells require a
balance between uptake and loss of water
excretion should make sense is it
getting rid of nitrogen metabolites and
other waste products so this is
balancing act
this özil regulation and excretion Osmel
regulation is based largely on
controlled movement of solutes between
the internal fluids in the external
environment there's this balancing act
that's occurring the fish in this case
is trying to maintain homeostasis but
the external environment could put a lot
of pressures on the cell and the
stresses on the cell so starting here as
a lot of challenges Osmo regulators
expend energy to control water uptake
and loss in a hyper osmotic or hypo
osmotic environment you may want to
review the diffusion and osmosis lecture
series if you're confused on some of
this well let's look at some of these
just in general this is comparing to
fish so we have our four
water fish and our saltwater fisher
sunfish and our clown fish the fish
salinity IV officially is 14 percent
that means the salt concentration inside
the cells in this fish is 14 percent
same thing here on our contest also 14
percent what is different val the
freshwater in water that's living in has
zero percent saline day it's freshwater
versus our clownfish has 35 percent salt
water as a result salts being absorbed
by the gills it's gaining water through
as moses look at the arrows pointing in
these fish do not drink because water is
being pushed in through osmosis a large
amount of dilute urine is evident in
freshwater fish contrast set to salt
water finish look at the arrows going in
there drinking seawater and what's being
excreted is salt through the gills it's
losing water through osmosis and small
amount of concentrated salty urine so
this is because of the different
environments that these two fish are in
looking specifically at that freshwater
fish when i say that live in a hypotonic
environment think back to this slide
here hypotonic if they did not regulate
the water intake these two should
essentially swell up to the point that
they could lice or burst their cells as
a result this water is constant beating
into as moses some salts being absorbed
by the gills they excrete a large amount
of dilute hearing a lot of water is
being excreted simply because the cells
again have 14% higher concentration
versus their a percent water is
constantly trying to move in as a result
these fish do not quote drink and this
is referring to the water fresh water
fish constantly take water by osmosis
they lose salts by diffusion and balance
it by excreting large amounts of dilute
urine salts lost by diffusion are
replaced in foods and the uptake across
their gills this isn't just a statement
of what the previous image shows so if
you found the previous slide better
that's great if not this puts it into
some nice bullets
freshwater fish challenges they tend to
lose ions and they tend to be gaining
water these are a couple fish species
for common to freshwater I've been in my
classroom and you're fortunate enough to
work at the pan fish lab station this is
a couple pan fish here they are black
crappie here yellow perch and in our sub
fish now let's look at this marine bony
fish our saltwater fish they live in a
hypertonic environment so what is
continually being lost as Moses water
lost as Moses because of the
concentration remember our fish still
has a 14 percent salinity but in this
case now our water is 35 percent
salinity it does drink seawater and salt
is being excreted through the gills as
well as small amounts of contrary
concentrated salty turns being lost
putting that into couple bolts here they
lose water by osmosis gain salt by
diffusion from food balanced water loss
by drinking seawater excreting salts and
filtration rates below very little urine
is excreted if nothing happened they
would shrivel up this is the type of
environment or stresses that's on them
and this again shows another image here
where we're seeing the direction of
movement of both water and ions sea
drinking seawater a lot being lost
through the gills and yelled salty urine
water through the skin is being
exchanged also a couple examples of
marine fish freshwater fish we talked
about this is marine fish so these are
fish that live in marine or saltwater
environments they tend to lose water and
gain ions so this is a flounder blue
fish and false albick are all examples
of marine fish these have very different
challenges than the freshwater fish and
all of these fish were caught in Long
Island Sound osmotic challenges again
this kind of shows you again our ozma
regular is explaining that energy to
uptake water as I said you may have to
pause the video and look at everything
that's going on here makes a great quiz
question for being able to compare the
stresses of freshwater fish and
saltwater fish so see some commonalities
and see some differences I try to keep
everything
same color look at the arrows and what's
moving in and out of the fish those are
examples of fish now we're looking at
pacifically sharks sharks fit into the
category is particularly sharks into
what we call Osmo conformers only some
of marine animals are ISO osmotic with
the surroundings and do not regulate
their osmolarity this means that the
fish salinity is 35% which is the same
as the environment that it lives in at
35 percent as a result they're ingesting
salts with their food water's being
absorbed to the gills and skin and salt
is excreted to the earing Osmo
conformers they're conforming to the
environment that they're in
as a result these sharks do not move
into areas with lower salinity into
brackish water because it would mess up
their ability to exchange ions water
ozmo conformers are conforming 35% fish
salinity 35% salt water salinity they're
conforming to their environment that
term osmolarity to sea having a
definition for it
solute concentration of a solution
determines the movement of water across
its actively permeable membrane this is
just referring to concentration of a
solution types of Osmo regulators
aquatic vertebrates gills are chief
organs for excretion themselves is a
carp kidneys are also evolved as Osmo
over guitar organs and fishes to remove
water or conserve water these are
examples of couple kidneys put it in a
graphical form if your asthma regulator
versus a conformer so if you're a strict
regulator it does not matter the
external conditions your internal
conditions are going to be strictly
regulated regulated meeting going to be
the same if you're a strict conformer as
the external environment increases so
does your internal environment
now an example of that would be salmon
they are strict as you see here not
conformal district regulators and in
this case this worm would be a strict
conformer so we flip back for a
I can see our regulators are regulating
they're maintaining that homeostasis
conformers are just changing what the
environment is perfect example here our
salmon regulating and our worm
conforming now when they conform this
organism Exodus label is general
organism just because they are
conformers does that mean they can live
and survive it that entire scale here
this is the area where this organ can
live if that salinity of the external
conditions gets too low this case is to
be the shark moving into brackish water
they can die it's lethal or if it's too
salty
it can also die there's this area where
they can live too high and too low could
be lead to death we looking at aquatic
organisms that are able to tell a wide
range of salinities
we have our American shad and our
American eel they move between the ocean
and rivers for spawning and reproduction
they spend part of their time in
saltwater in part and freshwater
migrating some migrate to the sea so
migrate off the river and the
Connecticut River here salmon I can come
up the river well we don't have a lot of
salmon we everyone smile couple come up
but we really have shad so shad kind of
did the same that salmon do they live
most of their time in the ocean and they
spawn in rivers and freshwater systems
they migrate up by the thousands of up
the Connecticut River beetles are doing
just the opposite they spend most of the
time feeding and growing in the river
and they're working their way down to
the ocean to reproduce so a Jonathas
fish are they like the American shad
they own that's been a very short time
in the river eyes are coming up to spawn
just shows that life cycle here is an
example the Connecticut River and where
things are going in estuaries and
freshwater and where they're living and
migrating to in the springtime eels are
working their way down south here to
where the ocean water is where this
salinity is higher and salmon or
American shad be working their way up
the river here here's some examples
convert salt water as adaptations to
freshwater and vice versa depending on
the direction of the migration and sea
they drink seawater and discharge salt
Gill's and in fresh water they stop
drinking and produce large leaves and
dilute urine in the gills uptake cell
not every fish can do this this is a
stress on the fish this kind of shows
where the American shad migrate up the
Connecticut River rocky here would be
approximately right about here
Middletown so it takes that little notch
so they can jump a very long way here at
the Holyoke dam they lifted the shad
over and they count them that's about 80
miles here and it can continue all the
way up through Massachusetts most spawn
in southern part Massachusetts in in
Connecticut waters so how do we do
stress in a stressed fish this is if you
get one you want to bring it home you
want to minimize the osmotic challenges
by placing the fish in conditions that
are I saw osmotic this could be to add
salt to the fresh water when
transporting fish this dilute salt for
the same situation for marine species
and its little cartoon here shows you
saw your life force dressed this poor
fish is really hoping no one pushes any
of these buttons and the power is up to
this circuit lastly we want to think
about more than just osmoregulation and
fish there's also temperature to
consider temperature exhibits their
greatest influence on fish texture
metabolism their digestion signals to
reproduce so if adding your fish to an
aquarium or pond be sure there's no
temperature or salinity shock and you
increase the odds that fish is going to
survive the next 12-24 hours
dramatically