okay here we're going to explore a
little bit about outdoor cannabis
production we see a private image of
that here this canvas is being grown
outdoors
it can also be considered in raised beds
whether each in their own separate
container they're on pallets to help
drainage so with outdoor production
there's some similarities but there can
also be some variability and exactly how
a grower chooses to go about this so
first off in general outdoor production
offers the least overall cost to
actually produce the crop it's a very
efficient method of production because
there's no need for lights electricity
you can utilize natural soil and that
may only require amendments instead of
basically starting from scratch as some
indoor grow operations have to go
through and do factors to consider when
growing outdoors climate there's soil
there's pests and there's neighbors or
what we call promiscuous pollen that may
be in the area there so looking first at
climate the US Department of Agriculture
hardiness zone map is a great place to
start looking at your particular region
you have to realize there might be micro
climates this only gives you a general
idea of what to expect you can also see
in your coastal areas there are large
bodies of water there can be moderation
in those temperatures compared to those
that might be far away or at higher
elevation and this is why if you follow
this degree of latitude it may not
always match up so if you're kind of
looking here you can see there's a lot
of variability but the west coast being
much warmer and then that same your
vehicle attitude here in kind of the
middle part of the country and here in
the Rocky Mountains also a great degree
of variability
now canvas is not frost tolerant as a
result frost is 32 degrees Fahrenheit or
zero degrees Celsius and lower that will
kill cannabis plant it's important to
keep these frost concerns in mind early
and late in the season for growing
outdoors walls of water this is what
they look like they can be used early in
the season to protect young seedlings it
is very labor-intensive but it doesn't
require any you know heat to be added
these water tubes basically heat up with
the sun's energy and get back some of
that heat during the day there's a time
investment in the unpractical on very
large operations remade style covers are
best suited for long rows and access
kind of like a blanket to help
tender vegetation remember only a heater
heated greenhouse can help protect the
crop if temperatures drop below 30
degrees otherwise they'll get up in the
morning and they look kind of melted or
black or damaged so you don't want to
kind of rely on these structures to get
them through and start them too early
these would be great if you kind of that
one kind of oddly cold night in the
early part or late partner growing
season
now soil there's many different soil
types to consider Clay's santé loam and
its main distinctions between those soil
testing is highly advised and
recommended both nutrients and texture
which can tell you a lot about a growing
site especially if it's in rented or new
field too you should also given that
idea if it's worth pursuing the location
if estimated cost to be too high to
amend it and we can make anything we
kind of need to but in order to get this
soil to kind of produce this it might be
cost prohibitive now to prepare the soil
the ideal times in the fall too a lot of
time for pH adjustments in particular if
it's necessary and give time for the
breakdown of amendments that may be
added so they can become plant available
in this frame still can be adjusted in
the spring but large changes need to
equilibrate over time which can limit
limit potential damage to the crop so
the earlier you can plan something that
really can have that soil test done
really earlier you can adjust that pH
the better your plant will be the
following season organic matter is
carbon-based components of soil you see
here being turned here's a chicken
manure and straw would be examples here
this often gets a lot of attention it
can be raised to very high levels with
excessive compost additions more is not
better necessary with organic matter
it's important for water holding
capacity but too much water holding
capacity and nutrients can cause more
harm than good people have been known to
burn their plants with excessive
additions of organic matter also it can
hold too much water in that area or
roots become waterlogged for a large
fuel application there's something
called a hard pan what this is the soil
compacted below the surface so if you
just kind of scratch the surface it
might be great but there could be this
hard hand layer located below that area
this can be an issue with where heavy
equipments being used can occur so it's
being worked when it was too wet or an
era been plowed excessively I
have that issue there of that hard plan
or that plow painful air but this is it
creates a layer that doesn't allow
natural percolation of water and Kanaly
impact root development so this is
something to be mindful of you're
looking at potential citement dig a hole
these penetrators or ways to kind of
assess the degree our presence of a hard
pan now raised bed growing again this is
still outdoor production raised bed is
an example of this the advantage is it
won't really quickly the plant is a hay
that's easier to work with in control
what goes in the actual box as far as
amendments or soil or adding vermiculite
or perlite or something else a special
mix if you want to add however the
negative effects with a raised band are
that so often often get too warm in the
summer as you can see here shade netting
has been used can increase irrigation
frequency the time and resources takes
to construct them and they're kind of
fixed in place once established not very
easy to move so if we have a well
established area by all means growing
growing beds or raised beds might be a
quality option for you but you do kind
of consider the pros and cons now
growing in the field err outdoor in
general typically weeds are a concern
and there's many options for weed
suppression you can use plastic which is
the easiest often the cheapest but the
end of the season disposal can be a
challenge or issue
there's biodegradable plastic Malta's
and that can reduce waste at the end of
the season
what's variable result with more field
trash than maybe wanted meaning there
could be particulate left at the end of
the season there's natural which would
based can be expensive can also harbor
pests from year to year
I'll landscape fabric as we see here can
be very expensive initially but can last
for many seasons so it might be a good
option once you can afford or justify
the initial investment outdoor growing
just like other sites you need to
consider fertilizers and irrigation
typically drip irrigation is the only
feasible method for long distances
incorporating an injector such as the
dosatron or dose traumatic here is
recommended so you can also fertilize
the crop over a large area efficiently
wind protection strong winds can break
plants can also increase daily water
requirements the goal is not to stop the
wind entirely but to kind of break it up
privacy fence
is a good option and help kind of break
up some of that wind which is better
than the solid plastic or vinyl fence
this kind of creates areas where a lot
of pressure can occur or gonna get
swirling winds it can also damage plants
staking and trellising and supporting
plants can help reduce the potential for
wind damage when I shop for wild animals
you are growing outside the exam like
every animal including some humans we
want to investigate or harm your crop
consider fencing operations that either
have a physical metal fences this does
here or electrified up for potential
animals metal is a permanent fixture but
somebody else can climb over or dig
under it well down Fault in electrical
fence it needs to be kept clear of weeds
and so that power can be kept to it for
the entire season insects of concern
want to keep a careful eye out for
insects that may feed on your plants
some can also transmit diseases
I want to monitor plants and catch a
pest early some can be very small as we
see with reps and white flies and a
feeds who want to be really inspecting
your plants well lastly promiscuous
pollen you want to know thy neighbor
want to know if someone else is growing
plants that are growing for breeding
purposes or could be pollen in the area
their goal is not to pollinate cannabis
plants because you want your female
plants to produce cannabinoids and that
seeds and the weather and prevailing
winds may carry pollen a few feet to
even betting many miles you may want to
consider early early planting dates for
unintentional to prevent unintentional
pollination high months of moisture in
the air coming these pounds ability to
reach or pollinate a female flower this
is where our potential misting or
irrigation systems overhead irrigation
systems may come into play till reduce
the chance that your outdoor growing
field gets miss pollinated by a local
area that may be breeding this is also
important if you have a high tunnel that
you're rowing male plants for breeding
purposes you don't want to have that
pond go out into the field because it
will mess up the efficiency and
production of your entire field crop