so here on this debaco university video
we're going to be considering uh post
harvest cannabis plant disposal
as well as other supporting plant
materials required
when you're growing outdoors and how we
should best approach kind of
considering their disposal
[Music]
looking at a pretty large scale outdoor
growing operation here
and looks like a lot of plants want to
be considerate of disposal of the plant
material as well as some of the
supporting plant material
in this example such as the plastic used
for weed block
as well as considering the support cages
as well as any irrigation or stakes they
also have utilizing this grow
so first off let's focus on disposal of
the plant material
per the epa cannabis waste must be made
un
unusable and unrecognizable before
disposal
mixed with at least 50 non-canvas waste
such as non-consumable solids
and stored in a secured waste receptacle
canvas waste can be disposed of in a
permanent landfill or through composting
incineration or by means of in-vessel
digestion
now landfills most campus growers and
processors are shipping chemist waste to
landfills
so this is why it's under federal
scrutiny composting
is the goal to provide optimum
conditions for microbial metabolism
to help that kind of breaking down of
the process there
of the plate material with the microbes
then there's incineration which must
occur at temperatures high enough to
destroy
the toxic organic components in the
hazardous waste as well as reduce the
overall
volume however with incineration note
that it is not the same as burning
leaves in your backyard it's a much more
controlled process
then speaking of controlled processes
the in-vessel digestion
is a more efficient method of composting
whereas the
waste is confined within a building
container or vesicle
in order to mechanically control airflow
temperature moisture as well as
odors this is just disposal of the
actual plant material
but there's also those plant supporting
materials we must consider
so for example we have to consider the
weed control
many times plastic or some form of row
cover is utilized in season but these
must be removed from the field
after harvest plastic is the most common
for many reasons
but one of the drawbacks of using
plastic is the end of the season
disposals we see that here
not only is a removal challenge but the
disposal can be even more
challenging there so getting out of the
field or out of the growing area
off to the side and removing it from
here can also present lots of challenges
biodegradable options do exist but often
they can leave feel trash and may still
need to be handled in some way
or tilled so again to be considerate of
what weed control options you are
utilizing
then there's the irrigation so if
utilizing drip irrigation this needs to
be cleaned up at the end of the season
many growers grow with one-time use
material it's only about four or six
mil that can be sufficient for a single
growing season
if you want to reuse the material and
this is referring to the drip tape
go with the 15 mil as if you take care
of it can be used for over seven years
again if it's handled properly might be
better suited for smaller growing
operations
larger growing operations that might be
utilizing plastic as well they might be
wrapping up the irrigation with the
plastic and disposing of it each and
every grow cycle
then lastly disposal the plant supports
so keep in mind that regardless of the
messy
method used plants often need some sort
of support a lot of wind outside
and a lot of other exposures some use
trellis netting or stakes
these can be reused in some cases but
it's more common with stakes
they will go through a soak of some kind
of sterilization before they're reused
using this kind of screen method this
can be kind of a
metal kettle fencing some growers
will utilize potentially concrete
supports
but keep in mind that don't just reuse
it from time to time
go through have a way of cleaning it
even if your plants didn't have any
disease
there's a chance it could be living on
your stakes could be living on your
trail standing support could be living
on
all your neighboring containers your
fencing be sure there's some form of
sterilization
process so that you're avoiding any
potential carry over
from one's growing season to the next
because particularly you can notice
disease comes in really early
on your plants even though you didn't
see it the year before because it's
living on the stakes living on the
support equipment
affecting early plants do yourself a
favor take that little extra time
clean up the things you're using from
year to year and ideally your plants as
well as your harvest
well thank you