on this tobacco university video if
you're growing plants outdoors
how do we kind of work on that
progression from the vegetative
to the flowering stage where are some
things we need to keep in mind
and what are some considerations we
should be making you'll all be presented
here
on this video lecture
[Music]
all right let's get into outdoor natural
progression of cannabis
from vegetative to flowering phases
so first off we have to consider the
photoperiod which also comes from just
the natural sunlight
and with outdoor growers plants will
flower based on the duration of sun that
naturally changes with the seasons
in mid-summer when days become shorter
than 12 hours is when
the photoperiod dependent varieties will
start to flower regardless of the
plant's age
however be mindful of any light
pollution
on the plants which can include but not
limited to garden lights
street lights or various spotlights that
might offset the plant's
natural perception of the photo period
now timing is key so with outdoor
growing there are set of conditions that
growers need to plan accordingly
the calendar will dictate the photo
period and also the
typical weather to be expected so both
play an important role in canvas plant
morphology development
so we want to make sure our timing is
spot on and everything looks nice and
good
because if we're off it definitely
starts to look very awkward
now that calendar so photoperiod
dependent varieties will go into flower
based on
the photoperiod so the timing of the
plants needs to be based on day length
that's timing based on when you choose
to plant them
autoflowers may not be impacted by the
day length
but there is also the growing season for
many areas which is shorter
than those that have a winter season so
keep that in mind even though
autoflowers will just
flower x number of days old we want to
make sure we're maximizing favorable
plant environmental conditions
based on the season season and timing of
the year
timing is important for outdoor growers
that is centered around their chosen
planting date
that's how you can modify what the
plants will be exposed to
so we're looking at photoperiod
dependence we want to take a look at the
calendar growers should look at duration
of time that has over 12 hours of
sunlight and when the critical day
length occurs
planting should occur to ensure that
there's enough time for the vegetative
growth of the plants
to support quality bud production and a
lot of this depends on your degree of
latitude so you want to be planting too
late in the season and
only allowing plants to go through veg
phase for a very short period of time
keep that in mind look at the calendar
when should your planting date be
now auto farming plants well they may
not change to flower
production based on the photo period but
there are other factors considered to
maximize your plant production
providing plants with longer days can
help increase plant efficiency
so this needs to be taken into
consideration along with the local
weather patterns to catch the optimum
growing conditions
so while planting height is in part
determined by the actual variety being
grown
can also be influenced by the timing of
the planting while a bigger plant can
theoretically at least produce more
yield a tall plant can be more
likely to become wind damaged late in
the season this is common areas near
coastlines that may get tropical storms
or hurricanes
so again take that into consideration as
well
lastly staking or plan of plant support
structures
for outdoor production plant supports
are an option
but this may be more applicable to small
growers
also the material you should be
considered as typically plants can get
quite large and require strong supports
which is often used with metal rebar
it can also depend on your pruning style
if you're going in large scale
production you may not be doing a lot of
pruning
if you're growing a smaller operation
outdoors pruning might be an option
screen of green might be another worth
consideration
we are laying out a bunch of trellis
netting allowing plants to grow up
to only keep them to maximize production
per plant
but to also provide some physical
support so take these all
and options into consideration when
growing cannabis plants
outdoors