on this tobacco university video i'm
going to go over
outdoor site evaluation if keeping in
mind
if you want to have that site for
cannabis production
all right let's get into outdoor site
evaluation for cannabis production
well first off there's five main
evaluation kind of standpoints here
you want to look at the history visual
physical
chemical and regulatory evaluation of
any site that you might be considering
to produce cannabis in and all none of
these are
more important than the other they all
kind of should go through
and go to go through the evaluation
process and make sure
that you meet all of those proper
evaluation standpoints
so that you're able to go into a field
knowing
you have all these at least passing all
these checkpoints because there'll be
plenty challenges growing outdoors in
general
so first off the history evaluation so
when we're talking about the history
evaluation well
what was the site used for before was it
dairy farming
uh it's likely to have be high in
phosphorus was it industrial
applications
are there any potential contaminants to
consider was it the hay field
uh is the p the ph might need to be
corrected um
why is it available other questions just
to ask there is someone just abandoning
the farm or they obeying it because it
wasn't productive for them
so these are just kind of like histories
things you can ask about
looking back at kind of what it was used
for and have an idea of what you might
be
walking into or at least we should maybe
have a little indication of what you
spend a little more time
reviewing then we did the simple visual
evaluation
so this is the most basic and should be
performed via simple computer search and
also a simple
on-site look there's great satellite
imagery
so you can find a quick visual
inspection what's going on hopefully you
can go there
as well now if you do make it out to the
field or have an option to make it out
to the field
it's good to make the evaluation after a
recent rainstorm because you want to
have an idea of how it may drain
or where water might be flowing to or
from within a field
now what plant species are currently
growing when you make that visual
inspection things you should be asking
yourself
is it many weed species is it very
disturbed soil
or is it wetland species because this is
likely a wet soil
it might be poor for cannabis production
any inconsistencies do you notice are
there empty pockets within the soil
it could be since prior usage could be
spills in an area
or sometimes those empty spots are rocks
or you see a lot of rocks kind of on the
side or
even within the field because this could
make cultivation quite
a challenge so you're going through a
physical evaluation
of the area so what's the topography
like is it very hilly
because that could be a sign of possible
soil erosion
do you notice any rocks you know do you
notice any large rocks because
cultivation could be a challenge for
weed control or even just initial
planting
also do you know what the soil type is
how well will allow root aeration
to occur and is there any ponding that
you notice
in any areas a poor drainage can be a
continual challenge and result in plant
stunting
clearly as we see here in this field now
if it's one little pocket one little
area
no problem but if you see a lot of this
occurring that could be a red's flag
there
also then we get into the chemical
evaluation so taking a soil test of the
field
what does the soil test say you know
looking at after we pass all the other
kind of steps
what take a soil test great to do as
you're also doing the visual
inspection this would be advised to get
a full soil test done that looks
for far more than just nutrients what
are you interested in the soil test on
this potential field
well consider the ph what's the organic
matter soluble salts
particle distribution and possible
contaminants such as
lead and aluminum for sure is what i'd
be checking in many labs perform those
tests
normally so just a good idea to get a
good evaluation of the soil
good chemical evaluation to have an idea
of while it may look good
what does the kind of chemical profile
that soil tests
suggest because it also gets into well
what amendments
might be looking at adding let me get
into lastly here the regulatory
evaluation
and even if a field completely checks
out growers should look into specific
town regulations
this can be highly variable from one
town to the next
so questions you should ask can you
build a structure good for cold frame
construction especially for early season
propagation
something to consider any setbacks for
cannabis production so sometimes there
are road or neighbor setback
requirements
how far do you need to be from other
areas
so there's also some distances greater
for public property such as a school if
that's nearby
something else to be considering looking
at those zoning regulations
and then fencing or signage requirements
does your town require a physical
barrier
or is signage required if so what must
state how large does it need to be
and you know just be aware of all these
things ahead of time
because it's one thing it's going to be
a lot of work to kind of go through and
purchase an area
or rent an area but you want to make
sure that it all checks out at least
from all these kind of
evaluation standpoints so you can try to
focus
on the actual growing aspect you don't
have to worry about any of these
potential barriers preventing you
from doing what you planned originally
on doing for your cannabis production