many growers looking for a simple form
of irrigation go with overhead
irrigation and that's what this video is
about
[Music]
all right let's get into overhead
irrigation equipment for outdoor
cannabis production
so first off aura overhead irrigation in
general
we're looking at overhead irrigation
it's a system that's a lot like a long
a lawn sprinkler and in small
applications
long sprinklers can do just fine water
is basically pumped under pressure and
sprayed down onto the plants
via a flat spray nozzle and that can be
very small here
or a very large application as we see
here it may be mounted as part of an
overhead network
network of aluminum pipes or even simply
mounted on this top of a stake
again depending on the size of the
operation now over the advantages
of overhead irrigation is that it
visibly
confirms system uniformity very easy for
a grower to check and make sure
there is an even spread of water offer
this also offers a very large coverage
area for a relatively small number of
pipes
a long product life often 10 years or
greater
can be used for germination fertigation
communication
and as well as frost control it can
offer
short irrigation intervals and lower
maintenance costs than other systems and
this is why overhead irrigation can be
so popular
however there's also some challenges
with overhead irrigation
as it has a higher potential for
evaporation in wind drift issues
compared to
drip irrigation it also waters both the
crops and the weeds it's kind of a
general kind of coverage
it can not be used or it's not
recommended to use with crops that are
susceptible to foliar diseases
because that wetting of the leaves can
increase the odds of that occurring
there's also higher potential of runoff
and erosion compared to drip irrigation
when utilizing overhead irrigation here
now the system can be portable which is
one of the advantages
is that this can help increase the
flexibility it's possible to set up some
mainline tubing and then move the
overhead sprinklers to these locations
of irrigation
this can limit the number of irrigation
heads required but can also become a
hassle which may reduce the chance
of plants getting proper amounts of
irrigation especially if you have
different fields
so just because it is possible to move
this around and go through and transport
it
does not mean sadly always the growers
will go through and do that
especially when you're irrigating tends
to be those hot long summer days
now there is large scale use of overhead
irrigation so
uh large-scale operations called center
pivots are popular in the west of the
mississippi river
now that you may have seen without
realizing it see big circles the pac-man
like looking things
out on fly flying over these
large expansive areas center pivot is a
big well here and this basically does is
rotate
right around goes right around in a
circle format and that's what you're
seeing with these large
looks like crop circles now when we're
looking at calculations
it's going to be quite simple you want
to calculate the flow rate in gallons
per minute
and then determine the coverage area but
getting into
more specifics can increase the amount
of complications but does
improve the efficiency there's a
reference article here as well as
another video i'll be going over to help
you with some of those calculations
to make sure you're if you're choosing
overhead irrigation
you're making it as efficient as
possible