here on this debaco university video
we're looking at the overview of
spectrum effects
on cannabis production
[Music]
so here we're going to take a look at
some of the different spectrums and some
of the effects they have on plants
so first off should start with a general
summary and this provides a quick
visual and textual summary of the major
classifications of the different
spectrums
in addition to the main impact on the
plant is also provided
meaning when we look at uv light that
can slow growth and enhance oil
production
in relation to cannabis for blue light
they can reduce cell expansion and cause
plants to be shorter
green light does penetrate leaves and
does facilitate human vision in
diagnosis
of different plant diseases or potential
nutrient deficiencies
red light is very efficient for the
photosynthetic process
and far red light can enhance cell
expansion and cause plants to stretch
so if you give plants blue and far red
you kind of have some competingness
there one wants it to keep straight
keep stretch one wants it to keep it
short and stocky
so again the amount and kind of
proportions of these you give a plant
can impact its morphological outcome
so looking at just the general mickey
curve here
so the mcki curve was developed in the
late 1960s to early 1970s it was an
attempt to understand how plants utilize
light interpret this with caution as the
study was done with multiple points
in time data points that was put into a
curve of a graph so kind of like a bunch
of little points
that kind of made into a graph plants
can adjust to their environments and
plants will make the most of the light
available to them which may result in
changes in their morphology
so just again keep that also in mind
that this is just a suggested curve and
gives you just an
idea of how plants may utilize the light
spectrum
looking specifically at some details
within this
looking at the uv light so starting at
that kind of 100 to 400
nanometer are the basics of uv light uv
radiation spectrum is divided into three
regions called uva
uvb and uvc as sunlight passes through
the atmosphere
all of the uvc in most of the uv uvb
is absorbed by the ozone water vapor
oxygen in carbon dioxide
meaning plants will be exposed to it
less than if they were say growing
outside of earth say the international
space station uva is not filtered
as significantly by the atmosphere so
it's able to penetrate and reach the
surface of earth to a little bit higher
degree the uv
region covers the wavelengths range from
100 to 400 nanometers and is divided
into those three bands
uva being 315 to 400 nanometers uvb
280 to 315 uvc 100 to 280 nanometers
the relatively long wavelength uva
accounts for approximately 95 percent of
the uv radiation
reaching earth's surface just to put
that in perspective there
with increasing altitude and there's
less atmosphere
is available to absorb uv radiation so
with every 1000 meters in altitude
uv levels increase by approximately 10
percent
just showing you the impact elevation or
distance from sea level
can have now uv implants response so
let's relate this now to back to the
plants
uv light response in plants is similar
to blue light meaning uv
does not drive photosynthesis and can
also trigger cannabinoid synthesis
and potentially reduce disease uv light
does cause some stress to the plants so
they may develop
thicker leaves and or protective
compounds as we see here
in the plant pictured with pigmentation
such as anthocyanins that purple
coloration some plants would do this
naturally
but if we're seeing that that is a
response usually to some sort of stress
in this case it could be a light stress
from uv
light here's a new look at some old data
so this is kind of interesting
research kind of i came across and some
inter interpretation of that research
so dr bugbee's lab in utah state
university
investigated physics kenneth mckee's
data from the 1970s in relative
photosynthetic efficiency
looking at the data the error bars
represent a range of plant species
from the paper showing small variations
among species when grown in the field
the growth chamber of plants indicated
larger variability and we kind of see
that here with the lines
kind of being a little bit larger on
here in the growth chamber a little bit
smaller overall in the field
the question is is it possible that
field grown plants the ones here at the
top
have synthesized compounds to block uv
for the protection of light reducing the
effectiveness
of those wavelengths and we're seeing
that here's our line
here's our uv radiation we're seeing in
the field less
a much reduced kind of amount of
relative quantum yield
and in the growth chamber yes the
variability is greater but we're seeing
an increase in that curve
is it possible because of the high
intensity of lights that the
field grown crops have to deal with are
they producing compounds that are
blocking out some of that uv
light to help protect them from
potential damaging effects
so just kind of a unique look at some
older data
now those blue photons as i mentioned
before blue photons
reduce cell expansion so it's going to
tend to keep plants a little bit shorter
and a little bit stockier
blue photons as a result keep the plants
shorter reduce leaf expansion here's
five percent blue is 20
but we see that plant is definitely
stockier shorter internodes
this morphology difference in cannabis
plants grown under five percent blue
versus 20 blue light we do see
pretty evident they are just on the
picture um the reduction in plant height
then we get into talking about green
light so while plants are green
indicating that the green wavelengths
are reflected by the plants this does
not mean
these are wasted wavelengths a lot of
people think oh why should i give them
green light it's just a waste
really that's not the case green
wavelengths of light penetrate deep into
the leaf and are absorbed by certain
plant pigments
which are of benefit to the plant
chlorophyll may have reduced absorbance
of green wavelengths but this is not the
only plant pigment so keep that in mind
there's other plant compounds in the
plant than just chlorophyll
we see that particularly in areas that
have deciduous trees that change color
as the fall time approaches we see an
expression of those pigments
when chlorophyll is degraded now green
photons in plant diagnosis
so green photons as part of white light
allows growers to see the plants and
better diagnose potential problems
it is much easier here to look at the
plants under this kind of full spectrum
light
than this high par purpley light to
diagnose for diseases look for
potentially nutrient deficiencies
and that's really important to catch
things early so while the plants may
grow well under both
this white light would be better to be
able for the grower
to diagnose plant problems at a much
earlier stage when it's easier to
control them
so red photons again in the 640 to 700
nanometer wavelength
and plant response what's kind of
looking like with these different
wavelengths
well red leds are among the most
efficient at converting electricity into
photosynthetic
photons and are relatively inexpensive
this is why you typically see a lot of
red leds chlorophyll strongly absorbs
red light in this it's effective at
photosynthesis
great benefit there many plants grow
under only red light
no blue will have a stretch tall
appearance thin large
leaves so keep that in mind that just
because it's a great light to
what looks like would be a good plant
response it's going to cause plants to
kind of stretch
kind of exaggerated tall appearance
leaves might be large it could be thin
that could cause some issues there so
this is why we want to give plants kind
of a mixed light this is a reason why we
see a lot of
red light given to plants in growth
chambers and indoor grows in general
then we talk about something here called
the far red
wavelength so a little different than
just red we're now in that far red
which is 700 to 800 nanometers far red
light is in a range of light that
the extreme red end of the visual
spectrum just before you get to the
infrared light
usually regarded as a region between 700
and 800 nanometers in wavelengths
it is dimly visible to human eyes so
keep that in mind that
we're kind of pushing the edge there of
the visible spectrum
far red and plant response vital plants
respond to far red light
well far red is critical spectrum for
plants that's utilized in the
photosynthetic process and can cause an
impact on plants
shape far red is also perceived by
plants photoreceptor
the phytochrome which is important for
light detection
and also timing and flowering in some
plants
so that far red kind of drives the pr to
the pfr the active to inactive farm
you can force the plant from the active
to inactive form quicker
with the addition of far red light we
see here the
regular plant and then plant grown with
far red how it
definitely increases the height the
internet spacing and the stretching
of that plant now we talked earlier
about
light penetration we'll notice the
difference across the different colors
of how light penetrates into the leaf
for blue we're looking at light absorbed
in the top layer
for green the light penetrates deep into
the leaf red kind of similar to the blue
and with light only being absorbed in
that kind of top layer
but then that important far red is also
penetrating deep into the leaf as well
that's just important consideration when
we're looking at how these
how these wavelengths might be utilized
by the plant
so that blue versus far red wavelength
so far red will enhance cell expansion
which is essentially the opposite of
blue photons they kind of like
play off one another plants grown
indoors with eighty to ninety percent
red light
and ten to twenty percent blue light are
quite compact with small leaves and
shorter stems
we see the white versus far red which is
plus ten percent far red here
it's very important with lettuce and
with other plants
it will cause plants to grow very tall
want to be mindful of you know how tall
we're letting our plants
get how leggy we might be getting them
looking at our seedlings we're looking
at shipping ceilings we want to
grow these large top heavy seedlings
they may break during
transportation with the lettuce here
we're seeing our white versus our adding
our 10
can definitely increase that leaf
surface area and that's typically what's
being bought
and purchased because you're looking at
the salad production
so that can really help increase
production per plant there by increasing
that amount of surface area
this shows seedlings grown at 68 degrees
fahrenheit for four weeks under leds for
18 hours a day
at 160 micro moles per meter squared per
second
consisting of 100 red and 50 blue 50
red you can see how that morphology
difference is quite staggering with the
red being much taller and the
mix even mix of blue and red being much
shorter
so that quick general summary of
everything i kind of mentioned here
photon color blue green red and far red
and look at the impact on the plant blue
photons inhibit cell expansion keep them
short and squatty
green photons aid with human vision to
be able to diagnose plants visually for
nutrients or potential disease issues
red photons are very efficient at
photosynthesis
far red photons increase cell expansion
now if you want to learn more this is of
interest to you
to learn a little bit more about this i
would direct you to researching some of
these scientists here to provide you
with some
more information they have a great and
lots of work out there
so by all means take a look search
search them up where you can learn a
little bit more
about the impact of photons and
wavelengths on plant production