now providing with an overview of
trichomes cannabinoids terpenes
clavinets
and cannabis is kind of a large
undertaking as a result I'm just going
to touch on some of the key aspects of
these and realize it they're much more
complex this will just give you that
general understanding of what these
different compounds are so starting with
trichomes these are small crystal like
structures that are produced that
produce the cannabinoids and turbines
they can be said to have an almost
translucent mushroom like appearance we
kind of see here and here these resident
glands are often sticky to the touch in
quality trifles equal a quality product
in cannabis these are extremely sticky
if a sunny do these trichomes are
capturing an insect here but you may be
more familiar trichomes on like a
hearing this kind of to like a tomato
plant that they occur typically for
cannabis we're looking at tricone
production under a microscope or a loop
to kind of magnify them because quality
trichomes typically directly correlate
to a quality product the cannabinoids
THC and the pronunciation here stands
for tetrahydrocannabinol this is the
compound that produces the euphoric high
typically associated with marijuana this
is what it looks like on a chemical
structure CBD or Kant cannabidiol is
does not have these intoxicating effects
of THC but has more potential use in the
pharmaceutical industry since what can
be classified as hemp as long as that
cannabis plant has less than 0.3 percent
THC from federal regulations terpenes
are volatile or aromatic oils that
impact flavor aroma and effects kind of
see them dripping here canvas does have
about a hundred forty different terpenes
identified but terpenes aren't not only
found in cannabis as we see in this
conifer resin these kind of pine trees
this are created by the same glands that
produce the cannabinoids it is the THC
in the CBD in addition to the terpenes
themselves it can also be an indirect
impact on how the body processes other
cannabinoids such as THC and CBD so they
themselves have some effects they can
also influence effects
other compounds flavonoids many exists
naturally in nature they primary produce
coloration or pigments to the plant to
help attract pollinators and offer
protection from damaging UV light if the
Cylons are probably most widely
recognized for their purple color so
just in purple cush could also add like
the purple mists and blue mists
blueberries poison ivy when it first
comes out will having these flavonoids
or specifically these anthocyanins to
help shield it from damaging UV or
intense sunlight and as it gets older it
will lose those pigments and have more
of that chlorophyll it's not well
documented which shows the possible
interactions with cannabinoids so they
may also to have some interactions
hopefully it gives you just a general
overview of these very complex products
that cannabis can produce so you can
understand at least a little bit of the
difference between them