here on this debaco university video
we'll go over an overview of far red's
impact on cannabis production
[Music]
so here we're gonna be looking at far
red's impact which is the wavelengths
right down here so let's get into the
video
well first off let's define red light
you might be more familiar with
red light is at least as effective as
other colors of light at promoting plant
growth
while red light may not be the most
efficient color for general illumination
for people
for high lumens is among the best colors
of light to stimulate plant growth due
to the role in photosynthesis
if you only grow plants under red light
with no blue light
they will be elongated or kind of a
stretched internode spacing
red leds are the most efficient of the
colors that's why you typically see them
a lot of times
integrated to those particular light
sources again here's that kind of red
light spectrum
located right in this area now here
we're going to talk about far
red light so a little different some
similarities but a little different
as far red influences the size of the
leaves the length of stems and
ultimately the height of the plants as
well far red may take some
may make some plants flower earlier so
there could be other impacts
when giving plants far red light to
measure it you need
a spectro odometer which is a light
measurement tool that is able to measure
both the wavelength
and the amplitude of the light emitted
from a light source
however this comes at increased cost due
to internal complexity of the device
so you want to make sure you have the
proper device
if you to capture this particular
wavelength if you're looking at doing a
study
we're looking at really analyzing
exactly how much you're giving plants
and this far red light is in that 700 to
800 nanometers in length
we can see the change in a tomato plant
and what looks like a squash plant as
well
control plants versus giving them far
red we see that definitely that much
more
stretched appearance now lights ability
to penetrate the leaf
so if we're looking at comparisons of
kind of different wavelengths
notice that both the green and also the
far
red light penetrate deep into the leaf
blue and red are absorbed mainly in the
chlorophyll which is located in greater
concentrations on the upper leaf
surface however the deep penetration
suggests that structures other than
chlorophyll are responsible for the
utilization
of these particular wavelengths if most
of the chlorophylls at the surface
make sense for blue and red to be
absorbed there but if they're
being able to penetrate deeper into the
leaf there may be other
methods or methods for the plant to
absorb
that particular light energy from those
particular wavelengths
so plant's response to shade so
reductions in the red to far right ratio
the rfr ratio
660 nanometers to 740 nanometers
proportion
are the most predominant so on the left
here
we have the y axis for full sun data in
the right
we have the y axis for both moderate and
deep foliar shade
data we're seeing a comparison here so
again here's our full sun and here's our
kind of our
moderate to deep shade kind of
colorations we see the moderate to deep
shade
we're seeing a definitely jump up or an
increase here
in the uh photon flux there so what does
this kind of tell us well that kind of
goes back to that ability
for it to penetrate deeper into the leaf
surface
so far reds and under leaf comparison
so we have the overleaf we have the
under leaf
above and below leaf spectrums
comparison here in this
chart provided notice how the under leaf
still receives about 50 percent
of the total far red compared to the
minimum percentage of other colors
so when i say minimum percentage like
well it's pretty equal we'll look
comparison to the greens the
yellows from the oranges and some of the
reds we're seeing it's a
large space there's a large gap there in
the king it's receiving a very small
percentage
here where the far right is only this
tall we almost see an increase
the distance here is almost halfway
about 50 percent of the total far red
it's able to
absorb under the leaf as it is in
comparison to over the leaf so that's
kind of an important part
of this image here now the red and far
red kind of ratios
so the ratio of red and far red changes
in full sun versus shade conditions
full sun has equal red and far red under
plant shade most of the red is used but
the far red will reach the shaded plant
you see here
so direct sunlight is our canopy shade
when we get to that far red spectrum we
notice that
amount relative photon flux density
percentage
increases dramatically this will induce
shade
avoidance by changing morphology and can
induce early flowering in some plants
shading from another plant reduces both
the light intensity and also changes the
light quality
changes in quality include red to far
red ratio so in direct sunlight the
ratio is about one
uh 1.4 and the shade the ratio is only
0.23 so there's a massive
shift in that now far red
plant shade impacts so here's that same
comparison here we're looking at the far
red
normal morphology should be a plant that
looks like this if there's a shade
avoidance plant it's grown in kind of a
shady location where
we're kind of looking at the wavelengths
here
or under the tree well we see shade of
voids they're going to have small leaves
that are going to stretch quite a bit
their shade tolerant plant this same
amount of light or kind of
filtered spectrum of light they're going
to have a much shorter compact
kind of morphology and the leaves will
become a little bit wider as well
again it's under the shade remember
direct sunlight where all these leaves
are getting the direct sunlight
under this tree are going to be what's
called the canopy shade we see that
spectrum definitely
shifts and changes for those plants in
this example
so their morphologies now looking at
petunia ceiling running under different
light for another little source of
comparison
b is blue r is red f r is far red micro
moles
per meter squared per second is the
subscript number
and high versus low light intensities of
red and far red while keeping blue light
intensity is constant
so we see kind of some great kind of
images here in comparisons
the blue light their subscript is
consistent through all of these trials
we see but the plants look very
different
what we're changing or in this study
changed the amount of red and far
red that the plants were receiving so
that intensity is the subscript number
so we can see that in this case it was
given twice as much red versus far red
here it was given equal red and far red
and we can definitely see the changes in
morphology
they measured specifically plant height
and it gives you that nice little
comparison to see what impact
the different wavelengths can have on
the morphology of the plants
now interaction of red and far red and
ppfd
so remember that's photosynthetically
photon
flux density transplanted seedlings from
previous slide to a greenhouse now so
that was kind of the seedling stage
now let's go a little bit longer in
their life all grown under the same
conditions
including light after transplant so
what's kind of an interesting note
is that while these plants started here
and they got different light treatments
they were then
all moved to a greenhouse setting and
they all got normal light
so how does the seedling environment
impact the flower cycle and we can see
that there is some differences
plants flower faster under highlight
intensity light
and also when grown under far red light
so we see that shift there when they had
equal blue and red
they weren't even flowering we could see
a shift in the days to flower from
transplant
with the blue and the intense red and
far red being the quickest here
for days to flower after transplant so
just an interesting note that in the
seedling stage the
wavelengths that plants are given can
have impacts when they get older
even if there's a transition point where
then they're all given consistent amount
of lighting
at least here in petunias now the impact
on yield with adding a far
red since that's probably an interesting
thing to kind of take a look at
far red is in the 700 to 800 nanometer
wavelength range
so it is outside of the ppfd range of
measurement
which only takes into account 400 to
700. lettuce is a leafy green that shows
great response to far red light
you're typically growing it for that
kind of leaf material
reduced ppfd in far red trials attempts
to provide all plants with consistent p
a pfd
of 350 micromoles per meter squared per
second
here we're looking at dry masses again
looking at lettuce yield with far right
added
dry mass data here was normalized to
have the
350 ppfd trials be an even 100 grams so
they're normalized here
those were set at 100 so we can have a
much easier visual comparison
both trials had far red added improved
yields
with the white or full spectrum light
having the largest yield overall
so this is in comparison to the red blue
only wavelengths compared to the kind of
white wavelengths
so as we see here not only are we having
an increase in
overall yield but in addition we're
being able to diagnose potential plant
problems
with this full spectrum led light as
well so better yield and better to
diagnose disease
overall probably a more favorable light
if we add
far red again getting that increase in
dry mass as well
just a side note in the study that they
were running at 300 because they were
assuming another 50 was coming from the
far red to keep that 350
amount of intensity of light the same
only changing the spectrum that those
plants were given
so added faraway light can increase cell
expansion so control in far red we see
the tomatoes soybean cucumber and
spinach the difference in morphologies
pretty stark and different even here
just looking at them we can definitely
see that there is
overall an increase in plant height when
we add that far
red there now common light sources in
percent far red produced
here's just some you might be familiar
with cmh lights or high pressure sodium
lights
just as note sunlight does produce 20
percent far red light
however when we saw the comparison
before why don't all the plants super
stretch as very high amount when we're
looking at sunlight
well keep in mind sunshine also has high
levels of blue light about 27
in uv a which reduce cell expansion and
stretching so there's kind of that like
balancing effect there some of these
other lights are just producing more of
that far right with reduction in that
blue wavelength
that's why you tend to get some more of
that stretching
now what's far red's impact on cannabis
production welfare can cause cannabis
plant stretching
so is advised to be of greater
importance later in the growing cycle
far red exposure may also induce earlier
flowering times in canvas so that should
be
make note of that when growing outdoors
the high 20
far red is counter acted by the very
high 27
blue light spectrum so don't say oh the
sunlight's got 20 percent farad let me
give my plants 20 percent
remember sunlight is giving a bunch of
other spectrums as well
when measuring light a pfd meter will
take into account
uv and far right light but this should
only be done with
led lights and not high pressure sodium
lights due to the strong
infrared spectrum they also produce
which will might give you an
artificially high reading
of pfd if you're taking into account
those additional
wavelengths if you want to learn more
where this kind of information came from
special thanks to all of the researchers
shown here
sharing their information hopefully
you're able to glean some information
from what i've kind of summarized and
presented here
as a way to kind of better understand
light's impact on cannabis plants