now this can be a common problem with
many growers and that's the simple over
fertilizing of the crop
just pouring on the fertilizer more and
more thing that's gonna do benefit when
actually it actually will result in
potentially more harm or negatively
impacting the end product so this is a
common occurrence with growers because
they want to make sure they get the most
out of their plants so they figured a
little more fertilizer it's not gonna
cost me that much more but I want to
ensure I get the best yield that I can
however it's important for these growers
to remember that over fertilizing can
not only hurt yields potentially get
into toxicity range but can waste money
and potentially contaminate groundwater
I want to keep an idea of sustainability
on a keep our rivers and waterways as
clean as possible without contaminating
them I also don't want to waste money on
it necessarily so these are both ways
that we're fertilizing can negatively
affect the grower and also the
environment signs of over fertilization
could be brittle leaves burn leave
margins and bloods that smell like
fertilizer does it make noise when
they're burned they're just ways to be
able to tell if you've over fertilized a
crop sadly many of these kind of wait
until the end result so it's important
to be mindful of that throughout the
process to be testing leaves to make
sure they do have some flexibility to
them and watching the margins for
potential over fertilization burn also
want to be careful with other things
that can cause a leaf margins to burn
such as being too close to the lights or
deficiencies even in some instances so
again just follow recommendations err on
the side of caution you can always add
more fertilizer and it's harder than it
is to take it away
once you've over added it so be mindful
so that you're growing their crop in a
sustainable manner not wasting money and
that potentially contaminating the
environment