okay here we look at some of the basics
of packaged growing media so it's nice
and easy comes in these bags potting the
X potting soil it's a little bit about
what actually might be in that bag so
looking at package mixes well they're
easy to buy in large quantities and the
very efficient process typically they
come sterilized which is great
often contain wetting agents and can be
purchased to match specific growing
conditions so as you can see there's a
lot of benefits to going with the
package mixes route now package label
versus content so I want you to be
warned here that the package may stay
the same or the exterior package may
stay the same but the soilless media
components or percentage of them may
change unexpectedly so I've seen this
happen where you kind of buy one thing
and you get the same thing or you think
you're ordering the same thing and it
comes in the same package but it's
something doesn't seem right that's
because potentially the percentage of
the components within that mix may have
changed from the company so just be
mindful of that when you're buying or
buying the batch of that what you think
is the same soilless media again now
there's also the package change so other
times the package may change but still
the same material so it's kind of a flip
case here you see three different Pro
mixes and this is ideally the same in
site material but you can see that the
packaging may be very different and in
this case it could be the very same
inside material so you may get one thing
that comes in white then it comes in
black and it couldn't white again
so again just be mindful and checking
and knowing what the ingredients were on
the previous mix that you used now
product frustrations on both these
situations this can be frustrating as a
grower so typically buying in bulk as I
dive in here and when we ordering be
careful and watch the first run of
plants with this new material to buy in
bulk gives you that consistency and
depending on the size of your grow
operation which want to be mindful of
the frustrations that can occur with the
change in the outside or more
frustrations usually change with the
percentage or the recipe of that soil is
mix so media bags keep in mind is two
measured in volume so watch for
compressed vs. loose package methods
here this is a three point eight cubic
for the compressed Bale and this is a
two point eight cubic foot
so again just be mindful of what you're
buying and what volume you may need
because this can impact how much you
need or what type of end use you might
be using again the compressed bales are
great for large applications a little
bit harder to move smaller bags easier
to move less total volume of material
looking at potting soil so this does
contain soil as it says in the name the
soils do maintain composure ingredients
such as perlite peat moss are added to
improve the availability to be used in a
container environment this offers easy
access to good base growing media
provides great root penetration stable
often near neutral pH often drains well
maintains constant qualities for the
duration of the growing season all a lot
of positives associated with this type
of bag mix think of it as soil out of
the bag it often has consistent texture
and wetting agents to aid in the ability
to retain water while still aligned the
importance for air for those roots
debris the goals use a quality company
and product when you're well familiar
with cutting cost here will result in
more expenses and frustrations later so
you go kind of with that what's on sale
one that can affect you potentially
later keep in mind though that there are
changes within companies so just be
mindful when you're buying them both to
kind of be mindful of exactly what's in
there and to be able to deal with those
situations soil less or what's called
potting mixes these are very popular for
the value they provide they're
relatively inexpensive and lightweight
compared to soil and sterile out of the
bag dude they don't contain soil I was
just a reason why they're called soil
less mixes the way to retain moisture
and provide good drainage for aggressive
root growth and offer an easy controlled
media they buffer pH they can have
fertilizer and moisture to make for a
stable growing medium so again this soil
is mixes even though they contain those
soil can offer a very beneficial
environment for your roots and for your
plants these soilless mixes again are
very popular for this reason they're
commercially produced or lightweight
they maintain consistent air and
moisture
good root penetration drain well
different blends to match the specific
needs such as germination mixes growing
mixes even orchid blends which is a very
high porosity and they're typically
consistent in near neutral pH while
allowing the grower to not need to do
any modifications to them upon arrival
the advantage of the growing media's are
starting with clean conditions
consistent particles and contents as I
said at least most of the time presence
of wetting agents typically near neutral
pH requiring no adjustments from the
grower ease of storage in getting more
the disadvantage of Graeme Diaz is a
lack of consistent product over time
companies can make changes as I said
sometimes they call them improvements to
their formulation it's just something
that's different it can be frustrating
from a grower standpoint purchasing or
shipping and storing can either be
potential other issues especially if
you're trying to buy in bulk we're using
the media's often not recommended
discarding meeting with the plans to
avoid carrying over disease or potential
pathogens which could jeopardize your
new or next crop her this does create a
disposal issues to depend on how much
you use innovating how big of an issue
you can have often the byproduct can be
incorporated into garden soil as you
know other means of disposal or
basically reusing it you're reusing in a
container based as wetting agents will
degrade over time and it's not advised
lastly we'll freeze talking about sauce
mixes well why not just use soil well
both offer a buffering system which will
be forgiving of great errors however
both who care a lot of time and labour
to move for containers so mixes are the
way to go so it's best for field growing
conditions soil less mixes are best for
potting or container
grows because of the wetting agents in
the go to handle that little bit strip
more stressful environment