here we're gonna learn about the Pincus
which while it is an accessory organ to
the digestive system it is absolutely
necessary for the full process of
digestion to occur and ultimately their
survival of the human being so looking
at the pancreas where is it well it lies
to prostate to the stomach from the
duodenum towards the spleen
that's importance located here because
you'll notice the digestive enzymes are
directly entering the duodenum it's
important because remember the duodenum
is directly connected or receiving items
leaving the stomach so this is a very
important it's located here so it's
really seeing those enzymes into the
early part of these small intestine now
it produces its several enzymes a lipase
is one that are just fat mineral lipids
amylase which digest starts trypsin are
chymotrypsin which is important for the
digestion of proteins so you can see
just right there the pancreas is
secreting enzymes to break down proteins
starch which is your carbohydrates and
also your fats in order for these
enzymes to function properly since we
are just coming out of the stomach we
they don't perform well at a very low pH
the pancreas as a result will secrete
bicarbonate which in neutralizes HCL
just hydrochloric acid in the time as it
directly leaves the stomach needs to
raise that pH so these enzymes can work
at a more optimal rate in addition the
pancreas is also important for Richelieu
sub Iceland and glucagon which regulates
sugar levels in the blood now the
pancreas it more than 90 percent of
cells have a function for the digestive
system however the pancreas is also as
this end is important for maintaining
the body's blood glucose or sugar levels
primary hormone of the pancreas includes
insulin and glucagon to both regulate
the blue blood glucose levels diabetes
is the most common disorder associated
with the pancreas so looking at our
images here we see our normal we start
insulin going through binding
causing glucose to come in member
insulin glucose into the cells here we
have a dysfunction which is diabetes
type one
the destruction of the Wiesel's where
insulin is simply now produced by
insulin at being producers nothing to
receive the signal nothing to bring
glucose into the cells in contrast to
this we have type-2 diabetes well if we
don't see end results the same glucose
is not being uptake by the cells but in
this case we have insulin being produced
however there is insulin resistance on
the receptor so as a result here the
receptor cannot bind the insulin glucose
cannot enter the cell in this case
Muslims that main produce to this fully
functional receptor has nothing to bind
to on therefore doesn't allow glucose in
and this shows the normal condition
where we have our insulin being produced
binder receptor a lot of glucose to come
into the cell now kind of taking a look
at this and the direct relation to the
pancreas we have our increase and
decrease in glucose levels insulin being
released when it comes to high glucagon
when it gets too low bringing it up you
kind of see it's kind of maintained in
this tight range trying to keep a
constant level in the bodies through
this what we call negative feedback
system so it comes up too high release
it down so here we're trying to put it
into the cell to try to reduce blood
glucose oh it gets too low looking out
I'm gonna take it out of the cells we'll
bring it back up so we have this kind of
up and down negative feedback system
this is this modal line represents the
blood glucose level we're trying to keep
this in a Titan range so while it is
increasing and decreasing that's the
graph shows this is kept in a very close
range it's not massive swings up or down
up or down it's a very tight range we're
trying to average out on this line here
going right down the center