okay here i'm going to describe some of
the basics of paper
chromatography which you might be
familiar with producing pretty colors
on paper based on using ink dyes
as just a model example to start off
with
how does chromatography in general work
what are the basic components
of how this works well it works through
what's called capillary action and
that's the movement of a liquid within
the spaces of porous material
due to the forces of adhesion cohesion
and surface tension
here we see blue liquid and we see the
different diameters of these glass tubes
as that diameter gets smaller we're
noticing that that
liquid is able to travel higher and
that's through capillary action
the liquid is able to move up in the
filter paper because of the attraction
to itself is stronger than the force of
gravity as those walls get closer those
forces of attraction is greater
they can travel further up this glass
tube as an example
and paper the pores are very small as
well and that
allows it to again move and fight the
force of gravity
so the solubility which is the degree in
which a material or solute dissolves in
a solvent solutes dissolve into solvents
that have similar properties
it's called like dissolves like what
that means is that if a substance is
polar
or has a charge to it for example water
is polar and has a charge to it
so a substance like that will be able to
dissolve very well in water if something
isn't
nonpolar you might want to use like an
alcohol base because that also
doesn't have a charge to it so it says
light dissolves like that's kind of
getting into the components
of the properties of the solute in the
cell vent
looking at polarity or charge being one
key example
this allows different solutes to be
separated by different combinations of
solvents so what to look for is while
you may see one color
initially this is looking particularly
at inks there may be
separated into two or more individual
colors
so this will happen over time with
certain color spots traveling
to the same distance within your paper
chromatography
in some examples the concentration of
the alcohol and the solvents is changing
resulting in different traveling
distances of the dyes and you're going
to see an example
of how that plays into on the diff
distance that certain colors will travel
so first off go over the basic kind of
setup here of
paper chromatography you have the
starting line this is where the inks
are initially placed you can see that
dots here they're posts
they're it go through the center of that
initial ink
you'll notice that the liquid level is
below those inks you don't want that
liquid level initially to come in
contact with the dikes it will dilute it
into this mobile phase what's going to
happen is
this mobile phase is going to wick its
way through
this chromatography paper it's going to
move its way up against the force of
gravity
as it does so it's going to pick up
these dies and separate them out based
on their individual colors
we then have the finish line which is
the highest point that the solvent
travels
and we have that stationary phase in
this case which is the chromatography
paper
and in this example it's all encased in
a beaker to keep everything
contained so chromatically over time
this doesn't happen immediately
initially can you have a really quick
start we can see how it very quickly
will progress
and in this example for this paper for
this
isopropyl for this material takes about
30 minutes to run to the top
you can see at 25 you have a pretty good
indication 30 would be the run time
sometimes you don't want to run it too
long or too little because you want an
adequate separation without it
overrunning or you don't want everything
to be compressed
either so really observing
our chromatography here as i mentioned
the concentration can play a role
and in this case this just shows you an
example of how it does play a role
here's our different percentages i'm
looking at alcohol-based
solvent and we can see zero percent
alcohol the dots barely move at all
and as we increase the percentage we're
noticing an
increased distance of travel so this is
important to take into consideration the
properties of the paper or the coating
on the paper
uh the solute the solvent
and what you're looking at separating in
this case 100 percent looks like it does
produce quite a good separation though
we do kind of lose some of that yellow
color at least in this example looks
like to me
70 offers a pretty good separation and
you're still getting some of that yellow
color in this die here
so if you look at certain dies and again
over those kind of
separation factors here try to zoom in a
little bit highlight it for you those
dyes do separate into purples and blacks
not soluble in low concentrations
partially cellular concentrations
greater than 20 percent
if you use this same kind of model here
and look at blue dyes we can see also
not very soluble
but completely soluble at higher
concentrations so this is again an
example where
you'd be wanting to run this experiment
at a higher concentration
and then we have green dyes separated
into blues
and yellows which might be a little hard
to see but try to kind of highlight some
of them
here its concentration devices of
isopropanol is greater than 20 percent
yellow silo concentrations of
isopropanol less than one percent so you
get kind of this kind of
mixture of depending on exactly what you
want to separate exactly what you're
looking for
there will be an ideal concentration to
look at and to be able to
use for your separation process lastly
here we have
red dyes so just looking at the red dye
i separate into reds and yellows the
yellow side will low concentrations of
the isopropanol
and less side of a higher concentration
right not one perfect amount of
isopropanol to use
it depends on what color you're looking
at investigating and how you want to
separate that out
so the red dye is slightly soluble in
low concentrations and more silent
concentrations greater than 20 percent
so this is something you want to
investigate further based on these
results
that is the concentration of isopropanol
that you should be using