on this debaco university video we're
going over particle size and texture
analysis
that you may get with your soil test
[Music]
report the image here shows a nice
little relative comparison
of the larger sand particle the midsize
silt particle
and the small little particle here of
clay
and this video is going to go over
particle size and also texture analysis
importance in regards to a soil test
report
so first off soil texture when we're
looking at the texture of
soil well soil texture is is a
classification instrument
used both in field and laboratories to
determine soil classes based on their
physical structure
a soil texture analysis determines the
relative proportions of sand
silt and clay in a sample the textural
class is based on the usda's textual
triangle classification
where there are 12 different textual
classes i'll
show a graph of that soil texture can be
determined using
qualitative methods such as texture by
feel
and also quantitative methods which
includes the use
of a hydrometer method knowing that
soil's texture can help
gauge the required inputs and potential
productivity
of a soil for crops and this shows the
the sand silt and clay particles in
suspension line this settle out using a
hydrometer here to kind of get an
idea of exactly where
levels that's reading and it will be
taken usually
uh very early on and then i'll let it
sit for about two hours and they'll take
another reading
and then they'll compare those two
readings if you want to see this
in action i have a path of soil through
a soil test lab
where they'll show you this exact
process now the soil triangle the
triangle is
used to determine the classification of
soil based on the percentage of
clay silt and sand notice how the
percentage of clay has a large
impact on the soil's classification we
can see that here
clay clay clay all these would be
considered a form of clay that's the
vast majority of this triangle
this is simply due to the small particle
size resulting in a high surface area
to volume ratio and how you try to work
this is you look at the percentage of
clay
on this side of the triangle with the
percentage silt and the percentage of
sand
so for example if i had 60
clay and i come down here and then i'm
looking
at we could say 30 percent silt
and then for uh sand we'd have only 10
sand here so where those would converge
would be
right here that would be considered a
clay soil
we could see again we have other options
here if we only had
10 percent clay and then we had 20
percent
sand we would then have to have 70
percent silt and that would classify us
as a silt loam so that's kind of the way
you read these three
sides of this soil triangle to get the
proper
classification now sand silt and clay
particles
alone is often classification given to
soil that is not predominantly
sand silt or clay and that just has some
a little different characteristics to
that
you can see clay we typically think of
it having a very sticky appearance
kind of that ability to kind of plate on
itself um they are in sand is kind of
composed of relatively speaking large
particles
that tend to fall apart from each other
and be independent
now true sandy soil has the largest
particle sizes here
and again that sand may not just be this
a single type of
snow it could be a combination sandy
soils though are known to have good
aeration
and drainage but a limited ability to
hold water
and also nutrients the composition of
sand varies depending on the local rock
sources
and conditions but the most common
constitutive sand in inland
continental settings is in non-tropical
coast settings is
silica which is silicon dioxide or sio2
it's usually in the form of quartz now
silt is a mid-sized particle and offers
properties in between sand and clay
silt has a moderate surface area with
typically a non-sticky plastic feel silt
usually has
a flowery feel when it's dry and kind of
a slippery feel when it's
wet silt can be visually observed by
hand lens exhibiting a sparkling
appearance
that's kind of that in-between kind of
soil there and
typically a more sought after soil for
growing crops
loan soil loan by weight is a mineral
composition which is about 40 40 20
conservation sand silt and clay
respectively these proportions
can vary to a degree however and result
in different types of loamy soils for
example there's sandy loam
silty lump clay loam sandy clay loam and
silty clay loam
and loam if you notice in that kind of
readout there it's important of the
order that they're presented as well
to classify most precisely classify the
soil
note that the primary difference on loam
in most dictionaries is soil with humus
or organic
content and no mention of particle size
texture and this is definition used by
many gardeners
in the u.s department of agriculture
textual classification triangle
the only soil that is not predominantly
sand silt in clay is called
loam loam soils generally contain more
nutrients moisture and humis
than sandy soils and have better
drainage and infiltration of water and
air than silt and clay rich soils and
are easier to till than clay soils
they're simply called to be grocery
freedom as being less heavy
less likely to kind of clump together
allow water to drain a little bit better
definitely compared to a clay
and also allow better aeration of the
root zone of a plant
then we get to our clay soils and our
clay cells are the smallest particle
size
have the greatest impact on soil
properties the high surface area allow
them to hold nutrients well which
reduces the chance of leaching
sounds like a good thing however this
soil can hold water which can result in
plants being more likely to be
waterlogged
also when clay soils dries it will crack
and be more difficult than other types
to rehydrate it's a negative
you can tell me if true clay soils have
the picture here if you start at one end
of the field
and you walk your way to the other end
of the field and you're six inches
taller by taking it to the end
that's because all the clay builds up
that would be a true clay so it has a
tendency definitely
to stick together now how do we
determine these different
textures by feel well there is this
ribbon test
and go through the exact kind of process
here that if you want to go through and
read it you can
but you're basically placing soil in the
palm of your hand
adding some water needing that soil with
a smooth plastic consistency to like a
putty
and then you want to see if does the
soil remain a ball when you kind of
squeeze it if it does you go on to these
next steps if it doesn't it might be too
dry you might have to re-wet it
or you might be simply dealing with a
very sandy soil where it can't really
hold itself together make a ball
open it up and falls apart it could be
done with the sandy soil if the moisture
is correct
if it does form a ball then you want to
go to the next step
where you want to look at does it kind
of form a ribbon can you moisten the
soil and kind of get it to form
a ribbon and based on the length of the
ribbon that you can get
will determine the higher percentage of
clay so the longer
the ribbon the more clay percentage you
have
in that soil then you can go to the next
step is to feel gritty does it feel
smooth
and that can help you just do a quick
test in a field
as far as determining what type of soil
you might be dealing with
again this takes some practice but you
can kind of go through here with some
soil you may have locally
and what you may know the type of and
see if you can follow this process there
to determine the texture by feel
now soil texture favorable for growing a
loam or a silty loam by weight again
it's about forty percent sand forty
percent silt twenty percent clay
variants in these proportions result in
different types of loam and as i said
listen them out here
sandy loam silty loam clay loam sandy
clay loam silty clay loam and just plain
loam
so again these are different soil
textures but all these in general
would be considered at least initially
favorable for growing plants
now lastly soil texture for the long
term
assuming no major modifications to the
soil the texture class should remain
fairly consistent
so it's not necessary to need to check
each soil test grower takes
while you should be kind of going
through and testing it for ph and
nutrients
soil texture you can kind of do once and
that's probably not going to change to a
great degree
however when initially performing a soil
test for a new or perspective
area it's a good idea to include this
test
this again just shows again how you
would read that with the different
percentages
to determine your exact classification
of the soil assuming you don't do any
major
large amendments of any kind this should
stay pretty consistent
and something you should know before
purchasing a field or
growing in a field so that you can make
the best adjustments and know what
you're walking into
before the plants even go in the ground