okay looking at hydroponic systems there
are some that require an airstone air
pumps there also some that are called
passive and these basically use a
wicking system to be able to transfer
the nutrient solution and as a result
reduce the amount of electrical
dependency it can increase the
reliability so first off passive or
sometimes called simple hydroponic
systems utilize what we call capillary
action through a wicking system you can
see the two different diameters of tubes
here you can see the smaller the
diameter the greater the water can kind
of wick or through capillary actually
move up against the surface tension here
these wicking systems last moving parts
it literally is just a wicking water
that's moving against gravity with no
need for moving parts this can reduce
the maintenance and also lower the
initial cost to the grower these passive
systems are the nutrient solutions are
passively whipped or transported to the
root system you can see here we have an
inverted bottle and it's being whipped
right to the root system also if you've
done chromatography you can see that
same thing here where that solvent front
is moving against gravity it's wicking
up the chromatography paper substrate
selection can be very important for
making like sawdust peat moss and Coco
car can be utilize there's also some
rock wall or rock wall like material
that can also serve as a wick of water
and nutrient solution this system has no
moving parts it's based on that just
natural flow of water based on capillary
action this capillary action is based on
the movement of materials and we can see
here where we've got the slow movement
of water up this substrate and again if
we remember back from soil types and the
clay particles versus sand sand being
much larger particles example here clay
being much finer or smaller particles
representing here and we could see as
those particle sizes decrease as that
diameter of the tube gets smaller the
height that water can be whipped is
increased as a result this is a very
low-cost setup and very easy to maintain
keep in mind though the kinds of
capillary action all
there are benefits the media becomes
saturated with water and as a result
very little oxygen can get in for a
scuba diver here kind of representing
that roots need to breathe and to
respire need to take in oxygen as a
result this can reduce the efficiency of
the system so when we're looking at
capillary action think of like
saturating a sponge the more water that
comes in sadly the less air there will
be there's a theoretical maximum there
but if we over saturate the solution and
over hold the water yields will decrease
simply because of the lack of oxygen
being able to supply to the roots
cutting down their rate of respiration