okay here we looking the path of air in
the body now this serves a nice overview
of the nose the larynx trachea the right
lung and left lung we're gonna look at
this in a little bit more detail and be
able to identify some of these portions
on how air moves to our body so the
first part with respiratory system zones
first one is the conducting zone this
provides rigid conduits for air to reach
sites of gas exchange so what we're
looking at is bida nose the nasal cavity
the pharynx and the trachea up in this
region these rigid zones stay open all
the time and they're what's allowing air
to both enter and also exit in addition
to the conducting zone we have the
respiratory zone this is the actual site
of gas exchange this occurs in the
bronchioles the alveoli ducts in the
areas down kind of within the lung that
we typically think of as where gas
exchange is specifically occurring
lastly we have a respiratory muscles
such as the diaphragm which is located
down here and other muscles that help
promote ventilation so our zones are the
areas where we're having that actually
either gas exchange or areas of gases to
move through and the respiratory muscles
are what's helping move that air both in
and out our respiratory zones continuing
on looking a little bit more
specifically at the path of air air
normally enters through the nostrils
passes to the larynx is here which is
our voice box and then to the trachea
and then it goes to the bronchioles of
the lungs the tracheal tube is formed by
stack sheesh C shaped pieces of hyaline
cartilage what that means is they're not
solid rings but they're actually C
shaped so you have a bunch of these C
shaped rings kind of all piled on top of
one another
allowing some areas of kind of
compression years you could think of it
kind of like being able to move but that
C shape is able to hold it open to allow
air to exchange continuing on the lungs
hang free and the thoracic cavity and
air tubes called Broncos connects each
lung to the trachea
continuing on the lungs contain millions
of these al alveoli many many many of
these because this is the actual site of
gas 6
between the air and our blood this
thoracic cavity is bound to the bottom
of the thick layer of muscle called the
diaphragm so the diaphragm is located
down here and that will move and help us
be able to allow air to come into the
lungs and also exit these alveoli are
tiny sacs in the lungs you can see them
here allowing co2 and oxygen to be
exchanged this allows for a rapid gas
exchange due to the extremely high
surface area to volume ratio that they
have they're also missing this image
does a great job showing this
surrounding a network of capillaries so
we want these blood vessels to be very
thin this allows the red blood cells to
travel one by one allowing for the
maximum rate of gas exchange we want our
co2 to diffuse out we want our oxygen to
diffuse in and that's what we see going
on both here and also here and that kind
of intense Network is very evident in
both of these images give you that
overview of the respiration here we can
look and there's tiny Airways again
we're branching from a large area to
smaller to a smaller these tiny little
air pockets and we have our alveoli here
which is our tensed network of
capillaries and it's allowing for the
actual gas exchange to occur this is
what's helping our cells diffuse out the
carbon dioxide and diffuse in the oxygen
as a reminder keep in mind that none of
this is occurring by active transport
it's all simply by diffusion by simply
having a greater concentration of oxygen
here and a lower concentration of oxygen
and the blood in this case oxygen will
naturally diffuse in and carbon dioxide
as a result will diffuse out this is
that general overview of the respiratory
system related to our gas exchange