okay here we look at the path that food
takes to the stomach now it's not this
kind of nice even path in the woods
there's a couple of interesting things
that do happen and how we get food to
move down on a controlled manner we're
going to investigate that further here
so starting with the pharynx now that's
colored here in purple
it's the throat as you may know that as
its involved in both digestion and
respiration so this is not dedicated
only to the digestive process it's
receiving food from in the air from the
mouth so here's again our oral cavity
here and the nasal cavity so air is both
coming in when food enters the fairies
involuntary muscles contractions close
off the air passageway so we see our
pharynx we're closing off the air
pathway to allow food to go down the
esophagus which is right here
we don't want food to go down this way
into the trachea because this is leading
to our lungs and it's gonna lead to
choking so we want
there's involuntary muscles when food
enters this will get closed off so that
our food can enter the esophagus
continue down his path towards the
stomach now the Swan of a bolus part is
fog the tongue moves back and forth in
the mouth you can see we're looking at
that food bolus here the soft palate
will elevate yours our tongue soft
palate will elevate pushing back walls
of pharynx this stimulates neurons to
send impulses to the Swan Center in the
brain and muscles will contract and
raised of earrings you see here so again
here's where we don't want the food to
go down this is leading ultimately to
our lungs the glottis which is right
here it's pushed back against the
epiglottis which keeps food out of the
respiratory tract and in the esophagus
we see that occurring here see it's open
here allowing air to come in and out
here we're closing that off to allow
food to continue down to the esophagus
and here once it's passed it can open
back up and we can breathe again
allowing our gas exchange so it's
important in this process occurs and we
close off that so if you choke we get
something you know goes down the wrong
pipe that's literally where this term
comes from because it's going down here
the TREC get instead of the esophagus
a little zoomed in version here the
epiglottis is a very important structure
here and that's representative right
here this is a flap of cartilage that
covers the windpipe turns swallow and
prevents food from entering the larynx
we don't want food to go down here so
when we're swallowing those tongues
moving this is the epiglottis closing
off here allowing food to go down the
esophagus and not the trachea now the
esophagus in the stomach the esophagus
is a muscular tube that connects the
fairness to the stomach swine's Center
stimulates successive waves of
contraction so how do I get that food to
move down there well peristalsis is if
you or seeing in this image moves full
fluid along the esophagus to the stomach
this food is moving along in a very
controlled manner and we may think all
just gravity is doing that we'll notice
actually it's a controlled set of
muscles it's kind of like squeezing a
toothpaste as you're working it down
this way if you were to be on your side
or even upside down in an extreme case
daily food would still move to the
stomach because of the muscle
contractions that's occurring now the
esophagus is its location it's a hollow
muscular tube it's about ten inches long
about two centimeters are about eight
tenths of an inch wide it could be solid
food and lipids to the stomach
ultimately I put this image here so we
can kind of see where it's located in
relation to the heart just remember
there are other organs involved here and
in this case it would be behind the
heart here that would be where our
esophagus would be located so it's
behind the heart when we're looking at
the end topical organization of all our
organs the movement of the digestion
materials this muscular layers to just
subtract it's smooth muscle this
peristalsis is the key part has a
rhythmic contractions and it's allowing
that food to be pushed down here moves
food through the digestive tract also in
alternating waves of muscle contraction
relaxation we kind of see that indicated
here we have alternating contraction
relaxing rejection is actually moving
that food through the digestive system
it can also be used here from mixing of
that food items also we have the stomach
and the gastric glands movement of the
food from the esophagus to the stomach
is controlled by a rain of food muscle
called a sphincter here we see these
is open here we have the center closed
humans lack kind of a true sphincter and
thus can be bigger jet eat food items it
was a true sphincter would not allow
that to occur we want this sphincter
though to be very functional because now
I don't want food to be able to add to
the stomach we don't want all the high
stomach acid that we have here entering
our esophagus if we do have a failure of
this finger that's how we get heartburn
it's the high amount of hydrogen ions so
very low pH the hydrochloric acid
entering our very sensitive esophagus
causing that burning feeling on
ourselves