here we'll look at pattern recognition
so high-low bunch of shapes here can you
recognize them as any particular objects
if I kind of move that shape over now
looks like I have a mug and a suitcase
here another example of pattern
recognition that if you're looking at a
bunch of patch of clover can you pick
out the four-leaf clover if there's one
there can you recognize that pattern how
it differs from what's around it despite
the similarities so getting more deep
details of pattern recognition well it
can be an object or an event so object
examples would be eye color handwriting
fingerprints these are all can get into
certain patterns
there's also gestures or routines can be
a pattern that we may be at a seat or
recognize with certain people patterns
in everyday life so how do they relate
well loan and credit card applications
income dependence to determine whether
the someone is worthy of getting that
credit that's a pattern how are they
behaving over time dating services use
age hobbies height to determine
desirability
that's another pattern in online pages
when we keyword search descriptions to
find documents that's looking for a
pattern in the particular document or
text block pattern recognition
applications
well pattern recognition is used to give
human identification it intelligence to
machines which required for image
processing it's used to extract features
from given video or image samples it can
also use this a computer this is where
artificial intelligence can come in and
pick up the faces and be able to analyze
those faces and compare them to a data
bank for example that's an example of
pattern recognition also similar objects
classifying then into different classes
or subgroups for example we have a large
population looking at males versus
females that's one way of classifying
people in this image we could be looking
at a whole multitude of ways of
recognizing similarity of objects
methods of pattern classification well
they can separate data belong to
different classes when new data comes in
need to classify it into a category so
if we're looking at you know red versus
blue of fruits versus the black if we
have another strawberry come in and
we're looking at that's going to be red
a bit an apple come in if it's a red
apple are going to classify that and
happen
method of putting that in a separate
case or class there's variability
there's intra and Inter class
variability intra-class different
typefaces of the letter T if we go down
with the different T that be intra inter
class variability B letters and numbers
that look it's similar so for example
the letter B in the number 8 it's an
inter class variability they look very
similar versus here they're all the
letter T but they have different
typefaces so they're intra-class
variability there's some of the
challenges we have when we're looking at
how do we class certain things
classification versus clustering well
classifications recognition we have our
clustering so here's our classification
of low-risk consumers and Harris
consumers we can cluster them as these
these groups here it just helps us to
determine when we get new data where
would that most likely fit or what can
we kind of gain from that new data that
comes in license-plate recognition is
one example is where an automatic number
plate recognition can be used to store
the images captured by cameras as well
as a text from the license plate with
some I figure Bailey to store this
photograph of the driver so we kind of
have that connection between that
license plate movie of that car that
time and potentially even going to that
driver
I've been important for crime-scene
investigation by looking at tracing
where someone went well I simply
recognitions are very important for
pattern recognition well cell
fingerprint classification we have five
categories arches tented arches all of
our loops radio loops whirls all these
can be a way of identifying certain
patterns and classifying them and
comparing them to a known set or
database yes face detection that's a
computer that dentists eyes human faces
and digital images this can also be used
with face detection software within
cameras potentially for focusing and
things like that obvious can be
automatic as well medical applications
it's gonna be important where our skin
cancer detection or what's the normal
what's not what fits into what pattern
being able to recognize something that
looks and different it's important and
these are all kind of evidence of
potential on skin cancers just based on
the image here depicted in all these
different sizes different than a freckle
for example or more
conveyor belts they also have pattern
recognition these are typically
computer-based but they can also be
human days whereas optical sorters can
recognize objects colors size its shape
structural or chemical composition can
allocate it into different areas this
can be achieved in a non-restrictive
hundred percent inspection in line at
full production volumes aligned list
ensure we're having consistent product
coming out or we're allocating out into
different areas different sizes or
different colors a lot of you do with
automation and optical eyes but this is
important that those computers can
recognize patterns now from patterns we
can have feature extraction so let's
assume a fisherman told us that sea bass
is doing a larger I should say longer
than a salmon there's a sea bass here's
a salmon we can use a length as a
feature and decide between sea bass and
salmon according to the threshold on
length so how should we choose the
threshold we need to accumulate some
data at least initially so here's our
length histogram looking at different
the fish here even though the sea bass
is longer than salmon on the average
there are some there are many examples
in this case where the fish this does
not hold true so here's our salmon these
are sea bass you can see that there's
definitely some indications where there
are some longer salmon than CBS and some
longer CBS and then salmon in some cases
but we develop that threshold where is
that kind of breaking point that we can
kind of say most the time it's true for
one or the other so average lateness at
histogram well looking here it seems
easier to choose a threshold at X but we
still cannot make this perfect decision
so here we're saying this is most likely
where the salmon are going to be
different than the sea bass where that
average lightness or looking at
different kind of colorations we can see
there's an always hold true because
there's definitely a area here where
most of the time that does hold true
Multi featured so this can improve
recognition accuracy I'm just using one
of those features we can have multiple
features we might to be able to use more
than one single features may not yield
the best performance using it
combinations features may yield better
performance
that's what's army knife it's got
another bunch of different things it's
multi feature can be used in a variety
of situations
using our past example we can use the
lightness of the coloration as well as
the width of the length of those fish
physical size how many features do we
include well this gets interesting does
adding more features always improve its
performance well more is not always
better
there could be redundancy or over
complication to occur so we had a little
far side Gary Larson cartoon pull out
pull out hidden artery it's getting too
much blood in this case there's a
certain point there's that ideal amount
then if you go over and above you can
actually cause a negative feature to
occur or get less useful data from that
so we classify things how to classify
things partition the feature space into
two regions by finding the decision
boundary that minimizes error no say
this is minimize error it doesn't
necessarily eliminate error we should
find the optimal decision boundary so
how do we go about finding this boundary
of our classification we have a
complexity models perfect classification
performance and training data is
possible by choosing a more complex
model however this can lead to
overfitting the data so it said of art a
simple line technically there's some of
those pink dots over here and some of
the black dots here well if we over fit
that model get too complex so we kind of
create this little crazy line here not
probably the best case not really useful
data but we kind of want where it's
mostly true doesn't always have to be
truce is over fitting the data sets
they're mostly vitro so a lot of times
that we form that generalization we
produce that kind of a simpler model so
generalization is defined by the ability
to classify produced to correct results
on novel patterns how to improve the
generation of the performance
well more training examples better model
estimates the simpler models usually
yield better performance so again while
the complex model may be accurate just
about all the time this simpler model
makes a lot more sense it's accurate
most of the time so when we're looking
at generalizing for a pattern it may not
work a hundred percent of the time but
in this case it's very easy to see with
new data that may come in where we would
classify that I just gave you a random
data point and said is that most likely
a salmon or a seed
and the point in it in this region who
say it's more likely to be a sea bass if
it was in this region what could it be
as salmon because of this simpler
delineation model makes it a lot easier
here with this complex model we kind of
get lost and kind of glean less
information in total so generalization
would be careful at how gentle you make
certain statements but in many cases
they can yield a more simpler model that
can potentially have better results when
trying to classify new data