okay so here we're gonna go over some of
the periodic table trends hopefully
you're familiar with the journal
Organization the periodic table and this
will allow you to develop a greater
understanding of exactly why it's
organized the way that it is and what
inferences we can make about certain
elements so starting with ionic trends
elements on the Left which are metals
tend to lose they also electrons to form
positive ions when more valence
electrons are the outermost electrons so
in this image here the gray circle
represents the neutral form of the atom
and the red represents the iron form so
when we're losing those valence
electrons the radius is getting smaller
but notice with the atom becomes smaller
in contrast here elements on the right
side the nonmetals tend to gain
electrons to become negative ions you
see here's our neutral atom in the gray
and when we're adding that negative
electron we could see that the Irenaeus
is actually becoming larger in this case
because here we're losing that outer
shell those outer electrons coming
smaller here we're kind of gaining more
and that's because causing our radius to
be some larger those ions so cations
positive ions and from smaller radius
anions are negative ions gonna form a
larger radius so we're talking about
ions here we're looking at binding and
occur and it's occurring or bonding keep
in mind two of the same types or two
negatives or two positives will repel
each other and a positive and a negative
will attract one another so that you see
that here positive and a positive are
repulsive and a positive and negative
are attractive that's gonna be important
to get to molecules and healthiness bind
together so our periodic trends
properties elements tend to occur in a
periodic way known as a trend and as you
move across a period or down a group so
we're going to be looking at knowing
element trends allows us to make
predictions about an elements behavior
we're gonna see that here so starting
first with atomic radius it's the
measure of the size of an atom four
elements that occur as molecules the
atomic radius is half the difference
between nuclei of identical atoms that
you see right here the average distance
from the center of the nucleus to the
edge of the adjacent electron cloud is
determined to be the radius so what does
this look like what's our trends look
like well Tomic radius increases as you
move down a group so it's just a group
one here as we move down our group or
our family we see the radius is
increasing well why does this occur
actually occurs to a lesser extent to
all of them here we notice this increase
that we see in our radius is because of
the increased number of electron energy
levels the more energy levels the larger
the radius so our if we compare our row
to here or a period two as you go down
to period four you notice these are
radius all gets larger putting that in
different kind of way to visually see
that see these are trying to give you a
3d effect at the height of columns and
we could see here these columns are
smaller indicating the radius is smaller
and these are taller and getting a
larger radius so we have an increasing
going from right to left and increasing
and radius going from top to bottom
now what tends to first students here is
the atomic radius generally decreases as
you move from left to right so if we
look at period four for example all the
way on the left here we see a large
radius we continue down that period you
get to here we see a smaller radius
occurring down this end this is due to
the increase in negative charges
providing a greater pull by the positive
nucleus reducing the radius so what does
this mean well here we have one electron
on the outside one negative charge way
on the outside
that's so longer it needs to be quite
large that positive charge can't really
of the nucleus can't let pull much in
here we have a lot of electrons on the
outside putting a greater negative
charge giving those positive protons in
the nucleus something greater to pull on
pulling them closer reducing the overall
atomic radius
ionization energy that is basically the
minimum amount of energy required to
remove a valence electron forming a
cation canines are positive ions
ionization energy increases up a family
and from left to right down a period a
helium peachie requires the greatest
amount of energy to remove a valence
electron we see that here a great amount
of energy see all our noble gases helium
neon argon require a lot more energy to
remove that electron than say our alkali
metals in general lithium our sodium our
potassium okay we're looking at trends
here look to an affinity I'll try to
finish the amount of energy released
when an electron is added to a neutral
atom or molecule to form an anion and
ions are negative ions it occurs when we
add an electron this follows a similar
trend ionization energy across the
periodic table so again we learn one you
can see electron affinity has some of
the same properties to that metallic
character refers to the level of
reactivity of the metal it increases as
you go down a family the most reactive
metals are found in the lower left
portion of the periodic table so if you
have a periodic table take a look at it
you want to find cesium which is going
to be in that lower left-hand portion
that's not found in nature as a free
element since it reacts explosively with
water and will ignite spontaneously in
air francium that fires the same lights
below the cesium and the alkali metal
group but is also very rare that most of
its properties have never been observed
so these are very reactive these have a
lot of that metallic character a non
metallic character relates to the
tendency to accept electrons during
chemical reactions kind of the opposite
what we just discussed nonmetals tend to
gain electrons and chemical reactions
and have a high attraction for electrons
within a compound the most reactive
nonmetals reside in the upper right-hand
portion the periodic table fluorine
being the most reactive since noble
gases are basically unreactive so we're
looking at trends noble gases are
unreactive when I look at fluorine being
the most reactive
with the non-metallic character the
small sample of pale yellow liquid
fluorine is considered is condensed at
liquid nitrogen you can see that here
varies if you be very cold that's
because you just the major fluorine
containing mineral fluorite so again
fluorine and fluoride too might sound
familiar very distinctly and very
different properties lastly here
metallic and nonmetallic characters more
of a general trend there's no clear
distinct division between metallic and
nonmetallic character as you move across
the periodic table there's an increasing
tendency to accept electrons which is a
nonmetallic property and decrease the
possibility of an atom that would give
up one or more electrons put the picture
here going from black to white you see
this large gray area to show you there's
not a clear division it's kind of this
general trend that occurs so again just
to go back to the first slide here of
our general trends we see how electron
affinity changes ionization energy
atomic radius again will increase it
would go top to bottom and right to left
the left-hand affinity follows
ionization energy and that metallic and
nonmetallic character it's kind of that
kind of gray area that black to white
kind of transition that does occur so we
have to review this just a little bit
focus especially on atomic radius while
learning some of the key terms here this
will help us develop trends to better
understand elements of the periodic
table that we met may not be able to
specifically study