okay here where I'm going to some of the
basics of the periodic table now just
looking at this kind of example periodic
table in front of us we see a lot of
numbers a lot of colors and every number
in color has a reason behind it look
first for a key in this case that you'd
be right here you can see where the
atomic mass is provided to us the
chemical symbol the name the electron
configuration the atomic number
oxidation states so on and so forth for
each of the elements also see further
color coding here to get into some of
the families where the noble gases are
located here the metalloids so again
everything here is well organized and
for a reason so P right table let's
break this word down just initially
periodic means occurring in intervals
and a table is simply a set of data
systematically displayed so why spend
time on the periodic table
well properties of the elements repeat
in a periodic way this is a very
important tool for chemistry it also
allows us to determine or infer
information about elements that we may
not know a whole lot about we know for
example in one particular family how one
behaves
we've gotta infer how others within that
same family behave because of this
intervals that occur Perik table basics
elements are arranged by atomic number
and a typical box contains here where is
in calcium as an example the atomic
number which remembers the number of
protons the atomic symbol C a remember
it's capital C lowercase a that's
important
that stands for calcium which is the
elements name and the atomic mass which
is technically the average atomic mass
which is the reason why is is carried
out to a decimal see also here are
magnesium and J's magnesium we have the
atomic number of two the number of
protons which is 12 the atomic mass
which is protons plus neutrons so in
this case we know we have 12 protons
therefore that must be 12 neutrons in
our oxidation state which this +2 means
that we know there's 12 protons protons
have a positive charge a lot of times
have a negative charge there
has to be 10 electrons because you have
this plus 2 charge 12 positive charges
10 negative charges will leave us with a
positive 2 as result now continuing on
our in our periodic table the periods
are horizontal rows so Row 1 Row 2 or 3
both floors this also could be referred
to as period 1 period to period 3 in
period 4 and so on it's important to
remember period 1 or Row 1 contains
hydrogen and helium as we see here in
here so when students go through and
they want to count either carbon or
nitrogen or oxygen little mistakenly say
that to Row 1 remember this is all Row 2
Row 1 is only contains hydrogen and
helium this is all these elements are
part of Row 2
now groups are vertical columns also
potentially refer to as families let's
see here these vertical means they're
colored cell so this is a group which is
a vertical column which is also referred
to as a family we see them color-coded
easily here now is there some
interactive periodic tables that we've
added a couple Ling's that you're
welcome to check out a lot of great
websites to help explain light of
research certain elements that provided
the couple provide you with a couple of
links here that you can access remember
in the description is where you can find
links to all the slides the
classification of the elements there's
three basic classifications
there's metals which is the vast
majority of the periodic table here
nonmetals which is located in this
region and then metalloids just kind of
have properties sharing kind of both
metals and nonmetals so your metalloids
are located here may separate the
nonmetals from the metals now the metals
in general occupy the left side of the
periodic table they have luster or shiny
basically cells at room temperature
except H G which is the abbreviation for
mercury ductile which is means the
ability be brought into wires we see
here this is with copper and valuable
just building a hammered into sheets
they're excellent conductors of heat
electricity
they tend to form positive ions so in
general if you're an element that's
classified as a metal odds are you share
many of these properties in contrast if
you're a nonmetal again located kind of
in the region over here in the periodic
table they occupy the right side they're
generally gases or brittle solids they
have a dull looking kind of appearance
and they are poor conductors of heat
electricity reminds the only liquid at
room temperature and they tend to form
negative ions so while most of them are
located in this region here I don't want
you to forget about this one that's
located over on the far side over there
this is hydrogen this is also classified
as a nonmetal or metalloids located
right here this be the yellow elements
in this particular periodic table as
presented and just go back for a second
the metalloids kind of share properties
that border both metals and nonmetals
they're not there's been a lot of time
at least in this lecture on those now
the families of elements elements of the
same family or group share structural
and chemical behavior characteristics
these are the families I'm going to go
over and you'll see if they're organized
into these nice columns this large block
here is a transition elements they're
considered the same general family here
so starting with the first one alkali
metals they're soft highly reactive
metals usually stored under oil or
kerosene to prevent their interaction
with air in water they are acting
vigorously with water produces potassium
Billy producing fire when just added to
water they oxidize readily in the air
and they're good conductors of
electricity it's important remember that
Group one is alkali metals in the often
it confuses the second group swimmer
group one alkali metals these alkali
metals have one valence electrons
there's a zoom in of those they will
lose an electron very easily and when
electron is lost metal gains is stable
nonreactive noble gas electron
configuration for right now I just don't
they tend to lose an electron so lithium
tends a plus 1 charge
as is rubidium as as francium as does
potassium all these are Group one alkali
metals
now group two alkaline earth metals easy
way to remember that these are Group two
is there's two words alkaline earth
so just alkaline metals these your
magnesium's strontium is your calcium
czar harder denser stronger higher
melting points than those Group one
alkali metals they are reactive but not
quite as reactive as Group one and they
tend to lose two electrons to gain and
more stable of child configuration group
3 through 12 are the transition metals
they're not as reactive as Group one and
to huge variety but all are shiny in
nature they form multiple ions they also
include inner transition elements and
rare earth elements so all these are
generally classified as our transition
metals continuing on along the periodic
table group 17 and here most reactive
nonmetals
they're called the halogens they combine
easily with metals especially alkali
metals it's seven valence electrons one
short less stable octet they tend to
gain an electron to become stable so
these 10 inform is negative one I am
they send form a positive one ion they
send from a negative one file hydrogen's
kind of on its own there it's the most
common element in the universe its
chemical family by itself is it behave
so differently it reacts with most other
elements rarely found in the free state
in nature and has one valence electron
here as you see now the Hindenburg was
filled with hydrogen's very reactive
with oxygen gas helium not he helium is
used in blimps today it's much less
reactive than hydrogen to reduce the
chance of explosions in fire
lastly here just touching on some of the
major element families within the
periodic table are the noble gases group
18 is all the way on the right-hand side
they have a very low reactivity they
have a filled valence shell SNP level
the highest principle energy levels are
also full very stable electron
configuration as a result it introduced
in signs weather balloons airships such
as blimps as you see here on neon sign
neon is a noble gas as is helium xenon
lights typically found in cars very
bright as in noble gas it's very low
reactivity we can add electricity to it
and it glows instead of exploding
hopefully this was a good general
overview of the periodic table so you
can develop a better understanding of
just why it's organized the way that it
is