okay I'm going to provide some
information about a personal chemical
analyzer called my DX and provided links
down here I'm not sponsored by this
company
I know growers used it and it's but when
very highly of it I want to convey some
information so that you're aware of its
existence and also what it does and why
it's been gaining popularity so first
off my DX is the first of its kind
portable chemical analyzer allowing you
to affordably and accurately identify
the composition of your chandus and
that's a quote directly from the company
it's a small device kind of the size of
a wallet here and it has it can produce
some very interesting results so the
goal of my VX is to provide growers and
medical patients with an easy-to-use
handheld tool to test their cannabis
plant material so this is the advantage
that it gives is that yes you can send
it off to a lab this is kind of that
quick easy way to tell it takes a very
small sample here and it goes into the
device right in this little tray here
and again bottom this contains links
more information so this handheld
chemical analyzer you can see how it's
not about large size at least in kind of
lengthen with the size of typical
smartphone it's links via a Bluetooth
device so you need there's mic shown in
relation to a smart phone and there's a
Bluetooth connection between those to
allow for easy acquisition and transfer
of the data so well perform the test it
itself doesn't have any readouts
directly on the unit it needs to
communicate with a device here via
bluetooth so it works of by a sample of
cannabis and then providing an
easy-to-read analysis for various things
this is just one example again pulled
right from their website cannabinoid
test for THC CBD CBN th T V a kind of
profile also of terpenes and again this
is an example here at you can see and it
kind of gives this nice coloration so
you'll be able to compare different
varieties easily and quickly now there's
also a crowd source or data to make
connections between personal effects
noticed for medical patients that's it
you know for pain for stress depression
on they're kind of populating
information there
based on what you feel and putting that
into a set there then it can be accessed
through the mydx app so again I'm not
sponsored by the company here but
personal kendall analyzed are called my
DX might be worth checking out
especially to make sure varieties that
you may be getting or testing very low
in THC and high in the medically benefit
of CBD