now while this will be a very short
summary here of personal protective
equipment or PPE those worth a
standalone video lecture here the sense
that PPE is typically see that
abbreviation or looking at pesticide
applications say how the proper PPE now
it's answer a personal protective
equipment you can see some examples of
that here now PPE these equipment is
designed to protect the individual from
injury or infection also keeping the
person or the applicator separate from
whatever they're applying now the exact
form of equipment used is determined by
the situation in the individual will be
facing typically though you'll see some
sort of head covering you'll see long
sleeves long pants boots and typically a
respirator involved with why I say the
exact form others different respirators
for different types of products some are
dis particulate respirators some might
be too specific chemicals that might be
evident here of the person making the
application so just understand that PPE
common abbreviation used personal
protection equipment and when you're
reading the label on a pesticide be
mindful of what they recommend and make
sure you have that on hand to separate
yourself from what you're applying