here we look at pesticide application in
safety and these rules apply whether
you're doing a large-scale spray or a
little spot spray or spring the whole
field with a backpack sprayer all of
these rules still apply in the key part
here what the safety is that you want to
read and follow the labels that are
posted there the label is the law is
kind of the nice little way to remember
that you want to use only what's needed
you want to use low toxicity pesticides
if that's an option when I consider the
weather if you're an outdoor application
don't apply just before a heavy rain on
chance it could be washed away when of
these proper equipments you're getting
good coverage for both the plants and
protecting you proper disposal of empty
containers when you're done or finish
the pesticide container avoiding teaming
the environment meaning don't apply
right next to waterways protect from
exposure for yourself post warning signs
as we see here in no emergency
procedures and that's good if you're
applying them also a worker on an area
that might be using pesticides again we
see these signs and danger and these big
red signs and the the skull and the
crossbones here so while it is word for
caution they can be applied in a safe
manner
if you do take into consideration what
the label says and properly protect
yourself there's different types of
pesticide products one is wettable
powders as we see here with the cocoa
powder making chocolate milk wettable
powders are a dry product that mixes
well with water to create a liquid
suspension that can be applied through a
variety of methods growers tend to like
this because of the smart small storage
space of the actual product then there's
actual liquid products and these are
liquid suspensions girls like the ease
of use of this and we see here with like
creamy reduce here ease of use with this
product but sometimes the binders can
hold that all the chemical and
suspension can cause increase the chance
of leaf burn so let's do some growers
didn't like the wettable powders because
they lack that binding agent then
there's dust or powders and that can be
applied simply as like this powder form
growers should have typically applying
these products and getting even coverage
especially for outdoor applications it's
almost not possible there's always a
little bit of breeze if you dip to get
around plants with the dusted product
there's making product applications so
any systemic synthetic chemical products
are not advised for cannabis because of
they will go through the entire plant
and can end up in the buds and when
burned can cause volatiles to form I'm
gonna be careful to read the labels
however this presents quite a challenge
for cannabis because there's typically a
lack of labeling of products
specifically listed for cannabis sprays
can be beneficial but can be over
applied so just be mindful of when you
made a last application and why you're
making that application Fido Texas City
can result as more damage than benefit
so you want to be mindful is you want to
be applying something to your plants for
the overall benefit not the hon watch
the spray timing low light is preferred
and that in Kurds outdoor applications
and low light also in indoor
applications you want to mixtures
products because you want to get it done
quicker wanna do what's called a jar
test or your mixing those ahead of time
to see if there's any interactions that
are occurring and hot temps will
increase the likelihood of damage to the
plants too important that outdoor
applications very experience the heat
wave or indoor applications if you're
applying it the peak of heating and heat
of the gross space that you have product
applicators the plant Arian location
will help in deciding what's the best
fit for your applicator
there's a pump sprayer as we see here a
hand or backpack and allows for maximum
control invest for small spaces and or
localized applications if we see here a
miss blower it's motorized in logic
quickest coverage with minimal effort
can also get really hot all on plans
very high applications it's basically a
leaf blower with a water tank on the
back through that electric foggers on an
offer many benefits as the miss blower
here but better suited for indoor
operations and again you can cover that
nice kind of fog that even coverage of
plants these are just some different
ways you can apply pesticides taking all
these into consideration will allow for
efficient application for the plants and
minimize environmental impacts