okay here we're a look at something
you're probably have heard of before and
are familiar with but may not fully
understand and that's the topic of pH we
might be familiar with the pH scale from
zero to fourteen acids are the lower end
bases at the higher end neutral is seven
which is pure water there's certain
indicators that will turn different
colors based on pH we want to try to
understand it for molecular level now so
first off to start pH what does that
even stand for it equals the potential
of hydrogen the scale is logarithmic
meaning it's not linear we're going to
see what impact each of these pH numbers
mean it's used to determine the acidity
or basicity of a water based on an
aqueous solution there's also something
called Poh which is the potential for
hydroxide so potential for hydrogen pH
that's referring to hydrogen here
hydroxide is Oh H this is the opposite
of pH essentially pH plus Poh equals 14
that's our 0 to 14 scale so if we take a
pH at the bottom here of 7 7 plus 1
equals 14 well 7 plus 7 is 14 so the pH
is 7 in this case the Poh is also 7
however anywhere else is where it starts
to get a difference something we may
consider an acid for example pH of 2
kind of rendering a near stomach acid
very acidic very strong acid pH of 2
that same substance with a Poh of 12
because 2 plus 12 will give us 14 sandy
we look at a basic solution here pH of
10 it's gonna the Poh of 4 because again
10 plus 4 is 14 continuing out of our
acids and bases an acid is a substance
that increases the hydrogen ion
concentration in a solution so our
assets here our pH of 0 to just under
700 chloric acid lemon juice grapefruit
juice tomato juice usually soft drink
urine saliva coffee soda vinegar all of
these are examples of acids I try to put
here is as the
each decreases as we get more acidic
here as this decreases the hydrogen ions
will increase so these stronger pH is
these lower pH levels love higher higher
concentration of hydrogen ions bases any
substance that reduces the hydrogen ion
concentration in the solution is a base
some bases reduce hydrogen ions directly
by accepting hydrogen ions examples of
basic solutions here there just happened
to be at the top of the baking soda
picture on 19.5 bleaches drain cleaners
long is seawater is actually slightly
basic these are examples of solutions
that are basic the pH scale as I said
the pH is an aqueous solution of the
hydrogen ion concentration times the
hydroxide concentration equals 10 to the
minus 14th here this measures the degree
of X acidity from that zero before to
the scale in relation to biology most
biological fluids are in the pH range of
6 to 8 in each pH unit represents a
10-fold difference
the scale is a logarithmic a small
change in pH actually indicates a
substantial change in hydrogen ion and
hydroxide ion concentrations so what
does that look like look right over here
for example well looking at pH of 1 our
hydronium ion our hydrogen ion is point
1 we go one point we notice we move that
decimal point one point to the last we
go another pH point well we have to move
that another tenfold so we can see that
this is a lot of rennes and that linear
it's a logarithmic you have this massive
increase in a change in the correlation
of pH values to hydrogen ion
concentrations so as from 3 to 5 you
know it's only ones only to 2 pH
different to this right so they page
difference of two well remember we're
moving it 10 fold each time so 10 a
hundred times more acidic as pH 3 to pH
5 there's something called strong acids
and strong bases strong acids and bases
completely dissolved in water
see here HCL divided dissolving
completely into hydrogen ions and
chloride ions sodium hydroxide same they
are into sodium ions and hydroxide ions
in contrast to that which we called weak
acids in a weak bases and these
dissociate only partially and kind of
are irreversible so if we go back to the
strong acids will notice that the arrow
goes away here we have this kind of
state of equilibrium there's going this
way and these are kind of slipping back
these hydrogen ions are binding and
going back and forth this is an example
of a weak acid and this is a weak base
it's going back and forth it doesn't
just go to completion in one way and
completely dissociate so water is both
an acid and a base which seems initially
a little confusing well if we take a
strong acid such as hydrochloric acid
and add it to the same concentration of
the base in this case sodium hydroxide
we actually get it's called a double
replacement we get water and salt we get
in salt water basically from a very
strong acid a very strong base the
reason why it's both an acid and the
base as we see it's in equilibrium here
h2o is going back and forth between
hydrogen ions and hydroxide ions now
ideally in pure water so being even kind
of split doesn't give us a pH of 7 as we
increase the hydrogen ions we then
create an acidic solution so you can see
here's our H HOH is the same as h2o
here's our chloride from here here's our
sodium this is kind of giving you an
idea of how things these bonds can
switch places give us very different end
substances the pH scale pH scales the
concentration of hydrogen ions in a
given substance pH equals the negative
log of hydrogen ions so we see here at
pH of 7 we have an equal number of
hydrogen ions and hydroxide ions as we
increase the acidity unity hydrogen ion
percent is vastly increasing just the
same opposite will happen if we increase
the basicity
the hydroxide ions will increase here
see it stays in a nice box and that
house always comes to equal 14 you take
our pH and editor Poh
now loving the problem here so how much
greater is the hydrogen ion
concentration in a solution with pH 2 in
a solution with pH 6 so we're looking at
hundred ion concentration we have our pH
is let's go through how we're going to
solve this so the answer here is a pH of
2 has a hydrogen ion concentration of
1/100 mole our pH of 6
high denying constant of 1 times 10 to
the minus 6 so we'll notice it's a much
smaller number 1 1 millions here so how
do we get this well by using the log
function you need a calculator to do
this you can do a couple examples here
we have 10 to the minus 2 that's what
the 2 is indicating the 6 is to the
minus 6 and we can see that the
difference between these two numbers is
10,000 times greater to to 6 so when
people say up H of 2 or 6 well it's
still on acid 2 2 6 2 3 4 5 6 oh well
it's only like four ish different pH
units it's not that much different it's
actually ten thousand times greater
hydrogen ion concentration at page two
compared to 6 so you can see it makes a
large difference buffers are very
important there are substances that
resist a change in pH buffers help organ
embody fluids in a narrow range
necessary for life the combinations of
hydrogen ions acceptors and donors form
a solution of weak acids and bases
that's buffering the solution this works
by accepting hydrogen ions from solution
when they're in excess and donating
hydrogen ions when they have been
depleted so what's happening with a
buffer it's kind of helping reduce the
large swings that may occurrence
Ellucian you see distilled water almost
no buffering solution we add a little
bit of volume of NaOH added to add like
one drop and we see the pH jump up
drastically in buffered solutions we see
that pH maintained a much more
consistent range
he's only slowly increase that's what a
buffer is doing well slowing or reducing
the massive differences or swings pH
it's very important for example for
blood pH or our normal pH is between
seven point three four and seven point
three eight pH of seven or seven eight
or getting into the very dangerous
ranges page of six or nine of blood pH
leads to death this is why it's
important we have buffers to help
maintain this normal pH in this tight
range so that we can allow us to survive
and allow our proteins to function
properly and allow us to be able to
carry out our normal bodily functions