if you are going to be participating in
growing plants hydroponically should be
very familiar in well versed with pH and
what it means and keep a close eye and
monitoring and also know how to adjust
it pH is the number one concern with any
operation but it's especially the case
with hydroponic setups because there's a
lack of buffer factors it can result in
quick changes in pH keep in mind that
it's a tenfold increase for every number
so if you're just two numbers off and
where you want to be that's that there's
two places that's a hundred full
difference in the hydrogen ion
concentrations and that can largely
affect and impact the nutrient
availability to your plants again
there's lack of buffer factors that
typically are more present in soil based
conditions if you are transitioning from
a soil base to a purely hydroponic base
you're gonna realize that pure water has
just about no buffering capacities as a
result the grow needs to keep a close
eye on this and people monitor and know
how to adjust it and not let it get too
far out of the ideal range because if it
does it will drastically impact the
nutrient availability to the plants it
can also burn or kill the crop if a
growers not careful