see a lot of times they'll hear where I
was talking about pH and maintaining pH
or checking for pH that's because it's
very important to plants why is the
impact plants so much well this kind of
graph right here is very important so
look at this a little bit more detail so
again why is it part of our culture well
pH impacts nutrient availability some
nutrients become unavailable to plants
at low or high pH levels so here's a
soil range an extreme soil range a pH of
4 to pH of 10 and the thicker the bar is
the more available that nutrient is now
here in this blue this slightly acidic
kind of column here that's where we
typically like to keep most P ages
you'll notice we kind of follow down
this range most nutrients are available
in the greatest amounts and this is why
it's important to plants so look at
nitrogen is for example here as we get a
pH kind of below 6 especially 5.5 its
availability becomes much less same
thing as if we get that pH soil above 8
the nitrogen in soil inherently becomes
less available to plants we see the
opposite here with some nutrients n or
more for acidic loving plants so for
example boron very thick here and 2 5
still maintains really thick and here if
we're a pH 8 or above becomes a lot less
available iron is kind of like the
opposite triangle here where once we get
a below pH of around you know around
that 6 2 to 6 and lower we see it's of
Exim amount availability molybdenum is
kind of the opposite where it's more
available at a basic range so plans such
as like blueberries that like that more
acidic range well they're liking the
iron in particular and some copper and
some other metals here so this is why pH
is so important because you can see over
different ranges how these nutrients
availability is greatly impacted and
here's how it kind of looks on the large
scale because the pH can determine in
amendments that needs to be used you can
indicate it's advantageous or necessary
to adjust pH level so x i'm sometimes if
there's like nutrient deficiencies are
nutrient issues one it could be low
amounts of that present in the soil or
it could be low amounts of that nutrient
available to plants in that soil so
sometimes simply adding lie
or sulfur to correct the pH can correct
nutrient deficiencies because those
nutrients that are already present the
soil become plants available