in this debaca university video i'm
going to go over why looking
at your ph values that you get back with
your soil test report
is so important
all right let's look at ph values
importance in the soil test report
so first off ph is the most important
and it's i know it's always hard to put
something
as the most important but one in doubt i
would say looking at your ph
is definitely very high if not the most
important
why because it impacts many plant and
nutrient aspects
if the ph is way off from your target
levels the rest
is much less important because when the
ph is adjusted
this can impact the availability of
other nutrients
remember soil test estimates to plant
available nutrients
not the total nutrients and this is just
a kind of a little
graphical representation that if we just
look at nitrogen here as an example
ph around seven uh pretty much that and
generally that
6.5 to kind of that little over seven
all in the green range
very available as we get more acidic or
more basic from that
we can see that the availability of that
particular nutrient will
decrease so this is why ph is very
important
because if our ph comes back very low
5.5
our phosphorus or potassium or sulfur
might be less plant available and show
up as less on a soil test because
remember
soil test is estimating the plant
available nutrients
not the total nutrients so what is ph
just in the general sense you would talk
about this
number that is that shows up it's a
decimal you know how does that kind of
relate to um
you know the what's going on in the soil
uh what does that number kind of
represent and what ph is we might be
familiar with that ph scale it's a
measure of the soil's acidity
it's a range from 1 to 14 with 7 being
neutral representing pure water
ph values below 7 you can see here and
below
are considered to be acidic while those
above are considered to be alkaline
the ph of a soil is not only affects the
availability of necessary
plant nutrients but also the solubility
of potential toxic elements such as
aluminum
and lead this is another reason why it's
important to know
the ph value of your soil
now we want to follow the lab
recommendations so here we see a soil
report
and they will often offer lab
recommendations as far as
amount of limestone or sulfur to be
adding and the
soil lab you select will know not only
the ph of your sample
but also if they're offering
recommendations they will calculate the
buffer capacity
which a buffer is simply resistance to
ph change
in relation to your soil type utilizing
all these factors will help produce a
good starting point
for correcting your soil's ph if it does
need to be corrected
remember though that the lab is only as
good as the sample you provide them
so make sure it is a representative
sample of the entire growing area
not just a single site to ensure the ph
adjustment will maximize plant for
performance
over the entire field and again follow
the
lab recommendations here they offer a
great starting point and you can see
over time
how that field how that soil may react
sometimes you make a
ph correction and it'll stay for a
number of years other times you need to
constantly
retest your soil and remaking
adjustments because some for
every reason shift from where your
target or ideal range would be