here we're gonna be looking at a portent
component of the immune system called
the phagocytes we see kind of a general
depiction here of phagocyte and a
foreign molecule being bound to being
destroyed and ultimately excreted here
as waste or as particles here so getting
into phagocytes they basically scan the
fluid areas of the body and macrophages
are one example and they are the chief
of
phagocytic cells in the body there are
free macrophages and they wander through
the regions in search of cellular debris
making the up to a hundred and meeting
cells before dying so here's just one
example here but macrophage is kind of
the web like fingers that come out and
attach to these foreign bacteria and
ultimately be destroying them so they
have that kind of binding that kind of
intake that lysosome to help destroy it
and then these I will debris is being
released through exocytosis and they can
kill up to basically a hundred invading
cells before they themselves um perish
yes I'm they called neutrophils and they
become a phagocyte addict when entering
infectious material so it's important to
help clean up the body to help prevent
potential infection they'll destroy
pathogens by breaking them down with
enzymes they died shortly after killing
the target cell so unlike our ones that
we saw before the macrophages
neutrophils they can't destroy hundreds
they died shortly after killing of the
cell the downfall is that these can
these neutrophils can also kill normal
healthy cells the collection of dead
neutrophils is also called pus if you're
a head that kind of area under the skin
that you can a poke and all that kind of
pus comes out what's actually a lot of
neutrophils they are the most abundant
white blood cells accounting for both 54
to 62 percent they're kind of that first
to come in to an infection and try to
clean it up as best that they can this
way they can be not quite as selective
as we saw with the macrophages the cinah
fills are weakly phagocyte addict
against parasitic worms they help
control inflammation increased activity
during parasite infection and older
check reactions these are the compiles
about one to three percent of white
blood cells here you can see not heavily
utilized by the immune system but still
offer another
a component of protection then we have
the mast cells and is binded in just a
wide range of bacteria they also release
histamine which if you have allergies
might be familiar with during
inflammation which is where it's
important but also as I said during
those allergic reactions those
histamines can kind of become overactive
and can kind of causes allergic kind of
reactions we have that's why a lot of
people take antihistamines to help mute
or reduce the impact that this has on
the body if it's over regulated it can
be quite the annoyance