all right here in this debaco university
video we're going to be
exploring phenol hunting limitations in
regards to cannabis so while female
hunting is done quite frequently
with many plant types including cannabis
i'm going to mention some of the
limitations if you are deciding to go
down this particular route so first off
funeral hunting is the
is the basis for selection so growers
have been breeding based on phenotypes
for generations and it still works
it is performed to this day so it's not
something that's just completely going
away
just have to be aware of some of the
limitations we do select this method
however with advancements and other
techniques there are more refined
methods
for the selection process they can help
speed up the process
and allow growers to start looking at
different aspects or characteristics of
plants
that may not have been possible years
ago
so first off with any form of growing
with any form
of plant production documentation is
important
you want to be tracking individual
selection progression and also the
environments that they're grown
in all are important tools to aid in the
selection
process and this can just looking at
here we have the we have the date
we have the day we have the trench ups
made any notes we have some actual
samples of leaves
so be sure to kind of document
the process because that will help you
as a grower be able to refine your
techniques
also have an idea of what traits you are
breeding for
is this will help the always challenging
selection process
you might see something you might have
to change your plans but at least go
into with some idea or some direction
as far as what you ideally want to be
breeding for
so knowing the environment is also a key
factor there
so when pheno hunting the environment
has a great influence on the final
product
so this needs to be taken into
consideration just because something
performs well it does not mean it will
always perform well
by knowing the particular conditions
that it did perform well and
that might be helpful to the grower or
breeder that might be selecting
that variety or letting others grow that
variety as far as knowing
what conditions it may prefer or like to
get the maximum production out of it
now here's a prime example here when
we're looking at um
bonsai tree hunters looking at different
phenotype selections
well bonsai tree hunters thought they
hit the promised land when they went to
the beach and found dwarf types of
common trees
dwarf types were becoming very popular
in certain times however when they
brought those trees that were very dwarf
in appearance back to the greenhouses
to breed them out because they thought
they found some unique genetics
they brought those greenhouses and they
found all the plants grew essentially
normally
so why was this the case that plants
that were definitely smaller
in dwarf why did they grow normally well
this was because the plants were dwarfed
due to the environmental stresses such
as water salt and wind that those plants
were exposed to
and once given the more normal or
favorable growing conditions
they then changed their performance then
we see the same example here where
there's a bonsai tree in a very small
container
here's a tree growing in a parking lot
with a very limited root base and here's
a tree growing that has a much more
expansive
root base while these all may be the
same variety or type of tree
you can see that they can produce vastly
different results
and the same thing maybe that to this
extreme level is also can also be seen
in cannabis so you also need to consider
what is happening
inside the plant while you may be
breeding and making selections growers
really do not know what the genetics of
their plants are
establishing the basic lineage can help
provide an idea but once the final end
product is produced it may be wise to
get a genetic screen or profile done
to determine just how different the new
creation may be
so that this is not meant to be a
letdown but if you think you're bringing
something that's really different and
unique at least phenotypically at least
what you can physically see
when you get to that kind of end result
or more towards those end results when
you really think you have something
unique
getting it genetically screened or
profiled might be advantageous
really just to see how unique that plant
actually may be
is it really different and unique or is
it really
something that is an influence of the
environment and really hasn't changed
any of the genetics
it's good to kind of know that before
you start mass producing it and
spreading it out everywhere
if it's related to your environmental
growing conditions or if you really have
some very unique genetics