in this tobacco university video we'll
be looking at phenotype profiling
related to cannabis and again phenotype
is how something physically looks
it's morphology how it looks to us when
it's growing as a plant
so that pheno hunting in general phenos
types are based on physical or visual
characteristics
this it is important to remember that
these traits can be influenced by the
environmental conditions the plant is
exposed to
so they can potentially change a plant's
phenotype based on what environment it's
growing
as a result documentation is important
for growing in general
but needs to include some extra details
when it comes to being applied to the
process
of pheno hunting growers should be extra
careful
take redundancies take as many pictures
and document as many
potential variables that they can to be
able to allow that screening process to
occur very efficiently
now we're going through and making that
selection well the greater number of
plants
grown makes it easier to find the
genetic standout if you're growing two
plants it's going to be really hard to
kind of phenol hunt
if you're growing 10 100 and 1 000 10
to be much easier as you get more plants
because then you can
likely see one that might be a true
genetic standout
because the goal is to be able to
recognize the differences and the amount
of plants that you have grown
this may be easy if you're looking for a
taller plant or one with greater
branching
but may be more challenging if you're
looking at chemical profiles to be
targeted and again this can be a form of
phenol hunting
but might be a little bit more difficult
because you can't just look out over a
whole grove of plants and see oh one's
genetically taller
maybe that's what i'm looking for once
maybe shorter what i'm looking for the
chemical profiles still can be done
but a little bit more complicated so the
overall goal
of funeral hunting in general is to
select a few individual plants with the
quote best traits
and continue to grow and propagate these
select few i put best in quotes because
that's going to relate to
what grow the grower is deeming
desirable
you want to continue to select the best
of the best by calling out or removing
those plants that do not fit the
intended breeding target and again that
breeding target may vary
based on different growers so that
phenotype selection process
well the selection process will take
time and does require
long-term dedication and careful
attention to detail
taking clones from the selected
phenotype is the first step
growing these out and then making
another selection process will reduce
the total
number of options in this example only
physical characteristics are determined
in the selection process
the final phenotype will at least
ideally have the greatest amount of
desirable plant habits
or products or whatever kind of
traits the grower is looking for the
amount of generations this takes is up
to the grower and
refinement of the selected traits some
might be done in a fewer generations so
might take more generations
this can be bred into another best of
the best selection or grown out to
increase the population of the selection
particular phenotype so again it's
important to keep in mind we see here
original phenotypes we have a whole
bunch listed
we have those first generation clones we
have the second generation clones and
then we have the final phenotype
so here we can see the og k5 you can
trace that lineage back
that was one of the many they made to
this first generation second generation
also it was the final generation
however i'll say this might be a little
misleading simply because it will often
take more than just two or three
generations
to get that one unique kind of selection
for a process
so just be mindful know what you're
looking for
importance of documentation so that
you're able to be efficient
with your selection process as possible
in hopes that you can get that final
unique phenotype you might be looking
for