in this debaco university video we'll be
looking at phosphorus importance to
plants
in relation to a soil test report
[Music]
so while these tests typically are not
known for giving super accurate results
they can provide some indication
and really here you'll be getting your
test at a professional lab
and we're going to look at phosphorus
importance in a soil test report you get
from
professional lab so first off the impact
of phosphorus
on plants phosphorus or chemical or
elemental symbol p is essential for root
development in the production of flowers
and fruits
so as a result does get a lot of
attention from growers
you can see here's a couple of the
things that are related to phosphorus
but root formation
promotion of flowers and fruits are
typical roles
associated with phosphorus however
phosphorus
is being regulated in more and more
states
native connecticut soils and this is
using connecticut as an example
and native connected soils are generally
low in phosphorus
and much of what is present is bound in
both organic matter
and inorganic forms not readily
available to plants
however over-application has led to a
2013 law
regulating the use of phosphorus on
established lawns
phosphorus is a serious pollutant of
inland waterways leading to algal blooms
and accompanying environmental and human
health risks
and this has gotten to the point that
new legislation or legislation has been
enacted
to regulate the use of phosphorus in
soils
so realize that this is a could be a
very serious concern
so when we're looking at those
phosphorus levels phosphorus is most
available in soil
ph around 6.5 and during moist warm
conditions soil tests provide an
estimate of the amount of readily
available phosphorus and recommendations
are made accordingly
the goal here is if it's very acidic
very alkaline a lot of that phosphorus
is locked up
that ph just right we have a lot of the
phosphorus being
plant available now what impacts the
plant availability of this phosphorus
and there's kind of a combination of
factors
that do impact its availability as i
mentioned before of course ph
is one of them but we're also looking at
organic matter
mineralization of organic matter
releases plant available forms of
phosphorus into soils
organic molecules can also reduce
phosphorus retention
increasing the amount of available forms
clay content in soils
soils with higher clay content have high
phosphorus retention capacities
simply because clay particles have a
very large surface air per unit volume
which can absorb phosphorus very easily
the mineralogy of the soil
mineral composition of soil influences
the phosphorus absorption capacity
example soils with high content of
aluminum or iron ions
iron ions tend to have the greatest
phosphorus absorption capacity
which will decrease its availability to
plants
as i mentioned before soil ph optimum ph
is between 6 and 7
results in the maximum phosphorus
availability
low ph acidic soils have great amounts
of aluminum iron
which form strong bonds with the
phosphate high ph soils when calcium is
dominant cation
phosphate tends to partici precipitate
with those calcium ions
and there's also other factors such as
temperature moisture and soil aeration
can also affect the rate of phosphorus
mineralization
from organic matter and decomposition so
in humid
warm conditions climates organic matter
decomposes faster compared to cool
dry climates and there's also erosion
and potential runoff
that can also occur that and to increase
availability we can also have weathering
dissolution and disabsorption as well
so how do we control how much phosphorus
you add
well an additional phosphorus beyond the
agronomic need of crops has
minimal effect on crop yield so why
would you be adding more
however the excess phosphorus is
susceptible to loss through runoff
and erosion it can promote algal growth
in freshwater systems
causing degradation of water quality
this is why it's important to know what
your phosphorus levels are
and in some cases where you've got the
optimum level or probably above optimum
you can purchase fertilizers that do not
have any fertilizer in them a 2404 is
the example here
because you already know you've got
enough phosphorus in your soil so no
need to add any more
and this would offer you the other
nutrients that you your crops may need
without running the risk of contributing
to fresh water
contamination through algal blooms and
general runoff
of excess phosphorus