okay here we look at photosynthesis
compared to respiration keep in mind
photosynthesis occurs in the
chloroplasts respiration in the
mitochondria photosynthesis has the
light dependent reaction and the Calvin
cycle respiration is aerobic or could be
an aerobic cellular respiration it's
going to be using glucose and oxygen
those that are being broken down into
carbon dioxide and water which are
needed by the photosynthetic process so
the general sense here the comparison
between photosynthesis and respiration
for synthesis assembles the sugars
produces stored or potential energy
respiration breaks down those sugars
into energy in releasing that cell
respiration and photosynthesis are
interdependent the glucose and oxygen
produced by photosynthesis are used in
cellular respiration the energy is
transferred to generate ATP with heat
carbon dioxide and water is released as
a waste product
the carbon oxide and water are then
available as raw materials for
photosynthesis we see that here here's
our light energy most of this is
assembling our the sugar molecule
c6h12o6 in taking out oxygen that's then
being used by the process of cellular
respiration breaking down that sugar
molecule to generate ATP heat energy and
also carbon dioxide and oxygen are
byproducts both are needed for the
photosynthetic process and the cycle
then repeats
looking specifically at a direct
comparison between the two first since
this only occurs in the light an occurs
in cells containing chlorophyll the
synthesis produces ATP with light energy
and uses carbon dioxide in water
molecules this is thought to increase
the weight of the organism respiration
near the end occurs anytime takes place
in living cells but to clear the
mitochondria those living cells and it
produces ATP with energy released from
the sugar molecules this releases carbon
dioxide in water and sought to decrease
the weight so we're producing our
photosynthetic process with the light
energy its producing that glucose
that glucose is kind of that stored
energy the stored energy for the process
of respiration is broken down returning
our ATP here that ATP is being used to
do work that work could be movement of
motor proteins could be molecular
transport could be synthesis of
biomolecules what's given off as a
byproduct it's carbon dioxide and water
we just need to put a synthetic process
to occur and around the cycle goes
should be it understand and compare and
contrast both photosynthesis and
respiration for some similarities and
how they're needed for biological
systems and also some differences