so this is intended to be a very brief
overview of closed synthesis which is a
very complex process try to break it
down to the most basic and simple terms
here now this picture is basic as I can
make it where we have a plant receiving
sunlight carbon dioxide from the
atmosphere water being absorbed through
the roots and as a result it's producing
oxygen and also sugar molecules here
this is the chemical kind of equation
here we're look at this in just a little
bit more detail so here's a little
different representation of that the
plants taking in carbon dioxide from the
air in the atmosphere specifically h2o
or water being absorbed in the roots and
root hairs specifically this is
occurring in the presence of light which
is allowing the chlorophyll in the leaf
to synthesize carbohydrates a sugar
molecule in releasing oxygen back into
the atmosphere now while we think about
this occurring with terrestrial plants
which is is very important also can't
forget about the oceans and the plankton
on it's occurring they're producing
basically half of the amount of oxygen
that we need to breathe now you'll
notice also in this picture ATP Calvin
cycle light reactions we're not going to
get into details for this lecture is a
very complex process I'm just going over
a very basic overview this is the
general equation so most of this is
producing sugar
it's just glucose and oxygen as
byproducts it's taking in carbon dioxide
and water and using light energy to
assemble these so if you can familiarize
yourself with this basic equation of
flow synthesis hopefully gains a little
bit greater appreciation for the
complexities of this process that plants
are going through allowing us to have
the oxygen that we need to breathe