here i'll be doing my best to provide
you an overview
of the photosynthetic processes we see
pictured here
a lot of times it's abbreviated capital
p lowercase s if you see that that
stands for
photosynthesis now the basic overview
is taking in plants taking solar energy
carbon dioxide and water to produce
energy storing carbohydrates in the form
typically of sugars
oxygen is generated as a byproduct and a
waste product for plants which is a good
thing for us animals
because we need that to breathe to go
through our cellular respiration
process and the water is absorbed
through the roots of the plant and is
transpired through
throughout the plant there to help move
water keep everything hydrated high
tucker pressure
and also remove nutrients now looking at
photosynthesis on a macro
and micro scale not all cells within a
plant
carry out or have all the components to
carry out
photosynthesis cells in the middle layer
of the leaf have the chloroplasts which
contain the photosynthetic apparatus
we see that here the dark green region
look towards the top that's the cuticle
and that's a waxy protective layer this
dark green section here is where the
photosynthesis
will be occurring at the highest rate
now within
the photosynthesis it's a very complex
sequence of steps in short though it's
conversion of
light energy into chemical energy so it
takes place in two stages we have the
light
dependent reaction and then we have the
calvin cycle or the light independent
reaction
the light dependent reaction is takes
place in the thylakoid membrane uses
light as the name implies
it's generating atp and nadph
those energy molecules are going to the
calvin cycle
which takes place physically in the
plant within the stroma
and it uses energy derived from these
compounds to make
3p ultimately will be made into sugars
from
the carbon in carbon dioxide now the
equation for photosynthesis which you
might be familiar with
is carbon dioxide plus water and
sunlight producing sugars and
oxygen now it takes six carbon dioxide
six water molecules light energy to
produce one
sugar or glucose molecule and six oxygen
molecules
uh it's this it's kind of deceptively
kind of simple when you look at it this
way
but there's a very complex sequence of
steps that derive this
uh this is requires a lot of
intermediate reactants but this is the
general
summary glucose is the primary energy
source in cells and
is made from two three carbon ga3ps
now photosynthesis is a transfer of
electrons and this is what's
termed a redox reaction since electrons
have a negative charge
when an electron is transferred there's
also a change in charge
gaining electrons meaning you're being
reduced losing electrons it's called
oxidation so you think about gaining a
negative charge your
total charge is going to become negative
it's going to be reduced it's going to
be
less than what it was before this is how
it gets the team
redox reaction reduction and oxidation
when you're transferring the electrons
something is getting reduced and
something is getting oxidized
so if it wasn't this transfers electrons
from water to energy
poor carbon dioxide molecules forming
energy rich sugar molecules
so again when you're kind of gaining
those electrons that's part of the
reduction in charge and losing electrons
is oxidizing
so we have this kind of simple way to
remember this oxidative reduction
redox process the water is oxidized
meaning it's losing electrons and the
carboxylate is reduced means it's
gaining electrons
photosynthesis uses light energy to
drive these electrons from water
to their more energetic states of the
sugar byproducts result of solar
energies convert to chemical energy
now remember this is called leos the
lion says ger
leo l-e-o losing electrons is oxidation
gaining electrons is reduction so leo
cisger
very commonly said easy to remember to
help you remember
what's going on with a redox reaction we
see here
reductions are gaining electrons the
carbon dioxide going to the sugar and
water
ultimately going to the oxygen is the
oxidation that's losing electrons in
that process
this all takes place as i said in the
chloroplast so i should probably
show you what a chloroplast looks like
in some of the components this is
where that photosynthetic process is
occurring and i mentioned
also the stroma where the light
independent reaction or the calvin cycle
occurs this is all within this membrane
here but remember there's multiple
membranes
so these stacks of style code called
granite from a third membrane
as well so we can see an outer and inner
and kind of a third membrane this is
what's allowing these compartments to
very precisely control where these
reactions are occurring
now chloroplasts from multiple views
here we can see that chloroplast
consists of thylakoid membranes
surrounded by the stroma the thylakoid
membranes contain molecules of the green
pigment chlorophyll for the absorption
of light
you can see the cartoon image how they
look here kind of all stacks this is
what they look like in an actual
i mean we can see those really dark kind
of banding regions
are those basically those thylakoids
they're stacked together the furnace
chronum
the absorbed light most of the light is
lost
as heat from the leaf so that's kind of
an interesting note that those leaves
are out there but there's
receiving light which is great they need
that to be able to convert those sugars
but they're also getting a lot of
heat energy the cooling aspect of
transpiration is very important for
plant survival
and that transpiration is kind of like
the plant sweating you think of it as
that
in that term where those high energy
molecules are being evaporated
reducing the temperature of the leaf so
it doesn't burn so we have
photophosphorylation which is generating
atp
adenosine triphosphate this is the
energy used by the cells to complete its
necessary function
that's the highest level and eating
triphosphate only having two phosphates
and they've seen
diphosphates because the next lowest the
lowest energy form is
uh amp adenosine monophosphate the
adenosine triphosphate atp is the energy
currency of the cell
so it can be able to complete many
necessary
and life-supporting functions