okay here we're looking at the equation
for photosynthesis which you hopefully
are becoming more familiar with in this
video lecture we're gonna go over some
of the roles of these components and why
they're needed to be able to carry out
this necessary process for life so
looking specifically at the first one
carbon dioxide is important now carbon
dioxide enters through the stomata of
the lead and it's gotta pick a little
bit of a journey to get to where it's
needed to be used first it's going
through the stroma thence diffusing
through the cell wall and then the
membrane and into the cytoplasm before
finally reaching the chloroplast so
there's a little bit of a process that
is required now carbon dioxide is this
source of carbon so all of the lignin
and carbon sources for the sugars
polysaccharides monosaccharides
disaccharides all comes from the carbon
of carbon dioxide now as we increase a
concentration of carbon dioxide it'll
plant may be experiencing we noticed the
rate of synthesis will also increase
however there's a certain point put a
saturation here begins to Plateau
here we're adding more carbon dioxide
but our photosynthetic rate is that
increase in it levels off this could be
due to certain limiting factors it could
be water the plant could be nutrients
there's certain limiting factors that
occur you see in this graph here ties it
with little bit of numbers our ambient
carbon dioxide level is about 410
ourselves we're kind of in this range
you can see there is some benefit that
adding increased levels of carbon
dioxide but then there's a certain point
where our rate just maxes out in
plateaus there so just know that carbon
dioxide is important it's got to be
diffused to get to the chloroplast and
is the source of carbon or this process
to occur another very important
component is water it's used for many
purposes in a plant less than one
percent goes to the photosynthetic
process most goes for cooling or engine
that plants receiving the light they're
getting a lot of heat with that through
the transpiration process are able to
cool themselves water is also the source
of electrons which as remember are in
the
outer shell here these are valence
electrons of our atom remember in their
nucleuses are protons and neutrons
oxygen is a byproduct because we're
going to be splitting water and limiting
water can directly limit this
photosynthetic process reason being when
a plane is turgid or has enough water
the guard cells open the stomata this is
great cuz it allows carbon dioxide in
allows oxygen to leave but in addition
to oxygen leaving water will also be
leaving when a plant becomes water
stressed this guard cells become
shrunken and close off it's eliminating
water from leading but it's also
preventing oxygen from leaving and
carbon dioxide from entering so this
water can directly impact the stomata
which can impact the rate that
photosynthesis can occur light is
another necessary component in light as
many different wavelengths not all
colors use are used in the same
proportion longer wavelengths are reds
and oranges and are shorter wavelengths
are our violets our Indigo's in our
blues ROYGBIV red orange yellow green
blue indigo and violet we have our
increase in here and energy with our
shorter wavelengths so x-rays in UV rays
have more energy than to our infrared
rays now we're going to see that the
chlorophyll uses different parts of this
particular spectrum so what does that
actually look like this is one of the
graphs and charts that would look like
here so our chlorophyll again this is
the site where all this is occurring
it's a very important component it has
properties similar to human globin in
our in our own bodies chloroplast
structures are aware this is actually
occurring and there's different types of
chlorophyll chlorophyll a is the
dominant chlorophyll we see here that
represented by the absorbance in the
solid line and we'll notice it's this
blue to kind of dark dark green color
and it drops off we get two greens and
yellows we notice another spike for
chlorophyll I in the red spectrum so
these are the absorption slights now we
talk about different wavelengths are
measured in nanometers this is showing
the specific
that chlorophyll a is is a able to
absorb chlorophyll B allows the
photosynthetic process to occur over a
broader spectrum of light as energy is
transferred to chlorophyll a now
chlorophyll B is these long dashed lines
and will notice the peaks for
chlorophyll B are close to but different
than chlorophyll a what this is allowing
the plant to do is absorb different
wavelengths of light in beta-carotene
also is slightly different now plants
are mostly green color because they're
reflecting a lot of that green plant so
it will absorb a lot of that green color
we see you strong in the Reds and the
blues are the wavelengths or the light
energy that plants are typically
absorbing at a greater percentage now
the world's compose the electron
transport chain
so our look trying to transport chain
it's non cyclic mean it only goes in one
direction try to put a picture here of
one direction to help you realize that
this particular electron transport chain
is only progressing in one direction
where is it occurring well we're back to
our chloroplast it's important to keep
yourself oriented remember the stroma is
the aqueous fluid surrounding the Granum
so you see it here and the thylakoid
lumen is occurring inside and the face
except resented by the red here inside
the actual thylakoid inside those actual
discs now we're looking at a
phospholipid bilayer we're going to be
investigating the proteins embedded in
that just because here are thylakoid
lumen is on the lower side and our
stroma is on the upper side don't think
that's always the case keep in mind that
these proteins could be down here and it
could flip so just be able to orient
yourself depending what picture that I
give you to keep in mind that the
thylakoid lumen is inside those discs
and the stroma is on the outside and
this electron transport chain that we
see is producing an end product we'll
see in the Calvin cycle for example
things need to be regenerated that's not
the case here it's a transport chain it
occurs only in one direction this might
be a little
using right now and that's okay but I'm
stressing the point it's non-cyclic
electron transport we're seeing our
light energy exciting our electron we
see all these arrows go in one way or a
react setting that electron moving over
here producing an end product
this is non cyclic it's called the Z
scheme because it kind of psycho Z while
this may seem a little confusing right
now initially if you come back to this
video after watching some of my others
hopefully you'll be able to understand
what the photosystems are doing what
some of the necessary proteins are also
contributing to be able to allow this
necessary process for life to occur