okay here we're gonna investigate the
topic of photoperiodism what this is is
the impact that day length can have on
the flowering of plants we have certain
plants that are called short day plants
the certain ones called long day plants
we're going to investigate what causes
plants to flower and when well first off
the purpose of flowering just in the
general sense is the goal is to allow
the plants to reproduce this needs to
happen in sync with pollinators plants
want to be in sync with their
pollinators because if they're not then
this bees neck Fila transferred the
pollen in that individual will not be
able to survive point city of plants and
chrysanthemums are short-day plants with
ports a is requiring even longer nights
or when thing about is shorter days to
flower this is why typically we see
these grown and producer vibrant colors
in the winter time lilies for example
hour long day plants and a farm this
spring as Ned shorten in the days of
lengthen let's investigate these short
and long day plants a little bit more so
the first part is well plants are being
able to perceive this long and short
days well how do they tell time well
they have two different ways
phytochromes our leaf pigments and
enable plants to sense light in dark
periods this helps the plant determine
the photoperiodism which is plant's
response to the length of light in
darkness
now the phytochrome system is a
biologically inactive form of the
fenachrone where PR is converted to the
biologically active form called pfr as
we see here under illumination with a
red light far red light and darkness
converted smelling back to the inactive
form so what does this mean well first
off our red light is referring to light
that's kind of beyond the 700 nanometers
we're kind of getting out of the area
where we can see normal visible light
and a little bit of lower of energy too
so this active form in periods of
darkness will transfer over into the P R
which is the inactive form now we can
use far red light to help make that
process go quicker or we can use red
light to help create an inactive
to an active form very quickly these
changes is initiating this in cellular
response so let's like this again here
are four other crumbs in particular they
have both the active inactive form
remember the inactive form is the PR and
it's converted into the active form one
absorbs red light we see here here's our
inactive PR for absorbing red light
particularly the 660 nanometers convert
to PFR the active form of the
phytochrome the PFR is broken down into
the inactive form one absorbs the red
light we see here for a quick version or
the active form can gradually revert
back to the inactive form in the absence
of light or that darkness period so this
transfer that occurs here this slower
version back to the inactive is how
plants can help tell the length of night
that occurs this is how again how they
tell time we can trick them with
different lights but naturally when the
Sun sets our active pfr s are slowly
going to convert to PRC an active form
the plant will simply measure this and
be able to tell how long it's been night
so one key important factor to all of
this is that plants class is short or
long day plants have the critical factor
in determining activities night length
so while we kind of use the term short
day long day plants can only determine
the length of time of continuous and
darkness this is how they're tell any
time and this is an important aspect
because this can help influence or
impact plants abilities to sense the
length of the quote day really they're
only able to determine the length of
night so way to think about this is as
soon as the Sun sets plants start a
stopwatch and as soon as they see light
as soon as the Sun rises they stop that
stopwatch and they look at that amount
and they're able to then tell whether
the short day or a long day but they're
only able to tell the length of
continuous darkness so let's put this in
a graphical form I'd be a little bit
easier to understand here so looking at
our short day plants they flower when
days are short the way the thing about
this is if days are short well the night
period is
we call the critical length so here's
our short day plant we see that thing
night was short okay meaning a long day
plants do not flower the short day
plants pfr inhibits flower and hence
flower requires low levels of pfr
resulting in long nights here's our
critical length and here's our long
night now that long night equates to a
short day in the plant will flower
because the night time or the length of
night the length of continuous darkness
was greater than the critical link where
it gets a little confusing here is where
we have a long night
but in the middle for whatever reason we
have a flash of light we notice the play
doesn't flower during this time this is
because plant seen a long day of
uninterrupted night light as I said
remember plants have a stopwatch they
see darkness they started the stopwatch
Oh light comes in they stop that
stopwatch and they look at the time oh
so what's the critical length and they
restart again and they count again oh
and they look at again they stop it nope
not long enough they won't flower it's
not a summation in total they need to
have continuous hours of darkness and we
see that evident here that continuous
hours of darkness is greater than the
critical length no flower here we have
that little burst of light and that's
causing them not to flower because each
of these parts is less than the critical
length so in this case they don't flower
short day plants really mean long night
plants these short day plants require
periods of darkness to be greater than
the undirected critical period these
plants tradition will not flower during
the summer months when night lengths are
short what a culture so can trigger
flowering in these plants by covering
the plants with an opaque black cloth
for about 12 hours criticisms are an
example of this everyone wants them to
bloom at the right time
so what botanist can do is simply block
out the light causing the night to be
longer in this case and causing them to
flower this is in comparison to our long
date plants and see again that
comparison between the two and discuss
these now and hopefully provide a little
bit of an example between the two so our
long day plants they flower when days
are long or
we're a night period to be less than the
pinnacle life so we see that here night
length is shorter than the critical
period boom the flower here's our night
length longer than the critical period
they don't flower but what's interesting
here if you have that burst of light
again and what this has created now is
sections of continuous darkness to be
less than the critical night light and
those plants will actually flower during
that time so long day plans to PFR
activates flowering and hence flowering
repairs high levels of pfr these results
in the shortened nights again here we
have a long night we have that burst of
light in the middle and that can cause
the plant to flower kind of putting it
together hopefully this picture here
makes a little bit more sense those long
days week long day in plants require
periods of darkness to be less than the
uninterrupted critical length these
plates will traditionally not flower
during the winter and autumn ones when
night lengths are long for colors
control flowering in these clamps by
exposing the plant to a light source
during the night so we see that right
here we're imposing those plants
exposing those plants this bright light
in the middle of the night breaking
apart that continuous hours of darkness
causing the flower carnations are an
example a long day plant so again even
though they're listed as long day and
short day plants we want to keep in mind
that plants can only tell the hours of
continuous darkness and that's how
they're determining whether they flower
or not short day plants will flower
during periods of long night long day
plants will flower during periods of a
short night we can influence that with a
burst of light here we're breaking that
cycle in the short day plant and here
we're breaking that hours mutinous
darkness here with the burst of light
causing long day plants to flower and
suppressing flowering in short day
plants lastly we there's some things
called date neutral plants and these
plants will flower independently of a
photo period but they may require a
period of cold in some instances rice is
a prime example of what's called a day
neutral plant it will flower regardless
of a lengthening day a shortening day a
burst of light or not it is a private
sale
all of a day neutral player