welcome to this debaco university video
where i'm going to go over
photosynthesis related to cannabis
production
[Music]
all right let's look at some of the
plant physiology and relate it to
cannabis production
so first off we have to understand the
basic equation and this is the basic
photosynthetic equation
any reactant in reactants here on the
left
can be a limiting reactant as far as
generating sugars and oxygen
so carbon dioxide is easily a limiting
factor especially during high light
intensities
so as growers to maximize plant
production typically sugars
in the end we want to make sure the
carbon dioxide the water and the light
are not
going to be limiting as far as the plant
is concerned
so we'll start with the light component
well that light spectrum
and remember we're looking here at the
visible light spectrum so if you look
here we can see all these different
wavelengths of light correspond with
different colors
overall the reds are the longer
wavelengths compared to the
violets in the blues here and these are
all measured in nanometers
and for plants we're seeing some
increased importance with also the
ultraviolet spectrum
as well as the infrared which are areas
outside of the visible spectrum
so looking at a comparison spectrum
this is a representative solar spectrum
looking at basically the sun
this is the kind of we're looking here
is the output of the sun
and what it produces as far as different
wavelengths go and wavelengths are
measured in nanometers
so this is sampled from 350 to 850 just
to give an idea of
the representative solar spectrum so
when we're looking at plants well
chlorophyll is important chlorophyll
in any form relates to the green
pigments
found in the mesosomes of cyanobacteria
and
in the chloroplast of algae in plants
chlorophyll is essential in
photosynthesis
allowing plants to absorb energy from
light
taking that light energy and ultimately
going to go and convert it to chemical
energy such as sugars
chlorophyll absorbs light most strongly
in the blue portion of the
electromagnetic spectrum
as well as the red portion but don't
take that to mean that it's only
absorbing those
even though we see the green color that
means it's reflecting green
there is some green light that is still
absorbed within plants
conversely is a is a poor absorber of
green or near green portions of the
spectrum
which reflects producing the green color
of chlorophyll containing tissues
but it still is absorbing some of that
green light two types of chlorophyll
exist
in photosynthesis plants uh they are
chlorophyll a
as well as chlorophyll b now looking
here plants absorbing more than just
chlorophyll
so while chlorophyll does get a lot of
attention we also did take into
consideration more than square fill and
chlorophyll b
there's also different compounds that
are absorbing different wavelengths
this is allowing the plant through
basically what's called an
antenna complex to utilize more of the
wavelengths of light that it's exposed
to
so this is helpful to the plant because
it's not just needing these finite
little wavelengths
it's being able to utilize a greater
portion of the light it's exposed to so
here's that kind of utilization of
different wavelengths of light and i get
my sources right here kind of gives you
a nice little visual comparison here
where we're seeing that green light yes
it is absorbing less
but less does not mean in this case zero
so as a result this you can see that
definitely in that bluer purple range
and whereas that orange and red range
we're seeing a greater percentage of
relative response
but all wavelengths are being utilized
in some way with plants
so here's a research article looking at
kind of the photosynthetic response here
with variations with the photosynthetic
photon flux densities
abbreviated ppfd so that's going to be
important here and this is a great
article if you wanted to research it
further
so when we're looking at cannabis
because this is focused initially on
cannabis here
is that canvas is a high light intensity
plant
sunlight has a light intensity of
measured in that photosynthetic
photon flux density of 2000 micromoles
per meter squared per second however is
not economical to provide
this light level for an indoor operation
canvas is often given around a thousand
micromoles per second to aid in plant
quality
in comparison a low light intensity
plant such as lettuce can grow well in
only 200
micromoles per second squared we can see
that evident right here where it almost
grows produces a little bit larger
leaves
compared to the higher light intensities
so this is why it's important
to try to find research on the
particular crop that is of interest
of you so that ppfd and temperature how
do these kind of correlate or how do
they kind of relate
it's important to take all environmental
conditions into consideration
so keep in mind that for the
abbreviation ci's
internal co2 concentration ca's external
concentration
looking particularly at cannabis leaves
here
so what the researchers found is that a
combination of 30 degrees
celsius in temperature and 1 500
micromoles
measured with a ppfd may be best
suitable for indoor cultivation of
cannabis plants in this case the
cannabis sativa that they were looking
at
so this kind of gives you an idea of the
light intensity but also the temperature
to maybe set as your targets if you're
looking at maximizing
yield of cannabis so when we're looking
at light we also need to consider the
light
quantity and also the light quality so
light quantity or dli which correlates
more with biomass and dli is the daily
light intensity that it's getting so
more light equals more plant
at least following the biological curve
or plateau so it's not a linear
x kind of or an exponential curve it's
just kind of this plateauing region here
light quality or color which is a par
reading impacts the morphology of the
plant
so if you give your plant more of the
red wavelengths it has a tendency to
stretch more
it has it more of just the blue
wavelengths it tends to stay more
compact
closer internet you can also see here
that with light intensity
photosynthetic rate some areas can be
light limited some can be carbon dioxide
limited and this all goes back
to that photosynthetic equation and we
could hopefully see now
how those different components from an
equation you may have learned previously
now relates to cannabis production