this video is on the animal phylum
echinodermata now as you can tell by the
duration this video it's not very long
but that was worth mentioning and at
least devoting a little couple slides to
in a little time Dale so first off what
does this exactly mean its refers to
spiny skin of the endoskeleton of the
calcium-rich obstacles just beneath the
in the kind of terms of skin these are
entirely marine animals they live
entirely in the ocean they include sea
stars sea urchins sand dollars in sea
cucumbers what's an interesting fact
about these is that they're bilaterally
symmetrical as larvae but become a
radial symmetry as adults radial
symmetry refer to that anywhere through
the midpoint a to draw a plane they're
symmetrical
but they're bilayers symmetrical as
larvae just a general overview here of
the anatomy again nothing that I'm going
to focus on particularly in class but
again if we do a dissection are really
just to appreciate some of the anatomy
of these animals I've included the
picture here at the end