as the title suggests we're gonna be
looking at the animal phylum Arthropoda
okay I've just kind of put this here to
hope to get you to remember and how to
pronounce the proper term there then you
can see some species located within this
phylum now what makes this particular
fiim unique is the advent of jointed
appendages now this is the most
successful of all the animal groups and
these jointed appendages are one of the
key distinguishing factors for this
phylum in addition to that there's also
exoskeleton made of chitin the muscles
attached on the inside of this outer
shells we see here in that outer shell
made of chitin protects against
predators and also water loss you see
that evident right here it's very hard
type structure now cannot support much
weight so that results in a limiting of
these individuals total size they have
segments they three in particular that
often fuse into functional groups when
the animal reaches the adult stage the
three segments are the abdomen the
thorax and the head so these are also
important to be identify on these
particular animals if we do dissections
up or we want to refer to a specific
region these are the three regions the
head the thorax and the abdomen you
should be familiar with now there's
certain subsets within this phylum that
lack jaws coalesce traits one of those
and they just simply they might have
mouth parts but they lack of jaws
spiders mite scorpions and horseshoe
crabs horseshoe crabs are interesting
that we have fossil records going back
about 630 million years ago they're the
only surviving type of this particular
TripIt uh so they're found and they're
not extremely rare found in pretty high
numbers along the beach in June in Long
Island sounds when they can come in and
they tend to group together when they're
mating so that's can be one to be seen I
also have one hanging on the wall to
preserve specimen isn't that true for
all author through Peter some have
actual mouth parts we
all those jaws properly termed mandibles
we see that in the human hair
highlighted in green we also see that at
the ant here these insects centipedes
millipedes have these mandibles which
are specialized mouth parts or jaws
maybe a little bit of a shocker of a
slide sorry for that our arachnids they
have four pairs of walking legs and then
these two entities are not used for
walking they're just more for feeling
for gathering food items for moving
things but not specifically for walking
so within the arachnid species there's
about five well 57,000 named species
within this so he just classify them as
spiders and gotcha something in that
category well there's ticks and mites
and daddy longlegs and scorpions and
spiders all lumped into this same group
of arachnids then these arachnids
there's among the first to live on land
going from water to air breathing
scorpions are thought to be one of the
first to make that transition from the
water environment to the land
environment
the reason is their lungs have a strong
resemblance of king-crab gills
particularly something called the book
log you see that here if you've ever
opened the shell of a crab you see the
lungs or gills really here it's very
similar to king crabs gills match the
lungs of a scorpion the lungs are
specific alongs they're called Booker's
they kind of look like the pages of a
book this is creating a high surface
area allowing efficient exchange of
oxygen and carbon dioxide these
crustaceans comprise of a diverse group
of mandibles about 35,000 species such
as crabs shrimp lobster crayfish and
pill bugs some be really small and some
can be quite large and they're all under
this same general classification here we
can see the diversity that does exist
now most crustaceans have two pairs of
antennae three pairs of two independent
is in various number of the legs you may
we remember from one of my previous
videos the importance of knowing your
orientation the dorsal views looking
kind of from the top down here the back
of the animal the
central's that underside of that belly
region and here's the side view
let me require you to know all the
individual segments here but again could
be advantageous for identification
purposes if we do a dissection of a
crustacean crustacean is just living in
New England want to point out some key
items here with our lobster we may think
of a lobster in New England the Maine or
American lobster here with its large
claws for most of the world though the
Caribbean or spiny lobster is what most
people think of when they hear the term
lobster so what makes the Maine or
American lobster so desired all over the
world its large claws the meat in its
claws you can see the Caribbean or spiny
lobster has a good tail meat region but
not really anything in great in the claw
vision millipedes and centipedes I just
want to highlight some differences
between these two mill peas and sanity's
have bodies that consist of hard head
region I'm sorry followed by numerous
segments today's are centipede and
here's our millipede you notice
immediately there's some very key
differences between the two and being
able to identify two different Hooten
two is important so let's go over some
of the key things to look for centipedes
have one pair of legs per segment while
millipedes have two legs per segment
also centipedes tend to be carnivorous
meaning they eat in this case this was
eating sadly a mouse set get caught in
the trap millipedes are herbivores and
they eat mean the eat plants so if you
ever have the option if you want to be
put into a tank of millipedes or
centipedes despite the more legs
I'd go with millipedes because they're
gonna be looking for a plant to eat and
not wanting to take a bite out of you
like a centipede may lastly we have our
insects this is the largest group they
are the most abundant eukaryotes on
earth and insects have those three
distinctive regions that I talked about
the abdomen thorax and the head and
they're the most versus is what makes
the reason why this particular phylum is
considered to be the most successful if
you're looking at number of species
simply because of insects are the most
abundant
eukaryotes on earth