okay here we're looking at the animal
phylum nigerians
remember here for a little how to
pronounce it my own kind of rendition of
how to pronounce it
but you should be familiar with these
jellyfish so Cnidaria their tissues that
lead to greater specialization remember
our sponges we're now going a little bit
more advanced still pretty primitive and
simple but we are having tissues now
being formed now these animals here are
radial symmetry symmetrical remember our
sponges were not they have a body plan
that allows them to interact with their
environment on all sides so it's a high
environmental interactions that are
occurring and it's because of their body
type allows for that and the radial
symmetry remembers one of our key
distinguishing factors for being able to
place the complexity of animals so
there's different classes remember
phylum is the broader way of
categorizing things classes are a little
bit more specific box jellyfish sea of
enemies true jellyfish fire corals are
all under the same phylum but you can
see here there's four different classes
ever wonder how a jellyfish kind of
reproducers me kind of see them floating
around in the ocean around the beach the
life cycle of jellyfish includes two
stages we have the Medusa stage and then
we have the polyp stage here the polyp
actually reproduces asexually by budding
and the Medusa here we can see
reproduces sexually with this permanent
egg gonna kind of see that life cycle it
goes around and budding here the polyp
and we have our kind of individual
coming from there originating from there
it's a pretty simple organized a pretty
simple life cycle overall but more
complex and our sponges because we have
the development of tissues in addition
to tissues this allows for greater
specialization so a major evolutionary
advantage is something called
extracellular and digestion of food that
audition begins outside the cells are in
the gut or gastrovascular cavity this is
a big advancement this form of the
addition allows animals to digest an
animal larger than itself so this
extracellular digestion allows it to
take in portions of food part
and break them down this gastrovascular
cavity we see here locate on the inner
portion see here shown this is a
photograph of what it looks like and
then here is the illustration of
morphology so we see here's kind of
looking this camera angle will be kind
of from the top here looking down into
it we could see evidence of this
gastrovascular cavity this extracellular
digestion which is a key advancement in
our animal classification cnidocytes are
stinging cells so jellyfish might
highlight that one in particular is
that's probably one you're most familiar
with and because you're probably told
and earlier to stay away from them
animals this phylum stinging cells so
these stinging cells are what gives them
the ability to collect food now from our
standpoint more bigger than than they
are but we get that stephenson nation
it's just not pleasant in depending what
type of jellyfish it could be deadly
even to us these meta sites containing
large organelles called NASA cysts that
are stored in the coiled thread in
barbed you see that ended in here when
when hairlike projections on the cell
surface are touched
so here the thread of barbed of the
toxins are fired from the organelle so
we kind of see here the be attracted
stage you can have any of everything
kind of being condensed in and had like
a spring compressed down and when that
liver is tripped then you get the
popping there of the barbed and the
thread and that's where the toxins may
be kept that's what's causing this teeny
nature that's specific to jellyfish what
a great video to kind of look at this is
a great link here it shows this in
slow-motion so jellyfish have harpoon
like barbed this is a microscopic view
here called out the mast assist which be
our prey it retract towards the tentacle
these can discharge so explosively and
they show that in the video that's
capable of piercing the hardshell of a
crab so this is not something to be
taken lightly
there's definitely quite the punch
behind it there it actually filmed it in
slow motion on this video so that
smartereveryday video great one to check
out and it gets you to a pretty
she ate even though you may not enjoy
the experience if you ever been stung by
a jellyfish but what's going on with
that animal inside the tentacles