okay here we're looking at the animal
phylum Analia and i little wait try to
get you to pronounce the word properly
and if you recognize this picture this
is the phylum that the earthworm falls
under so what's key about this
particular phylum well it's the rise of
segmentation so this is kind of in the
early innovations of the body plan of
her sila mates segmentation is one of
those key factors this is the first kind
of Philemon shows this as an
evolutionary kind of stuff the basic
body plan of a annelid is that the tube
within a tube concept so the the
digestive tract is suspended within the
tube of the seal so we see a tube within
a tube and this actually holds true for
us our intestines and our digestive
system is a tube within our body cavity
so that's where the term tube within a
tube comes into play
now I'm not going to require for at
least my class all in knowing of all the
individual identifications here but it
could be helpful if we do do a
dissection of an earthworm kind of the
outside view here and layers
segmentation there's three key body plan
characteristics one is repeated segments
one can be specialized segments and
would be these connections so each of
these plays a role when we talk about
segmentation of a particular animal so
worm reproduction they're very important
for soil health they pull organic matter
carbon based typically into the soil
mixing the material worms have both male
and female reproductive organs and this
column is the main assumption to store
the eggs of the worm that's located
right here so that's I could tell I'm
right there this earthworms meeting
mom's kind of a rare sight to see
they're very sensitive to ground
movement and if you're walking very
heavily on the ground
although these worms are very quick
about going back down into the burrows
below ground where you won't see them we
want to learn more about how earthward
reproduce is a great youtube video link
provided here there's might be a little
bit shocker of an image probably
expecting this but if again we do that
earthworm dissection this is another
great way to do it or if you're not
fortunate enough to be able to take my
class
experience it for yourself this is
another video linked here 21 minutes of
an earthworm dissection so hopefully
find that interesting be a little bit
longer than this video here few features
here segments within a long body it's
covered with mucus to help conserve
water and we are terrestrial base these
animals need to find a way to conserve
water they have the presence of both a
mouth and anus they have stitch hair
called bristles that aydin's our
movement through the soil calmly our
method i'ts meaning each individual
carries both male and female organs firm
anatomy again remember earthworms
accelerate nutrient cycling in the soil
plant system this is the head region the
mouth region this is where they're first
taking in some of that food and passing
it through that tube within a tube
concept and I'm not gonna be requiring
to know all the individual parts just
realize the heart yes that is plural and
will many lines they have more than one
heart there and passing and helping
their circulatory system along so just
because they're more primitive doesn't
necessarily mean that they contain less
organs and we have you could see example
of hearts with it being plural there's
more than one if you've been following
on some the other videos this is kind of
is that quick summary do you know what
distinguishes these three particular
phylum apart from one another what
similarities they may have just kind of
that quick little review slide for that
quick comparison can be able to separate
these three different phylum if not
there's videos in each