okay here we're gonna take a brief
overview of the pilum eleska found kind
of a cool image here of a greater blue
ringed octopus and a snail both are
classified under this particular phylum
so start off with these mollusks are
sila mates they have a soft body and
it's comprised of three regions we have
a head foot region visceral mass
canoeing the body's organs and then a
mantle which envelops the visceral mass
and is associated with gills that
capture oxygen from water and release
carbon dioxide's it's kind of the way
that they breathe now looking at that
head foot region you know the foot
region of looking in this case of the
snail and the head region located here
visceral mass is that main area
containing all the organs and that
mantle hearing kid in blue here is that
area that's allowing that gas exchange
between oxygen and carbon dioxide so
there's three main groups of mouths
there's a castro paws which are your
snails and slugs actually may be most
familiar with bivalves with clams
oysters and scallops and cephalopods are
your octopus and your squid
these are all classified under the same
phylum a little bit more of a detailed
look here as we can see over here all
the different types this snail the
gastropods we have a little bit of
description there are clams sea ice kind
of it's partially open here bivalve
contains two shells that's where we've
got two valves bivalve comes from
cephalopods such as the octopus they can
release ink when they're trying to
escape from predators and they have ways
to propel themselves also very smart
animals here a large brain of
considering their relative body size and
very soon videos on them they can figure
quite a bit of complex problems and
puzzles out which is quite interesting
now looking at addition here our snail
for example as is rad you lot this is a
feeding structure now this is a very
unique structure
it's a rasping tongue like organ that
has rows of pointed backward
teeth look at it here it's like there's
kind of a little bit of rough region
when we look at it very specifically and
close up in our microscope we see how
aggressive this can be this backward
kind of rows of curved teeth here this
is how the animal feeds doesn't have
true teeth this backward facing allow
food to come in easier and it has it
creates a much harder time for it to
exit it would get caught here and it
allows it to be worked into the organism
for digestion the basic body plan you
can see here again there's not so much
going on here that we need to kind of
worry about no these for purposes of
this class but we may be doing
dissections of animals within this
phylum so this might be a good area to
kind of come back and refer to you just
have kind of a general idea of how this
body system compares to some others that
I talked about in other videos lastly
here are Cielo mates they have an outer
surface of the mantle that secretes a
protective shell I mean not every Cielo
mates with that for one moment several
species here have can no longer have
shells but many do so again it's a
distinguishing feature but those that do
have shells in the outer surface it's
access protection and there's multiple
layers and it's comprised of protein
calcium and pearl and so if you've ever
opened in this case a clam it's kind of
got that nice shiny pearl like look
that's because it is composed of some
pearl substance there's many species in
various forms this is an illustration
that shows you not the anatomy of an
aquatic gastropod so again this is just
one example of this very diverse phylum