here when I take a brief overview of the
animal phylum Chordata the title slide
image here we see the glass catfish
which is one of the few chordates with a
visible backbone now of course they're
improving on the skeleton they exhibit a
truly internal endoskeleton with muscles
attached to an internal rod called the
notochord is that evidence here in the
cartoon image in this red line here the
innovation opened the door for a large
body size is not possible of early
animal forms how looks kind of in real
life here we see a great image here
we're looking at the 40 notochord cells
are highlighted in a red here now this
is immunofluorescence so that's why
they're glowing red in this image can
read about it here but that's just
showing you that line is indicating
where the notochord is located in this
particular individual yeah I said large
increase in size and based on if you
watch the videos in the correct order
you can see all of these animals are
much larger
they all have internal scale he's either
made of bone or cartilage and that is
what the muscles are working against
most endoskeletons are made of column we
get a couple here for example the shark
where we have set more of that cartilage
intact but most of these contain that
internal skeleton made of bone now
there's approximately 56,000 species of
chordates they all share these four
principal features at least some point
in their life maybe not at all stages
but at some point they'll have all of
these the presence of a notochord a
nerve cord pharyngeal pouches in a post
anal tail this kind of creates a little
bit of a detailed form this has an
individual here living in an aqueous
environment looking at some a little
more detail in this case but this gives
you an appreciation for the complexity
of some of these animals next slide here
I'm gonna give it just kind of that
brief overview and we see that here so
we have the four main common features
that notochord that nerve cord
pharyngeal slits in a post a male tail
and keep in mind they may may not all
exist at the same time but in order to
fit into this phylum they have to exist
at some
point in the animals life cycle now
improving on the skeleton will not all
crates actually vertebrates
these are actually two examples of ones
that aren't vertebrates tunicates here
have a unique look to them and lancelet
here these are two examples of chordates
that aren't vertebraes with p speaking
of raised vertical rates have two
important aspects and it's a great image
here vertebrates have a backbone that
replaces the role of the notochord see
that here firm eights also have a
distinctive well-defined head region and
this is two distinguishing factors for
vertebrates that fit under the animal
phylum chordates