here we're looking at the animal phylum
plaid e Hale Minty's cloudy human t's
kind of a mouthful to say there and I do
my best to kind of give you an
indication of how to pronounce that I'll
refer to the video has kind of salad or
flat worms they don't look like this
very simple but we're getting slightly
more complex for watching these videos
in sequence so first off is solid or
flat worms they have bilateral symmetry
so this body symmetry differs this
bilateral symmetry means that only one
plane can cut through the organism in
half to produce mirror images so we see
the example here the butterfly and here
also of the fern this is bilateral
symmetry all distinct left and right
have same here a distinct left and right
have these flattened have this type of
symmetry different than some of the
organisms we talked out previously this
allows for a greater degree of
specialization to occur now radial
versus bilateral symmetry so remember
radial symmetry rail arrangement of
parts around a central axis with these
having evidence of bilateral symmetry
there that distinct right and left
halves from the mirror image with these
right and left halves we have a little
bit more detail we can go into women
talking about any animal and we want up
what dorsal versus ventral these are
terms I'm going to use we get into body
systems also so the dorsal side versus
the ventral side dorsal side see the
fish is up here and here think of the
dorsal fin of a dolphin the ventral is
the underside here and that's the
ventral side of the fish anterior and
posterior so anteriors towards the head
prostrate towards the tail in this case
so to be the anterior portion here
there's to be the prosti riyer portion
here with the tails located so just
again some key terms you should be
familiar with solids and platforms bile
and symmetry the bilateral symmetry
produces these three embryonic layers
thank you mrs. Owens is the three
different types of layers we're going to
talk about now initially they might
sound a little kind of weird but I think
it makes sense once you understand the
terms so ectoderm will develop on the
outer coverings of the body and nervous
hecto means external i exterior humanity
of it mesoderm will develop the skeleton
and muscles that's the middle layer
mesoderm acromion middle layer here i'd
refer to here to the human body in hopes
that make a little bit better connection
so that ectoderm that our body coverings
think that like our skin cells of our
epidermis here mesoderm is those
skeleton muscles in our middle part and
endoderm the internal layer developed
into digestive organs such as our
intestines so while this is still that
these three layers will still exist for
solomon flatworms even though they don't
have these complex systems hopefully
connecting them to these common body
systems that you're familiar with will
help you remember echoes on the outside
measures in the middle and endows on the
inside
in addition saladin problems are the
simplest of all bilateral symmetrical
organisms so yes there are more complex
that we've talked about so far but
overall they are the most simple they're
like any internal cavity other than a
digestive tract they're the simplest
animal in which organs are found these
are called a Sosua mates we see that
everything here this is their gut region
is their ectoderm here's their mesoderm
here and an inner would be their gut and
that's about it so what they look like
very very simple here this is a real
world image what they look like most
problems are parasitic though some are
free-living and flat ones range in size
from less than a millimeter to many
meters long see here's like a tapeworm
extremely long others are very very
teeny-tiny celery flat worms they have
actually gone through a process called
degenerative evolution parasitic
flatworms lifestyles resulted in the
eventual loss of features not used or
needed by the parasite example parasite
flat ones don't need high spots
philosophy church that lacked adaptive
purpose for a parrot ism is often called
degenerative evolution think of them
it's like gating features and then that
using them and then kind of losing them
over time it's kind of evolution kind of
going backwards simply because those
advancements are not needed it's an
example a close-up of a tapeworm
tapeworms are a classic example of this
today
illusion the body the tapeworm has been
reduced to two primary functions simply
eating and reproducing
that's it they don't need any other
specialized features there's consuming
food and every producing I have a little
bit of how they look in the inside of
the body inside the intestine system
here and in the close-up now asada
flattens have an incomplete gut this
means flattens have a digestive cavity
they have an incomplete gut with only
one opening so hopefully you're not
eating during this video here but the
gut branches throughout the body so you
see here it's involved in both digestion
of food particles and also the excretion
of waste of the same area these
parasitic flatworms lessened entirely
and absorb food directly through their
body walls there's simple system they
lack circulatory system and all the
cells must be within diffusion distance
of oxygen in food this is why their flap
that great surface area to volume ratio
we have a very basic and simple nervous
system also free living forms have I
spots if you see here that can
distinguish light from dark so it's in
accurate to call these eyes they're just
ice spots because they're just sensing
light or dark lastly here gastrovascular
cavity is not a complete digestive
system so in the flatworm that has a
gastrovascular cavity with one opening
that serve as both a mouth and an anus
the excretory system is made up of these
tubes connected and every system is
composed of interconnected nerve cords
running the length of the body remember
it's very simple though and all to get
that food from the central gut region to
any of its cells they all have to be
within diffusion distance for that to
occur