here look at the animal phylum Porifera
or sponges now the reason why I have
this tenet down here and you'll see that
in some of the videos I put below the
name is kind of how to pronounce it RIF
or raw so I'll just kind of spelled out
the way kind of best put it down they're
not correct kind of English as far as
pronunciation goes but just gives you
that idea of how to properly pronounce
the phylum here and we're talking about
sponges here Porifera this is how they
look this might be kind of the most
famous sponge you might be familiar with
here but we're gonna be talking today
about the real sponges that live under
the water and not necessarily in
pineapples so this fund is animals
without tissues that's the key
indication here for what defines a
sponge that's one is our animals they're
not plants they're the simplest of
animals their bodies are a little more
than masses of specialized cells invade
an angelic matrix and the clumps of
cells disassociate from a sponge can
give rise to new sponges so how do we
get a new sponge from original sponge
well this clumps of cells kind of break
apart and they reattach to an area and
it can regenerate another sponge there
so again Rim the phylum here we're
looking at the diverse amount of sponges
that do occur so while some are
different colors and pretty fit some are
brightly colored some others are more of
a dull color and that's just associated
with that particular sponge variety what
is a sponge well and they'll have
tissues so the body of the sponge is
perforated with many little pores here
this is kind of a zoomed in version of
that sponge is a filter feeder which
traps any food particles that pass by
this is again a zoomed in version here
so as here micro villi being able to
kind of filter out water that's being
exchanged through the sponge this is
typically why there's this long kind of
tube like shape here Yves another
example just kind of have a look there
ain't a symmetrical they're asymmetrical
heterotrophic it has no cell walls so
you're gonna no cell walls again in the
case because we are talking about
animals and they do need to consume food
they're not making their own we see
indicated here our water in and water
out so they are exchanging water from
the outside environment here's a little
short video here about filtering barrel
of tuna sponges
and since I'm just another look here
we're seeing waters coming in and went
out the top and it's coming in all these
little hairlike the futures are kind of
out there they're kind of being used to
try to absorb or pick up food particles
that pass by this specialized cell type
see this is a little bit more of a
detailed version of zooming in here
where our water's being pulled into the
sides and it's being exited out the top
and as it's being pulled in again these
micro abilities all these little hairs
this high surface area is increasing the
odds that they come in contact with a
food particle that might be in the water
here that's brought in I'm not going to
go over all the names in the details
much another basics here we have our
specialized cell types even though the
tissues are present they're still taking
in water that contains food particles
are filtering that food out and ideally
the filter and water here is exiting out
the towel hopefully this gives you just
a little bit of an insight of how the
simplest of all the animals lives here
the basic sponge