so how do physical body barriers relate
to the immune system and more
specifically how do the three images I
included here relate to that well the
reason why I've put these images here is
to see if you can make connections
between typically non-traditional immune
system pictures to see how they do
relate physical body barriers well the
sense here is representing that physical
barrier so does our skin the shoe
stepping in gum here that sticky
substance is going to represent the
mucus which is important for trapping
potential invading microorganisms and
the bottle here of the unknown kind of
acid poison is going to represent our
stomach acid on way we chemically
combative aiders so more specifically
I'm securing our borders at first line
of defense that skin those mucous
membranes
you may remember keratin in the skin
component of our hair prevents or acts
as a very strong physical barrier to
most microorganisms it's also resistant
to weak acids and bases bacterial
enzymes in toxins so this keratin is a
very strong substance and acts as a
great physical barrier in addition we
have her mucus what you've ever been a
little sick and sneeze you may notice
this kind of sticky gelatinous kind of
material that's called mucus and it
provides similar protection to
mechanical barriers coach the hairs it
traps inhaled particles it's also part
of the upper respiratory tract that's
ciliated so they sweep dust particles
from the lower respiratory passages this
kind of sticky substance acts as a way
of trapping some of these invading
organisms that we may take in and
breathe in this sticky substance just as
we feel it sticky is what's trapping
those organisms that can then be swept
up through and ultimately digested in
the stomach
now the stomach itself has its own line
of defense and that produces chemicals
particularly we have acid so our skin is
slightly acidic at three to five pH and
that is able to inhibit bacterial growth
keep in mind that our digestive tract
such as our stomach can be
hydric low
acid-producing very low pH some times
right around the pH of 2 sebum earwax
and these chemicals also toxic to
bacterial saliva tears also contains
I'll let lysozymes
mucus traps micro raisins enter the
digestive and respiratory systems so you
could see many of these our body has a
lot of these physical ways to combat
potential invaders