so physiological disorders and tomatoes
what causes them the main cause is both
extremes extreme cold or extreme heat so
when we're looking at extreme cold
looking at frost damage this would be
blackened splotches and the leaves most
evident in the upper leaves how to
prevent will protect your plants in some
way with some sort of cover or really
had a controller just add heat or be
mindful if you're putting them on early
planting out don't put all your Tomatoes
out so you don't lose the entire crop
leaf burns the other one it's a Browning
those leaves you see here often confused
with disease be careful when you make
applications this could be evidence of
spray damage with a high Sun I want to
shade your young seedlings when they
first go out into this field and how to
control it well nothing can be done once
the leaves burn that's a very quick
rundown of the extremes that caused
physiological disorders in tomato plants