on this debaco university video i'm
going to break down a scientific article
that looks at plant structure effects on
chemical uniformity in cannabis plants
[Music]
all right let's take a look and see how
plant structure affects chemical
uniformity in cannabis
so first off this is the research
article um here if you want to look at
it in more detail i'd recommend you do
because they do get into some great
specifics of their pruning methods you
might want to read this article
once you find the pruning method you
think you want to investigate further
you might want to go back here to this
original source
so first off plant morphology and bud
location so plants shoot growth pattern
and shape is commonly manipulated by
growers worldwide by numerous techniques
including planting densities trestling
plant hormones and by the physical
removal of plant organs and that's
according to the researchers there in
addition to the physical location of the
inflorescence on the plants in relation
to the light source it was also
investigated in this study it was we'll
see both these factors contribute to the
quality of the total harvest so we want
to keep in mind that not only the
structure of the plant but in relation
to those buds into the intensity of the
light can also impact their overall
quality
so here's the description of some of
their pruning methods and they go
through them and they're kind of they're
pretty they're quite extensive uh here
which is great they have a control which
is great and a defoliation this bb
lr is bottom branches and leaves removed
commonly referred to as lollipopping so
where you see what they said vblr you
can think of that as lollipopping then
they went through and they have primary
branch removal secondary branch removal
single prune and double prune i kind of
highlight the double prune here and
that's pruning the plants twice at the
duration of the single prune and a
second time at the transition to the
short day or flowering treatments this
just a reminder uh in this trial
they stated that this experiment was
conducted in a randomized
random experimental design with six
replicates replicated groups for each
treatment was arranged in three rows out
of which a plant from the center row was
then sampled here so this gives you an
idea of their general structure based on
the different plant architecture
manipulation treatments that they
mentioned here
so let's kind of look at the data now so
we kind of learned all the backgrounds
there well now let's get into the actual
data component of the architecture
related to the cannabinoid yield the
results revealed that pruning the plants
twice during cultivation was the optimum
practice for increasing yield and other
treatments decreased or did not affect
yield quality so i know there's a lot of
numbers here but we're looking at the
different architecture manipulation
treatments on the left
the cbga in grams per plant c b
d a c b d v a t h c a t h e v a t and c
b c a all in grams per plant i know
there's a lot of numbers here but what
we're noticing is i highlighted it here
with a little kind of green outline box
here
is that the double prune method for all
of the treatments here had the highest
rate of return in grams per plant of the
various cannabinoids provided here and
there is some variability we are talking
about plants we are talking about kind
of a living organism here
some had very close similarities to a
a being the highest number and then
subsequent letters indicating
significant differences from a
statistical ten standpoint using a two
keys hd test
being different from from the comparison
there so again the kind of take home
message here we can definitely see
the double prune method improved all of
these particular cannabinoids there so
that's where you can go back to the
original article look some more of the
description of the details of that
particular pruning method
now they also mentioned or looked at
influence
sampling locations so influences or
blood sampling locations one through
five kind of shown here on the plant and
this is an image of a control plant
which basically didn't have pruning just
to give you an idea of where that
sampling may have occurred
trimmed influences was dried at 24
degrees celsius and 55 air humidity for
14 days in an environmentally controlled
chamber in the dark so it gives you an
idea of their kind of drying and curing
process
now light penetration
so therefore the architecture of
manipulated plants can be utilized to
increase yield biomass and
standardization but the cannabinoid
yield should be addressed by other means
a considerable reduction of light
inception down the chute was observed
and the extent of spatial
standardization of the cannabinoid
profile correlated with the effect of
plant architecture and light penetration
to the lower parts of the canopy so what
does that mean let's give a summary of
that basically
as we see here just an under plant shot
not from the study but just a random
plant with lights above it the
penetration of that light diminishes
quite quite substantially so as you get
deeper into that canopy the light
penetration becomes less and less and
less and this suggests that low light
availability at the bottom of the plant
or in deeply shaded regions of the plant
is a powerful inducer for reduction of
those chemical standardizations
meaning those buds that are in the shade
that are further away from the lights
are simply going to yield less
cannabinoids so having good plant
structure but also exposing those buds
in some way to the greatest amount of
intensity of light coming down in this
case
was advantageous to increase those uh
cannabinoid profiles there and
standardizations
so the light and buds so how does this
kind of right relate to
many growers in support of the screen of
green method highlight the idea that
maximizing light exposure will improve
bud quality which this study kind of
confirms there and this is support of
this screen of green method where all
those buds are kind of grown on the same
uh platform there the same plane all
pointing up all getting the maximum
amount of light however though
keep in mind that the added labor in
time to properly perform this screen of
green method so when an operation is
looking to maximize plant growth and
efficiency the screen of green may not
be the most advantageous of pruning
methods but for those that may be with
plant restriction numbers can only grow
so many plants and really it's not the
grower doesn't have the main focus on
efficiency and quick turnover times this
is why the screen of green method is
probably so popular with many growers
because it is a way to kind of produce
more of those top quality a buds from a
single plant
so lastly optimizing that plant
structure so the double prune method um
as stated in this article
is that allows for maximum light
exposure to as many buds as possible
it's proven to be advantageous and this
gives the idea that slightly smaller but
well structured plants
can be top quality producers so you
don't necessarily need some giant plant
to have high quality high yielding
production smaller more manicured better
trimmed better pruned better allocation
of light to buds ratios can be
advantageous now we don't want to
necessarily go too small make it you
know a little bonsai plant
but look at this study i think it
presents some good information that some
growers may have known but kind of gives
you some scientific background and may
maybe you find a new pruning method that
can help increase your yields uh without
really having to change that much since
i do still understand your strain or
cultivar does this pruning method or
that architecture change
you could see an improvement in your
yields best of luck