this video lectures will get plants
adaptations to terrestrial living
how did plants make the change from
living in a mainly aquatic environment
such as the ocean here to living on land
which has a lot of challenges associated
with it well adapt ins is distressed
real living in general plants are
complex multicellular organisms that are
autotrophs proposed synthetic overall
now their primary terrestrial down that
organisms on the surface of Earth in
nearly three hundred thousand species of
plants are none today and this just
gives you an example of some of the
diversity within odd plants so adapting
to this terrestrial event green algae
that were probably the ancestors of
today's plans are aquatic organisms that
are not well adapted to living on land
before their descendants live on land
that they had to overcome many
environmental challenges so just making
this jump even to the rocks here you see
green algae pictured right here
questions are how did they and these
plants learn to absorb minerals how do
they conserve water being on land and
how they reproduce on land these are
some of the major challenges plans out
the face so again comparing that algae
to that plant the whole algae performs
photosynthesis surrounding water
supports it and it can hold fast in this
case in the water well terrestrial based
plants have beliefs buccal stamatis
stems and roots help support them and
we're going to go over these in detail
so to start adapting to the rest
environment plant macro nutrients those
are the big nutrients that plants are
mostly composed of they constitute only
one percent or more of plants biomass
which is their dry weight these are
things might be familiar was seeing on
fertilizer such as nitrogen potassium
calcium phosphorus magnesium and sulfur
and these may not be an exact elemental
form but they're what plants needs so
that you don't get this yellowing region
here this is the potassium deficiency
I'm going to make sure your soils
fertile and has the proper amount of
nutrients to support the plant growth
now peach influences nutrient
availability so we see here a pH of
seven which is neutral most of the
nutrients overall in land are most
widely available as we decrease or
become more acidic receive
two nitrogen potassium phosphorus
sulphur calcium all start to really get
less plant-available same thing if the
soil becomes too alkaline it can also
reduce the availability of certain
nutrients you see iron here being the
exception at a lower pH it's more plant
available so what is pH just reminders
and measure of the hydrogen ions and see
here pH of 0 being extremely acidic pH
of 7 being neutral and pH 14 being very
basic we see where some common solutions
you might be familiar with great so
coffee slightly acidic blood is just
ever so slightly basic milk of magnesia
ammonia bleach a lot more on the base a
lot of your household cleaners are basic
in this again here also gives you just
that Journal scale of what it is in pH
remember mathematically is equal to the
minus the log base 10 of the hydrogen
ion concentration so way to think about
this is a very acidic environment has a
lot of hydrogen ions as we work our way
to becoming more basic we notice the
hydrogen ion amount decreases and the
hydroxide ion increases this is it's a
proportion because it forms this nice
rectangle at page 7 or neutral the
hydrogen ion concentration would equal
the hydroxide ion concentration and a
pure water which is what neutral would
be is h2o so you see one hydrogen ion
and one hydroxide becomes h2o h o H is
reduced to h2o and just these little
brackets meet concentration so different
crops are different target ranges and
what to think there's one golden pH to
reach grasses are 6.2 to 7 blueberries
are much more acidic four point five to
five Tomatoes like you grow in your
garden 6.0 to 7 so there's different pH
ranges for different crops what all
crops have here is roots and these roots
are responsible for absorbing minerals
along with water the first plants
involved the symbiotic association with
fungi called mycorrhizae this is a
beneficial fungi that helps absorb
nutrients so the plant is able to morph
absorb nutrients while the plant gives
the mycorrhizae the fungi sugars that it
makes from the leaves this is what it's
a symbiotic relationship both species
are benefiting so adapting terrestrial
living one key living on land is of wing
preventing key being dry drying out put
inside of watertight waxy that are
coming kind of cuticle this is what it
looks like here it allows water to beat
up highly waxy lipid based water enters
the plants only through the roots
Nikhil's will prevents water loss to the
air so water's coming in the roots
through the stems here and end up to the
leaves going through this is an example
the leaf what we're gonna learn more
about in another video but this cuticle
is is protective layer limiting the
amount of exposure water can evaporate
out one area that water can leave is
called the stomata specialized pores
that allow passage of water through the
cuticle remember these are pores si
holes in the leaves because the plant
can regulate them as we see here they're
found in leaves and sometimes between
portions of the stem they allow for the
passage of carbon dioxide into the plant
or in the photosynthetic process and
water vapor and oxygen can pass out of
them and again the plant can regulate
whether that's open or closed when it's
open water can leave but allows
necessary components that carbon dioxide
into the leaf however there's only so
much the plant and keep these open
before it dries out and could die so
Monza give and take process you know
letting water out and co2 in however the
plant can only let so much water out
before Wilson may die and we see here's
the example of the stomata in a
cross-section microscopic view of the
leaf you see that very thick cuticle
here on top and also in the bottom only
allowing water loss through the stomata
one of the other challenges that plants
face go into the terrestrial environment
is reproduction as plants could not move
it was necessary for plans to pass
gametes from one individual to another
early plants needed a film of water for
sperm to swim to the egg and fertilize
it later pollen was developed along the
transferor Gammage without drying out so
very early plants as we see in losses
very low to the ground in that civil
water now plants have developed ways to
use potentially
err they can use also use pollinators to
help that so these are some of the ways
plants developed and dealt with some of
the challenges going from the aquatic
environment or the algae or common
ancestor may originated to the dry
environment of land