okay here we look at plant stems in a
little bit more detail I thought this
was kind of an interesting image to show
here some of the tree trunks from
different angle
showing the stems and where I'll learn a
little bit more about them more than
just trees but how there's different
types of stems to depend on different
types of classifications of plants so
starting with the stems in general they
often experience both primary and
secondary growth remember primary is
growing upwards and downwards secondary
growth is the growth in the diameter of
a plant stems are the source of the
economically important product called
wood and the primary growth of a chute
leaves first appearance primordia so I'm
not going to quiz you on all the
individual little tiny terms here I
figure it's worth putting on a good
picture kind of to describe some of
those and the leaf primordium here gee
that's kind of off to the side here and
that's where the leaves are initiating
this is our highest rate of cell
division here at E and that's the apical
meristems you should be familiar with B
is the ground meristem here and C is the
leaf gap of it in here so it is familiar
to familiarize yourself with this
microscopic look at a stem a little bit
more of a macroscopic view that you
might be a little bit more familiar with
this stem anatomy nodes this is the area
where our leaves are originating
internodes is it simply the distance
between two nodes the blade or the leaf
and the petiole which is the supporting
structure that supports the leaf or the
blade so just be familiar with the stem
anatomy to be able to recognize that we
will be doing some activities where you
have to identify certain stems and
leaves in this video might prove helpful
in the future so hypo and epi coddles
all the epicotyl in the hypo caudal all
are in relation to the cotyledon leaves
so you can see this is clearly a dicot
because there's two seed leaves and the
stem region below those two seed leaves
is called the hypo caudal hypo meaning
below or under so hypo Connell is
underneath those two cotyledons and the
epicotyl is above those two cotyledons
or seat leaves in this case so if I ask
you
the epicotyl or something with the hypo
cattle these would be the region's you'd
be looking in addition to tissue
patterns and stems we have monocotyledon
stems so these are monocots as remember
from our grass blades or our coordinate
the cross-section contains a more
scattered approach that in dicots we
found some excellent on lines and
excellent microscopic images showing an
appreciation for what these stems
actually look like in these different
types of plants so we're talking
monocots we're talking stems they
produce no secondary vascular tissues or
cork when I say more scattered our
vascular planners are more scattered
even though you may initially say that
yes there's a little bit more towards
the perimeter which is true but they are
definitely more scattered when you
compare to the dicots
so this is what the stem would look like
in a monocot looking at herbaceous
dicotyledons stem remember her basis are
not going to produce any form of wood
structure so herbaceous dicotyledons
stems they have discrete vascular
bundles and they're located mainly on
the perimeter
so you'll notice the pith in the middle
here and all the vascular bundles are
located on the perimeter to go back from
one moment at the monocots here notice
that yes there's a more concentration
towards the perimeter but they are
scattered and the interior as well
within the pith as you see here with the
herbaceous die-cuts they are only in the
perimeter of the cell understand in
these cases the cortex the epidermis
from it's the outer portion and our
vascular bundle now if we zoom in our
vascular bundle we notice here that we
have on the top we have our phloem and
then as we work our way down we have our
xylem there in the middles our vascular
cambium here producing phloem to the
outside in xylem to the inside again
it's a pretty good images that I found
online links are in the description what
do you do I call this stem so these are
dicots that are producing wood heartwood
and sapwood are two examples so let's
get into these a little bit more detail
well produces secondary xylem which is
wood older trees have a visually
distinctive sections here
we see the heartwood is the darker wood
in the center and that's located in this
region right here the SAP wood is
located towards the outside it contains
still function in xylem you see here
this lighter portion is the SAP wood the
annual ring marks are lines that are
between dark late wood and lighter early
word and that's what's causing the
annual rings we can use these rings to
determine a little bit of history of
what this particular tree had gone
through you see I took a little arrow
here and it's kind of pointed one of the
annual rings they're looking at a
microscopic view we have the primary
xylem here on the inside the pith in the
direct center the wood region here which
is made up of the secondary xylem then
we have the vascular cambium again where
our phloem and xylem are being produced
this would be considered in general the
bark region and our phloem would be here
on only the outside I gave the example
of people who go around and particularly
in areas they get a lot of snow and
don't want to cut down trees to dry them
they want to leave them standing timber
they will go around they'll cut into the
entire circumference of the tree still
leaving the tree vertical but what they
do is when they cut into that with a saw
they're breaking all the flow they're
eliminating all of the sugar transport
by eliminating the sugar transport that
tree will eventually die over time it
will dry out and in the winter while
there's snow on the ground they can go
through and cut down those trees because
they're dry if you have a wood stove or
no one that does you don't want to
freshly cut a tree down and burn it will
produce a lot of smoke a lot of SAP
doesn't burn very efficiently having dry
wood is definitely much more
advantageous and by cutting just the
phloem and leaving the tree standing
it's easy to find the trees in a thick
snow pack it also dries the wood out so
it burns efficiently
now comparison between dicots and
monocots tabs I try to do this quick
division here these would be the die
cuts here on the left there's to be the
monocots here on the right you can see
that much more scattered approach in
monocots die cuts definitely keeping
those vascular bundles towards the
perimeter only having a large central
pith region zoomed out a little bit so
now just looking at one portion here we
see our monocots and dicots again
remember those vascular bundles in both
case
is contains Island to the inside you
phloem to the outside Wow but we see the
dicots organized all along perimeter and
monocots scattered throughout to give
you that in a kind of a cartoon kind of
representative image of our dicots and
monocots stems this is how they would
look I could see him very much the same
like the quality microscopic images that
I chose to present earlier