okay here I'm will be showing you two
ways you can protect your plants one
then is in the insect netting and one of
them is going to be reflective mulch and
here so in Sec netting I think it's
going to be a wave of the future because
it's the only item that will work a
hundred percent assuming that's
installed properly this physical barrier
between the insects and the plants
eliminate the need for any applications
on the leaves and this also works 24
hours a day whether it's a very rainy
spring or whether it's a very dry spray
enough to keep applying anything works
great in raised bed situations as we see
here and also in long field applications
now in second etting there's different
mesh sizes to control certain insects so
the finer mesh sizes are advised if
we're trying to control really small
things like aphids would be an example
in larger typically less expensive
larger mesh sizes can you use for larger
insects it depends on what insect you're
specifically trying to control will
determine what insect in and you
purchase now it's more than just a crop
cover it's also highly recommended to
install in your season extenders so for
example your high tunnels doorways in L
venting sides fans anything that you
have in greenhouses this should be all
covered with insect netting maintaining
that physical separation if you're gonna
put it on a door don't have to make it
in a hinge door because they can get
stuck open or be left open have some way
that you can have to lift maybe a
portion of the net to get in and so it
self closes this physical barrier is not
a new idea so while it's being newly
applied for insects bird netting on
grapes is very common to keep birds out
from picking away at all the wonderful
grapes before they're harvested the
other thing I want to mention for
protecting your plants would be
reflective Malta's this would be silver
plastic reflects sunlight is that the
same as grey plastic so I had to farming
it into that issue where I want the
silver the shiny the chrome when you
apply it be sure you wear sunglasses
even on cloudy days because it does
reflect the Sun and it is quite bright
the goal is to confuse so how do these
work those goals to confuse insects so
they cannot tell where the protective
underside of the leaf is so
great first trips which are common pests
on onions we see here even though this
is not 100% all reflected there's that
black strip running down the center it's
still advantageous so even though we've
thought the multis may not be 100%
effective if you're going to apply a
plastic kind of barrier here for a weed
suppression it's worth a consideration
because it can aid in reducing
especially when plants are small at
reducing the chance of 3rd pressure on
onions