in this debaco university video i'll go
over planning the arrival date of
cannabis clones
once you get them shipped in to allow
you to maximize your harvest
all right let's go over planning the
arrival date for your cannabis clones
well first off when planning for the
arrival date you really actually want to
start with
the harvest date and when it comes to
selecting that
ideal arrival date or week you first
want to consider when is your harvest
date going to be
if you're looking at an outdoor
operation you know when are the leaves
going to start
turning when is the photo period going
to start changing this is what you
should take into consideration
for when you want the plants to come in
you also want to be mindful of your
typical for outdoor locations
your typical starting and end day of the
growing season
when's your last frost and when's your
first frost date that you're in
for your area now if you're in an indoor
operation
you have much more flexibility and it
really depends on
if all of the equipment is operational
you know because you have control over
the environment
control over the photo period the
lighting the temperature hopefully the
air circulation
you have a lot more opportunities for
flexibility outdoor locations
definitely more limited and a little bit
more precise
with the date they want their clones to
come in
now for outdoor locations you want to
know your growing season and there's
plenty of these charts for different
areas
i want to know what your plant hearty
note hardiness zone map is what region
you're in
this can really help you best pinpoint
the ideal
location for of your location ideal
timing
for your given location i'm going to
give you an example here for the
southern new england
area uh later in this presentation
so you want to also consider the photo
period so the photo period can be
determined the flowering time
except for if you're planting
autoflowers so be sure to be
the plant timing will allow for plants
to be large enough
to support flowering you don't want to
have it be too late or too early
here we see some photo period changes in
the duration of time
we're looking at the temperature lag
behind photo periods again all factors
to take into consideration
we can see the description of that
located um right here
uh for the given area in japan but again
this is true for any area
so be mindful of what it is for your
area so you can maximize your production
now my as i said later i was going to
give you that earlier i should say i was
going to give you that southern new
england example
and gel recommendation is to have clones
arrive in early june that first or
second week of june
and if growers want to have a second
planting that should arrive in
late june or potentially very early in
july
now when we're considering this for the
southern new england
area it kind of matches the native
strawberry timing
so again just something else there to
use some native plants in your
area to kind of gauge what timing you
should have some people may use
different trees different bushes for
flowering times
to give you an idea of when the season
is just right
so take this all the consideration but
hopefully you can get that timing down
to maximize your growing season and
ultimately
maximize your harvest