okay I'm going to cover some basic plant
tissue types you see here we've already
talked about loss and flow ohms and
vascular bundles so the epidermis may
sound familiar but we're gonna score
some specific ones for plants so there's
three main types most plants have these
three main types what we call ground
tissue in which the vascular tissue is
embedded dermal tissue shortens the
outer protective covering of the plan
and vascular tissue which conducts water
and dissolved minerals of the plan
conducts products of the photosynthetic
process through the clamp so we can see
them here our xylem and phloem right
it's part of our vascular tissue the
dermal tissue doesn't like the epidermis
and the ground tissue is this middle
portion here and this is a cross section
of a plant's stem so three kinds of
plant ground tissues so we break that
down a little bit further this is a
great little summary here we've already
talked about phloem and xylem now we
look at some of these other types here
so parenchyma cells they're live at
maturity and they carry out the basic
functions of living of living including
the process of photosynthesis cellular
respiration and food and water storage
they have a very thin cell wall and
these are the parenchyma cells we
located down here and we see their
unspecialized cells that carry up most
of the plants metabolisms here moving on
we also have colon comma cells it's
mutated here they're also living at
maturity and they provide much support
the plants organs which secondary growth
has not occurred uneven thickening of
the cell wall see some are thicker some
are thinner regions it's the wall
thickened with pectin and cellulose so
but it's uneven in our clinic of the
cells they also function and support
even though they are living the last one
of your cells way here are sclerenchyma
cells they usually do not contain living
cytoplasm immature may have tough cell
walls and secondary cell walls we see
the image here even thickening of the
cell wall and the walls the
with lignin so snoring chimera mainly
consisted of dead cells that have
primary secondary cell walls which
provides support so we could see our sky
rain come are very thick : come on very
uneven and think about containing kind
of those chloroplasts they're moving on
within our dermal tissue
it's a flattened at the dermal cells are
the most abundant cells in the plant's
outer layer or epidermis the epidermis
is often covering a waxy later called
the cuticle and that's a barrier against
water law so here's our cuticle is our
upper epidermis remember we don't want
our plants to dehydrate and burn so they
have this protective layer cuticle you
kind of think of like your nails cuticle
on your nails ah provides protection
same thing for here but in plants they
don't want to lose water ran way through
their leaves they want to control their
water loss through there's just no Matta
here
lastly the vascular tissue is
responsible for conducting water and
dissolved minerals of the plan conducts
products of the photosynthetic process
throughout the plant since they run
about way of saying xylem and phloem are
two examples members eylem is taking
water absorbed in the roots sending it
to the shoots the phloem can move from
the shoots to the roots the roots to the
shoots wherever it's basically needed
it's transporting sugars typically our
leaves are main sources and this flower
could be producing petals or a fruit and
that might need sugar so nutrients from
this leaf could be coming up to here
these roots could also be actively
growing and some sugars could be sent
down that way too so hopefully that's a
quick overview of some plant types take
a minute might want to in particular go
over review this slide to be able to
compare these different types of ground
tissues