now looking at plant leaves here
something we all might take for granted
we kind of assume oh yeah plants have
leaves
hopefully this lecture will try to give
you a little bit more of an appreciation
for some of the complexities and
differences within leaf structures or
different plants so starting with the
basic leaves are like living solar
panels and the goal is to collect the
sun's energy so our solar panels are all
through the field here so the leaves
their goal is to kind of collect and
absorb as much of that Sun energy as
possible so that the plant can
efficiently carry out the conversion of
this light energy to sugars so starting
in general leaves are usually the most
predominant shoot Oregon and are
structurally diverse and we see just a
couple examples here growth occurs by
means of marginal meristems and the
marginal meristems grow outward and
ultimately form the blade portion which
is the flattened portion of the leaf and
once the leaf is fully expanded the
marginal meristems ceased to grow so
once they reach maturity those leaves
will no longer grow only in the early
stages will leaves grow and as leaves
are growing as an important note while
we think it leaves always producing
energy when a leaf is very small and its
foot first expanding it may actually be
a sink it may actually consume more
energy than it provides at maturity
though leaves will definitely produce
more than they ever took initially
though sometimes they get going that
small leaf might be more of a sink than
a source until it gets fully mature and
it reaches maximum efficiency so looking
at cross-sectionally so what is a leaf
I try to provide some nice examples here
and try to relate kind of a cartoon
image to what a real microscopic image
may look like so remember our cuticle
located at the top here we go this arrow
will indicate right here at the top is
where the cuticle is the palisade
parenchyma variety this region right
here this is the upper portion a leaf
and this is important for absorption of
a lot of sunlight spongy parenchyma here
it's spongy because it needs to allow
for gas exchange and for water exchange
and then if you look here our stomata
right allowing for the influx of co2 and
the release of oxygen protected by our
guard cells
well that's located right in this region
here is where the stomata would be
in our Meza filters this entire area
between the upper and lower epidermis
this red region right here this would be
the mesophyll section this is a very
high-quality image and hopefully this
kind of cartoon and well-defined image
here can help you interrelate so when
you look at the real image you're able
to recognize these certain regions on
the leaf cross-section so looking more
on a macroscopic something might be a
little bit more familiar with or the
leaf parts the notice where attaches to
the steps the noted be down down this
region the petiole here is the leaf
stalk the blade is contains a network of
veins in vascular bundles and the margin
is the very edge here of the leaf in the
midrib in this case is very strong in
this and the tip would be the very end
the reason why to pick we point out the
margin is that is important potentially
for identification purposes and we may
do a lab where you're kind of
investigating different leaf structures
and the margin is one thing you can use
for identification
so dicots and monocots do differ so i
have some examples here a is a monocot
and this has leaves with parallel
venation mean all the veins are run
parallel to one another in contrast with
pinnate venation
and this is where at least as a main
midrib distinguish it as a dicot so
here's a strong midrib here and then we
have the network that branches off from
there same thing here is this a
real-world example we have that strongly
driven we have a branching from there
gingko biloba as I put this book called
palmate finish and kind of spreads
things like the palm of your hand kind
of spreading out and that's included by
these leaves here remember a ginkgo is a
gymnosperm in the same classification of
conifers as pine trees this is just one
example of public elimination
this is pinnate venation in essence
parallel leaves can also be expressed in
different types of simple or compound
and these are variety of forms that
exists simple leaves are single
undivided blade so you here that's
banana tree nice simple leaves then we
get into compound leaves they have a
blade divided into leaflets so
we could see here palmately compound
then compound leaves that leach is
divided and they're divided in a palmate
form then we've pinnately we have that
strung midrib here and then we have
double compound leaves example here all
right yes this is kind of like a leaflet
within a leaflet here so these also can
be helpful in use for identification of
certain leaves for certain species of
plants to kind of give you just kind of
a quick general cartoon image cool
pinnately compound describe leaflets
that are arranged in pairs along a
central axis then palmately compound
describe leaflets that reading out from
a common point at the blade end see some
examples here pinnately the native
paintings lobed hidden compound the
compound has those distinctive little
regions lobe we see these definitely
lobe regions and same to you for the
palmately how many don't load we see
some looms developing and prominently
compound so there's almost individual
what looks like individual leaves now
how they're organized on the stem is
another key factor and something that
you may not notice a lot but when you
start looking at it it can be
interesting so the goal is to maximize
sunlight exposure this is why leaves are
arranged in different patterns alternate
is when leaf spiral around a shoe we see
here alternate we see one going here
down when going up when going down up
they're alternating their pattern kind
of like left right left right left right
is ultimate opposite occurs in the
opposite sides of the shoe so here's our
shoe and we have them going in opposite
directions one the left one to the right
originating head at that same central
node see that again represented here we
have world which is kind of interesting
these are leaves that circled on the
stem is a group there a world appearance
you see the world world in the world
here so there are three different types
of leaf arrangements and patterns that
they have continuing on with that
parallel palmately infinitely good three
examples here I'm going to parallel that
palmately kind of like the palm of your
hand
infinitely has that strong midrib and
these veins that we're seeing different
arrangements of are composed of both
xylem and phloem
now looking at shade leaves may
initially appear similar between these
two but are specialized for their own
particular micro environment they tend
to be larger then our Lessman mesophyll
layers and fewer chloroplast for the
shade leaves you can see here the leaves
in direct Sun and that much darker
region are able to absorb a lot more Sun
so that pack in this top region our
shade leaves are a little thinner they
don't contain quite as many chloroplasts
they're simply not able or exposed to as
much sunlight if they don't build up the
reserves like these ones in the Sun
these ones in the Sun higher
photosynthesis rate better exchange with
water in carbon dioxide and oxygen
that's why we see a little bit more
complexity a little thicker here in the
ones exposed to Sun our arid regions go
back from one moment here where it says
it tends to be larger that's not thicker
that's larger in area that's kind of
like wider when we say Roger and we can
see that and leaves it might be shaded
if you have a tree or a like a tomato
plant to the shaded leaves didn't be a
little bit larger or lighter in that
case arid region leaves have many
modifications to handle these
environmental stresses may have
succulent water retaining leaves like
this aloe thick leathery leaves if you
ever touched an aloe plant fewer and or
protected stomata we see here's our
stomata a self stomata but they're
recessed into the leaf a little bit more
but not located right at the surface of
the underside here they're recessed a
little more protecting them eliminating
water from leaving as easily creating a
little bit more of environment that can
handle the some of the more arid regions
aquatic environment leaves this is kind
of an interesting though the stomata we
present in higher numbers and the leaves
upper surface so these lily pads because
they're floating in water if they had
this Timon on the underside it would be
able to breathe they had a higher
percentage of stomata on the upper side
of the leaves as we see here which is
not characteristic of most of the other
plants that we've seen for gas exchange
wanted to be protected well in this case
if the underside is immersed in water so
therefore we dab it on the upper side so
they can more efficiently exchange gases
now they're specialized lease here are
called tendrils
she looked closely at our pea plants
they have these little tendrils that
will grab onto the cages that we have
grapes are another example in squash
plants this helps support on the stems
as they grow these technically well they
look like little curlicues they're
technically modified leaves other leaves
are insect trapping losses are very
specialized our pitcher plant they look
like little pitchers
flies will fall in here I mean it
trapped and then slowly get digested
these tend make plants in all three of
these cases where nitrogen is very low
because they're basically breaking down
the flies AHS in nitrogen source sunny
does he look like these little kind of
little water droplets well these are
extremely sticky and if a fly or bug was
to land on these he'd be stuck here and
then the plant can consume them and the
obvious one the Venus flytrap when the
flow slice lies in it tingles these
little fibers and then these close up
and they will eventually consume the fly
again to get some of the proteins in
nitrogen from those flies just some
general waste to help organize or
identify certain plants you don't have
to be responsible for all these
different types but when we do
identification of certain leaves these
slides might be helpful so you're
welcome to pause them and try to compare
what leaf sample you may have and how it
relates when we talked about a couple of
these appalled mainly the one example
here you can see there's many different
shapes and arrangements two leaves also
we talked about that margin being very
important on there are different types
of margins that we can look at and these
are different classifications that we
have to help identify certain leaves and
last we have a nation it talked about
some of the similar one needs to
parallel the palmately independently
both there's even more than that so
again very important for identification
purposes and kept on these nice large
slides to help you be able to cross
compare if you're trying to Ananias
sample leaf putting it all together
these are the all the different types
here and again I highlight each on its
own individual slide