now looking at plant temperature certain
plants are going to have different
preferences for different temperatures
for the most part most plants like
consistent conditions within a range
typically plants can be there too cold
will slow down their metabolic rate and
plants have that ideal temperature but
even it can get too hot for plants that
even live in tropical environments so
hover is better to a point and I stress
this because photosynthesis is most
efficient at about 85 degrees Fahrenheit
this is about 30 degrees Celsius under
normal carbon dioxide levels so this
should be the maximum temperature
obtained under normal growing conditions
so here we have net photosynthesis here
we have temperature we could see it
increases to a point but then as a
temperature increases the actual net
photosynthesis will decrease so it's
important to try to stay as close to
this range as possible to maximize the
plaintiff ition see the reason i say at
normal co2 levels myself up here is that
when you when the growth space is
enriched with co2 the theoretical
maximum temperature increases by as much
as 10 degrees Fahrenheit to almost 95
degrees Fahrenheit or from 28 degrees
Celsius to about that 35 or so degrees
Celsius this is because of plants able
to kind of take in that carbon more
effectively able to not open their
stomata as much there's a variety of
factors but under increased co2 levels
the plants typically can handle and
prefer warmer temperatures and you'll
see a net rise in photosynthetic rate
but even then after a certain point
there will be a reduction in the net
photosynthesis
even in enriched carbon dioxide
environments so the minimum temperature
target always keep your plants above
degrees Fahrenheit to help avoid
stunting below 55 degrees plant matasso
mows down dramatically if plants
experience 32 degrees Fahrenheit or
lower they will freeze and burn causing
them to die even if we have 235 that's
really gonna potentially do some damage
and definitely 32 and below will
basically kill other plants there so
you've met all plants how they're kind
of optimum range that they want it to be
at so in for canvas were typically
looking at that little maintaining right
around that seventy five ish degrees
Fahrenheit temperature consistency is
another great thing the goals
maintain the temperature and a grow
space within the close range
fluctuations can lead to stress and
reduced growth so it's because the
midday temperatures just fine
want to make sure it's fairly consistent
through the entire day at the metronome
here that consistency data back and
forth kind of regulating that nighttime
temp to that date I'm template we can
see the extreme conditions here where
it's nice warm in the greenhouse and
there is snow outside so it's important
to maintain those consistent conditions
to keep growth as efficient as possible
those day/night through the entire
growth season