okay you were just gonna look at a brief
overview of plant tissue testing and how
it kind of relates to cannabis so when
we're looking at you know deltal paying
an idea of the nutrients we can test the
soil or the soilless media you can also
test the actual plant material that's
what this is about the actual tissue on
the plant so when you are tissue testing
there's important points of know one is
where you sample is important maybe
having at the top sampling at the side
branch is having a lower branch that can
play a role in the nutrients in that
particular plant also the stage of that
plant in its development plays a role in
the nutrients so if a sampling from a
younger plant versus an older plant that
can influence where you want to take
that sample for the ideal or best
consistent results now the advantage of
tissue testing you all know what's
actually inside the plant inside the
actual tissue this could provide a
comparison from the soil to get a better
understanding of the differences that
may be occurring so is a nutrient high
in the soil but low in the plant or
something really high in the plant that
may not be in the soil this can help
give you a better picture a more
holistic approach of not only the soil
but also how the plant is reacting to
the nutrients you may be feeding for the
new students that may be present or
absent in this soil profile or even the
soilless media now kind of the
challenges and this is ridiculous
is that having a standard to compare to
there's a lot of other tissue testing we
take corn and tomatoes while there's a
lot of testing to compare to it can be a
little bit hard for canvas also sending
the physical samples and finding a lab
that will them to take the samples can
sometimes be a challenge shipping them
in the mail there's some potential
issues with that and also certain labs
simply just do not want to deal with
cannabis samples so you might feel a
call the lab ahead of time before
sending anything and figure out a way
that may work because tissue testing can
offer a valuable tool to evaluate the
nutrients inside your plan