a very common method of drying cannabis
is
simply putting it out to hang to dry so
on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over some of the details of
plant
hanging for efficient drying as well as
show you some examples of actual
cannabis plants going through that
drying process
so you can make sure it applies to your
particular growing situation
[Music]
all right let's get into plant hanging
drying system regarding cannabis and
here we see a drying room
uh with some canvas being hung out to
dry we noticed that there is a lot of
space between the different areas here
this is allowing a good air circulation
we see the fan running in the background
we see temperature humidity controls
here very clean environment
this is kind of giving you an indication
of what a true drying system
operating at peak efficiency should look
like now the drying process
is critical so after all the work of
growing the harvesting the goal is to
maximize the quality of the end product
you're going to produce
while you cannot create high quality end
product and
in the drying process you can certainly
lose what started out as a high quality
product if you do not perform this
correctly
so a lot of growers spend a lot of time
worrying about nutrients and plant care
and pruning
also make sure you're also putting the
effort into a proper
drying process to allow that final
product
to show its true qualities now this hang
drying
method very commonly implemented is
considered by some to be the preferred
method
for for preserving bud conditions now
the quick method
at time of harvest it does not require
high labor investment of time to
manicure the buds
that's one of the reasons why it's so
advantageous several buds in the same
branch can also dry together as we saw
in the previous image
making it also a very efficient process
now different growers may choose to
remove different amounts or percentages
of fan leaves but again that amount
does offer the grower an option for the
drying environment
now the hang drying downfall because no
method
is absolutely perfect so this method
does require that there's plenty of
space
to allow not only the hanging of
branches but also sufficient airflow you
don't want to have all your branches all
packed in in that room you want to make
sure that there is
sufficient air flow here we see down in
iowa above the plants below the plants
all those are important areas
to allow that air to be able to mix
evenly there should be space between the
branches and also between the rows
so be sure not to over pack a dry room
because it's going to cause uneven
drying
inconsistent drying and issues in the
end
now it can be cut and hung but not
advised so
some growers will like to take the whole
plant cut it and immediately dry it
and while each bud does not need
individual attention to the degree
that the rack system would require
talked about in another video
there should be some time spent to
remove some of the leaves around the
buds on a branch
it is possible to simply cut the branch
from the original plant
or even just cut the plant down and hang
it for drying
though this is not often advised as we
see here can be done but not usually
advised
some care should be taken to remove at
least some of the fan leaves
as this will help ensure an even and
consistent drying process
and also reduce the initial humidity
that will need to be regulated in the
area
so keep in mind want to keep the
immediate particular region the bigger
range
so you can have uh dehumidifiers if you
remove some of those
uh fan leaves that are not needed anyway
you're reducing the stress
on the system so your system can be able
to maintain
those target humidity levels a little
bit easier
now there's a dry hanging myth i've
heard some growers say that when hanging
the plants upside down
the plant components will not that's
just or not
drain into the buds that are fixed in
the plant so things oh drying upside
down perfect
all the good kind of left over
cannabinoids and terpenes
they're all going to be able to kind of
work their way down through and with
gravity
end up in the bud and that is not the
case they're fixed in the plant
the reason why we hang them upside down
here is simply because the ease and
simplicity of this method
not because we're using gravity to force
anything down to the bottom here and
concentrate it in the buds
that simply is not the case now you want
to be cautious of
light so here we're seeing that same
image at the beginning with the lights
off how it is
mostly kept with the hanging drying
method the spacing of plants for the
purposes of increased air circulation
also means they'll be exposed evenly to
light want to keep that light minimal
both the intensity as well as the
duration so again that duration of light
should be minimum in the sense that you
don't have to always keep them in the
dark you have to run in there and get
something go through something
go right ahead uh but keep the lights on
for the least amount of duration
and make sure you're not turning all the
lights on just a minimum amount of light
that you need to get in
and get out keep in mind does not mean
we kept 100 dark the entire time
but just be aware that light exposure
they are getting it and keep it to a
minimum
some growers will say i want to go in
there today because they're drying if
you don't have to
then don't but don't think that you're
forbidden from that area during the
drying process keep it short
keep it quick and it should be fine now
let's go into it let's take a look at
a real world example of looking at some
canvas
that is going through the drying process
with this hang and dry method
and hopefully this will allow you to see
a couple slightly different systems
the consistencies amongst them to see if
it applies to your situation
okay so here we're noticing a plant
that's recently been harvested
flipped upside down and is now in the
drying process
keep in mind while it is efficient to
flip them upside down and to dry them
and they hang them this way
it does not increase any of the
cannabinoids so it's common
misconception oh they flip it outside so
all the
good chemicals and juices and terpenes
all kind of get to the buds
that's not the case they're locked in
the plant where they're going to be this
is just very efficient
kind of easy able to hang them easily
able to stock a lot in
a small area so this is a great way to
go through and dry your plants
but don't think by drying them this way
it's going to increase any cannabinoids
that might be in the stems
and work their way down that's simply
not the case
okay so this shows some nice drying here
we're noticing
uh this is all came from the field and
we noticed kind of hanging on this deer
netting creating a nice little
area here down the hallway which really
helps dry very efficiently
also creates a very nice visual effect
the deer netting where we're drying all
the cannabis buds and the actual wall
here and this is important to maintain
this because we do want to have
a certain gap here to allow air
circulation to come through
the hallway is on this side but we did
not put these up here against the wall
which is a good thing because you do
want to have that even air circulation
to allow efficient drying
and also even drying and as i come on
this side you can see the hallway
let's kind of get that hallway like the
wizard of oz kind of look to it where we
look at the emerald city
uh and here we have a nice green area
with all the cannabis buds drying
and drying in a way that looks very nice
and also is very efficient
so here we're seeing some cannabis
that's recently been harvested and is
now looking at being dried
ready for the next stage of processing
and by going through and hang it like
this we see a very efficient way to
dry it and keep everything consistent
notice how there's space under underside
everything there's a walkway we've got
humidity monitoring
we're trying to maintain consistent
conditions there's also a lot of air
moving
in this area all very important as well
as the muted
lighting to help again us monitor the
plants but also
ensure that we're not getting direct
sunlight and then they might be doing
any damage to them