I'm here we're gonna investigate plant
hormones in the general sense I'm just
giving an overview of the impact that
certain ones can have as you can see in
the picture here hormones can impact
plant behavior dramatically if used in
the right amounts so hormones in general
hormones are organic substances produced
in small amounts that regulate or
coordinate metabolism growth in
morphogenesis there's a couple listed
here which I'll have separate videos on
described in more detail cytokines can
induce the growth of the shoots auxins
can promote route initiation
gibberellins consume late stem
elongation and others can trigger
velocity we're not going to focus on
this one too much here we're also going
to go over abscisic acid so basically
one processing just in the general sense
looking at a receptor that binds we have
this hormone again there's small amounts
but they're binding to a specific
receptor then there's signal
transduction
these are relay molecules the number of
molecule at molecules activate and be
increased exponentially this is why
hormones are needed such small amounts
because they can initiate a large
response through relay molecules these
really molecules can then impact a
cellular response by affecting the DNA
expression in this case so the activity
is initiated indirectly via the action
of secondary messengers notice this
small round val-kill is able to get
through the pore of the nucleus and
adjust the cell a response by adjusting
the gene regulation now we have some
different examples here of different
types of hormones keep in mind there's
two key categories there's lipid soluble
hormones or steroid hormones give the
details here key part is these are able
to go through the phospholipid bilayer
and enter the inner part of the cell
making directly initiate the production
of proteins within a target cell
because they easily diffuse that
cellular membrane the hormone cells to
bind to receptor in the cytosol and that
forms a receptor hormone complex
receptor : complex and enters in nucleus
okay here and that can bind to the
target gene of the DNA transcription of
the gene creates messenger RNA that's
been translated to the desired protein
within the cytoplasm lipid soluble
hormones
those are all considered steroids now
other ones are water silo horns and they
have a little bit of a different process
water so hormones can't diffuse through
the cell membrane these hormones must
bind to a surface membrane receptor see
here receptor that initiates a cell
signaling pathway within the cell
involving proteins these protein kinases
phosphorylate proteins in the cytoplasm
this activates the proteins in the cell
that carry out the chart is specified by
the hormone so there's a little bit of
extra binding site it needs to cry on
the external surface because water
soluble hormones can't go through the
philosopher lipid bilayer those lipids
remember those tails are hydrophobic and
it will repel that so these proteins
need to bind to a surface protein
receptor here are steroid hormones be
able to go right through water Cylons
need that extra receptor binding complex
this Centro's it again the lipid soluble
hormones see here an example of animals
would be you know I would a little bit
easier to relate to the same thing
occurs in plants lipid silyl can diffuse
right through the membrane the hormones
bind to receptor in the cytoplasm the
receptor home on complex enters the
nucleus and adjusting gene regulation
that dream regulations related to
transcription ultimately translation
resulting an inactivated protein water
soluble hormones on the other hand these
need to bind to the exterior surface
he's bind with a protein complex and you
can see in a roundabout way they are
also producing activated proteins but
they have a little bit of different
pathway that protein kinase activated
protein kinase requiring ATP and that
phosphorylation that's occurring is
generating the protein within the
cytoplasm we notice here were had seen
transcription translation with actual
DNA and gene regulation here we're kind
of sidestepping the nucleus and we're
just generating activated proteins
within the cytoplasm the five major
classes of plant hormones that we're
going to be discussing our auxins
typically for shoot apical meristems and
that's where they're typically found
they're for stimulation
vascular tissue and lateral buds
cytokinins they're produced in the roots
and transport
there they interact with auxins they
said they stimulate cell division
gibberellins they can be an apical
portions and they're responsible for
seed germination and internode
elongation ethylene is in leaves and
stems and young fruits considered its
obsession which is the dropping of
leaves the flower and the fruits and
fruit ripening in abscisic acid mature
leaves root caps is where it's produced
and it can suppress a bud growth it's
also important personal motto opening
this gives you a quick overview of
hormones in their function the word that
may be found at different sequences of
the plant you knows for germination only
tuber Elms are really the most active
where one look at flowering and fruit
development pretty much everything but
ik of cystic acid is involved in some
way that cystic acid is key for seed
dormancy a little bit for our obsession
with eskalene also plays a role in there
so you can see that just one hormone
isn't doing just one task and we evolved
in multiple different tasks we're going
to learn about each of these in a little
bit more detail so you can appreciate
some of the specifics that these
different hormones and their ratios and
concentrations can impact plant growth