here we're looking at plant production
and what it takes to initially get
plants started so that ideally they can
grow well during the season and you can
get a bountiful harvest off that only
see a nice collection of fruits and
vegetables here from the speaking
generalities but a lot of these things
can apply and and take them as reference
points for whatever specific crop you're
looking at growing
so starting with the main summary our
goal is to turn this into this it's some
way to take our fruits of our labor
literally speaking and generate a some
sort of profit to not support the farm
but our activities maybe offseason and
to allow us to have financial income to
grow the following year so it all starts
with the seed not always because there's
grafted plants so you decide what you
plant now certain market demands may
require you to grow certain types of
crops but specific varieties is where
you come in and you can make that
decision
grab the plants are worth considering we
see some examples of some grafted
Tomatoes here through disease resistant
root stock meaning the bottom portion
here the roots in the soil can be
resistant to certain soil borne diseases
and there's a better tasting portion on
top there's oftentimes the top portion
that's maybe better tasting may not have
the disease resistance that we want
versus the plants that are disease
resistant may not have the taste we want
so grafting we kind of get the best of
both worlds
literally the downfall of grafted plants
as they do cost more but in the end it
might be worth that cost remember if you
do grow grafted plants to leave this
graft union above the soil line
particularly with tomatoes if you bury
this graft union below the soil line
roots will form from the top section and
you'll lose the ability of the advantage
I should say of having that graft union
so what's just left there's so many seed
catalogs so many seeds we didn't
varieties how do you kind of go about
developing its selection for what you're
actually going to plant so what to look
for is do some things the descriptions
will always provide you the best quality
so keep that in mind you're reading the
seed catalog every seed sounds like do
no wrong because you're
supplied with the best qualities
behavior is important to make sure it'll
fit your growing situation for planning
purposes you wanna be careful on some
varieties whether it's a bush or a vine
that can impact your row spacing that
same one's better than the other but
just be aware if you're buying a bush
riding it to be more compact in the vine
variety tends to spread out war
vegetable seed selection tips we want to
be looking for certain things disease
resistance that we can get it your
market interest because if you grow it
you can't sell it there's no point
flavor it's gonna be subjective and then
a plant behavior is it a tall plant a
vining plant at spreading plant and we
type the picture of the horses here we
want to take kind of all the horses and
select what we think is gonna be the
winner for our situation may not always
be the winner all the time in every
growers situation but for your specific
conditions you want to pick what you
think is going to best fit in with all
of your other constraints you may have
disease resistance is a big one that's a
very important feature to look for this
potentially saved the crop with no
needed inputs from you there's a typical
key and each manufacturer may have a
slightly different key but this is some
very common ones beryllium well Fusarium
brunet nematodes tobacco mosaic virus
this is example one form one out to
visit was Tomatoes we could see the
tomatoes here the plants at least look
pretty well shot the plants here
immediately where the steak is from this
row down look very healthy this was a
tomato variety there's a mountain
mountain merit when it first came out
and late blight came in you could see
how devastating this was here's a grower
that didn't have to spray anything by
choosing just a certain variety that was
resistant to the disease they're able to
get a much healthier plant versus the
ones that will not resist it so I
mentioned the terms resistance Missi
resistance some manufacturers nickel
tolerant these are not interchangeable
terms how it means that the plant may
get the disease but typically will
survive resistant translates to in most
cases it will not contract the disease
at all so if you have the option of a
tolerant plant or visa student plant
choose a resistant plant
it's more likely to survive than a
tolerant plant open up a seed catalog
against residents don't try them all
there's 8 million different varieties it
seems like and you're trying to select 1
2 3 4 not a thousand not a hundred not
grow a whole bunch and see what makes it
try to be selective on the varieties
that you do give a try realize that each
year's different so before you commit to
just one variety try it for multiple
years and develop an idea of your
standard variety for comparison so is it
that better than what you last year do
you have a variety to really like that
can offer your comparison for me I use
for example better boy Tomatoes that's
kind of my comparison how does it
compare to the better boy is it taller
is it more disease-resistant
I do produce quicker yields more uniform
yields so on and so forth that's my
example of my tomato variety comparison
I want to try something new I always
point it next to a better boy variety
and see outperforms didn't conduct of
seeds versus transplants so again pros
and cons to everything
seeding very easy can avoid root
disturbance the cons is the fear of the
unknown if you put a bunch of seeds in
the ground and crows come through behind
you and pick the seeds out of the field
yes that's happened to me you're looking
a week later and you're wondering why
there's nothing germinating
transplanting the advantages you have an
instant field right Thrun what was empty
in the morning can be fully complete
with plants for the afternoon avoids
potential animal damage because you've
got the see the transplants not the
seeds growing right in the ground the
con to this so there's more time caring
for the seedlings that are hurting off
process if you're seeding you don't have
to go through gets a big cedar here this
is an example of a large scale corn
cedar you can hand see the field at no
problem
if you are gonna do transplants one of
an adequate germination environment I
wanna make sure it's warm well-lit good
air circulation and easy access if
you've done in the basement that's not a
problem there's a bunch of tomato plants
being grown for a winter warm has a
relative term don't have to be super hot
just warm well let you see a bunch of
different lights here good air
circulation is important no one in a
closed environment and easy access in
and out for you
with good seed starting mix seed
starting mix potting soil should be
selected seed starting mix has finer
versus a regular just potting soil it's
better for seed to soil contact to get
the moisture content there so you want
seed starting mix not necessary potting
soil it's a little finer and it was
especially good for those smaller seeds
trays are often used want to select the
appropriate size to maximize the area
but not restrict the seedling growth too
much be sure to label them all so you
don't get confused or move one for some
reason then realize oh I don't remember
what variety that was we see here also
labels in different pots here every tray
is labeled that's an important then time
is money standardize your trays and
added Dib ler to help speed up the
production yes there's a little hand
iblis you can use but this is just some
dowels on a piece of wood you flip this
over merely puts a hold the right depth
all the trace at the same time you drop
all your little seeds in and you go on
to the next tray again that speed
efficiency standardizing your trays that
planning process is important it helps
you in the long run germination once the
seed emerges it will need the light
so brilliance have the proper spectrum
compared to regular house lights there's
many options when you're looking at
lighting this is what the plants absorb
you can see not a lot of green it the
chlorophyll is strong in the kind of the
bluish spectrum spectrum and also the
red spectrum different Calvin
temperature charts you need different
types of lights will produce different
color temperatures there's Minneapolis
I'm gonna go through a few of them and
compare so I'm just you have an idea but
LED metal halides high pressure sodium
fluorescent in natural light or the
common options comparing LEDs which
effect these purple kinda lights
compared to metal halides or
high-pressure sodium
this happens to be high pressure sodium
produces kind of that more orange color
middle house rousseau whiter light
advantage to the LEDs though low power
consumption efficient spectrum you can
actually dial in spectrums here the cons
are they are quite expensive they don't
cover a whole lot of area metal halide
inhale and HPS high pressure sodium czar
easy to find to booking one bubble cover
5x5 area the cons are
power consumption now they do consume
quite a bit of power and eight generate
a lot of heat so those should be taken
into consideration fluorescents versus
natural fluorescence relatively low
power consumption can fit easily over si
trays but they need to be kept really
close to the ceiling so you want to put
them on a hanging chain so you can raise
them as the plants grow upwards and not
good for long-term growth they don't
really produce a lot of light Naturals
free can be just hard enough time it's
great but when you're starting your
seeds and germinating them it could be
short day lengths and that could cause
issues and also I'll cause temperature
spikes really get hot during the day and
cool off at night so again just
something to consider
most of girls I see do use the
fluorescence so just use it as a
comparison hardly not that I mentioned
especially using fluorescence or kind of
a weak intensity and light you want to
make sure the plants are coming from
protected to a consistent environment
that they're ready for the extremes of
outside light temperature of the outside
world wind in seem like a desert even
they might be wandering them they keep
them inside that's where the air
circulation is important keeping the
bees on them hurting them off getting
exposed to natural sunlight before just
putting them outside from the basement
transplanting an early protection you
want to consider temperature swings
water stress humidity temperature
related animals who disclose and mice
attacking the plants you could go
through if you're a really
labor-intensive make little Hut's to put
over the nutrients plants here we see a
grower here as we block down walking
board so don't come back the soil and
they set up these little plastic kind of
walls this prevents wind damage
especially in these large leaves when
the image from curtain Corrine and
knocking the plant over causing damage
the top is left open so there's not a
temperature consideration or reason for
concern but the sides are protected in
help harden them off in the way of winds
damaged plant requirements how towels
are gonna get them and then the
varieties that you select so consider
this when your seed selecting do you
need hoops for early season protection
and they can support shade cloth as a
way to harden off some plants it may
take a little bit longer and they can
also hold insect netting so you might
may want to
go outside and mainly cover with in
forensic netting especially important
for cucumber beetles for our squash
plants especially have later plantings
squash bugs even protecting from a fits
if you have small enough mesh size so
just again things to consider when
you're going to be transplanting outside
in season care shell Sandra weaving you
could see these stakes here
do you have materials is a good question
well the tomatoes need staking let me go
buy some stakes well odds are a lot of
other people have that same idea and you
may not be able to get the stakes you
need weeding what method are you gonna
select for me to have another video on
weeding there you can use just regular
organic kind of hay mulch here or you
can use plastic pruning for tomatoes and
particularly how you gonna do it a
single loser double leader no pruning
heavy pruning it all depends harvesting
how often in at what stage you can
harvest you can pick tomatoes at what's
called the breaker stage with little
pink on the bottom or waiting them to
get fully red again all decisions need
to Nathan develop a plan for net harvest
we want to consider when you're
harvesting field heat utilities want to
harvest in the early morning or late
evening midday can cause them to dry out
pretty quick they contain a lot of heat
from the Sun particularly in the summer
and it's introduced storage time how
often do you want to be harvesting at
what stage do you want to harvest
they've been on your market or if you're
doing a farmers market wholesale on the
CSA community-supported agriculture or
something else restaurants all can
influence this but again things you want
to have in your plan for consideration
example summer squash repair of
continual harvests now people can do
those almost every day
tomatoes can be harvested before fully
ripe it will call the breaker stage is
they starting a little pink at the
bottom here if you're doing berry crops
and they can be very labor-intensive you
want to pick them out when they're
basically fully ripe that have an idea
what's ripening so you can have an idea
what you have for a harvest in post
harvest storage of the crops we grate
your harvest it where is it going to go
and after you're done with the crop
field cleanup this could often be left
to the very end of the season but
certain crops if they're if you're done
with them you want to find a way to
basically remove them or kill them off
they can hurled Harbor disease or other
cool BOTS or some type of refrigeration
system is a great thing to be putting
into your plan and considering so you
can cool and remove that field heat
large stackable storage bins and have
good air circulation also important in
worth consideration so again this comes
back to that planning that time
investment and having an idea of what's
going to occur over the entire season