okay here I'm gonna go over the very
basics of plant breeding and first and
foremost there's kind of two ways to
look at this there's a traditional way
which is what I'm gonna focus on here
where you have a donor variety strand
and recipient you're kind of getting
that mix of that new variety and we have
genetic engineering which is we're
taking these very specific desired gene
and very precisely inserting it into the
DNA sequence so this is still breeding
as you are still producing a new
individual but in this case if they're
very directed and only producing that
desired gene being transferred at one
time traditional is kind of that many
genes are transferred and the hope is
that desired gene will carry over and
here's that desire gene hope that desire
gene is carried over but there's also a
nice mother carry over she make
engineering is going to take them to
just that desire gene they only insert
that one we're gonna again focus a
little bit more the traditional breeding
here so a pure reading lines so starting
with the basics this is established
lines that come true from seed in order
for this to happen there needs to be a
limited amount of variation and reduced
amounts i gossiped ii the genetics need
to be either homozygous dominant or
homozygous recessive
this is different than clones because
clones are taking the same plant
material here we're having a male and
female are having a crossbreeding that's
occurring but essentially all of the
offspring are the same so there would
not be high variability at the x over
the puppies here pure breeding lines is
always going to kind of come true from
type whatever you get in the parents
here across to parents are going to be
very similar and you're gonna get
basically the same thing as a result
you're not going to get different colors
different splotches on different coat
patterns now for other terms use just
crossing selfing and sipping these are
common terms used within growers and use
when they're generating seeds are doing
crosses so the first are obvious one is
crossbreeding this is simple breeding of
two different variety gather and this
can create the highest degree of genetic
variability here we see a homozygous
recessive green color
Peapod and here we see a heterozygous
Peapod with one with yellow being
dominant we cross these together and we
see the variability that we get not only
and phenotype how they look but also in
genotype even kind of see the same thing
down here we're looking at our punnett
square we have two purple flowers both
heterozygotes I mean they both contain
this other recessive gene when we bring
these together we get 75% or 3 out of 4
phenotypes will be purple one will have
a white phenotype if we look at the
genotypes one is homozygous dominant at
a for one out of four will be homozygous
recessive and two will be heterozygotes
this means that this will always produce
the purple gene if it's bred with
another homozygous dominant all their
offspring will be considered to pure
breeding the same goes for the pure
breeding white here where they're
homozygous recessive these they'll
create a little bit more variability
just as we see here so again phenotype
genotype crossbreeding will kind of
create the highest degree of variability
something called sailfin this is the
name implies it's taking pollen
fertilizing the same plant no in canvas
this is because their money assistance
is very difficult to do this is the
concept of kind of getting that
feminized seen sort of speak this
selfing in general as you see here with
a lily flower this restricts the genetic
variability of the offspring you simply
have the male pollen fertilizing the
same female here so this is gonna limit
the genetic variability sitting this is
taking two seeds from the same plant and
that's the same individual plan and
using one plant for pollen and the other
for the flower this is a way to create a
small amount of variability because they
both came from the exact same original
plant in the offspring so you're getting
some variability but not a lot this is
kind of you looking at maybe refining
something or selecting for something
more specific so what's a hybrid so I
use corn as an example this hybrid corn
is probably pretty well known and
understood hybrids are botanically
different as an offspring from two
plants that are different species or
varieties so what this actually does
what the hybrid does it creates a
mixture of genetics and is often the
results of some crossbreeding
depending on what plants specifically
cross bred so what is this kind of
an example we consider these two
different corn plants that were
crossbreeding together this one produces
very small kernel system produces very
large kernels but it's kind of a smaller
cob itself we can crossbreed these to
develop a hybrid this hybrid has larger
kernels but more of this longer shape to
it and maybe has a greater area so this
is the resultant to be a hybrid we're
kind of seeing evidence of both of the
parents resulting in the offspring then
we can do something called f1 hybrid
synthesis hybrid vigor it's thought to
produce seeds or plants that are 25%
bigger than either parent alone well how
is an f1 hybrid example here as it's
accomplished well by developing two
distinctly stable breeding lines we have
violet and white flowers for obvious
examples we would self cross these for
about seven to nine generations and self
across white flowers in this example for
seven to nine generations after we have
these two isolated generations we breed
them together we would cross these
together to ideally hopefully create the
best of both worlds in the resulting f1
offspring so what does this kind of look
like in real life well this is kind of a
nice example here that I found we're
seeing seeds offer hybrid vigor which
can not be obtained directly from a
clone hybrids are created by crossing to
true reading parents to produce f1 seeds
and grow more vigorous in each parent
let me see parent one on this side
parent two on this side these are corn
plants this is the hybrid here so we
could see as we go through this
time-lapse showing the progression and
see this this plant here tends to
produce bigger and better than either of
the lines that it was used to breed with
and again isn't growing the full terms
is growing for about a little over 30
days we can see even from the beginning
the wider leaves the bigger plant then
either of the offspring there so again
just interested to see how hybrid vigor
can play out and this is something you
cannot get from clones lastly here's
something called the f2 generation well
this is further generations are just
continuations of the original breeding
lineage and it's tracked through
family treatment pedigree the downfall
is a resulting f2 generations offspring
may vary greatly from the f1 parents so
we take a pure breeding line a pure
breeding line that kind of self that 479
generations we get our hybrid vigor but
then if we plant that seeds from that f1
generation we do get something that may
revert back to one of the original so
just keep that in mind if you ever have
some hybrid plants or hybrid tomatoes it
you grow you save the seeds you may get
offspring that look nothing like the
original because it's reverting back to
one of the original generations