okay I'm gonna give a very brief
overview of plants app testing because
some growers are using this they can buy
kits that they can use at home the age
field provides a very quick way to
analyze some of the nutrients that may
be going on in their plant allowing them
to make quick changes if needed so with
our SAP testing there are some
limitations because the SAP can be in
continual flux kind of like taking a
blood test depending on what time of day
or what you may have eaten that can
change your blood sugar levels and we
have ways of regulating that plants kind
of the same thing they can kind of
change what's going on in that SAP
throughout the day also lights on lights
off when you're taking that sample that
can also influence it the advantages it
is giving quick results it's good that
similar to a blood test we want to be
mindful that depending on when we
fertilize when we feed our plans when
we're taking that test how greatly that
can influence their results also for
foliar feeding that can also cause a
swing potentially in these on sap test
results so again not saying it's a bad
test but the homeowner kitchen remember
are not necessary performed with the
proper protocol in a lab so just being
mindful of the data that you are
collecting this way not saying it's
necessarily bad but just be cautious and
mindful that when you're testing
something that can change so quickly
that could influence your results and
may be taking samples over a period of
time and kind of taking an average of
those might be a better approach than
using a one-time test and making a large
decisions based off that test results