so in this tobacco university video i'm
going to cover plastic containers for
cannabis production
[Music]
all right let's look more at plastic
containers here
so first off when we're looking at
plastic containers they're very popular
and they're popular for good reason
they're made in a wide variety of shapes
sizes and colors
the shapes are round or they could be
the square type
sizes it could be under a gallon to all
up to potentially 25 gallons or
sometimes even slightly greater than
that
in colors from a black pot to a white
pot and a whole bunch of colors
in between there are a lot of options
when you're looking at
plastic containers i would say the round
black pots tends to be the kind of the
most consistent the most popular
but there are other options that are
available now
the plastic is considered to be kind of
the standard as far as containers go
plastic containers are often the least
expensive they tend to be easy to use
and very simple to clean which is
contributing factors to why they're
considered to be the standard
they may not be currently kind of a
trendy kind of container to
use but they are still very effective
and they're still used quite on the
large scale
now the reasons why some people may not
like a
plastic container to utilize for their
growing area is that plants can become
root bound in plastic pots
due to minimal natural aeration because
of the impermeable
material there this will reduce the
plant's access to nutrients and also
water absorption
may even hinder the ability for the
plants to aerate themselves also
ensuring that the substrate has
natural porosity can help reduce the
negative impacts of plastic containers
in the image we see here we see very
solid root mass here along the sides
however we don't see very many roots at
the very bottom
and we also see kind of where the
drainage hole was here right in this
vicinity here we see the sharp angles we
see kind of some discoloration to the
roots
so these are just important things to
keep in mind and while there might be
some
drawbacks these plastic pots are the
most popular
for good reason because of a lot of the
benefits that they bring
and a lot of the kind of the standard
process and also reusability in some
cases
to help reduce any sort of cost and help
maximize plant production