if you're growing in a small grow space
and want a very simple
way of adding carbon dioxide to your
area
looking at point injection behind a fan
is a great way to
easily add carbon dioxide to your grow
space
and here at tobacco university i'll
describe some of the details with
utilizing this method
[Music]
let's get into the video looking at
point injection behind a fan for carbon
dioxide delivery
for cannabis production so this point
injection behind a fan pretty simple
method
the sense that it's very simple to
assemble
and also very cost effective mainly
because most likely you have a fan your
grow area anyway
so adding the point injection behind the
fan just will help
increase the efficiency of its
distribution
in larger rooms there should be multiple
points of injection but this can help
ensure that there is a more even
distribution with equipment
that's likely already in place in your
facility now an oscillating fan would be
of course
the best option because while any fan
will help disperse carbon dioxide
using an oscillating fan will help
disperse the gas evenly
even more efficiently across the grow
space now keep in mind chromaxine will
want to
sink in the grow space so if you're
injecting at a higher point in mixing it
around this way
as it naturally wants to fall down
through the grow space it'll actually
fall through the plants
and be naturally dispersed through them
allowing for a very efficient uptake
now the direction of the fan so fans
should be dispersing
air across the tops of the plants so
again that co2 can fall through the
plants because it's heavier than air
however be mindful of the placement of
the exhaust system
you want to be injecting your co2 maybe
to higher up the canopy but you don't
want to have it right next to your
exhaust system you want to have that a
separate area
so that the co2 will naturally want to
fall down and your exhaust will pull out
the hotter air
and limit the amount of co2 that's
wasted by going out your exhaust system
for cooling
the plants now the placement of the
sensor
with this system as we can see here
another fan being utilized
and when deciding where to place the
sensor it should be about one half to
two thirds
of the travel distance of the air moved
by the fan this will help provide an
overall carbon dioxide concentration in
the grow space
you don't want it too close or too far
away kind of trying to get that
average reading that the plants are
experiencing so as your controller
is monitoring those levels and trying to
maintain certain levels it's the average
level the plants will be
exposed to to help allow for a very
efficient
growing operation with carbon dioxide
enrichment but always
make sure no other factors are limiting
to get the best
benefit from enriching your growth space
with carbon dioxide