welcome to tobacco university's video
presentation
of pollen's role in forensic science so
while we may not consider palm to be a
vital role in forensic science
those that are very detail-oriented and
can
discover this it may play a very
important
aspect of the evidence collection for
pinpointing a crime scene
so pollen's main role pollen is simply
that
small little tiny almost dust-like
appearance that flowers will produce for
the gold pollination to produce seeds so
pollen is used to help provide those
links this can take on different forms
but the goal is to aid
in allowing to strengthen a case with
increased evidence linking so while it
may not be the only thing
used it can help strengthen a case and
really provide
an investigator some solid evidence and
information
we want to make note that the same
concepts can be also applied to spores
that are applied here as shown for
pollen
now what is pollen well pond is simply
the male reproductive cell of flowering
plants those angiosperms
and cone bearing plants those
gymnosperms found
nearly everywhere which makes it great
to consider for crime scenes
and pollen has many unique shapes and
sizes when viewed with the aid of a
microscope
we may see it here as this all this kind
of little tiny yellow particulate here
but under a microscope it can look
vastly different within the same genus
there are often similarities
but between different plant species
there's definitely some noticeable
differences
as this pollen can be kind of like
nature's snapshot which what does that
mean well pollen can help identify the
area or the region
that a particular crime may have
occurred it can produce a pollen
fingerprint meaning what plants exist in
what area if we find that pollen we know
that on that individual that garment or
that clothing have to be present in a
certain region
can also help us pinpoint potentially
the time of year
meaning what pollen is found what
flowers bloom during certain times so
there might be a limited window for
certain plants
and that might really help determine the
time of year
that that garment was found or that that
clothing was present
at that crime scene now ponca used to
determine if the body was in a
particular place at a specific time
frame it can also identify the season
the crime was committed
if a body is discovered and contains
non-native pollen it was likely
moved prior to its present location so
all these can be vital
information that can be gathered to
again help strengthen
a case when we're looking at developing
what may have occurred at a particular
crime scene
now as i mentioned the pollen can have
very different looks well what do you
look for
you want to visually inspect with a
microscope when i look at the pawn shape
you want to look at the size
the surface texture and not knowing
anything about pollen in general if you
look at the images located down over
here
we can definitely see there are some
distinctive visual differences
good investigator would compare
specimens from the crime scene with that
on the suspect
and or victim to determine if there's a
similar pollen signature
or the likelihood of there being a match
between those two