so here I'm gonna talk about the
pollination process there's actually
very important to our basic survival in
food production of food in general here
we see an example would be going through
and doing this exact process I'm going
to be describing so start with why there
are different kinds of flowers so this
is again pertaining to angiosperms and
the pollination process so insects and
plants have a co-evolved so that certain
insects specialize in visiting
particular kinds of flowers a particular
insect carries pollen from one
individual flower to another of the same
species these are the most numerous
insect pollinator birds can also
pollinate some flowers especially red
ones so if you have hummingbird feeder
typically you put red dye in it
grasses and some other endosperm have
reverted to wind pollination so just
because there are inset polymers they
don't pollinate necessarily everything
so beasts and UV light which is
interesting
BC UV light so flowers look different to
them compared to us so remember our
visible light spectrum here UV is
ultraviolet ways so ultraviolet talking
we're over here in our light spectrum
here getting closer to our x-rays and
gamma-rays
then we are from our infrared or our
radar waves there so it's called
ultraviolet because it's beyond the
violet spectrum so what we see versus
what bees are able to see differences in
color sensitivity between humans honey
bees and hummingbirds is what provides
flowers to actually look different I
think these are some notable examples so
under normal light we see this as a
consistently yellow flower
however under UV light this is almost
like a target region that develops in
the center that's where the bees are
going to see and so they're going to
target to try to find the the pollen or
the nectar in their case same thing here
normal we see our nice kind of yellow
here under UV light we see that
distinctive darkening center region and
same goes for this flower and also this
flower provides kind of that extra
highlight to tell the bees hey come here
this is where the nectar is as I
mentioned those flowers matched a
pollinator so hummingbirds tenda
pollinate red flowers in
notice they have a very long beak thin
the beak at that and the flowers
replicate that bats call me white
flowers and have sweet smells and open
at night those sweet smells are so the
bats can help detect them moths are also
nighttime pollinators and some gourds
will calmly very white flowers that open
at night again
ants can also pollinate here as we see
here and all this pollen greens overhead
go through and go through the to the
next flower to help transfer some of
that or even help that same flower get
crossed
get pollinated by twin itself
pollination process in seed plants free
waters not required in fertilization
process pollination by insects wind or
other agents transfers pollen to an
ovule the pollen grain then cracks open
and sprouts as a pollen tube in bringing
the sperm cells directly to the egg what
we see here so here's our flower and
you're not familiar with the parts you
can refer back to some of the other
videos that I have particularly
gymnosperms and angiosperms see the
pollen lands here on the sticky stigma
and its travels down here and a store go
all the way to reach the ovule so
there's no distance that it needs to
travel so just because the pollen is
transferred to these stigma doesn't mean
it automatically gets pollinated that
needs to be able to survive and live and
be able to travel all this distance now
in particular we have something called
double fertilization so tubes from or
pollen grains are required to produce a
seed one sperm fertilizes the egg to
produce that zygote to men the other
fertilized polar nuclei to form eight
the three and end of sperm which is the
food source for the embryo so this means
one pollen grain is fertilizing the egg
to produce this I go the other one is
fertilizing this area here to produce
the food for that seed once in
germinated to initially feed on so we
see here's our pollen grain or pollen
tube two sperm cells coming down both
fertilizing this particular one
technically is fertilizing it the other
one is making the endosperm which is the
food region here so palm green adheres
to the statement
two cells generates this cell in tube
cell the pollen tube grows into the
style generator cell transfers inside
the pollen tube dividing the form to
sperm cells the pollen tube penetrates
the opening ovule to calm the macro file
here one of the sperm fertilizes the egg
to form the diploid zygote the other
sperm fertilizes two polar nuclei to
form the triploid endosperm which
becomes the food source for the growing
embryo this is an important process that
does occur here's the same image down
here this double four ization energy is
produced special highly nutritious
tissue called the endosperm for their
seeds when a flower is pollinated the
pollen tube grows down from pollen grain
on the stigma pong game contains two
haploid sperm the first worm fuses with
the egg at the base of the ovary the
second firm fuses with the polar nuclei
from the triploid endosperm cell which
divides faster than the zygote and gives
rise to the endosperm tissue remember
this endosperm tissue is the food region
for the cell for the UM seed the process
of fertilization to produce both zygote
and endosperm is called double
fertilization
now pollination process is actually
accidental so it's kind of amazing that
something we're so dependent on as far
as sustaining our species providing the
food for the world is actually an
accidental process the pollinator gets
nectar and accidentally transfers pollen
as we see here the male flower so here's
a be going down getting nectar bumping
into this portion transferring pollen
over again the bees more concerned about
that nectar than the actual pollen the
bee flies out of this flower and this is
a female flower as the squash plant that
produces both and that's why I chose
this to show it distinctively here's the
bead throwing back down here to get the
nectar and now it's kind of taking the
Palmetto the quired here and
transferring it to the stigma here
that's why you typically see these in
these types of flowers with their heads
down trying to absorb the nectar down
here they're not really concerned with
the transfer of pollen they're more
concerned with the acquisition of the
nectar and the pollen that's getting
transferred is simply an accidental
process
we have two parts of pollination is
something called cross-pollination
paalam is transferred between two
different individuals from the same
species here is one flower is another
flower sis cross-pollination advantages
increases our genetic variability in the
species but it can produce unfit
individuals versus self pollination
where we see pollen from the same flower
getting poly it with the same flower
this pollen from the same individual is
used to pollinate the same plant the
Evangelist produces seeds when
individuals are isolated the kind of
reduces to genetic variability and
doesn't open the species up to really
adapting much to the environment so
again pros and cons to each but both can
occur and produce viable seeds
lastly the lifecycle of an angiosperm
tying a lot of the other videos together
tying in some of the flower anatomy some
of the terms we discussed previously
such as meiosis and mitosis the sperm
cells the egg cells pollination process
something you may want to review and be
familiar with for the quiz coming up on
this section