welcome to this tobacco university we'll
be exploring a video here
on polyplotization for the genetic
improvement of cannabis
sativa and specifically we're going to
be breaking down
a scientific study that looked at
investigating this particular type
of polyploidy levels in cannabis
sativa now when talking about polity
levels just keep in mind we are diploid
organisms so polyploating is referring
to
an abnormal or an increased number in
copies here and we'll explain that more
as the video goes on
first off i want to be mindful that this
is the research article if you want to
look at it yourself
provided with the reference here the
citation and a direct link
as well as a copy of the first page here
so first off what is this poly
politicalization well
this is the multiplication of the whole
chromosome
complement that has occurred frequently
in vascular plants so just as a quick
biology review your haploid is your
gametes in this case if we're talking
about plants
this would be your egg cells or your
pollen grains
diploid would be the normal organism but
here we're looking at the polyplusation
the
3n or the tetraploid the 4n multiple
copies here from what would be
considered normal
the main the maintenance of a stable
polyploid state over generations
requires specific mechanisms
to control pairing and distribution of
more than two homologous chromosomes
during meiosis so that's just a brief
overview of what we're investigating
here
we'll get to see this how this actually
changes the canvas plant's morphology
so first off why investigate this in the
first place you know what's the
justification for even
considering this well the poly
politicalization is considered a viable
tool in the genetic
improvement of crop plants the
evolutionary success of
polyploid plants in nature and under
domestication
has been attributed to the buffering of
mutations
we see this in comparison looking at the
regular diploid
compared to some of the other types of
ploidy levels most
evident here with the strawberries we
have a wild strawberries to our
cultivated strawberries everyone wants
larger bigger fruits and this is kind of
one way
potentially through genetics and these
polly levels
to accomplish this so looking
specifically now at
cannabis leaves collected on leaf
stomata morphology of mature fan
leaves so we're seeing this comparison
here of a
is diploid b it's tetraploid we see the
same thing here with the stomata with c
and d so the leaves collected after four
weeks is vegetative growth and one week
under flowering lights that's when this
material was collected from the plants
down here this black and white images
we're looking at nail polish impressions
to show the stomata on the
uh kind of underside surface of the fan
leaves
the ab axel um surface now when we talk
about nail polish impressions it's
literally kind of a way that you can put
nail polish down and kind of lift that
to get an idea of what the stomata look
like remember the stomata are the pores
in the underside of the leaves
that regulate water loss and carbon
dioxide intake
so you want to appear larger in size on
the tetrapointed plants we see that
right here these bars represent the same
size
see these are clearly larger than the
diploid organisms here
then looked at trichome density so
specifically speaking to trichomes which
knows very important in cannabis plants
when we're looking at trichomes the
images show the trichome density
again at that same leaf surface there of
the fourth sugar leaf of cannabis sativa
strain
plants a and b are diploid so here's a
and b these are both diploid
c and d are the tetraploid down here
leaves were imaged on the seventh week
of flowering and note the sidebars
oh sorry the scale bars are one
millimeter to give you a size
comparison there we can clearly see that
there is definitely
more trichomes or the increased density
here on the tetraploids
now the inflorescence architecture
looking at the specific colas or the
flowers here
the influence apex top cola and buds
shown in the
for two plants during the eighth week of
flowering of cannabis sativa strain
week 12 after transplanting and one week
before harvesting you an idea when this
was occurring in this plant
a and b are diploid i'm sorry a and c
are the diploid here in the same column
here
b and d here are the tetraploid and
images a and b represent the cola
and c and d represent the bud morphology
a little bit closer there
again we've not seen stark differences
here but if you look at them long enough
you can definitely see that there are
some morphological differences in the
influence architecture
now looking more at the data so that's
kind of the large scale look well how do
these actually compare when we look at
some of the graphs in data generated
well the phytochemical content dried
buds and leaves of cannabis sativa
plants of different
ploidy were assessed using hplc and gc
for cannabinoids and terpenes
that's high pressure liquid
chromatography and gas chromatography
there are those abbreviations
a is the cannabinoid profile so we can
see right up here and b
is the terpene profile of the chart down
at the bottom
data or means plus or minus the standard
error where 10 diploids and nine
tetraploids were
analyzed means of different upper and
lower case letters are significantly
different using the anova
with two keys post hoc test with a p
value uh
greater than 0.05 to give you an idea of
the statistics behind this
now what's the summary here as we kind
of look at the bars and different colors
we're looking at here
well the phytochemical content in the
lower leaves is high enough
for the trim leaf material to be used
for extraction in both pleity
levels studies which can which could
almost double the total production
yields that's important remember that
the dried trim leaf material also does
contain
a levels that would be worth going
through the phase of extraction
total chirping content of tetrapod
leaves is comparable to the diploid bud
interpreting extracts from the
tetraploid leaves may have commercial
value despite low levels of cannabinoids
and we kind of see that comparison there
looking at our diplomatic tetraploid
our differences here again everything is
reduced in the leaf overall but does
give it some thought there
as far as potentially taking that
material not just discarding it
but going through the process of
extraction and here in the diploid we
see the leaves being uh
lower than the buds uh and here we see
the leaves overall being a little bit
higher we see that blood definitely
being a b
making it's a little bit higher there
indicating more genetic
similarities here but beating distinctly
higher in the tetraploid bud
compared to the diploid there so again
just looking at some of the stats we can
clearly see there are some differences
on the phytochemical content
now what do these results indicate well
tetrapod
canvas plants generally grow comparable
to traditional diploids so that's a good
note for those that are
actively growing this plant it's going
to behave pretty simple the tetrapod
cannabis plants reduced rooting was
noted so that's just might be an area of
concern
or something to keep an eye on tetrapod
chemists have
a similar chemical profile to diploids
with notable increases in cbd
and subsequent terpenes so that increase
in cbd
is important and that's what makes it
advantageous
to be potentially considering this as a
grower here of producing cannabis to
look at tetraploids potentially
so what's that kind of grower's
suggestion general summary well using
polyplusation canvas plans
may be an effective method for
maximizing cbd and terpene production so
that's a very important note there
i do want to make note that if you do
read the article in a little bit more
detail
they do state that really they did not
see much of a change in the
thc levels but it was noticed in cbd and
definitely terpene production
for these polyploids so again just
something there to consider
something you may not have been thinking
of before and this
just allows or shows how scientific
research can really potentially
continue the breeding process in the
improving
of cannabis plants