okay here we look at population
demographics and what we see pictured
here is a population pyramid and it goes
over and it shows the number of
individuals in a certain age of the male
and female gender here in this case this
is representing the u.s. population for
the year 2010 so we're gonna look at
some of these and understand a little
bit more about what this may show us so
first off population demography well the
demography is it statistical study of
populations there must many people and
graphically a measurement so it's a
measurement of people and we may be
familiar with kind of the world
population here in billions I and the
exponential growth that we're in and is
it going to continue at high rate
continue at a medium rate or low rate
erection to grade is the question here
that we're looking at so this study
helps us predict how population sizes
will change going forward and the growth
rate is sensitive to the sex ratio it's
the males to females and the age
structure how many young people how many
older people and how many middle-aged
people so if we look here at the world
here well the sex ratio the portion of
males to females in a population is the
basic definition of this the number of
births is usually directly related to
the number of females is they're the
ones that convert children so we see our
map indicating here while blue indicates
countries with more females than males
we see that it here countries with the
same number of males or females are in
green and countries with more males and
females are in red there and note it is
here so this can be a little misleading
when we see some of these large areas
I'll remember this is just looking at
the country isn't saying that there's a
definite border here it's looking at
just the sex ratio of the different
countries we can see a definitely a
general trend here of these countries
having more males and females and in the
United States here and North America
overall having more females than males
the gender gap and in the other child
sex ratio overall there are more males
and females in various
Indian states particularly in the
northern area where they're going to be
as many as 125 to 130 males to female to
100 females what are some of the
long-term impacts overall population of
this country so in the country that has
this many more males than females how is
this going to impact different areas and
that's the thing we need to think about
and when there's a gender gap these are
some of the questions that are generated
and as the impact it can have on that
country in the long term
now the gender gap in the worldwide view
here looking at gender equality here
again in red we have a larger gender gap
and in green we have a less gender gap
there gender gap of one would be
incomplete equal here and we could see
here the different countries where there
is a greater gender gap where that is
existing based on 2013 data and this
gender imbalance is very evident in
China where it's in 1982 and the
ultrasound was widely available we see
now an increase in the number of males
present in 2012 for every 100 girls born
there were a hundred and sixteen boys
born here now this Chinese gender
imbalance problem the gap may not look
large but it represents a gender gap of
about 34 million women in 2011 there so
there's a lot more males than there are
females despite our growing population
here overall in billions is uneven there
are more males than females there
just a general population demographic
well in Singapore
I hear we have a poster that says 1 2
and that's ideal the goal here was to
try to limit the amount of population
growth that may occur and on the picture
here countries at by birthrate those of
the brighter collaborations here we're
seeing births per thousand and
population we're seeing a lot higher
birth rate in the countries here of
Africa so the age structure as I
mentioned cohort is a group of
individuals of the same age with
characteristics birth rate of London C
is the number of offsprings born in a
standard time that directly relates to
the death rate or mortality or looking
at populations here it's the number of
individuals that die in that same period
the relative number of individuals in
each current defines populations age and
that goes back to the first image we saw
with the bars who are looking at the
number of individuals of male and female
sex ratio there how many occur in
particular population so the birth
weight is the number being born death
rates number dying off how these relate
to one another will determine a
populations demographics