okay here we're looking at population
distributions if you look at this image
in the apples in it you can look see how
they're distributed as you can see it's
kind of a random and distribution
however if we look zoom out from this
one particular image and look at the
entire field we would see odds are these
apples be concentrated in one area so
let's look at population distributions a
little bit more detail first off we look
at a normal population distribution if
we look here we see as you increase n or
the number of individuals we see a more
defined what we call a bell curve here
with the odds are or normal average
being right here in the center again and
a form you see it increasing we see a
little bit more they define
characteristics it 16 to 32 to 64 now
we're really getting a sense of this
normal distribution curve often referred
to as the bell curve what this means is
the average will be here in the middle
and 34.1% will be one at standard
deviation to the right and thirty-four
point one on the right to the left I
should say and as we get further away we
see a smaller percentage there's a very
small percentage it'll be way out here
same thing here on the other scale what
I think about this would be height if
your measure height of a bunch of
individuals of the same age you'd have a
couple really tall people a couple
really short people and the vast
majority of people being in that normal
distribution or close to that average
height now fish population is
distributed over a temperature range or
again we're looking at population
distributions
well how water temperature influences
fishing for small pelagic species
bluefin tuna and mahi-mahi or dolphin
are pelagic species in normal conditions
you can see most of the fish here are
about 50 meters down from the surface
but during an El Nino where we have that
increased water temperature these
pelagic species enjoy certain water
temperature as a result they'll be found
much deeper in the water column in this
case if we're a fisherman here using a
net to catch the fish you can see during
normal conditions nope
well but during El Nino that because
those fish go deeper seeking that
similar water temperature then that is
an effective in this example now
specific population distributions we
have something here called a random
distribution and occurs when there is no
competition and agonism or tendency to
aggregate which tends to be rare so this
random distribution we could look at the
hillside here the presence of conifer
trees is random the presence of maple
trees is random oak trees is random and
it kind of looks like this is kind of
like you took a bunch of marbles and
just kind of threw them out over any
area it's a random distribution here we
have a uniform distribution which
results from intense competition or
antagonism between individuals and tends
to be rarely found you can see here with
the Penguins pretty much all evenly just
the distribution is very evenly spaced
kind of like students in the class you
can see they're all kind of like facing
here like we're viewing from the teacher
standpoint however we don't see it we
typically seen classes it's talking or
on their phones and we see kind of most
of the payments here nicely facing the
camera here are paying attention another
population distribution would what we
call clumping this is the most common
distribution because environmental
conditions are seldom uniform
reproductive patterns favorite clumping
and anal behavior patterns often lead to
congregation we see that here there's
kind of like little clumps of these
particular organisms the Optima t4a
population growth in survival is often
intermediate one under crowding can be
as harmful as overcrowding so we want to
take this into consideration we're
looking at populations too we often
think of the negatives being too many
organisms in one area in certain cases
under crowding can also be harmful or
just too few individuals in an area
looking at population dispersal looking
at the spread of the Africanized may
beans we see them evident here in texas
and spreading out early so the question
is how can you explain their success in
expanding their territory these
Africanized honeybees looking
specifically our population to
versal why are they originally brought
to Brazil arre Tricia's brought the
Africanized honeybees to Brazil 1950s
attempt to improve productivity of the
Brazilian bees so these African
honeybees were brought to Brazil we see
they've expanded well beyond that they
originally brought with good intentions
however how can you explain the success
of Experion in territory we see them
starting to move into Mexico and Texas
and southern regions of the United
States
well Africanized honeybees produced more
offspring they defend their nests much
more fiercely in greater numbers and are
more likely to abandon their nests when
threatened by predators or adverse
environmental conditions so they're just
a couple of the ways to explain how
these Africanized honeybees be able to
vastly increase their population
dispersal the population growth rates
the increase in population during the
period of time expressed as a percentage
of the population at the start of that
period
it reflects the number of births and
deaths during a period of time now you
can see here the average population
growth notice here Germany and Japan
they are below zero they actually have
negative population growth rates which
means that they are ever a year that
goes by their population is decreasing
so it's possible population growth to be
negative here something want to consider
well look at the average and if things
are well above or below that average how
that may influence the world's
population that may influence the
resources that we use on a global scale