in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over post-harvest cannabis
plant disposal as it's something indoor
growers as well as outdoor growers
need to take into consideration
[Music]
all right let's get into post harvest
cannabis plant disposal
so first off want to think about the
post harvest waste
since the goal is to only harvest the
buds there is a lot of plant biomass
that is not needed
and becomes waste products and this is
speaking to plants
that we're not looking at producing kind
of fiber for
growers need to keep this in mind as to
also have this as a plan for disposing
of this excess of plant material it's
really the only end goal result
is the actual buds and flowers and the
leaves may be immediately surrounding
those
so keep in mind this is more than just
plants yes the plants are a source of
waste but you also need to consider
other plant supporting materials this
may depend on your growing situation
again with your indoor grower
or an outdoor grower but regardless
growty to take into account all plant
material and supporting plant material
into consideration when it comes to
waste disposal
now for indoor operations indoor
operations
have some situations that are not
present for outdoor growing plants for
example
indoor growers have to consider how
they're going to dispose of their
containers
this substrate that they might be using
as well as the lights
such as the bulbs and ballast that they
might be using and i'll have a separate
video
i've really focused on indoor growing
operations
now for outdoor growing operations
they're not immune either to considering
harvest disposal
outdoor growing operations have some
situations that are not present for
indoors
they a lot of times have weed control
products such as plastics for example
it to be disposed of irrigation
equipment also an important
consideration
for items that will need to be disposed
of
so if you're an outdoor grower of a
separate video on that but keep in mind
in both situations indoor and outdoor
there are
post harvest disposal methods post
harvest waste products
that growers need to be mindful and
considerate of
when they're trying to implement some
sort of growing practice so they don't
get caught
the end of the season with a large
area to dispose of a large volume of
material outside of the plants that they
may not have considered