in this debaco university video we'll be
looking at potassium
as related to a soil test report and why
it's important to watch and monitor your
potassium levels
so potassium typically called potash is
important we're looking at your soil
test report however when i say soil test
report we're typically not testing these
little
homeowner kits here we're getting it
tested at a professional lab and basing
our results off that
so plant potassium requirements so when
we're looking at our plants we do
require
large amounts of potassium and elemental
symbol k
potassium is released from rocks and
soil minerals as they weather
often the supply of potassium from the
soil is limited
and inputs of this nutrient are required
simply because there might be potassium
present but typically not the levels
that were required by plants
so what are the potassium functions
within that plant why is it so important
well potassium is critical for numerous
plant functions and especially aids and
hardiness
and potential for disease resistance and
also we can see for increased root
growth we see potassium building and
strengthening the plant
water status for growing fruits it can
be in that actual fleshy component of
the fruits
so there's a lot of functions for
potassium in the plants
this is why it's typically needed in
large amounts
now when we're adding potassium
fertilizer
we want to look at the timing of that
potassium fertilizer
so typically plants need potassium more
in the second half
of the grow cycle so growers should add
fertilizer to best
match this if all the fertilizer is
provided at the time of planting
this can increase the odds of
deficiencies later in the growing season
and also increase the chance that the
potassium added will be leached
and kind of wasted to potentially become
a contaminant to the local environment
so when we're looking at that kind of
days after planting and that kind of
when's potassium going to be needed
we're going to be looking at that later
portion here
that potassium uptake would be needed so
if we fertilize everything here in the
first 30 days
well the total amount needed not really
that much
much later in the season needed in
greater amounts so again
good time to fertilize in this example
here looking at the graph
would be about that 30 to 40 days or so
assuming there's some levels in the soil
and to allow for that
really high demand phase to be when the
potassium is
most available so how do we spot a
potassium
deficiency potentially and it's going to
look like this in many crops
but potassium can move within the plant
so deficiencies are likely to show in
the older
leaves first it typically expresses
itself as a yelling of the leaf margins
or
edges of the leaves we can clearly see
that here
and also to a less extent but still
prevalent here on the leaf margins here
as well
so that's how you would spot potassium
deficiency but hopefully you catch it
early enough
where if you don't get into this
situation but if you are starting to see
this
you might want to check your potassium
levels because likely
they're going to be deficient in that
nutrient