you were to look at potassium deficiency
in tomatoes we see kind of a great image
here of initial onset of a potassium
deficiency Taylor what potassium does in
the tomato plant and how to correct it
or prevent a potential deficiency in
your plants so first off potassium just
in general what does it do why do plants
need it keep in mind that it is a mobile
nutrient so plants can kind of move or
translocate that through the plant
plants deficient potassium tend to be
less resistant to environmental stresses
diseases nematode attacks this is why
it's important for growers to make sure
their plants are not becoming potassium
deficient in addition that can also
affect quality such as shape the color
the vigor the size of the actual
tomatoes can actually cause a yellow
shouldering as well as we see that kind
of up here activates up to sixty enzymes
involved as growth helps translocate
sugars and starches within the plant
increases protein content maintains
trigger pressure its water pressure
reduces water loss and wilting so you
could see this is involved in a lot of
things most notably as I said for the
marketable fruit a yellow shouldering is
one kind of issue that can occur in that
allow customers to even pick up your
item and to purchase now to better show
a deficiency did I chose to grow tomato
plants in a hydroponic setup in a
greenhouse which allowed for precise
control you're also going to see a
comparison of a control plant that had
the optimum rates of all nutrients and
then a test plant was potassium
deficient so this kind of shows the
image here of the potassium deficient
plant these are the lower leaves they
will start to get a yellowing kind of
color to them towards the margins so we
can see that right here here and here
and these are the older leaves so the
original root stock would be all the way
to the right of the image here and above
me here is kind of the newer growth so
typically those older leaves are
impacted first they will have the first
ones to sharpen it to show this
yellowing or this discoloration so
that's important to keep in mind of
where you might be seeing the yellowing
leaves where they might be occurring for
the older leaves and towards the margins
you may have a potassium deficiency
starting now on our older leaves this
kind of shows that newer part of the
growth as I said they start to get that
yellowing first now the newer growth may
look perfectly fine and normal so keep
that in mind that while they look normal
now if no corrective measures are taken
they will start to exhibit the same
yellowing so it's important to make sure
that you're looking at those older
leaves notice had oh they're older gonna
die anyway this could be a sign of
something progressing through the plant
notice compared to the control plant so
as I said the - potassium to control
notice the newer growth looks very
similar green pattern looks the same but
we do not see that yellowing of the leaf
margins of the older leaves in the
control one that was fed a balanced
fertilizer now how to prevent this or
how to correct the potential deficiency
if you do notice it will keep in mind
potestas important for fruit finishing
in the end yield so it might be
something you might see a little bit
later in the season or past flower fruit
set tends to be needed in eggs in that
more mid to late season sulphate of
potash zero zero fifty is 50 percent
potassium typically applied based on a
soil test has a very low salt level and
only adds potassium so a great product
to choose especially if you can add it
to the soil before the plants go in the
ground
potassium chloride one it's very
commonly used zero zero 61
it's got a greater percentage of
potassium higher percent of that
compared to the sulphate of potash that
I mentioned previously but it does have
more salts with it it's a chloride so
just keep that in mind
kelp used by a lot of organic growers
great source of potassium usually about
a teaspoon of powder or two ounces of
liquid per gallon can be applied to the
leaves it's organic however keep in mind
that while it is a source of potassium
it's nowhere near the 50 or 60 percent
of the two previous products so it's not
really concentrated enough to typically
correct a deficiency so just keep that
in mind it's good to kind of supplement
and keep the plants ongoing but if you
have a deficiency it may take a lot a
lot of kelp a little excessive amounts
of kelp almost at that point to correct
efficiency so just keep that in mind
that wall does have potassium it's not
nearly as concentrated as the other
fertilizers that have mentioned here