on this debaco university video we're
going to explore the potency of cannabis
grown under led
and hps lights based on a scientific
article so this is a debate that
constantly goes on so let's look at some
scientific research and see how this
changes the potency of cannabis
[Music]
all right let's get into this highly
debated subject led versus hps lights so
first off this is the research article
here's the links provided fairly
recently published and so if you want to
go back to the original article here you
go i'm going to kind of break it down
and give you the summary of it here
so first off this is the great debate
hps high pressure sodiums versus led
lights however most people do not
consider this to be a debate they feel
that led lights or nothing this is kind
of the wave of the future these are the
old school methods they only want to
grow under led lights and this is kind
of part of that debate and to some
extent but let's look at it from a
scientific standpoint here
so first off this article compared these
different lights here they had one hps
light the e papillonian 1000 watt double
ended hps and then they had three led
lights that they were looking at in
comparison um comparing here i should
say
this is all the lights part of the study
however after their comparison of the
led lights then there were only two
they kept with the of course high
pressure sodium for comparison and they
kept the fluids bioengineering which is
now known by influenced by osram the
spider
plus led lights the first part of the
study really was geared to evaluating
leading led light manufacturers and
models to identify which option provides
the most uniform distribution of the
light at the leaf
at the leaf and canopy as well as the
important
factor at producing a consistent end
product so they wanted a basically the
best of the best for led lights at least
in their uh
measurements of their data collection
the fluence by osram the spyder x plus
model clearly demonstrate optimum light
distribution photosynthetic response and
also maintain leaf temperature within
the optimum range to achieve maximum
photosynthetic rates so that's why they
chose that one over the others just to
go back for a second for the two others
that were presented here this ultimately
is the led light that they compare to
this high pressure sodium there
so let's get into some of the data here
probably the most interesting part was
figure four in this study all the
cannabis cultivars grown under led
lights yielded an increase of thca
percentage with an average increase of
5.39 percent the mean of 25.06 percent
thca under eight led lights versus only
19.67
under high pressure sodium lights here
so it shows you the potency and provided
that yes led lights does yield a
greater percentage of thca however most
squares would stop here and say throw
out all their ap hps and go with leds
but let's just explore this just a
little bit further
so first off what does this generally
mean to the growers many growers would
think that led lights would yield them
more thca which is when while this study
did show that there are
did show this there are other factors
that must be taken into consideration
with indoor facilities there are other
environmental control factors that need
to be optimized to ensure quality
harvest temperature humidity
regulating that temperature keeping
within tight ranges
the intensity of the light the
area that the light covers there's a lot
of other factors that need to be taken
into consideration
so just don't think that led lights is
going to be your only way to get high
thc a levels in this example now thca in
lighting to break the 30 percent or even
35 percent total thc theoretical barrier
one does not need led lights as this can
be done with high pressure sodium lights
used during flowering so just understand
that 30 is kind of that theoretical
barrier even 35 percent seeing test
results that show
flower that does have higher than 30
percent thc total thc and that is they
are grown under hps light so i think you
have to have led lights led lighting
though can help this but all factors
must be taken into consideration
especially coverage area and related par
readings as well as feeding schedules as
well as
stresses and non-stresses to the
cannabis plant and again to prove these
total amounts we're looking of course at
getting an analytical report a third
party tested so we know exactly what
those values are coming in at
now for the growers general
considerations so just keep this in mind
that sure led light technology may be
the way of the future but at the current
time taking into full cost of initially
purchasing ownership and number of
fixtures needed hps is still price
competitive so keeping that in mind
there's a lot of other factors that can
consideration in a grow facility led
lights led lights do offer the advantage
of being full spectrum at least in some
cases so growers can see the plants in
their true
form basically without the need for any
filtering lenses and there may be some
beneficial wavelengths of the light
produced that can aid in cannabis plants
ability to produce certain compounds at
greater concentrations than grown under
other lighting but this does not mean
hps lights are useless and if available
to growers they should still continue to
utilize them because we have to consider
yes we've got a lot of other factors
we've got some more heat of course with
hps lights but a lot of times to get the
full power reading coverage area of a
thousand watt double ended hps you may
need to purchase more led fixtures so
again that needs to be kept in mind
there as well as the other kind of
changing over of electrical panels we
need to keep all of those various cost
repairs maintenance all in mind when
we're looking at a grow facility
so what's the general take home message
of this article well many companies
produce led lights but in general you
want to live by the motto that good led
lights are not cheap and cheap led
lights are not good hps lights can still
produce quality canvas and for the cost
are worth serious consideration
by more growers i'm not saying that led
lights are bad just look at the full
cost there a lot of people say oh led
lights run
with less wattage
they need less cooling and that may be
true but just keep in mind the mounting
heights as well a lot of times led
lights do need to be closer to the
planes to be effective or if if you
increase that spacing your coverage area
may not be as great so look at the full
picture when considering light changes
but if you have access to hps sites
don't consider them to be a horrible
option they may be a great option for
you to utilize
and may be actually more cost effective
in some cases than led lights