so many labs will provide you with
soil test reports of aluminum and lead
even though it may not be part of
nutrients you're looking for for your
plants
but these two can be potential
contaminants so it's a good idea
to look at those numbers and to realize
what harm they can cause
and what levels are considered high so
this tobacco university video will
hopefully answer some of those questions
so let's get into potential containments
of aluminum and lead in the soil test
report
so first off aluminum is not an
essential plant nutrient
though it's commonly seen in some soils
high levels of aluminum in the soil can
also interfere with plant uptake
of phosphorus and may cause injury of
sensitive plant species like lettuce
and beets as soil ph decreases
the solubility of aluminum increases
it's an inverse relationship here
we could see here there's our aluminum
concentration in parts per million
here's our changing ph
as we become more acidic we're noticing
an increase in the aluminum
concentration here
and typically above fights five parts
per million because they're toxic to
tolerant species
well less than two parts million is
generally considered non-toxic and we
can see just how a simple change
in ph can really impact that
now as i said ph does impact aluminum
this can also be seen
with plants in the degree that they are
able
to produce roots soil test results often
indicate
elevated aluminum levels in soil with ph
levels below
5.0 liming soils which will increase the
ph
to an acceptable level for the crop
being grown will typically reduce the
amount of
aluminum that's available to plants and
that can be a good thing
acid-loving plants like rhododendrons
blueberries azaleas
have high tolerance to soil aluminum
levels so for those plants
perfectly fine however aluminum is also
responsible for the blue color of
hydrangeas
because of its effect on pigmentation
formation
which is why the blue flowering
hydrangeas are grown in
low soil ph levels and here we're seeing
just the example that
ph of 5.1 the 4.0 can have on the root
development
simply because of the alteration in the
availability of aluminum in that soil
now going on to lead so lead is a
naturally occurring element in soils and
typically is present in soils
in the range of about 5 to 100 parts per
million total lead
soil test results indicate an estimation
of the
total lead it's always good to just have
an idea and look at that number
so what how do you determine whether or
not your lead levels are of reason of
concern
well only when total lead levels
typically exceed about 400 parts per
million does a u.s
environmental protection agency the epa
list it as an
element of concern if the lead levels
are elevated you should receive
appropriate information about potential
problems with elevated
lead levels and guarding practices to
minimize exposure to lead
we kind of see just a general example
here of soil lead concentrations
keep in mind as we get above 100 parts
per billion we should be keeping
children out of the garden do not grow
root crops
safe to grow legumes fruiting and leafy
vegetables getting above 400
that's bringing to a lot more
restrictions but even at just above
100 typically want to start to take
caution if you are
seeing lead lead levels above 100 you
may want to contact the lab or see if
the lab is any information
about what might be safe or not safe to
grow there
in the soil lead levels and here we see
another little comparison chart here
interpreting the estimation of total
lead and soils
because there's no federal standards for
soil lead that has been determined for
soils where vegetables
will be grown it is well known that
plants vary in their uptake of soil lead
but generally lead will accumulate in
leafy green tissues
and in plant roots the university of
connecticut soil nutrient analysis
laboratory strongly recommends that
soils containing 400 parts per million
total lead or greater than that number
should not be used for growing
vegetables
herbs or other food crops however even
levels under that there still might be
reason for some concern
typically a hundred and less no real
precautions necessary
but as we get over 100 we start getting
more and more
suggested actions and restrictions
potentially on crops to grow in that
particular soil
so best measurement practices for garden
soil containing lead
well i've got a whole bunch kind of
listed here again you're welcome to
pause the video and take a better look
at it
but generally gardens should be located
away from older painted structures
and heavily traveled roads because there
was once led in
the gasoline and also lead in paint
giving planting preference for fruiting
crops like tomato squash peppers and
soils or elevated
lead bubbles remove outside
leaves of green leafy vegetables peel
the root crops and wash all vegetables
thoroughly to remove soil particles
maintain a soil ph of 6.5 to 7.0 by
applying limestone at recommended rates
because this will reduce the
availability of lead uptaken by the
plants
so again we see that ph being very
important maintain student organic
matter between five and ten percent
organic particles will bind the lead
making it less available to plant uptake
and in general we want to be shooting
for that general five percent
is just a general target 10 is getting
up there but that can help reduce the
availability of lead
maintain soil phosphorus levels by
applying the recommended amounts of
fertilizer to the garden plots
phosphorus can reduce lead uptake by
plants minimize dust and exposure to
bare soil through the use of mulches
wash hands thoroughly after contact of
lead contaminated soils
do not bring food or drinks into the
area with contaminated lead soils
soil and tools gloves shoes have
elevated levels also clean before
storing or bringing indoors
and lastly considered raised beds or
containerized plantings in soils with
elevated lead levels
and i put the resource there at the
bottom for a fact sheet if you want to
learn more
but keep in mind knowing if your soil is
high
in lead you cannot tell by looking you
have to go through and take a soil test
it's highly recommended you do in
general
but also take a look at the lead levels
because that may determine what you can
grow
it's definitely good to know what the
nutrients and ph
are and whether that soil is safe to
grow whatever food crops you're planning
on