okay here I'm gonna explain a little bit
about powdery mildew which we can see
evident right here on the leaves which
is commonly seen sadly in many grow
operations ah because you can spread
quite easily and cause issues in many
grow spaces so first off powdery mildew
it's probably one of the top concerns
for growers and it literally looks like
white powder which is actually mycelium
that can produce spores mycelium once
seen with the naked eye it's an
indication there's much more environment
control measures should be taken this
means is once you see it at this level
if you consider it at the microscopic
level you're not just seeing one small
nice thing I'm you're seeing many many
mycelium on the surface giving us a name
implies that powdered look to the leaves
and that's an indication you're probably
a little late to the game
but you should definitely be employing a
control measure at the first sign now
we're to look well this is mainly found
on the leaves so this is the area you
should be focusing your scouting we want
to look at the most shaded leaves that
are either under one leaf or deeper into
the canopy now it can occur in areas
near the buds but usually it first shows
up that those shaded in sheltered areas
that are away from the light and also
tend to have higher humidity levels it
typically will start also not only on
these leaves but on the underside of
these leaves so you can see here on the
upper end but typically when we're
scouting or searching to threaten those
I see them at the very early stages you
want to turn these leaves over and look
at the undersides because that's tend to
be a little bit more protected and a
little bit more moisture pendent now how
to prevent parry mildew well it thrives
in conditions that are humid to the
point do forming on the leaves an
additional large temperature swings can
encourage the development as a result
you can have a little bit more pressure
in the spring in the fall because of
those temperature fluctuations that
naturally occur the goal prevention is
to maintain a dry leaf surface and avoid
large changes in temperature in your
grow operation and if you're an indoor
you have a little bit more control over
this for outdoor or tunnel production
keep in mind of those fall in spring
times when you're having those wide
changes in tempo terrific and moderate
that they're going to be a way to reduce
and hopefully prevent powdery mildew
formation how to control it will oxidate
as we see here the stabilized
concentrate hydrogen peroxide is good
for a quick spray option to accomplish
the same end goal with much less work so
the advantage here is you're able to
kind of quickly clean the leaves and
hopefully then go through and implement
preventive measures this is a good
product because I mean peroxide doesn't
last very long so the rants of having a
long-term residue is basically vastly
reduced if you're looking for a bit more
stable control milk can actually be used
and that's may sound a little weird or
strange but 40% milk and 60% water whole
milk is preferred due to the fat
spreading it more evenly across the leaf
surface and with the pH change that
occurs with milk with the coating of the
leaf surface this is a great organic way
to try to control powdery mildew
especially once it's seen on the early
stages and while this may not kill the
actual mycelium it definitely slows down
the progression and ideally will prevent
the initial formation of powdery mildew
if you know that you're in a
high-pressure situation