okay here we will get pregnancy
childbirth and development of
individuals so you can gain a greater
appreciation for what occurred early on
in your life starting with the placenta
so this is before you're born you had
this connection to your mother this
connection is the placenta through the
umbilical cord the placenta itself is a
flat and circular organ in the uterus
pregnant mammals it provides nourishment
it maintains the fetus through the
connection of the umbilical cord what's
occurring in this connection is between
the fetus and the mother is carbon
dioxide urea and hormones that are
generated in the fetus of being
exchanged with the mother as a result
the faeces acquiring from the mother
nutrients oxygen antibodies vitamins and
water you see a lot of arteries and
veins here because a lot of nutrient
exchanges that are occurred
reason why it's gaining oxygen from the
mother and giving carbon dioxide the
piece itself can not directly exchange
the gases with the outside world it
needs to have this connection to the
mother to be able to allow that process
to occur now physiological changes for
expecting mothers in their effects
during pregnancy will be variable based
on the individuals however there's some
key areas that will notice a change
because of the unborn child as it grows
and develops one in particular is the GI
tract gastrointestinal tract some
mothers will experience morning sickness
this is due to elevated levels of
estrogen and progesterone urinary system
our urine production --all increase to
handle the additional fetal wastes in
the respiratory system and expect the
expected mother could have shortness of
breath or difficulty breathing
so because her diaphragm may not be able
to fully expand because of the growing
fetus cardiovascular system the mother
will have blood on increase about 25 to
40 percent because of now it's needs to
also exchange the blood of the unborn
child it also be headaches
there can be muscle pain leg pain lower
back pain all these can occur it will
vary with you one mother in another
now stages of childbirth estrogen
reaches peak during the last weeks of
pregnancy this is from the onset of
labor until the cervix is fully dilated
about which is about 10 centimeters
initial contractions are about 15 to 30
minutes apart
and lasts for about ten to thirty
seconds in duration strong contractions
are defined as ones that occur every two
to three minutes and lasts for about one
minute keep in mind this is a child
entire childbirth process is a positive
feedback loop and after the child is
delivered the placenta is delivered
within about thirty minutes of birth and
it termed the afterbirth
so placenta we were talking about looks
like this very read it's highly vascular
occur there's a lot of those nutrients
to be exchanged between the mother and
at the point of being in uterus the
unborn baby now upon birth is an Apgar
score that's given every about one of
the five minutes after birth an infant's
physical status is assessed on these
five characteristics I'm just giving a
quick 0 to 2 score and Apgar score of
about 8 to 10 indicates a healthy baby
lower scores reveal problems so for
example the pulse is taken pulse rate
it's greater than 100 that's giving it
to if it's between 60 but less than 100
is given a 1 it's less than 60 that'd be
a zero at the area for concern but also
be looking at for example activity is
there active movement of the recently
born babies or some fluctuation is there
none and you can see here it's a quick
way to be able to assess the baby's
physical status post al development
babies are typically double in birth
weight within a few months different
body parts grow at different rates it's
in allometric growth what's important is
that early on nerve cells are producing
an average of greater than 250,000 per
minute however at 6 months neuron
production ceases permanently so this is
why it's important you don't damage your
nervous system is beyond 6 months the
nerves cells that you have you'll have
for the rest of your life your body does
not make more or repair connections
lastly of our stages of child
development so we have our infant and
babies defined a zero to two years old
toddlers or preschoolers or two to five
years old these are were meltdowns are
very common it just seemed totally seems
like they always say no you have to
learn how to accept no from others in
this can be a very challenging time
school-age children ages six to twelve
generally are getting more independence
process learning and making good choices
and hopefully in developing or setting
the stage for good life skills at lesson
sir teenagers are 13 18 year old years
old and this is the time that begins
defining oneself and realistically kind
of putting the future and talents become
refined so even though many students
kind of fall in that 13 18 adolescence
through teenager years it seems like
they may have behaviors of toddler or
preschoolers at times even though they
should be focused on kind of
realistically planning for the future
and hopefully I'll be finding their
talents or skills so they can continue
those beyond 18 years old and being able
to develop an interest and carry that on
for the rest of your life in maintaining
that interest