all right so now you've selected that
plant for cloning
and now you've come to tobacco
university to learn how to prepare that
cannabis plant for the cloning process
and that's what we're going to provide
here on this video lecture
[Music]
all right let's get into how to prepare
a cannabis plant for cloning here at
tobacco university
first off the chosen one so once a plant
is chosen the grower should make some
adjustments to help ensure
maximum clone yield from that particular
plant
and keep in mind we're looking at having
a lot of those shoot tips a lot of those
vegetative propagation points to allow
multiple
clones to be generated from that
original plant
so younger plants typically are easier
to clone so if you have a choice between
a younger and older plant
typically the younger plant would be
preferred however oftentimes it's not
until the harvest time that
plant's full potential is actually
realized and that's when the grower
determines
they want to go through and clone that
plant once it's identified the chosen
plant should be placed in a vegetative
light cycle
of about 18 to 20 hours of a continuous
light
if the plant was in active flowering
stage this will delay the transition
back
to the vegetative stage so again for
timing purposes
as growers just keep that in mind
now when we're up potting the plant here
so again we have our chosen plant we're
going to go through this kind of general
up potting
process well since a plant for cloning
will be
a mother or stock plant many growers
elect to put the plant into larger
containers
to reduce the overall stress and allow
the plant to get larger
so again this could be at any stage
typically we'll have a
soilless medias we see here put the
original container in there so we know
it's going to be a good fit
to allow good soil or media contact with
the roots
to ensure that there's no air pockets
there to cause drying want to have that
root transition to the larger pot very
easily this is a good little technique
to go through when you're up potting
that original plant
now the pruning method that you're
choosing to use may have to change
compared to the original once you
determine that plant that you're going
to go through this process with
the goal for a plant to be cloned is to
produce many branches as possible
so often this may lead to different
methods of pruning might be implemented
because now your goal is to create as
many little branch points as possible
and not necessarily grow a plant to
produce the maximum number of buds
we want to have definitely a lot of
branches want to be selective with our
pruning method selective with our
method that we go through to help
maximize the number of clones
we can get off a single plant the
fertilizers to use
so while you want to keep the plant
healthy do not over feed it as this will
make the cloning or rooting process
much more of a challenge this is
particularly important in the case of
nitrogen
so whatever night or whatever nutrients
you might be adding look at the
kind of levels it's good always yes to
fertilize but be mindful in particular
of nitrogen if you over nitrogen feed a
plant it'll grow
very quickly but it'll become kind of
spacey internet spacing wise
and it will be much harder to root
so keep that in mind also you want to be
scouting for
pests keep the plant healthy is very
important i just have a couple insects
listed here
this also pertains to disease this also
pertains to light stress nutrient stress
water stress
all things to take into consideration
and to make sure that you're having
those
at a very stable levels so you're not
stressing the plant out
also you want to shift the plant to an
isolated location the goal is to keep
the plant
in isolated area to limit the chance of
contamination with other plants that you
may have
and this is where a grow tent can be a
great environment to help isolate that
plant
to allow you to do certain things to
that plant to help maximize again the
ability for it to be cloned that might
require a slightly different environment
or conditions
that you're growing your other plants in
so grow tent in this case if you're only
doing one plant
it's a great option otherwise an
isolated room would be an option for
larger scale growers