welcome to this debaco university
student series video we're going to see
preparing a growing area in easy cloner
before plant material is harvested so
it's important to get everything all set
up ahead of time before you go out and
harvest the plants you know that's the
fun part because you want to make sure
everything's mechanically working and
ready for your clones
[Music]
all right so we're looking at this
student series video here looking at
preparing the growing area just to give
you a little background information if
you will this was the general starting
material and we could see there's a
hodgepodge of items here so the goal for
kiara was to turn this collection
materials into a functional cloner once
this test was achieved then plant
material could be collected and that
will be on a separate video remember
it's important to get everything
mechanically checked and working
properly then dial in nutrient
concentrations followed by ph once this
is achieved you can go get the plants
once you cut your plants you want to be
having the least amount of time before
they enter the cloner so let's see how
keira went about setting up this
collection of materials to get the area
ready for the soon to be cut clones so
far we only started out with just the
table and our light support so we had to
go out and make sure all of our area
were sanitized so we wiped down both the
top and the bottom and the surrounding
areas to make sure it's all sanitized
and clean ready to go for our plants so
that there's no cross-contamination
we then hung our light ballasts up onto
the light support and connected them to
each of our lights of course had to
individually go through and plug each of
them in but each light is different
we're using fluence led lights we made
sure to have them
evenly spread out so that all of our
plants can get an even amount of light
if that doesn't happen then of course
you're going to have weaker plants which
we don't want we have one high and we
have one low just because we don't know
exactly how tall our cloner is going to
be yet how far they're going to need to
be from the light so that's why we have
them adjusted differently that's the
good thing about the ratchet light
hangers because they're adjustable so
depending on how the plant is growing
you can move them accordingly
now we're at the stage where we would
test out the light before we actually
you know get everything set up
and it looks like they're working
perfectly so now this is the step where
we would grab our cloner and start
setting it up on the table
after we're done setting up our lights
we're going to set up our easy cloner so
the first step to do that is to fill it
with as much water as required this one
i'd say takes about 10 gallons but
before we do we want to take the tap
water that we are planning to use
anyways and test it using our guardian
meter this reads for conductivity ph and
temperature
like i said before this water is
straight out of the tap so our
conductivity is reading low at 120 quite
the opposite for the ph it's reading a
little high at 8.1 so for what we're
going to do first is adjust our
conductivity with our clonex grow
solution
this will help us adjust our
conductivity to be raised higher the
reason that we would choose to do the
conductivity before the ph is that the
this solution has a direct impact on our
ph so while we're trying to massively
change our conductivity from 200
somewhere up to 600 we're just dialing
in very slightly with the ph up and down
just a few so like i said just make sure
we go into our next step first of all
adjusting the conductivity
before we go about adjusting anything
with the water we want to make sure that
it's at a proper level so that our
aeroponics filter actually works we
wouldn't want it to be too high or too
low so that nothing is really working as
it should this wants to spray up at the
bottom of the plants so that each of the
roots get
them the nutrients that they need given
up to them and if the water level isn't
correct then this won't function
correctly we just tested it and it works
properly you could see this because all
of it's dripping as it should be if it
wasn't then we would have to adjust the
water level higher or lower before
adding nutrients to make sure it's at
the proper level
so now we need to raise our conductivity
levels and lower our ph so in order to
do this we're going to add our clonex
clone solution
the bottle recommends adding
5 to 10 milliliters per each liter of
water so i have my recommended amount
pre-ready to go
i'm just going to add that slowly in
and we're just going to wait a little
bit to see how it adjusts the
conductivity after that we can go in
with our ph up and down and fix the ph
so now we just wait
so as you can see
our p our conductivity has raised to 770
which is the perfect level and our ph is
at a 6.6 which again is right in the
middle of where we want it to be
you