okay here I look at preparing and
selecting clones image here was not
chosen by accident all these are females
and silhouettes because when we're
selecting clones
I want to be selecting an outstanding
female plant for its high cannabinoid
production so hooda clone will starting
out with easy plant such as tomatoes
prison Thea's the practice on might be a
good initial plan to start with the goal
is to clone a unique individual with
desirable traits to ensure the entire
planting of superior individuals is
obtained so as I say start with the
tomatoes or person theists are really
easy and they can help you refine your
techniques before you go on to canvas or
other crops the reason why I want to
select that unique individual is you
want to capture like lightning in a
bottle so you can replicate that one
particular unique individual
so you've up a whole crop of those can
you clone auto file although flowering
plants well yes but just because you can
do it doesn't mean you should you want
to avoid auto flowering plants root
Alice in particular is the cultivar
subset I since these will produce poor
quality plants due to the natural life
cycle not being easily extended into the
cloning process so typically we're
looking at non auto flowering plants
being advantageous to clone and trying
to avoid the auto flowering ones but it
is possible
ideal time for cloning in actuality any
plant can be clinic any stage of growth
and development but there are more
ordeal times to mechanized production
and efficiency the ideal time is when
the mother or stock plant is about at
least one month old we don't want to go
much younger than that the school is to
ensure that the traits you want are
expressed and provide plant time to
produce many branches to allow for easy
cloning cloning to early you will simply
get enough offspring off that initial
stock or mother plant preparing mother
plants for cloning the stock plant has
been fed less nitrogen will help the
today's produce roots faster over
feeding may produce nice lush growth
vegetative growth in particular but will
increase the time it takes for that
cutting to actually root ideally the
mother plant should be in the vegetative
stage to reduce rooting time and provide
clones that will not potentially flower
early so if we have a mother plant
already flowering will cause a delay in
production since the cuttings must go
kind of
backwards in the vegetative state before
they then reflowed
so again another plant least a
one-month-old in a vegetative state is
the ideal candidate for a lesser mother
plant or stock plant I want to avoid
those high nitrogen's even though they
do produce those deep green robust look
to a plants because canvas can what's
called a luxury consume which means they
can take in more than the plant needs in
that mention result and delay in the
production of roots and also the root
quality might be poor there's a fine
line between too much and too little
nitrogen so when in doubt I suggested to
under feed because you can always add a
little bit more it's very difficult to
take away selection tip when selecting
that unique individual with renewable
states for replication you want to pick
out that one special plant cloning just
an average plant will result in average
offspring you want to multiply a plant
that is unique and can be difficult to
find when looking at natural plant
select the stem that is still useful but
nearing maturation to help reduce
rooting time now say select that unique
individual it's very easy in this case
to select unique individual but here we
have this field of sunflowers might be a
little more difficult so it could be a
slightly taller plant the one producing
more petals could be one that flowers
earlier instead of later so there's
different nuances you want to take into
consideration with a larger population
you're more likely to find one unique
individual they're not always as
clear-cut as this but the reason why you
want to select that one individual is
your immigrant a lot of these plants it
was just average well that maybe you can
get from other means plant material that
is not ideal for clones while older
plant material will be slow to root and
may have poor overall root production
and should not be the first go-to
material that's all that you have by all
means use it very young material may
also not be able to support itself
through the stressful cloning process so
you kind of want that nice in between
that the two young not the too old to
allow for increased odds of success in
your clones taking root storing clones
in general I don't recommend it however
if you're transporting plant material
taking fresh cuttings should be placed
in a plastic bag it's been like misted
with water in place about 40 degrees
we're trying to hold them rooting gel
can be applied when we first take
then but that can get very messy and our
bag so if you take the cuttings to apply
the rooting hormone and put them in some
sort of plug and store the plugs that
could be a way to try to reduce the
stress on that militating cutting that
routing gel initially placed in this
situation just causes a mess if they're
not directly placed in the media there
so again we want to try to cut them and
get them into the environment as quickly
as possible some of this is that may not
always be the case you can hold them for
a little bit but you want to really
reduce that duration clone harvest to
flower harvest it takes about three
months from a cutting clone to
harvesting flowers again I can vary a
little bit this means you want to aim
for always having about 1/3 of plants in
a vegetative state two-thirds in a
flowering state this will allow you that
continual harvest and kind of allowing
plants to always come in the flower I
always have a plan for meditative ready
place those always ready to take some
clones have a stock mother plants so it
takes a lot of coordination when it does
you can have a nice continual harvest