welcome to another debaco university
video here we're going to be looking at
presumptive
and confirmatory testing for drugs
presumptive tests are the ones that are
going to be used initially on site
confirmatory is going to identify the
specific substance and typically
performed
in a lab setting so initially those
presumptive testing
as i said typically initiated by law
enforcement or those first on the scene
and they indicate if the suspected
substance is present or not present
test kit will typically produce a
positive indicating color if the
substance is present we see right next
to me here
a testing reagent for ecstasy then
laboratory testing that confirms with
certainty the presence of the suspected
substance
would be performed later and just as a
side note that presumptive testing can
also be performed at a laboratory
setting
as part of the analysis process to at
least determine or justify
what further tests should be carried out
and here we're looking at the
presumptive test for the
dukinoi reagent now the duke noise
reagent
is a positive test or we'll be testing
samples of
suspected marijuana or a thc
the duke noise test is conducted by
placing a small sample
of the suspected material about the size
of the tip of a typical pocket knife to
give you an idea
inside a test vial as we see here in the
image above me
the deep blue purple tint of the liquid
indicates
inside the vial indicates the test was
positive
for the cannabinoids present in the
sample
other thc containing drugs such as
marijuana hash oil
and others will produce a light blue to
dark purple reaction
using the duke noise reagent test so
again this is just
one example of a presumptive test
now this confirmatory test that i was
mentioning earlier confirmatory tests
use instrumental analysis to positively
identify the con
the contents of submitted material
typically it's a multi-step process to
separate out
individual components and compounds the
process determines the chemical
characteristics of the compounds to be
compared
to reference materials the goal is to
make a positive identification
in this qualitative analysis and helps
determine what substances
are present and if one or more of those
substances is illegal
the reason why this is typically done at
a laboratory settings because it has a
high degree of
specificity so we want to be sure we're
being very clean
very sterile and isolating we're getting
to identify the actual chemical profiles
versus a presumptive test or kind of
like an up down positive negative a
general idea
and then we'd identify those specific
substances
with this confirmatory test performed in
a laboratory setting