okay here we're going to be looking at
the three primary nutrients now the
reason why I have the picture here is
typically these three primary nutrients
are ones that were going to be kind of
rescuing the plant with it could be
feeding the plant and our ones that if
they show a deficiency would be the
first we would go through and add or at
least rule out if it's not the nutrient
deficiency that we notice first one
being nitrogen so we're looking at a
fertilizer value the three numbers that
are indicated there are nitrogen
phosphorus and potassium nitrogen is a
key component of proteins and
chlorophyll both which are involved in
the synthesis and transfer of energy
it helps plants with rapid growth of
leaves it gives that merkon that
satisfaction of adding fertilizer and
seeing the plant grow nitrogen often
comes from fertilizer applications and
can be fixed from the air by legumes and
also some soil bacteria however while
gives that nice rapid growth of leaves I
caution you because over-application can
cause plants to have long Internode's
brittle dark green leaves it can be
difficult to route when cuttings are
taken we see here with the giant pumpkin
the example what it looks like a plant
that is overfed and nitrogen get these
kind of bloated dark green leaves these
really long stretch stretch to the
stalks here and also get some splitting
that can occur all these are negative
effects of adding too much nitrogen now
phosphorus is an essential part of the
process also for photosynthesis it's a
critical component of DNA as we see here
in that sugar backbone it encourages
root growth and blooming and it's
typically added if you see a bloom
fertilizer typically it'll have a lot
more elevated levels of phosphorous in
it also comes in fertilizer it's the
middle number keep in mind and it's also
present in manures if you over add
manures while there are great organic
source of nutrients a lot of times you
can over add your phosphorus I have the
match stick here because there's
phosphorous in the area where you strike
it against the box of the mattress some
sort of rough and surface
last one is potassium as our primary
nutrient it's absorbed by plants in
larger amounts in other mineral elements
except nitrogen in some cases calcium I
can see here being added in very large
bags to be spread on a field potassium
is supplied by plants by soil minerals
organic materials and also fertilizer
it's involved with carbohydrate
metabolism fruit from
and disease resistance as you're getting
later in season typically potassium
demands will increase in the plant I
just remind you that potassium is
represented by the letter K phosphorus
by the letter P keep those straight and
try not to get those confused a lot of
students will mix up potassium and
phosphorus