okay here we go look at primary and
secondary immune responses and this
graph here on the title slide bruce's a
good summary so our concentration of
antibodies here on the y-axis in time on
the x-axis with our initial exposure and
we see our response immune response is
actually quite low the primary immune
response is a low affinity of antibodies
we do have a recognition over time we do
have an increase in the concentration of
antibodies and ideal it clears up the
problem and then the problem goes away
and our antibodies reduced in
concentration however we notice here at
the lowest point this not near the low
rate of initial exposure we do notice
here at this particular point we have a
secondary exposure to this same initial
threat to the the body so the immune
system becomes activated we see becomes
activated a much shorter period of time
and it increased concentration of
antibodies this is because we have a
high affinity of antibodies able to bind
very efficiently and after the disease
is gone vitamin taken care of we see the
decrease again but we noticed that our
secondary response is much greater and
it takes a lot less time so looking at
this a little bit more specifically in
industry that's a little confusing here
with all different colors the primary
response is the first encounter with a
foreign antigen there's only a few B
cells and T cells that can recognize
this antigen as a result binding of an
integer to its receptor on the
lymphocytes stimulates cell division the
clones produced and this is called
clonal selection now we're looking here
at this different graph our relative
level to antibodies in some cases and we
have our days of infection here on the x
axis so we see some of these are
antibodies IgH sound familiar
IgG sounds familiar we also have natural
killer cells neutrophils so this is not
relative level of antibodies that we saw
in the first one this is just relative
level of immune response and we can see
our innate immune system occurs you need
early stages and then our adaptive it
takes over later that gives us more that
long-range control and memory IgA ABC
has a long delay and it comes up our cd4
t-cells occur
over time IgG is very quick early on and
then tapers off in plateaus here looking
at a very simple graph here antibody
concentration our first sex scene or
infection we have our increase decreases
to a point but keep in mind where that X
is our secondary point of infection
occurs it's not anywhere near as low as
the first time we see a decrease
interation and an increase in our
antibody concentration this second time
around
continuing on how this looks specific to
IgM and IgG if you look at the antibody
lecture you'll see reference to these
don't provide a little bit more detail
on each of these well compared to the
primary response the secondary antibody
response occurs more quickly and
produces antibody levels that are higher
and more sustained the secondary
response mostly lives IgG so notice our
primary and our secondary both have IgM
involved both have IgG involved but by
far the secondary ones mostly involves
the IUD we see that rapid rapid increase
and that much higher level antibody
concentration of IgG the second time
around then that first time well we
still notice in both cases IgM is first
initiate while IgG and the secondary
times is a very important component
types of acquired immunity so we have
our acquired immunity there's two main
forms we have active where organisms has
their own kind of educated cells we have
passive where organisms acquire only the
antibodies from another source so our
natural acquired an artificially
acquired well the active were cells it
educated here could be a vaccine dead or
in attenuated pathogens then we also
have our passive which is an injection
of immune serum this is two different
types we can get artificially acquired
immunity naturally acquired immunity
through the active process is infection
contact with the pathogen this is where
we actually get sick a passive version
of naturally acquired our antibodies
passed from mother to fetus via the
placenta or infant in her milk it's a
passive way of occurring as antibodies
particularly for cows it's very
important very soon after birth
that they're fed the mother's milk
because that can help get antibodies to
cross over the barrier so they become
part of the individual if you missed
that only about one two-hour window of
colostrum is the actual mother's milk on
the earlier stages the antibodies will
not be able to pass the barrier and that
individual can easily become sick it has
to go through the active process which
can be very dangerous so a passive is
that simple passing of the antibodies
lastly our summary of how the immune
response works we have our immunity
innate immune system remember this could
be physical barriers and our adaptive
immunity we have both artificial which
in the antibody transfer in immunization
or natural which is passive through the
maternal mother's milk example or
through the placenta and active through
actually getting sick through the point
of infection so hopefully that clears up
and gives you a little bit more detail
of both primary and our secondary immune
responses