okay here a look at some probiotic
editions commonly added to soil or to
plants to help protect them mycorrhizae
is this perilla root shield and
actinovate are some common ones we also
see this evident in like yogurts this
year so eager where see the use of
probiotics too so that there's some
beneficial microbes in this particular
product that has live cultures so first
off probiotics are beneficial microbes
adding microbes or life to your soil
some companies sell blend sbrick and get
a wide mix of microbes with one
application
other companies favor mono species by
trying to match a species with a
particular purpose so again you have to
look at some of the labels and some of
the of what they include so looking at
mycorrhizae for example this helps
increase root to soil surface area
interaction works best when plants are
grown in stressful conditions and
there's two different types of
mycorrhizae there's endo mycorrhizal
fungi which grows within the roots and
can form symbiotic relationships with
about 85% of terrestrial plant species
African missus is kind of what Chilton
41 endo mycorrhizal fungi species
ectopic arezzo fungi live on the outside
of root cells and they're mainly form
relationships with conifers and other
hardwoods there remember that canvas is
an annual just want to be focusing here
on the endo mycorrhizal also your
Tomatoes your squash pepper plants can
also associate with endemic arise alumni
it's a semantic relationship that works
because the fungi provides increased
soil contact with the roots to benefit
the host plant so it's kind of this
inter relationship so the fungus here is
providing this increased web increased
interaction with the soil as in return
the fungi is able to get sugars from the
plant which is made in the upper leaf
structures so again this is kind of that
symbiotic relationship between these two
thumbs provides increased surface area
plant provides of sugars Aizaz beryllium
policier is a nitrogen fixing bacteria
it's often used in the early stages of
plant development so keep in mind that
this is a warm weather derived species
so apply it in cold soils wild little
benefit with bacteria
they can go through this very quick
exponential phase as temperature
increases and make sure they provide
with enough food and resources otherwise
we'll go through a very quick death day
it's quick to rise quick to fall I'm so
again in soil environments
this is typically associated with root
structures and again it will increase
with heat and heat of the soil so be
mindful of that that applying at the
cold soils will do a little good there's
also a product called root shield
Buechele plus it's made by Bioworks it
contains two active ingredients two
different strains of trichoderma Nickell
colonizes plant roots to help reduce the
chance of infection by a pathogen
these are granular in a winnable powder
the Grail is preferred due to the longer
shelf life in ease of application like
very very fine sand the wettable powder
cannot be run through drip irrigation
systems and has a shorter shelf life so
while they both have the same end our
active ingredient same end result the
grain there can be preferred simply
because of its longer shelf life it can
be easily mix into growing media lastly
we've act at innovate made by the
valiant it came to this streptomyces
particular microbe in it it does have
some supporting scientific documentation
swearing the ability to suppress disease
and can we run through drip irrigation
systems so this is kind of an
advantageous this particular fungus and
it's all of these can be very expensive
so you have to be mindful where they're
being used but I just want to give you
some ideas that some very common
probiotics that should be potentially
considered if you're having a problem
and you want to approach it in a
biological way