I have yet to find a farm that is free
of problems but what separates some of
the more successful farms from the less
successful ones is how they manage for
problems and while you can't plan for
everything some things can be managed
for sometimes you can have a plan in
place to help reduce the problems or the
impact that it may have in your
operation so this competitors planning
ahead for some of the common or expected
problems I see here we got pari mildew
on squash late and early Blanton
Tomatoes leaf hoppers on potatoes I'll
remember there's more than just disease
issues to consider we're not thinking
about insects when I think about some
other impacts that could happen such as
staking and wind or weather related
things animals so there's more than just
disease issues that we need to plan for
plating head for the some common
expected problems I said squash and
powdery mildew almost a guarantee you're
gonna get that especially later in the
season at fruit set Tomatoes early
blight for sure hopefully not late
blight irrigation in some instances for
certain fields potatoes have the leaf
hoppers carrots for growing carrots
you're doing some form of weeding what
we're gonna have in place these flame
weeding you're gonna use solarization
gonna handpick what are gonna go through
and do broccoli animals to get the
woodchucks and as I show here you know
this doesn't relate to exactly to
growing but when it snows are you ready
with a snow blower do you have chains to
go on the tires are you plan planning
ahead for this you don't want to have it
snow and then realize that you've never
seen snow before again an idea and place
it in the equipment ready to go problems
and general solutions again this is just
a quick kind of one-hit summary here if
you have a fungus problem you use
fungicides bacteria bacteria sides virus
you want to use vector prevention
typically viruses come in with insects
want to prevent the insects new
treatment balance when I do a soil test
you can have an idea what's low what's
high water no your field where's the wet
spots where the dry spots insects
there's many options with those animals
usually a physical barrier works the
best environmental there's only so much
you can do and grower error look in the
mirror for who to blame you can make a
mistake
can only make it once for disease
management prevention is step one if
you're going to apply a corrective spray
read the label there's chemical and
organic options for spray products
regardless rotations need to be
considered whether using organic or
chemical means
I love Benjamin Franklin's quote here an
ounce of prevention is worth a pound of
cure if you can try to prevent the
disease from occurring with may be
increasing plant spacing so there's more
air circulation planting not where
there's a wet portion of the field it
can really save you a lot later in the
season for insect management they send
their Holly variable with a lack in size
they coming up for in numbers this is a
little leaf hopper very very small
insect and this is a field I visited
with potatoes you could see this is
advanced advanced severe I would call
hopper burned but the leaf hoppers doing
this major damage to this crop how every
loss of potatoes growing here not too
far over really haven't touched these
crops still potatoes so different
varieties can it be favorited by some
insects versus others apply the physical
barriers a great way really the only
form of 100% control for insects you're
separating that with basically a screen
assuming there's a good seal with the
ground and the winds not blowing it up
there's also no tears in it so while it
does work a hundred percent then it's if
it's a hundred percent installed and
properly and 100% functional you don't
to have a tear in it and have the
insects get in and then be trapped on
the inside and God's actually a worse
situation also for insects we want to
consider good bugs
there's beneficial insects that do show
promise but timing is important for
releasing them we want to also provide
habitat and find a proper match that's
important for these beneficial insects
some are very specific which is great I
can buy them in various places online we
want to get them shipped at the right
time and you want to release them and
ensure you have a good environment for
those particular insects so they can be
able to survive and seek out some of the
bad bugs that you may have you can also
plan to trap crop so this is where the
perimeter play
you have that trial copy of your main
crop on the inside when I plant a
variety of crop that's favored by the
target insect I'd be on the outside
for example squash bugs like Blue
Hubbard squash in the some other
different types of squash varieties are
very good selections to make I suggested
though over here suggest that you start
about three weeks prior to the planting
of your summer squash winter squash
cucumber cantaloupe or watermelon so
timing again we went with the trap
cop-out early so that the insects find
that it's a little bit more mature and
that's what you're going to monitor and
that can really reduce the impact on
your main crop because you're able to
control the insects or monitor if the
insects at the perimeter and it could
prevent them from getting to your main
crop or basically not spraying your main
crop you could be only spraying your
trap crop and many different options to
consider regardless so timing is
important timing the plant that can
influence pressure when you're planting
early or late also want to consider your
neighbors what their timing may be as
far as planting and someone goes in
really early that can increase insect
pressure potentially or really late in
the season
certain diseases could potentially come
over on earlier earlier or later
plantings it's like the baseball player
here timing is important to hit the ball
internal combustion engines timing is a
big deal also and that is really putting
this all together and getting the timing
right and make it really easier as you
go through the season but if you miss
your timing or don't plan properly you
can be fighting that and get very
frustrated so hopefully this helps you
develop at least a little bit of an idea
and put that plan together with the time
frame and you can be more successful as
you grow this year and into next year