here we're gonna learn about some
problems of the nervous system that you
either may have sadly been familiar
yourself or know someone that may have
had one of these this kind of occurs
when the nervous system doesn't work
100% right we're starting with the first
one very common for people playing
sports or concussions the temporary
disturbance of the brain's ability to
function and due to a hard blow to the
head so what's happening here is in this
case we have the head reaching a nice
hard object here and as traumatic brain
injury changes the way the brain
functions is soft tissue that the brain
is made of causing the brain to jolt
forward ultimately causes a shift in the
brain and it can cause injury to occur
this injury could be very minimal
bruising or very minimal swelling
tearing the blood vessels but if it's
pretty intense this can lead to greater
and greater concern so most concussions
are mild and can be treated with
appropriate care but if it's a severe in
cushon this is why there's concussions
protocols and a lot of sporting events
now it's a severe concussion it can
cause a longer term effects it's left
untreated some of games that are
associated with concussions and
particularly as footballs being number
one
this shows football leads the way and
high school concussions other sports
pose risk as well below are the rates of
concussions per at the per hundred
thousand games and practices nationally
so footballs the highest boys hockey
boys ice hockey star next highest
followed by boys lacrosse holiday girls
lacrosse girls soccer boys wrestling and
girls field hockey with Mike footballs
typically such high it's a very contact
oriented sport and there's a lot of that
abrupt stopping here so tackling that
occurs as a result they've tried to
design helmets and put protocols in
place to reduce the occurrence and the
impact of concussions have on players
paralysis is another form it's a loss of
sensation in movement of part of the
body due to an injury the spinal cord or
brain keeping the mind the higher the
damage occurs on the spinal cord the
greater amount of impact it will have on
the body if it's lower
in the spinal cord here lower parts of
the body would be affected high occurs
in the spinal cord if you think about it
from that point on South is where the
paralysis could occur this is why for
especially for car accidents want to
maintain especially this upper portion
as intact as possible because the higher
up that damage occurs the more of that
body that will be affected Parkinson's
disease is when the brain doesn't
produce enough of the neurotransmitter
that transmits messages from the brain
to muscles so symptoms are tremors rigid
muscles shuffle walking and loss of
facial expression see here a healthy
brain a Parkinson's selling affected
brain we see the reduction in any amount
of neurotransmitters being produced keep
in mind
normal neuron would produce this many
Elan for normal movement here's a person
affected with Parkinson's disease we see
our dopamine produces much reduced even
though the number of receptors are the
same simply having a reduced amount of
dopamine reduces the amount of receiving
of that signal causing a poor movement
of the person's muscles continuing on we
have Alzheimer's disease this is a
gradual shrinking of the neurons in the
cerebrum this can cause memory loss
emotional disturbances in inability to
function its own and ultimately sadly
death by the body simply does not being
able to make those necessary connections
to produce vital bodily functions
epilepsy is another one this is an
abrupt transmission of a message between
the neurons and the brain sorry had
abnormal transmission of messages
between the neurons in the brain
this can be abrupt in the sense that a
seizure could occur in part or the
entire part of the brain here we see a
partial seizure this is normal EEG
levels normal brain activity the partial
seizures that increase them out
generalized seizure grandmom's where the
whole brain kind of goes through this
mutated massive elevated signal levels
throughout the entire brain this would
be called epilepsy
well I'll see those at least that we're
going to discuss here our multiple
sclerosis or tay-sachs disease these
both result from a digit generation
of the myelin sheath located in neurons
now these myelin sheets offer of
protection notice that there's this
electricity transfers here not having
protected the single kind of dies out
here the signals being able to jump and
move a lot quicker this breakdown of the
myelin sheath is what's reducing the
signal I'm reducing that signal is
causing all sorts of potential symptoms
be everything from cognitive impairment
to simple pain to not having our organs
function properly all this is because of
a loss of the neurons ability to
transfer signals