okay here I'm gonna go over the basic
steps to process information in a
scientific sense so first part there's
kind of five major categories are steps
to observe you want to explain those
observations hypothesis testing we find
hypothesis repeat is necessary and then
communicate findings while they are
steps I don't want to think this reaches
a significant or set end point it does
kind of represent more of these circles
a good way to think about it where you
are necessarily may be repeating the
results of necessary anything get to the
end that may generate more questions
that require more observations at
quarter to explain those and around and
around it goes now observations do not
assume when you're observing just
document which you may see use your
senses when possible typically in
science labs taste is not used but you
can look at what you see which you may
hear which you may feel and I say do not
make assumptions because here we're
looking at for observing through these
cameras you may not see something that's
very close for example this pigeon sit
in there here don't assume that this cat
can simply attack this mouse there could
be a piece of glass between those two
looking at explain our observations
while not late always wait you mean well
you may not be always able to get to an
answer it can help generate or start the
thought process so developing kind of
sequence of things seeing other things
may connect trying to problem-solve
experience you may see bring maybe
others in initially for ideas are all
good ways to try to develop that initial
explanation of your observations cues -
hypothesis testing well how about
testing is used of stats to determine
the probability of a given hypothesis
being true or not if you perform it
correctly there's actually four steps
through this that can use statistical
software so step one formulate the null
hypothesis and alternate hypothesis null
indicates that there's no significant
differences between trial groups and it
can also be thought of occurring by pure
chance as this look like in an example
if I'm determining a fertilizer will
make a plant grow better the null
hypothesis would say the fertilizer will
not make the plant grow better in
contrast to that the alternate
observations will show real effects
meaning the fertilizer will
make the plants grow better ah step two
is using a statistical test to determine
whether or not the null hypothesis will
hold true
there's the main different types here if
you take this deaths course you'll get
into them in more detail binomial test
one sample t-test chi-square test
one-way Nova's things like that these
are all tests that are used to help
determine the likely or unlikely hood of
a result being true now step three is
during a p-value and it's a number
between zero and one that helps
determine the significance of the
results the smaller the p-value the
stronger the evidence against the null
hypothesis so what this means is that we
have a p-value of 0.05 that would mean
95% chance that the results are against
the null hypothesis means only a 5%
chance of there being an error that's
why it's important of a very small value
and while we meet mean of calculating
this we're gonna understand this because
we may be looking at data or other
people's results and they typically will
include a p-value so once you know what
that means
step 4 is when you have that p-value
you're comparing to the acceptable the
significant value sometimes called the
Alpha value it's it statistically
significant the null hypothesis is ruled
out and the alternate hypothesis is
determined to be valid so going back
again to our example fertilizer making
plants grow better if we fall in this
range fail to reject the null hypothesis
this would mean likely the fertilizer
did not make any significant difference
here we're looking at the four above
that critical value looking at well
maybe that fertilizer in this case did
make a difference compared to our
control group so again null hypothesis
is this simply for leisure will not make
the plants grow better and if we have
enough data to support it
we may show results where that 4-letter
did not change anything but if we have
that p-value indicating the results are
probably not by a chance indicating well
we have a big enough sample size and
more grew better that can cause us to
reject that null hypothesis and
therefore it is accept our alternate and
when we're finding the hypothesis if
needed consider other sources in areas
of investigation
so it's not too late to change your
hypothesis you know when you're looking
at something other doors might be
opening I'm going to be fine that you
might want to look at potentially other
options as you get more data they want
to repeat the process if necessary it's
why it's important to kind of think of
this as it's circle even if you do get
to the end often the initial ideas do
not pan out so maybe necessary go
through the steps with new information
and develop a more refined thought
process there and you want to
communicate those findings so it's
important to communicate your findings
to others this can be officially in a
court setting or publications or
informally at like a local level tilaka
both oral and written reports are
required at the end written reports at
Pala standard scientific guidelines it
should be included introduction vector
information methods results discussion
and also recommendations these are great
ways to kind of build that community
take other people's ideas and continue
to work with