many times you hear the importance of
scouting your plants
well here i want to go through on this
debaco university video
provide you with the procedure to how
properly to go about scouting your
cannabis plants for any potential
problems so you can catch them early
and implement control measures before
the problem gets out of hand
[Music]
all right let's go over the procedure
for scouting cannabis plants for
potential problems
so know what the normal looks like this
is an important very first step what
should your plants
look like this pertains to the obvious
above ground portions of the plant
but do not also forget about the below
ground portions of the plant
they may say oh yeah the leaves need to
be green well some cultivars some
varieties
might have a lighter green coloration
might have more anthocyanins more purple
coloration
so just keep in mind to know what the
normal for your particular
plant that you're growing what it looks
like so you know if things are outside
of what the normal is expected to be
also know what is common well and this
is before you go and inspect
know what you're likely to find keep an
open eye but there can be some expected
issues as plants age and in the
particular growing environment
for example if you're late in the season
in the fall outdoor growing or even
indoor growing
powdery mildew might be of increased
odds
so things to consider of know what to
expect but also
expect as always the unexpected
no one is hot this year so for example
every year there's a certain disease or
an insect that might be
very prevalent particularly for outdoor
locations try to get an
idea what others might be seeing this
will help provide some hints on what you
should be
especially on the lookout for that
particular year and i still people
in the at the end of the year i can
always tell you what we should have been
looking out for but each year
there's always seems like there's
something that is hot that year
something that is really prevalent that
year and it could be based on weather
or weather patterns temperature things
like that
and this leads us to the disease
triangle so understanding this you need
to have the pathogen present
you need to have the environment you
have the host plant and they need
all three need to interact for a period
of time to get disease
now the pathogen can be fungus bacterium
or virus the environment
is going to be what conditions are
favorable for disease development you
need a host which is a plant that can
get sick
and you need you need that disease
triangle then they all interact with one
another
if you only have two of them you run the
risk of having that
but when you have all three come
together that's we get the full-blown
disease or
issue and that's you're trying to break
the sides of the triangle here to
prevent your plants
from expressing that particular disease
so what's some basic list of equipment
that you need to go through when you go
through scouting
well a map if you're inspecting large
areas or
multiple fields pen or pencil and paper
to write down any notes you see
hand lens for inspecting uh for
potential small insects or looking at
really detailed things
pocket knife potentially cutting into
plant portions bags if you're going to
be collecting samples
and a camera now if you have other
equipment all the better for example a
lot some growers are usually using
drones for very scouting very large
areas
that would be a great option but these
are kind of like the basics that you
would need to ensure you can do an
effective scouting
of your plants also when you want to
consider the
recent events for outdoor you want to be
looking at the weather what was the
weather what's the weather predicted to
be
that can influence what you might find
for indoor environment know what
treatments that the plants were given
and also what conditions and data
loggers here last 24 hours or so
what conditions were those plants
exposed to
then we're talking about scouting
patterns as in a lot of plants girls not
to follow a single row
but to get an overview of the area now
that can be kind of a transient kind of
look a zigzag scouting a diamond pattern
if you've got to get back to the same
point so just keep in mind you don't
want to just go down one row because
that might give you
a kind of an uneven look or kind of a
bias
to your scouting and you want to
evaluate the plants
so consider the entire group of plants
as well as individual plants look for
patterns
it could be more difficult we only have
a small number of plants that might be
quite large
but in the larger area here we have much
more plants look for any sort of
patterns that you see
what are some consistencies one end of
the field look different than another
go through as part of your hopefully
unbiased evaluation then you want to
classify the issue
so is it random are only a few plants
here and there showing
whatever you're noticing could it also
be on different portions of plants
so it's going to be at the top of these
plants the bottom of those plants the
midsections
this is typically a sign of early
insects but it could be other things
if you're seeing aggregated areas issues
found in groups or sections
pockets of similarities would be noticed
typically associated with a soil issue
or disease
and or water excessive water instead of
kind of a dry pocket
or it could be a really wet area that's
typically seen these aggregated groups
this kind of
see here took all the plants random
which is going to be random throughout
aggregated being little clumps now
there's
aggregated versus the repeated so
aggregated again could it be down a
slope could be a little depression here
collecting water could be aggregated to
the edge of a field maybe did
did a fertilizer row get missed or is it
repeated is it only down
certain rows in a certain area did
something happen in that particular area
is it a low spot a high spot
what did the tractor went through and
fertilized you know over fertilizer
under fertilize this particularly to
have a skip in this particular section
again all things to be looking for all
things to be documenting
and how do you document well simply by
taking pictures this can involve a
general
field images as well as individual
plants portions of interest are valuable
but sometimes having the larger image
can also be helpful so for example we
take a picture of this yelling leaf yes
this leaf is yellow
we look at the whole plant establishment
in general is it just one leaf is it
just one
area on one plant is it not all the
leaves of the same age across
all the multiple growing environments
and growing sections and growing rows
all that plays into developing an
accurate diagnosis
now if you're not able to diagnose in
the field or want to get a little bit
more information
sometimes collecting a sample is
important
i want to be sure to click the clean and
early symptoms and advanced
portions of plant symptoms so that clean
sample is something that really doesn't
look infected or look like it
has any issues you want to collect a
portion of that because sometimes in the
lab
they might be able to see that very
early onsite of something then early
symptoms something's not too advanced it
hasn't really broken down
just starting where you're first able to
detect the issue and then advanced
symptoms
as well should be included in your
sample if you're collecting roots be
sure to collect them with the soil
around them
for analysis in the lab because that may
also play into the material that's
needed
when in doubt contact the lab as far as
what sample they want to collect for
what you suspect to ensure that you're
sending a quality sample
so hopefully you'll get a quality result
because remember the lab
is only as good as the sample you send
them