I'm gonna go over the process of trying
cannabis now when we think about drying
there a hairdryer we think about putting
clothes out in the line to dry some
methods are quicker so methods are
slower and there's advantages and
disadvantages to both so I'll try to
present the proper way to try cannabis
so the importance of drying first off
regardless of what process you choose so
it's this is a drying is very critical
that it can make or break the end
product that you have freshly harvested
material will have little potency n--
will burn very poorly so this speaks to
the importance of having a drying
process the goal of the drying process
is to have an even slow progression to
allow a high-quality end product to be
sold our use now this drying process
fresh green buds that are full of
moisture and that would cause them to
have a potentially diluted kind of like
poor taste and to burn unevenly so if
you're just a pic of blood right off of
right off the plant and smoke it or add
heat to it it's not gonna it's gonna
have that high moisture content you're
not gonna get really the potency there
and it kind of greenish taste it's
usually referred to as I'll proper
drying will remove about 75% of moisture
which will concentrate the taste on one
smoked and also concentrate those
cannabinoids this drying process that
takes a slow time for plants over a week
is better than trying to speed dry the
material so that 75% that's lost we
don't want that to curl in one day we
might have a slow dry down process to is
that will produce a higher quality end
product a lot of growers believe in
hanging the plants cutting them down and
hanging them hanging the plants upside
down is a an OK way to dry them that's
fine but it will not help drain the
cannabinoids to the flowers so this is a
good way to dry them but don't think
it's going to help increase the
cannabinoids by having them flow down to
the buzz sound with the force of gravity
that's an old myth Canadians are fixed
in the plant while that move based on
the position during the drying process
so again hanging off sit down great way
to dry them but don't think it's gonna
concentrate cannabinoids in any way
faster speed running is not advised
quick drying result in the end product
that burns with a harsh smoke that kind
of
kind of tastes as I had said often snot
the goal in seeking to produce a high
quality end product Heath it's often
added will reduce the drying time to
only a few hours which may sound great
but if you dry it with too much heat
about over 200 degrees Fahrenheit they
can degrade cannabinoids often they'll
need to be dried and then maybe read
right after they're allowed to kind of
go through a sweating process but
container so that can just sweating
could potentially cause some moisture to
build-up could cause some mold to
develop some other growth will actually
dice up the buds and cut them up but
this is not really a preferred method
since most end-users want to see and
inspect the full intact bud that's a
sign of higher quality dry time should
be about five to seven plus days or so
to allow for uniform drying with minimal
cannabinoid breakdown
it's desiccation process at drying slow
processes advised large leaves from
plants can be removed harvest helping
even in more dry this drying process can
think of kind of like aging wine and
barrels here slower and longer is
typically beard is better and producing
the higher end product same here can be
applied to cannabis