so while not often done producing
cannabis seeds so many times grossly
their purchase seeds are clones rather
than going through the [ __ ] producing
their own I just wanted to touch on what
it does take to produce cannabis seeds
so you make an informed decision whether
it's something want to pursue or not so
British in seeds is often not advised so
due to variability that seeds do produce
the time to select out males when we do
plant seeds the lack of cannabinoid
production within the square footage of
your gross space and chance of
pollinating females unintentionally
through pollen that may get caught up in
ventilation systems or nearby plants
here because you can see it's very very
fine and it does spread quite well even
though you may try to control it the
seed keep in mind the plant has to
invest energy to fully develop in the
seed because these do contain in embryo
this is a peach here but in embryo and
endosperm which is the energy storage
that's where a lot of the energy goes to
and a seed coat as a protective shell to
help protect that seed and again there's
a little simplified rendition of what a
cutaway
of a seed might look like now when
producing seeds it takes about six to
eight weeks to ripen those seeds and the
way you can kind of tell when they are
ripening is when the seeds are rattle in
the pods they're fully mature and
harvest can occur just slightly before
this time but it's good to wait until
then I mean it'd be as pronounced as a
rattlesnake when you kind of get that
rattling kind of sound would be kind of
move the flower here that's a good time
to know that those seeds are probably
ripe enough and ready to be harvested
now if you don't wait long enough so
some girls try to shortcut the seed
production phase you harvest them too
early often the seed quality will be
poor and every dur reduced in
germination rates the reason for this is
that the endosperm may not be fully
developed
provide the embryo with enough energy to
start on before it's able to emerge from
the soil and start capturing sunlight so
just sound the quick picture here we
could see some of these seeds this one
this one one over here are not very
mature those darker seed coats and
your seeds will typically indicate a
fully mature seed it's had time to fully
develop its seed coat which indicates
that the endosperm is probably as
well-developed as could be and that will
increase the odds of germination some of
these that are lighter colorations or
even it's like green color typically
have very poor in germination rates so
you can use this also to kind of inspect
your seeds when you do go through and
harvest them to make sure that you're
selecting for the ones with the best
odds of germination and again it takes a
little time to wait so that is so just
so you're advised on what it takes to
produce cannabis seeds and typically
growers will commit to just seed
production and that try to grow on
pollinated flowers with seeds because of
the degree that the male pollen can
spread and could potentially cross
contaminate other areas or grow rooms
that people may have said