in this debaco university student series
video we're going to take a look at
proper fluorescent light settings to use
for clones we're going to be utilizing a
par meter so i know many people can't
justify the expense of a par meter so
hopefully this video will give you some
insight
to know exactly how far and how to set
up your fluorescent lights so you have a
successful cloning operation
[Music]
all right now just before we get into
the video here just realize these clones
or these plant leaves are about eight
inches away from the light uh as a
source of comparison and also the light
used was an agro-bright designer t5 324
watt fluorescent light
was used and that's going that we're
going to see because it offers these
great adjustments we're just going to
see what adjustment works best for our
operation here with the use of a par
meter so we've just switched over our
lights from our led to our fluorescent
lights this is because the leds were
providing a bit too high of a par
reading for our liking and so we wanted
to move to something a little less
intense
now for this lighting setup we have a
few different options this one has four
of our lights on
this option has all of our lights on
where this option has just two of our
lights on now we need to figure out
which is the best for our grow operation
so we're going to use a par meter to
read each of these lighting
settings and determine which one is the
best
right now we're at our lowest light
setting of just two of our lights on and
we're reading at a about 104 103 par
meter
i would recommend that you hold your
sensor just as a note at plant level
instead of too high or too low just to
make sure that you're getting an
appropriate reading
now we're at our medium lighting option
with just two of our lights off and
we're reading at a good 210 par reading
now we're at our highest setting with
all of our lights on and we're reaching
about
340 for our par rating
based on the size and shape of our clone
so far
our ideal par reading would be at around
200. now all of the lights on at 300 is
a little too much but fortunately we
have the option to dim it down by just
turning our middle two lights off to
give us the perfect par reading of about
200.
you