irrigating and watering plants is an
essential part of growing but properly
monitoring plant moisture and knowing
and maintaining proper plant ministry is
very important and many growers will
miss this either over or under watering
so proper plant moisture want to be in
that you know ideal range don't want to
be too high or too low rare cases on
both ends typically I find a little bit
more common as the over watering so over
watering well what's the problem with
over watering often growers just love
their plants too much when they go there
if you need to do something so often
they feel like well plants need water so
the water it's kind of like filling a
cup of water then just keep the faucet
running - can cause it's wasting water
from one can also cause roots to rot
that's can be in very great negative
that can occur from this over irrigating
reduces oxygen content in the root zone
we see the extreme example here of trees
growing in pond here looks like it may
have been flooded and we see that
they're unable to survive so this is a
many of the negatives associated with
over watering plants be careful on what
media you're using because that can
dictate and help regulate how much water
you need to add and if you're changing
media's you need to change your watering
regimen now if you're under watering
plants this can cause plant stresses it
can be difficult to read wet the solar
of media once some media dries as better
if it's peat moss base to become
hydrophobic and really hard to re-wet
this is where if you forget about the
plants or a pump fails and you go back
to reward can be a very difficult
process to initially rewetting will dry
out sometimes and this is a high clay
and crack above media if it's contains
in particular peat moss or clay pebbles
that can be another challenge to get
that to re-wet back to its original
condition so of course your goal is to
have the correct amount when I provide
plants with the moisture they need allow
Reed's to grow and breathe keep in mind
that this amount that you're providing
them to have the correct amount could
change over the growth of the plant and
when that plant is small it's going to
require less water and as it gets larger
it's gonna require more water on this
can be changed too and you go to
transplant and type of media that you
may use so always make sure you're
maintaining the proper size not going
too much or too little trying to hit
that nice perfect
to keep your plants happy which won't
turn make you happy