in this debaco university video i'm
going to handle the often controversial
properly naming of cannabis and how we
should go about that
[Music]
all right let's get into properly naming
cannabis or really any plant
so first off it's often ash we use the
term strain or variety or sativa or
indica or hybrid or something else and
really all the both terms are inaccurate
really cultivar is what should be used
because this is a cultivated variety so
cultiva as far as we're looking at that
cultivars kind of how we're getting that
we want to be sure we're using the right
tool for the job and this is the proper
way to go about naming plants that's
been established
now just taking another plant as an
example for example an apple here
the macintosh apple
we can see here that should proper
scientific names i should usually be
italicized as far as the botanical name
for all eating apples macintosh between
single quote quote marks in roman
letters is the cultivar name so here we
could see malice palmia and then we have
the macintosh this name helps
distinguish it from the hundreds of
other cultivars of apples so this same
concept botanically should be also
applied to cannabis now sadly it's not
really being applied in this way but at
least this would be the proper way to
name this
so word of caution just in general
contrary to what you may have heard the
distinctions between the different
varieties is genetically debated
differences in morphologies are the main
source of classification with many new
cross breeding occurring there's been
mixing types leading to the blurring
between the two groups so for example
this leaf morphology
has a strong sativa indication
where this one right below me
has more of an indica kind of morphology
but keep in mind with the hybrids and
the breeding that's occurring you can
get sometimes a blending or a mixing of
the two quite often
even though we might just look at this
quick image and say oh yeah sativa and
indica
might be more to it than just that
so that requires that genetic testing so
the is work in progress a library of
different genetics there's no clear link
between plant morphology and
cannabinoids produced this is another
important distinction that just because
we see an indica or sativa name we can't
automatically associate a certain amount
of cannabinoids or terpenes with that
variety with that cultivar if you will
so as a result
we need to be aware of the differences
that occur the hybrids that occur we
have to look more at the chemical
profile
and not just indica or sativa when we're
talking about cannabis as is so often
done
now name is sometimes meaningless
another issue is consistency among the
varieties people will purchase the same
variety from two different shops with
vastly different effects this is because
the lack of our current genetic
screening and also checking to help
ensure consistency this is part of the
issues with cannabis is that lack of
consistency on many fronts
so the general classification of
cannabis as we can see here canvas is
classified as cannabis sativa regardless
of its origin however it can be further
classified into three main
classifications the sativa the indica or
the rhodalus
so
the reuteralis is the autoflowers so
those are going to flower based on
day old not photoperiod and we have our
indicas and our sativa which are
photoperiod dependent and if you give a
general kind of morphology of the leaf
and plant structure you can see that
here so hopefully this kind of gives you
an idea of how to properly classify and
name a cannabis even though it may not
be the current system that is being
utilized