okay so here I'm gonna go over proper
lighting for cannabis and how the
different stages can have different
light requirements so the general light
requirements looking at the Gro stage
clones typically will be a little bit
less par or PPF the ratings and a
seedling something because of the stress
that they're going under now keep in
mind that there is a range provided here
and that can depend on other factors
such as temperature and humidity and
just general growing conditions but
something to shoot for for clones is one
or two hundred seventy just a little bit
higher than two hundred ceilings one two
three hundred two people want to keep
them not getting leggy want to keep them
nice and robust so that's a good range
to shoot for vegetative we're increasing
kind of from that 300 to get high is six
hundred and we're pushing them into
flower that kind of end finisher they're
looking for six hundred plus so these
are kind of just general light
requirements and gives you just
something to shoot for or it gives you
an idea of a range of what the canvas
plant needs at different stages of
growth now
herbs will ask well should I add side
lights you know a man I'm looking at a
lot of lights on the ceiling and putting
down shared side lights
well we've reflective walls are advised
and while silent may not hurt the actual
effectiveness may not be worth the
additional cost over over plant lighting
is the most efficient it should be the
focus along with the quality reflector
that you're using a little less
importance on side lights the reflective
wall service is advised those room walls
as much attention is painted reflectors
do not forget the walls of a grow room
except Falls can add light that would
otherwise be lost or wasted typically
reflective material be like mylar which
is about 92 to 97 percent of it with
reflect ability and rest Oleum 28:51 40
ultra matte interior chopped pink that's
kind of his white paint is something
else to consider if you're looking at
the need to paint the walls of a grow
room lights can play favorites so even
lighting is the goal but sometimes is it
not possible so may be necessary to
rotate plans to ensure the receiving
evenly disbursed light so kind of use
that here's our salad what we do add to
your salad well some people might pick
more of one thing then
there so they can kind of play favorites
so keep in mind if you see a plant
leaning over the one way I want to just
rotate that plant 90 degrees so it's
just getting an even amount of light and
not going to have a hard time kind of
pruning that or trellising that or
getting that plant to grow in the way
you want it you want to maximize light
so while it's not advised if you are in
a grow room where space is an issue they
used to light the perimeter from a high
intensity light you place clones or
seedlings as this grower has here it's
like a diffused light of lights that
you're already running as you can see
here the candle as you get further away
get more diffused light however if
possible you want to avoid this scenario
because it can involve mixing plants in
different areas in different ages which
can potentially infect plants with
disease or cross contaminate with
insects so again this can it be done
sure is it advised typically when I keep
your clothes the seedlings in an
isolated separate location plant spacing
overcrowding will reduce yields and lead
to an increased chance for disease the
goal is to only have the tips of two
plants touching to ensure maximum plant
density while still providing the
opportunity for good air circulation
this is why lights can determine the
area or the gross space that you have
this shows a little bit of the ideal
situation here where just the tips are
touching you can see what one plant may
have been moved you can see how that
looks like a gap here this is a little
bit too dense here we're seeing kind of
leaves in topple leaves it's kind of
reducing the amount of light that can
penetrate this canopy lastly there's
this thing called light stress some
glower some growers will give plants 36
hours of continuous darkness before
inducing flowering they claim quicker
time to flower however this isn't
unnecessary stress and I do not advise
this 36 hours of darkness simply move
the plants over to the grow room you can
flip the lights to 12 hours and 12 even
12 and 12 you don't think this 36 hours
at enthuse darkest that's unneeded
stress on those plants so for this
provide you just a good idea of the
proper lighting for cannabis and the
general requirements at the different
stages provided for you there