this is an important aspect for all
indoor
cannabis growers and that is looking at
the proper placement of sensors
in the cannabis grow area so follow
along in this video and we'll go over
to make sure you're properly placing
your sensors for accurate readings
[Music]
all right let's make sure you're
properly placing your sensors in your
grow facility
so first off it's important to realize
that a sensor is only as good as its
placement
keep in mind what conditions you're
monitoring and how the placement of the
sensor will
impact those readings while there are
many conditions that should be monitored
temperature will be used as the example
provided here we want to make sure we're
right on point uh because we're off by a
little bit
that placement's off a little bit it's
really going to throw things off in the
facility in general
so where do you place your temperature
sensor what would be the kind of the
area that you place it in your grow
facility
well take a grow room or grow tent as an
example
near the top is often going to be higher
than average temperature
will be a given since heat is going to
naturally want to rise through your grow
facility
in the middle or at plant height gives a
general estimate of the area's
temperature
if you put it near the floor it'll be a
lower than average temperature given
that
colder air tends to sink as well as co2
so again that mindful of that area where
you're placing that sensor
so the obvious choices agro would say
would be i want to have my sensor at you
know plant height
while this is where most growers put the
monitor system this may not be
the best location reason being you want
to make sure you're taking other factors
into consideration
where is the light placement how's the
air circulation patterns in your grow
tent or grow room
are there doorway locations is that
impacting things are there viewing areas
are there
vents how is that going to impact
different factors when you're looking
specifically here at temperature as i
mentioned that light
placement so you want to ensure that
there's not a light directly on the
temperature sensor as this can cause an
inaccurate reading when i have some idea
where the plant is but want to be
mindful of where the intensity of the
light is
where that heat source from that light
is going and being projected we don't
want to
put that temperature sensor near that
because we're going to get a false
reading or a not accurate reading for
the grow area that the plant is being
exposed to
those air circulation patterns that i
mentioned is the plant height getting
more
or is plant height getting less air
circulation from a fan
this will also impact the temperature so
you want to have an idea
of you know what is the general airflow
pattern in your grow facility is that
plant height really the best height
there
for temperature readings in that grow
facility
and doorway locations and doorway
locations could be physical doors
they could also be as we see here they
could also be
doorways as far as plant access points
so putting the sensor near the entrance
way is common practice to make
reading easier but you may want to
consider this is actually representative
of the field location
so in their growing location we want to
put near the doors and just kind of like
peek in and see what the temperature
is but again is that the best location
so what is the best location then well
the best location really comes down to
is an area that's representative of the
growing space so typically yes that's
around plant height
that should be the general kind of
consensus that's where the general
conditions are located
but look very hard at your system look
very hard at your environment
is that really representative what's
going on overall
you know we want to make sure we're away
from any fans and not too close to
lights
where are you going to place that
exactly because where you place that
sensor that's what your readings are
going to be based off of
so if you place the center in a poor
location if that's not in the right or
proper representative location in your
grow space that all the numbers you read
are going to be skewed in one direction
or another
causing you potentially to make false
data collection
and potentially not maximize the growing
facility a growing environment
and adjustments for your plants