okay here we go over the proper
pipetting procedure and while there may
be different types of pipettes the basic
procedure holds true for them all so
piping could be the most important lab
technique to master so take time to
learn how to do this properly the reason
why is it the most important technique
to master is you're already dealing with
small quantities so small variations can
have a dramatic impact on your end
result so take the time to go over work
with this it's gonna seem easy the first
time but keep it at it so you can really
refine it and reduce the chance for
errors the journal schematic here of a
pipette Gilson was used because that's
what I could find online the template is
generally common to all pipettes you
want to be fairly the specific mantle of
the pipette you might be doing and your
replacements list for the model if you
have opted ensure you're getting
everything I create because again we're
looking at small variations making large
potential effects and there are Springs
and seals in them so again these are
things that can wear out over time so
just keep that in mind if you are
working in a lab I know pipettes can be
expensive to purchase but if you're
going to be working in that lab I would
recommend you get your own personal set
of pipettes to use now while they are
expensive even to initially purchase you
want to go the extra step of getting
them calibrated and keep them to
yourselves that this sounds selfish but
because these small variations can make
a large change you want to make sure to
have an accurate set so that your lab
data has the most accurate and
consistent it's possible to reduce the
potential for a long range work that you
have to do it or redo an experiment now
when pipetting the number one reason for
errors is actually distractions so you
want to be sure that you're kind of
focused on what you're doing and avoid
distractions
your attitude is important if you're
angry moving fast and you know not
following the proper procedure that's
going to cause skewing of the results as
well you need to ensure you're slowing
down and taking your time because
rushing will equal mistakes it just kind
of rush through his I have to do all
this and just get through it quick it
would be advised not to do it at that
time because again you could be
inserting more errors in the end the
basics of pipetting houses typically
they can be held in the left or right
hand the plunger has two stops so a pee
when you push it down with your thumb
you're gonna reach off you're gonna feel
first up and then push even further
gonna feel second stop so the first stop
is the amount of volume stated on the
pipette this will dispense the correct
amount of liquid so what you would do is
you take your pipette if you're going to
take up a certain amount of liquid you
die press that pipette you put it in the
liquid to depress it to the first stop
put it in the liquid and then release it
slowly and you take up that liquid you
have to dispense it into another
container you're gonna push down and
feel that first stop just about all the
liquid will be dispensed if you want to
go on to the final and next stop and
they'll add a little bit extra air you
know ensure that there's nothing left in
the pipette tip is that second stop is
that extra help dispense that liquid and
I'm gonna let it return to its normal
position so when you go through and you
feel this is you'll that first step in
second stop that first stop or the end
result here to that first stop will be
the amount that is stated on the pipette
but there will be a second staff that
will push a little extra air out this is
why for being aggressive you can push
down beyond that first stop and take it
more liquid and not properly assess the
reading that's on the pipette and it'll
be causing a massive skew in your
results first step is to select the
correct pipette so it might send other
all pipettes aren't they the illicit
tips and these are different and that's
because there are four different amounts
select the one that's closest to your
target value whether it's a larger a mid
or a small volume so let the right
pipette if you have that option because
while you saying oh listen can do both
they may not do it as well or as
accurately step two is to set the knob
properly in the sort of that amount when
you're setting that the pipette knob
will actually rotate in turn I know the
volume the peph it's used in the scale
so you're able to dial this in correctly
a lot of them will say exactly what they
are this measures 10 to 100 microliters
this matters to 100 to 1000 microliters
so just be aware when you're grabbing
and set it properly
step 3 have the tips in easy to reach
area these really the tips because
you'll be using a new one each time you
go through a chance for the liquid make
sure they're an arm's reach out and out
of the way
the experiment but still close enough
that you're able to use them this
robotic arm here and all the pipette
tips are located really close and the
different pets are here so you want them
close but not necessarily in the way
lastly you want a pipette slowly avoid
the creation of bubbles so this will
cause volumes to be inaccurate so you
want to allow it to be taken up slowly
and dispensed slowly again this pipette
is a little filter tip as well so this
is another level sometimes they will
have that something won't have that
regardless if you're using the filter
one of the extra cautious of them slowly
because that air does have to pass
through that filter but you want to
ensure that you're as accurate as
possible cuz you're gonna be peeing this
again and again so only that was helpful
on going through the basics of a pipette
that when you go and grab one you'll be
at least initially familiar with it and
then the key part there is simply just
keep practicing with it