okay here I'm gonna go over the proper
use of a centrifuge and while they may
look different they all operate in the
same basic way so the basics centrifuge
is a piece of equipment that puts an
object and rotation or a fixed axis it
spins and the whole point is to separate
the substance of different densities the
denser substances as you see down here
will appear towards the bottom of the
tube and the less it has dense
substances will be up here so these can
be slightly different in density and by
spinning it at a certain rate for a
certain time you'll develop that kind of
tell it down there and allow that
separation technique and align up or
this off in most cases here AUSA version
by centrifuge solids can be separated
from solution in prime example this is
separating the blood into plasma and
cellular components so the plasma and
the buffer II of kind of leukocytes the
white blood cells with recites or the
red blood cells down here so well
initiate may look as one solid red kind
of liquid you spin it down you look at
this yellow portion called a plasma and
your observer sites or red blood cells
will be down at the bottom they are the
most ends there will be a thin layer so
you look carefully this kind of white
blood cells and some platelets as well
will be that yellow portion that's
simply all located in blood but through
the densities in the centrifuge process
you're able to separate those out
centrifuge safety because they do spin
at a very fast rate it's high rotational
speed or definitely in the thousands or
ten thousands even higher in some cases
they must be balanced or you run the
risk of damaging the equipment yourself
or items around it so even if you want
to centrifuge one thing you need to make
sure that the centrifuge is balanced in
the sense that the mass is the same on
both sides otherwise it'll get out of
balance and will walk itself off the
table can run into things concurrently
damage the rotor and equipment all bad
things and at the end whenever it's done
it's tempting but do not attempt to
touch or stop the spinning rotor by hand
or with another tool or object so a lot
of times the time I might go off you
lift it up and go grab your hands to
stop it and grab your equipment you want
to try to avoid
this at all costs reason being it could
spit at a very fast rate when I let it
slow down naturally because you're
putting pressure on one area on
especially the higher end balance points
might be damaging that rotor a little
bit or catching your finger on one of
the tubes here and just all bad things
there so setting up a centrifuge you
want to place the correct size and type
of tubes in the centrifuge some are
specifically made for the high rate of
spinning and you'll always want to use
at counter balance the counter balance
is by mass not my volume so as you put
you know 10 mils of something on one
side and its water great put water on
the other side you know what our base
you're in good shape but make sure it's
by mass not like volume that's we want
to keep it balanced using it sometimes
it's a lot denser than water you know
and someone just put water on the other
side because the volume might be the
same but the mass will not put the tubes
opposite of one another
as we kind of see here in the centrifuge
if you have more than two tubes only the
ones I will have the equal mass of these
two can des equal mass and these two can
have equal mass it does not mean these
all have the same mass these two need to
be equal and these two need to be equal
those that are directly across from one
another sometimes you do when
experiencer you're loading the entire
thing up and that's fine as long as the
masses are right around the same lastly
you want to enter the RPM revolutions
per minute it's an option I mean close
the lid so sometimes they are all preset
so no you can adjust the RPM I'll turn
the timer and press Start remove the
tubes carefully after center view has
completely stopped spinning to prevent
the mixing so some will be more stable
than others you want to carefully remove
those when ID can't remove that top
liquid portion sometimes things want to
keep that pellet want to extract that
whatever the protocol calls for just be
mindful of this is the proper way to
centrifuge so that you eliminate errors
in this separation technique