so a lot of times we talk about taking a
soil sample and sending it off to the
lab now that's a good thing sometimes
it's forgotten about the proper method
about going about when collecting that
soil sample and the importance of
following a proper method as you can
send something accurate to the lab
reason why this is so important is the
lab is only as good as a sample you
provide them it's your responsibility to
follow the proper sample technique to
ensure the results the lab provides are
representative of your field conditions
the labs going to test the soil or to
send them and give you results your goal
is to make sure that's a representative
of your field so that the results that
they give you can be applied to your
exact particular situation now how to
properly correct a soil sample there's
kind of a few different ways I like to
use kind of a simple way my step one is
to collect something you can pour the
soil with and typically a 16 inch piece
of inch and a PVC pipe works great it's
easily found it's inert so again this is
a great tool to have then I take a
five-gallon pail you may need to add a
plastic bag to ensure there's no
contamination depending with that bag
that pail was used for previously when a
clean bags are getting a clean sample
they take a large hammer for pounding a
PVC pipe into the ground so I got a PVC
pipe I got a five-gallon pail with shoes
you has a bag liner and I have a large
hammer step 2 is to market gradations on
that PVC pipe so you know where 6 8 10
maybe even 12 inches are your goal is to
get a soil sample of 6 to 8 inches deep
depending on the soil type you may want
to go deeper so I kinda have six as that
minimum they hit a rock or something if
I can get down to 6 to maybe 9 inches
that's great
I don't want to go much over 12 I'll
step 3 we walk randomly over your
growing air taking about a dozen or so
cores or samples that we place in your
five-gallon pail
they'll be sure to avoid potential
biases such as corners edges or areas of
uneven fertilization the whole point
here is you want that representative
sample if you want to just walk from one
corner right down the line take all your
course this way you kind of want to take
one maybe from the middle one over here
over here come back around take them
over here kind of gives you that random
kind of sampling you want to typically
avoid corners because they may get over
or under fertilized and they may not be
representative of the field and why just
to avoid
the Long's one straight line here that
nice random sample is going to provide
you with the most field representative
results now after you have all those
cores you want to mix up your sample in
the pail want to take a subset sample of
that that sub sample should be about a
couple of soil you don't want to send
them like a really small cut a thimble
you want to send that full cup there
because it's gonna allow them to perform
the test that they need in an accurate
manner step 5 which is probably the most
annoying of all the steps sometimes it
is to fill out the appropriate paperwork
I'll label the bags with your sample the
title was your name mail to the lab one
hint if you are mailing a lot of samples
zolab you might not consider flat rate
boxes because it fits it ships and so it
can be very heavy so if you get charged
by the weight that can increase your
cost of shipping a lot they can fit into
one the flat rate boxes that might be an
advantageous and cost-effective way to
go
so when filling out your paperwork so
you want to be sure that there's a lot
of test options typically which one's
best for me typically you could look at
what they have necessary I want to go
with the cheapest or all of them we want
to look at what's going to fit your
conditions what's going to give you the
most amount not of information just the
most amount of useful information
I start with determining why you're
testing your sample do you have any
background on the not on the area you're
just looking for the general nutrient
profile adjust the pH for Seibel salts
what organic matter again those are a
lot of options there when in doubt you
can always contact the lab but just in
general you're looking at typically that
standard soil tests will give you great
base information and then there's
typically more details available from
there