now many growers will say it's not
possible to propagate cannabis after it
flowers I'm here to tell you that it is
possible well it may not be easy if you
do find something truly unique it is
worth at least taking a shot propagating
even after a king of his plant flowers
so again it's not ideal that you do this
but sometimes it's not until you harvest
that you realize you want to preserve
the genetics you have in front of you
and it is possible but it does present
greater challenges which may reduce your
overall success percentage so keep in
mind if you are trying this for the
first time and you haven't propagated
before you may want to try to work on
propagation with a normal plant that's
in the vegetative state before you go
through and take on this challenge but
if you do have that unique individual at
your other to do you want to make more
of an propagate is worth at least a try
how you gonna go about doing this is
want to start by leaving some
underdeveloped lower branches with
foliage on your chosen plant you then
want to move that plant to an 18 hour
light six hour dark photo period you may
want to supplement with some nitrogen
fertilizers which can be done the day
after harvesting the goal here is to try
to push that vegetative growth I'll push
those leaf production these odds are if
you're harvesting you're just coming off
a flushing phase maybe or a reduction in
nitrogen they're fertilizers in general
so you want to give it a little bit of
that grow fertilizer boost it'll take
about thirty days or so the plant should
be ready for harvesting clones from
takes about a month or so after
flowering to kind of get it back in a
vegetative stage to kind of get it to
where it's growing again to where you're
able to harvest some vegetative cuttings
from that plant so you can go through
the entire propagation process so again
while this may not be ideal if you do
have that unique individual by all means
try it and I wish you the best of luck