okay human go over proper cannabis bud
storage we're looking at you know a
storage closet here many of the same
parameters apply to cannabis because
again we're looking keeping the product
that we've produced Kenneth keep that
shelf-life as long as possible and the
quality is high for as long as possible
so storage use an airtight container to
preserve the aroma taste and potency now
the airtight container can kind of be
like the seeable Tupperware container
can be this little popped up here or can
be canning jars here which are another
great option keep in mind we do want to
be keeping whatever we're storing away
from as much late in adverse conditions
as possible
to again extend that shelf-life in
potency as long as possible that's some
storage options that through sealed bags
and kidding jars are great options
however be sure the container they are
in is air tight to avoid moisture
infiltration so that can be a vacuum
kind of pack here which typically is
used for meat products it can also be
used for leafy greens key part there is
to eliminate moisture from getting in or
escaping and keeping that as interior
conditions very consistent now the
temperature that should be stored at
dried buds can be stored reduce
temperatures because this will reduce
the temperature will help preserve the
long-term potency by reducing that
temperature you increase inversely you
increase the storage time of that
typically refrigeration temperatures is
advised four degrees Fahrenheit or four
degrees Celsius
getting away from those really warm
growing conditions but not necessary in
the conditions where it's really
freezing just those cool conditions four
degrees Fahrenheit or so off a
refrigeration can help increase that
shelf life and ensure your cannabis buds
that you've worked so hard for are
stored in the proper conditions