so this is intended to be a short
tobacco university video
for those considering or looking for the
pros and cons of growing your own
cannabis clones
where some of the advantages were some
of the disadvantages stay tuned and
you'll learn about them here
in this video
[Music]
all right let's get into the video here
so first off growing on campus clones
what's the advantage why would you want
to consider this
well you allows you as a grower to know
the source it allows you
to grow to also control the timing of
when those clones will be ready
to grow into the next stage of plants
they can also be known in a consistent
supply you don't have to rely on anyone
else so these are a lot of the kind of
pros or advantages here that growers
seek and why they would consider
growing their own clones however with
any decision or any
decision you're looking at there's not
always all just positives
some of the disadvantages if you do
decide to grow your own clones is that
the time and resources required or
needed to be devoted
to production of those clones sometimes
it's easier just to buy the clones
instead of going through this process of
having all these materials and timing
all set
the cost of setting up that clone
production has to be weighed to
determine whether or not
that is going to net a positive yield in
the end
and also not only the cost you also have
to consider the space and environments
required
to be able to ensure you have the proper
cloning environment so it's not a waste
of time so you actually
have good odds of producing quality
clones
so again if you're thinking about
growing your own clones hopefully this
has provided you with some of the
disadvantages some of the advantages
and has given you some background so you
can make an educated decision
on what you want to implement for your
growing area