so here we're going to be looking at
protein structure we've seen this
initial image different ways of
representing structure to try to show
the three-dimensional shape because for
proteins is we're going to see here
shape is very important to their proper
function so just give you a basic idea
is there's four main stages of
organization this is just the amino acid
sequence and this is going to take on an
initial shape is going to start to form
and ultimately here the fourth stage of
protein structures ultimately make a
functional protein so the general
overview of protein structure levels are
the Assembly of the amino acid sequence
the initial folding or forming alpha and
beta sheets we have the packaging here
or starting at a three-dimensional
structure in an interaction where we
have a complex of a protein molecule
making this functional protein in the
end so starting with the basics protein
assembly the primary structure the
specific sequence of amino acids is
what's going to form a protein so we're
looking here at a ribosome this occurs
in the cell in the cytosol and this
involves polymerization of amino acids
attached to the tRNA so here's our
messenger RNA here encoding for the
sequence we have our ribosome and we are
building our primary structure which is
our T RNAs bringing in the amino acid
sequence binding here allowing us to
follow the messenger RNA sequence for
amino acids this is using the primary
structure this is just the amino acids
being linked together
now those amino acids it from a linear
kind of chain here this is only one
dimensional a perfect linear amino acid
polymer is neither functional nor
energetically favorable folding needs to
occur so this is just a link of amino
acids but now we need folding to take on
the proper shape and what we see here is
that initial folding is creating now our
secondary structure this is folding then
this shape is taken down because of
hydrogen bonds again this occurs in the
cytosol of the cell involves localized
interactions which is the primary
structure here developing an alpha helix
this would be a beta sheet these are
both part of the secondary structure
occurring so that secondary structure is
the chemical nature of the carboxyl and
amino groups all the amino acids this
permits the hydrogen binding to form
this is causing these molecules to
become more stable
hence this defines the secretary
structure within a protein and as we see
here alpha helix and beta sheets the R
groups of the variant group is what
impacts the likelihood of secondary
structure formation so primary structure
was your amino acids listed here now
let's take the secondary structure the
secondary structure is nonlinear
starting at that three-dimensional shape
is because of those variant groups that
are now able to interact the interaction
as we see here here's a hydrogen bonding
and there's also Vander Waals
interactions causing this structure to
take on this specific shape is it as I
said there's alpha helix and beta sheets
and they have regular hydrogen bonding
patterns and we can classify them as
that the beta sheets you may assume here
forms a very flat structure the Alpha
helix kind of looks like that DNA we're
kind of getting that wrapping that does
occur this cytosol wasn't it now our
tertiary structure involves interactions
between secondary structure elements
yielding the next level or tertiary
structure so you could see right here we
have an alpha helix here with a beta
sheet now we're getting further
interaction that's occurring these
tertiary structures is final
three-dimensional shape of the protein
and see that image here they're
nonlinear and there's three-dimensional
so that's why it's important to show
this rotating so you get appreciation
for the unique three-dimensional
structure that it does have now protein
interactions so we see here tertiary or
quaternary structure so now are getting
different interactions that occur with
these polypeptides
there's multi components now interacting
this does still occur in the cytosol and
its proximity to other folded and
packaged proteins this involves an
interaction among tertiary structure
elements separate into calm energy these
are nonlinear three-dimensional
structures it's an example here kind of
a cartoon image this is hemoglobin you'd
see a distinctive one two three four
different structures here all coming in
interacting with one another to form a
functional final protein structure here
so that three-dimensional shape as we
see here very important so I show it in
a rotating basis you get an idea of the
uniqueness from all different angles
here each protein has a unique structure
and that's important to remember
now that amino acid sequence that free
energy memorization leads to that
structure and the dynamics will then
lead to the proper function so this
amino acid sequence looks like kind of a
garbled kind of a misprint here each one
of these letters represents an amino
acid those amino acids from a chain and
through the structure and ultimately the
dynamics to form the proper function
that folding process will make this
amino acid sequence a functional protein
now folds can be used for classification
there's a simple fold architecture which
is the overall shape and orientation of
the secondary structure as I mentioned
here as alpha and beta barrels for
example we can classify these at what we
call fold families this is a
characterization that takes into account
the empirical or biological properties
this is important because shape
determines function here we're Clannad
classifying in different shapes we could
also classify them as super families
which in addition to the fold tailings
includes evolutionary or ancestral
properties this gets into trying to
track different proteins or shapes over
the course of evolutionary time so this
is an interesting video here it tells
the helps you to understand the
importance of protein folding now
because protein folding does occur we
need to have a way to allow proteins or
amino acids to fold properly
so to help newly produced proteins fold
properly or something called chaperone
proteins and this is what they look like
there's little it's good doughnut here
there's literally this kind of
protective interior structure these
chaperone proteins allow a protective
area to allow these amino acid sequence
to fold into proper functional proteins
if these protein if these chaperone
proteins have deficiencies it played a
role in certain diseases cystic fibrosis
in all centers disease
is an example of two of them where
proteins don't fold properly so can I go
over that same thing we have a primary
structure which is just even the last
sequence that then will lead to
secondary structures which are alpha
helixes and beta sheets tertiary
structures the initial three-dimensional
structure formed by the assembly of of
those structures
lastly the quaternary structure this is
where their interaction forming with
multiple peptide chains it's just
another way to kind of look at it with
the amino acid sequence we're getting
into initial structures they're kind of
forming a three-dimensional shape and
there's interaction that's occurring
here at the final stage