so here we're gonna talk about the
basics of proteins now the reason why I
don't have a static image here but one
that is rotating is three-dimensional
shape is very important to the functions
of proteins as we'll see here that's
important to be able to view this
protein from all sides so proteins are
composed of amino acids so there's
different subunits that are linked
together that'll ultimately form the
protein so there's 20 common amino acids
in the standard genetic code and they
all have different side chains or R
groups this is the variant group and
they determine the properties of the
amino acid how will interact now in
additional to amino acids can be
incorporated by special translocation
translation and mechanisms so there's 22
genetically encoded amino acids but 20
are the common looking a little bit more
in more detail to this basic components
of an amino acid we have this basic
structure here so there is that our
group which is the variant group and
that's again what makes each amino acid
unique then there's the amino group the
hydrogen group in our carboxyl group so
the amino acid gets its name from the
amino group the amino hydrogen and
carboxyl group these are common in
standard across all amino acids what
makes them different is this R group
that provides them with a different
structure and also a different function
so we look at the amino acids here this
is a list of 21 of them and we could see
them kind of organized based on some of
their properties here so what are some
of those properties that an amino acid
may have well they could have a positive
side chain they've got a negative side
chain it could be you know acids with
polar uncharged size changes you could
see those organized here special cases
and then amino acids with hydrophobic
side chains here and they're each given
the name a three-letter kind of code and
then a single letter code so in
eukaryotes
there's only 21 amino acids but 20 of
those are the in the standard genetic
code plus there's one other one there
but we're going to focus really mainly
on those
t-there humans can listen to size 12
though of these amino acids which means
9 are considered essential and they must
be consumed in the diet humans cannot
manufacture or produce those particular
amino acids they need to be consumed in
the diet and that's why they're
considered to be essential ones that are
included here I just included the
capital letters here you can go through
and find it if you'd if you'd like just
to get you familiar with some of the
coding systems that we use for listing
amino acids now within our proteins here
we amino acids are linked together as I
mentioned before but they're linked
together by peptide bonds that is the
result of dehydration synthesis so what
is this kind of referred to in me well
if you're dehydrated you're losing water
well in this synthesis process there's
actually a water molecule that's
released I don't think by linking these
amino acids together there's going to be
leaders and leaders of water generated
there's just only one little water
molecule so keep in mind is that massive
amount of water but we are dehydrating
this process and releasing water so when
the bond is formed there's a release of
a water molecule now we could see that
here that's happening between our two
amino acids here amino acid one amino
acid two could also see the same thing
in the image over here
this peptide bond to form Oh H plus H is
H two O two hydrogen's and an oxygen and
we see the same thing here kind of
highlighted here where we have our two
hydrogen's and our oxygen forming that
water molecule when that's removed then
these are linking together here forming
this peptide bond between that carbon
and nitrogen atom now a dehydration
synthesis first hydrolysis if you
remember from one of the other lectures
or we'll be seeing hopefully in the
other lectures something called
hydrolysis so dehydration synthesis we
just talked about removing water to
linked molecules together so here a
bunch of molecules we're removing the
water molecule we're linking them
together hydrolysis is the opposite you
can think of break it apart as
hydrolysis water and lysis means to cut
or to break adding water to break bonds
so here we have a bunch of bonds here we
have water coming in breaking that apart
and getting now into our individual
kind of molecules or amino acids in this
case here enzymes are responsible says
break down a construction process more
on that later and other videos that you
can check out if you are interested
lastly our proteins would be called a
polypeptides what's a polypeptide well
it's a long chain of amino acids we kind
of see them here represent by their
three-letter code we have kind of one
two five six seven eight nine ten all
the way down here to 129 you see how
they're linked together and when we have
these long polypeptide chains sometimes
those one letter codes are advantageous
to make it easier to kind of read and go
through the polypeptide so poly meaning
many peptide referring to the bonds many
of those bonds linked together many of
those amino acids linked together by
those peptide bonds makes a protein