well there may be many pruning tools to
choose from and generally fall into
three main categories which I'm going to
discuss briefly here of those three
the first one is plant removal and this
is done at the point of harvest and
requires heavy duties loppers we see
here it seemed to be very robust and
good for cutting the entire plant down
at the main stem then we have four large
cuts which should be avoided ideally but
often necessary at some points we have
these large heavy-duty hand pruners the
last one is detailed pruning let me see
evident here this requires more labour
but can result in a more efficient plant
over the season and these have a very
small cutting area and these are kind of
for the cutting those nice weak stamens
those nice kind of weak leaves out makes
a very quick very efficient operation
can fit your whole hand in there so
those are the three main types of
pruning tools there to use was a typical
cannabis operation