here I'm going to go over pruning of
cannabis and while there may be
different techniques for the most part
in the end the goal is the same to kind
of trim out the plant to make it more
productive so looking at plant pruning
in general it involves selectively
removing portions of the plant with the
goal to allow the plant to only put its
energy into parts that will produce its
greatest yields I want to cut off the
ones that are just not going to produce
well so can focus its energy elsewhere
different methods can result in
different flowering times so keep that
in mind that if you are switching or
pruning nothing it could adjust your
entire growth cycle and your flowering
times I'm going to be sure to clean your
tools and wash them frequently to reduce
the potential for cross-contamination as
you move from plant to plant
if one plant does have an internal
vascular disease you want to have your
tools be the transmission to go through
and infect all the plants down that well
and also while it can be fun to prune
initially and you kind of enjoy moving
plant material don't get prune happy and
cut I call the Charlie Brown plant where
you look back at the plant and go if I
should have taken that much of it so
just keep that in mind also the goal for
pruning is you want to remove the weak
branches so this can be referred to as
freshening up at the plant these poor
yielding portions should be removed
because they're hurting your yields
overall and they themselves are not
going to produce all that well
dead or dying leaves should be removed
it's like the one pictured here on a
regular basis again to reduce the chance
of disease and that is a technically a
form of pruning be sure to discard these
leaves away from the main crop and by
removing these leaves and and weak
branches in general you can also
increase the air circulation in your
plant these are all great benefits some
people say well I'm not gonna prune you
know what's the downfall if I just kind
of let the plant grow and do its own
thing well this can increase plant
density which is advantageous in small
spaces it's most beneficial if your
plants are growing under three feet tall
in the short season so there are options
where you potentially can get away with
not pruning but it's not really the most
efficient method I should state should
still take care of you move older leaves
that are browning there's good harbour
disease or potential for insects
the downfall when you don't prune is you
have this kind of situation that could
develop we have poor air circulation
mainly
will not get adequate light penetration
this can make them you know reduce the
productivity the plant in general but
also get into some cases here we have
the opposite or if you don't prune
plants to get really leggy you're not
kind of pruning them to kind of take
away the apical meristem to make them
kind of grow outward a little bit more
so that's a potential another downfall
again depending what cultivar or what
plant stock you're using it's also plant
topping this involves removal of the
main chute to create two stronger and
shoots to develop so removal the apical
dominance or that main stalk is
advantageous because then you can have
now a two-litre system this is coming
for poinsettias and this is referred to
as pinching the plant this removes the
presence of a dense top bud but overall
yield will not be that negatively
impacted because now you're gonna have
more buds growing off these branches and
the port leader system is kind of like
what I just showed is kinda do it twice
remove the top dominant apical meristem
allow for four main branches to grow the
goal here to produce a large dense but
at the flower tops training these newly
developed four leaders is needed to
maximize the benefits of this pruning
style so again this does require a
little bit of a commitment throughout
the season and you gotta kind of set
your plant up early for this then
there's the film technique and it seems
4fi missed
instead of clearly removing the top grow
that I got showed in the previous one
just below the bud the traditional
method the bottom 10% of the butter is
actually gonna remain with this
technique this allows for different
growing tops to form kind of see that's
evident here a little bit the zoomed in
version here this can induce the
emergence of eight or more branches this
is beneficial in producing many branches
especially if you're looking at cloning
it's often used with the what's called
the screen of green style of growing but
very common for cloning simply because
you have so many branch points Nevin
would say will help me just don't want
to have all these branch points all the
time is this can have more branch points
correct but it could potentially reduce
total size of each of those buds
there's the bending of the plants less
stress on plants and pruning just his
name implies the branches are bent to
the ground and staked and play
this can be used to kind of jump plants
around it's called tip propagation used
with raspberries sometimes this is not
quite the full bending the plants
technique but gives you the idea of kind
of setting that plant up potentially to
go to that technique now it's more
commonly those plans so they get close
to the light source with a limited
ceiling height so you know that one
branch is getting a little bit high and
kind of branch it kind of Bend that
branch over to keep it away from the
light but not lose anything on that
particular side shoot there's a sea of
green SOG focuses on flowering plants
early can be done at one foot or about
thirty centimeters tall with the goal of
producing fewer but larger buds which is
kind of an example here come with town
and grow spaces that are growing a high
plant density then there's a screen of
green and this uses mesh screen netting
it's layered horizontally you see here
above the plants and the growing tips
grow through that material typically
players must remain in a vegetative
state a little bit longer several more
weeks than the previous sea of green
that I had mentioned so again this is an
outdoor operation a little bit better
for this area look not quite as height
limited a little bit longer growing
season so again you have to choose what
fits your particular operation there's
something called lolli popping and this
is a technique that involves removing
the lower growth of the plant that
receives little to no light could see
this down the whole grow facility the
goal is to have plants make the most
uses energy it produces by having it
focus on the upper buds and branches
timing of the photo period flip is based
on cultivar and height for plants make
the slips for indicas about three three
and a half feet to revive more time for
the vegetative state and sativas you tip
some we want to flip maybe a little bit
earlier they're almost sometimes half
the height since they can grow much
taller during the flowering phase this
might be a little bit specific to the
particular cultivars you are growing
within the indica of the city folk
classification lastly here we have super
cropping the goals produced very heavy
yields with minimal number of plants
it's accomplished this by the plants
that yield that are held higher in the
vegetative phase longer super cropping
involves bending the upper branches see
here this 90 degree angle occurs right
here down so it allow for more light
to reach deeper into lower parts of the
plant but keeping the plant material
away from the lights this allows the
extended vegetative phase with minimal
leaf burn and this is referred to as
super cropping