here I'll be providing a little
background and Pythium also known as
damping off and with the picture here in
the title slide this is a disease that
particularly attacks the roots or the
root structure of plants so it's
important to be able to find a way to
inspect those if you suspect that your
crop is infected with Pythium so first
off identification so there's different
species of Pythium but they all have
similar preferred conditions that's very
common in younger plants or seedlings as
we see here can reduce the germination
rate when using seeds now what's kind of
unique about this disease is well we
have an entire flat here of plants
growing UT Pythium will affect certain
areas so it may not be widespread and
infect all plants but it may occur in
small pockets now if you find a pocket
here where plants are becoming infected
you look closer at those seedlings
typically if you look at the base the
stem and soil point of intersection is
where you'll see this kind of browning
and discoloration this can include
plants that are wilting we have a yellow
coloration to their leaves and the key
part here is to you see that in a plant
especially a seedling inspect this soil
line to see if you see conditions that
look like this above the soil might be
perfectly green but at that soil line
typically the air you find that now this
disease is very rarely found in soilless
mixes but can be easily unintentionally
inoculated by growers using either dirty
tools from an infected area or ever
using some soil are having very cool
temperatures in their ceiling flats now
again where to look it's encouraged by
over watering and poor drainage so you
want to look at that soil line the root
tips are often brown and dead resulting
in stunted plants this brown tissue and
the outer portion of it easily pulls off
leaving strand of vascular tissue
exposed so if you do see this you do go
physically kind of rub your fingers
around this typically that very outer
coating will come off very easily and if
you're looking at a quick inspection
look right at that soil lines can see
that Brown ring that's an indication you
could have Pythium or damping off how to
prevent this keeping tools and interiors
clean and sterile
important control fungus gnat larvae
these can aid in this spread of Pythia
I'm especially growing conditions this
is where control onion insect can help
prevent a disease for flood and drain
setups a strain filters recommend to
prevent media from flowing into the
reservoir which can carry the disease
that way and of inoculate on sadly your
reservoir conditions at paper Pythium
are high salts over watering in wet
weather conditions and we mat have
control over all of those keeping in
mind that these are areas that you can
look at to on records and documentation
may be doing to see if you are kind of
falling into one of these categories if
you have fast drying growing media that
may be a way to discourage the formation
Pythium and a way for you to prevent it
we see again in this image here we're
receiving that kind of initial area kind
of spreading out but not affecting all
plants you never see Pythium infected
roots compared to what normal or healthy
look roots should look like
seems he definitely is that reduction in
total root area that's also going to
affect the above-ground growth how to
control it what's difficult to control
once it's established make sure
irrigation water is clean in the sense
it's disease-free this is a particularly
important for using recirculated water
fungicides can be an option but use them
with caution and follow labels
instructions and they may not offer a
great level of control see here with
port cities where one area is infected
and other plants are not in this case
you might have removed these plants and
definitely ensure that the water from
these plants it's not going through and
infecting the entire crop in this grove
facility