all right in this debacle university
video we're going to be
looking at questions to ask when
selecting a cannabis strain to grow
there's a lot of options out there
there's many different types
but what are some questions you could
should be asking yourself
as far as knowing your conditions
knowing your environment to be able to
try to select a strain
that will grow well in your area so
let's get into some of the questions to
consider
now some of them be looking at one of
the first steps to determine is the area
you will be growing in
how large is it or how many plants so
this might play into the number of
varieties you might be choosing
uh the height of the plants you know how
large how many if you're doing any
trials
questions to really list realistically
take a look at
then you also want to have an idea if
what your goal
end product will be can also influence
your selection
meaning are you looking at the very end
to produce quality dry flour or will
your
end product be going for extraction that
may play into the
type of flower that you're looking at
producing whether it's going to be kind
of a flower that's going to be visually
appealing
in large maybe or maybe a lot of small
flowers that are ultimately going to go
to extraction because no one's actually
going to see
the actual plant material at the end
then the plant morphologies this is
an important consideration because when
you're considering your area
you also want to consider the plant
morphology should be considered
remember the plant morphology is asking
questions like how tall will the plant
get
will it need frequent pruning does it
take a long time to grow when
does it produce the maximum flower
production how long should i let it go
how long after i flip it into a
flowering photo period
will it be expected to expand to have a
tendency to produce fewer buds but
larger buds more buds and smaller
may that affect my pruning strategy so
again all of these
ideas need to be taken into
consideration this is just the basic
morphology or structure of the plant
then it's also considering your
environment are you not height
limited you know can the plants get
however tall that they
that they can you know is there a
ceiling it's going to limit a grow tent
potentially to limit that
so if you're not ceiling height limited
this could lead to the selection of more
sativa dominant strains because they
have a tendency to stretch more
however just because you have the height
and particularly an outdoor situation
doesn't mean you need to you'd
necessarily utilize it
if you're growing outdoors tall plants
may be subject to late season wind storm
damage that's an important consideration
also more plant material may increase
the need for pruning which may increase
your expenses in both
labor and time so again just because
you're not height limited does not mean
you automatically select
the largest tallest growing plant
now just obvious consideration is are
going to be growing indoors or are you
going to be growing outdoors
so looking at the location potential of
seasonal timing
particularly for outdoor growing can
influence the strain selection
would you go with in the general
category the photodependent
true sativas or indicas or an autoflower
there's rudalus
where they're going to flower based on
the number of days
old and that could influence based on
the timing that you might be growing
outdoors
depending on what the conditions might
be repeating an indoor environment you
might be able to manipulate the lighting
a little bit more than say the outdoor
environment
now the autoflower remember you're going
to count the days for the autoflowers
they offer the advantage of knowing how
many days until flower and harvest for
planting purposes
however this will this offers the
greatest yield since the plants tend to
be smaller overall so it's important
consideration that
oh i don't have to worry about flower
and photo period i can put them in my
indoor whatever i got some veg
plants i got some flowering plants the
root owls or the autoflowers won't care
but because they tend to have smaller
plants will that offer the yield
that you're looking for these can be
limiting as there's a set of number or
fixed
days of plant production so can you
maximize each day
it's also important consideration there
where because there's only a limited
number of days
every day lost could be a greater
percentage of that plant's life or the
photoperiod dependent ones
you could always delay or shift when you
change from a vegetative
photo period to that flowering photo
period
so why not select the highest cbd
producing
plant looking at the strains i just want
the highest cbd producer
most growers will easily be drawn to a
strain that has the biggest numbers of
cbd or certain terpenes maybe
however this should be a consideration
but not the only consideration
as you need to know if you can maximize
plant production based on environmental
factors
just because a plant can produce a very
high cbd percentage
does not mean it will produce giving
your certain growing conditions so you
may want to be selecting one
that morphologically is a better fit
initially so you can get kind of
growing in some of the experiences with
that so you're not just getting the
highest cbd producer and maybe
having to deal with a very hard to
manage
plant morphology or one that requires
special pruning so again these are just
some of the questions you should be
asking
instead of just kind of randomly
selecting there are a lot of options
which is great
you need to need to be wise and select
the correct option
that best fits your growing conditions