welcome to this debaco University
follow-up video from one of our previous
student series with Kira looking at
rabbit damage so here we're going to
look at rabbit damage on Kim's plant
with a follow-up on how to mitigate and
help get these plants to harvest
[Music]
now here it's the return of the rabbits
so while they're nice and small they
were doing quite a large bit of damage
and there was fencing around the entire
area but it had simply had too many
points of entry for the small rabbits
it's like any good grower you're going
to analyze the situation and develop a
method try to mitigate that
analyzing the situation that seemed like
there was a concentrated area for this
damage so individual plant protective
measures were put in place to help
Savage the Salvage the plants and these
plants were of the Fairly large size
luckily the rabbits hadn't come in
earlier they can simply just mow down
the entire plant and again while rabbits
are small they could still damage fully
grown cannabis plants so it kind of had
reminiscent themes of the Monty Python
rabbit there where it's able to take
down and Destroy something very much
much larger than the rabbit itself
so the overall method is very quick
which is kind of key it's a simple
method which doesn't take much time
which makes it more likely to be
implemented simply putting an arbor
guard tree trunk protector as we can see
right here with a zip tie or on the stem
ground level the reason why they're so
cost effective they only cost about two
dollars and fifty cents to under two
dollars per guard and it simply depends
on how many you buy as far as the price
for the plants that had damage a simple
stake here we can see right on the side
and a rope was support was added watch
out for drip lines though under the weed
barrier when you're punching that stake
in the ground always find a way to kind
of find one or two so make sure you
repair that if you do or do move it away
at the beginning before you do go
through and punch the stake in this can
be put around other plants too to
prevent the issue from happening as a
preventative as well
now these are here it's going to
demonstrate just kind of how they look
on the actual plant they are meant also
to keep line trimmers from damaging tree
trunks so they are pretty uh rigid they
are pretty solid and they can be
utilized from year to year I would just
recommend you sterilize them so let's go
out to the field there and let's hear
from Kira about our follow-up on our
rabbit damage
this is a continuation of our bunny
damage video a few weeks ago a bunny
came through and Nod on the bottom of
our beautiful cannabis plant here and
resulted in actually falling down and so
our response to this was to put a collar
on the bottom of our plant to make sure
that the bunnies can't come through and
start gnawing on this again that perfect
bunny level
and another thing that we did was add
supports since this was like I said
trampled to the ground pretty much we it
needed extra support and to be able to
keep itself upright if we didn't add
these Stakes then it would still be on
the ground when this plant fell this
Branch specifically endured a lot of
damage I mean it's pretty much almost
completely severed from the plant other
than the connection right here and so
while most people would see this Branch
almost completely severed and just
decide to remove it sometimes it'll
choose to survive with this super super
cropping method and all of these
branches here as you can see will
actually start facing up towards the Sun
so that all of the buds can receive
proper light it's called tropism and it
causes the plants to look up to the sky
towards the light so even though this
plant received extreme amounts of damage
and this branch almost completely fell
off you can still see that it is
thriving even though it has been damaged
very heavily