and this debacle University video The
Rack or screen drying system for
cannabis will be covered so you can have
an understanding and depth on this
particular drying method
[Music]
all right as the image shows here let's
get into Rack or screen drying system
for cannabis and the rack system we see
here the canvas is usually sitting on
screens that's why these are
interchangeable names
so first off in general the drying
process is critical after all the work
of growing and harvesting the goals to
maximize the quality of the end product
that's produced and while you cannot
create a high quality end product in the
drying process you can certainly lose
what started out as a high quality
product if not performed correctly so
you want to do everything right up to
this point but don't lose it at the end
take the time learn the drying process
in the curing process and make sure
those are done correctly so you can take
your quality cannabis Buds and turn them
into high quality dried buds
now the drying racks as I mentioned
racks are often used in more commercial
settings where there is a high volume of
plant material to dry in space wants to
be utilized efficiently want to be very
efficient with the space that you're
using drying racks also reduce the risk
of contamination to develop by ensuring
efficient air circulation amongst the
buds and we have another crack that can
be placed on top that's very easily
stackable while still able to maintain
good level of air circulation
the rack system also offers the ability
to Aid with organization in the sense
that same quality buds can be placed on
the same rack but it's in the same plant
but it's in the same grow it just helps
overall with the organization process
there
now the construction of the racks
themselves is the goal is to have an
efficient and repeatable system that is
standardized we see that located right
here very consistent rack to Rack screen
to screen area to area while there is no
true correct size uh there can be large
and or small and it can still be
efficient that's depending on the
dimensions of your room the amount of
plate material you'll be drawing at the
same time and a few other factors as
well however the goals are not overly
packed racks since airflow is an
important component of for the system to
operate correctly I want to make sure
we're having everything operate
efficiently in general while light
levels should be kept to a minimum the
rack system offers natural shading of
the buds as we see here but we do want
to keep these lights minimal we want to
keep them on for a short duration as
well as the intensity of those lights we
want to be very minimal because we don't
want to risk degrading any of the buds
that we may be having in the precious
cannabinoids or terpenes
now when it comes to developing your
rack or screen system you don't want to
cut Corners setting up a rack system may
come with upfront cost which after the
growth and production of the actual crop
there may not be a lot of money on at
this point in production but don't skimp
on this particular system however many
of the costs will not be reoccurring so
that's a good thing and properly drying
the final product is critical to getting
the best price possible so do not go for
an inferior system don't go for over
packing a system subcar materials some
can be very cost effective as we see
right here some can be more expensive
but easier to sterilize so just be
mindful of the system you're choosing
and make sure that you're getting one
that's not going to put your final crop
here at any sort of undue risk
now theoretically there is no size limit
with these systems while a drying rack
system there's really no size limit in
any Dimension however make sure the
entire area of the racks take up is
climate controlled and I put a little
note here this can be a challenge with
very tall systems to make sure the
lowest and the highest racks are under
the same conditions with minimal
variability you don't want to have these
be really wet and needs to be really dry
you want to make sure you're getting
even air circulation from the very top
of the drying area to also the very
bottom of the drying area and again
while no theoretical size limit the goal
here is to keep these conditions
consistent as possible
now you do want to trim the flowers so
before setting the flowers to dry some
care should be taken to perform at least
an initial rough trim to reduce the
space each takes up and help aid in air
circulation around each bud and offer
even drying and this is no matter what
system using viewing the tray system the
circular system the stackable system
that is just general good
recommendations there so that you have
an efficient and effective drying rack
or screen system for your facility