here on this debaco university video i'm
going to be going over
radish use in organic farming systems
[Music]
okay if you're wondering how you might
want to incorporate radish in organic
farming systems
this is a little research article that
i'm going to provide a great summary of
so first off that article this is that
if you want to look at it in more detail
but for the citation right here
so if you want to look at some more of
the specifics
here is your resource to look at too i'm
going to provide a summary here
so first off the radish seed stock well
when we're looking
at our radishes there are currently
two radish varieties that are marketed
for cover cropping
with certified genetics graza raza
and tillage radish all radishes
are insect pollinated and
cross-pollinate easily increasing the
likelihood of genetic variability
if not grown in strict isolation of one
another
so the effects on soil structure well
when we're looking at under favorable
conditions
roots can actually extend three feet
deep in only 60 days
the root commonly referred to as a tuber
even though it's not botanically correct
can extend more than 12 inches after
radishes winter kill their large fleshy
roots
desiccate and the channels created by
those roots tend to remain
open at the soil surface this opening
that we can see
located right over here created by those
roots
tend to allow for improving of
infiltration surface drainage
and also aid in soil warming all great
benefits
however radishes can also have effect on
weeds a good stand of radishes can
eliminate nearly all weed growth both
during and for some time after active
radish growth
the to obtain near complete weed
suppression radishes should be planted
early
basically six or more weeks before frost
at relatively high population densities
which is considered to be more than five
plants
per square foot into a clean seed bed
so they don't really compete well
initially depending on that clean seed
bed you can have kind of those kind of
suppression weed suppression allopathic
effects
even post radish removal or death
now the effects on seed bed preparation
well after winter kill
or other causes of mortality radish
residues deteriorate rapidly
as a result fall biomass production is
unlikely to interfere with spring
field work which is a great thing unlike
some other cover crops
so when we're looking here at the dates
this is basically the month of
april and we're looking at volumetric
soil
concentration and then we're looking at
daily range of soil temperature
we're seeing rye compared to a radish
here
now the rye tends to have colder soil
temps than the radish overall
so that can be important for spring
planting we're trying to get that soil
warmed up
quicker to get germination here we're
looking at no cover crop forage radish
and rye
rye being up here and then down here
being the forage rash that volumetric
soil water concentration so we're
reducing the amount of water in that
soil learning to infiltrate more
in the early spring that is what can
help allow our soils to warm
up we're removing some of that water now
we see here at the end must have been
some rain events that occurred
but for the most part reducing that
moisture can allow that
ability for growers to go into a field
earlier
that effects on soil erosion and runoff
so radishes grow rapidly when planted in
late summer or early fall
and 10 pounds acre drilled on a 7.5 inch
rose can provide
full canopy enclosure in about 3 weeks
this canopy interrupts raindrops
minimizing surface impaction
and detachment of soil particles
decomposing residue
due to winter kill can still provide
early spring
erosion control all great things we look
at it kind of here in soil loss in
pounds per acre at farm a and farm b
we can see no cover crop versus cover
crop being a radish
the erosion from the three february to
march storms was negligible
for forage rash despite rapidly
decomposition soil surface residues here
so we can see just clearly here two
different farms the massive difference
that the incorporation of radish as a
cover crop
can impact on the reduction in soil loss
and as we all know
soil is very important so anyways we can
reduce erosion and runoff
are good things lastly there are some
potential problems so not everything is
perfect because radishes have little
tons for wet soils
so radishes are very responsive to
nitrogen and nitrogen deficiency limits
their ability to compete with weeds
and grow through compacted soil so not
great to put into a really severely
nitrogen deficient
field rashes are only moderately cold
hearty and need about six weeks of
favorable growing conditions to produce
sufficient biomass
to achieve most of the potential
benefits so again keep that in mind as
well
as a warning rotting radishes residues
can produce a powerful
rotten egg-like kind of sulfur-like odor
particularly during winter thaws
if you have neighbors close by and are
planting in high densities
that could potentially cause you some
problems so just be aware of that with
everything there is a
benefit and there can also be some
drawbacks so just want you to be fully
aware before you commit to this entirely
but definitely worth some consideration
for some of the benefits but also keep
in mind some of those drawbacks