okay you've gotten your soil test back
and you're looking at your ph
value and if you need to raise it or
lower it
this debaco university video will help
you
with that process
all right let's look at raising and
lowering ph values
based on your soil test results well
first off you have to know what your
plant prefers because there is no ideal
ph across all plants there is ideal ph
for different plants
some like very acidic moderately acidic
slightly acidic or sometimes even
very alkaline we can see a list here of
plant preferred ph's
the optimum ph is based on the plant
species you are growing
most garden plants prefer a soil ph
between 6.0 and 6.8
just to give you a general range this
includes cannabis however hydroponic
growers tend to favor
a slightly more acidic end of that range
of 5.5
to 6.5 notable exceptions are
acid-loving blueberries which prefer a
ph
of around 4.5 to 5.3 potato varieties
without scab resistance are also grown
in lower ph
and by lower ph i mean the 5.2 to 5.4
range
simply put to inhibit the growth of this
disease organism
so again look at the different lists
here see what target ph range you will
be targeting to match
your particular plant now also region
can impact
ph geographic area can also influence
native soil ph generally soil ph by
region on the east coast here we're
looking at usually the 4.8 to 5.5 range
midwest you're talking that six to six
and a half in the southwest around that
7.5 to 8.5
so depending on the region of country
that you live in here in the united
states
you might be looking at more of
looking at raising your ph maybe more
lowering your ph there
now getting your plants to that optimum
ph range how does that kind of play into
things here
well you will likely need to raise or
lower your soil's ph to reach the
optimum levels for your plants
and again we're looking at trying to be
as close to that optimal range
as possible because you could get into
toxic or root damaging conditions
or also poor nutrition based on the
nutrients not being available to your
plants
so if you want to raise this oil ph well
you're looking at typically adding
a limestone so ground limestone is
commonly used to help
raise soil's ph lab
soil testing labs will often offer
recommendations that's based on the
actual ph
the plants being grown and the buffering
capacity of the soil
so it's good to use their
recommendations at least as a good
starting point
typically the lower the ph in the more
clay and organic matter in the soil
the greater amount of limestones
required to raise the soil ph to the
target level
that'd be important if you're looking at
comparing different fields they might be
at the same ph level
but why does the lab recommend different
results for one versus another
it could have to do with the particular
content
of that soil now we're making limestone
applications just in general limestone
recommendations by the soil lab are made
in tons per acre
or can be pounds per hundred or pounds
per thousand square feet
so know the square foot of the area of
growth space that you'll be growing in
limestone needs to react with the soil
so it's highly recommended to be tilled
incorporated into the soil in some way
we don't just want to go through apply
it to the surface and then walk away
can you apply it to the surface that's
fine and then go through making sure
you're working it into that soil
if you're not going to incorporate lime
then apply no more than 50 to 75 pounds
per thousand square feet
or five to seven and a half pounds per
hundred square feet to the soil surface
at any one time reapply one to six
month intervals until the total
recommendation is administered
and that's again important for that
surface application you don't want to
create a solid little
layer of that you want to give it some
time to kind of work in hopefully with
rain events
into that soil profile now what we're
looking at are
limestone options while it is all
limestone there are actually additional
options
the main two being either powdered or
pelletized
this will take several months to a year
for soil ph to increase
i have moved ph in winter months so it
doesn't necessarily take a full calendar
year
however it is possible to move a full
point even over winter months as i
mentioned
if you're using powdered lime is applied
and tilled into the soil
because the pelletized while it's the
same type of lime
that powdered lime can be a little more
quicker acting because it's got a
greater surface area so it can come in
contact with the soda particles a little
quicker
but it is much more difficult to apply
the pelletized line the little pellets
here is much
easier to apply but may take longer to
adjust the ph
why this be the same if they're both
limestone well they're essentially both
limestone
but inside a small coating here of the
pelletize
to make the application easier as a
result that coating causes a slight
delay
as the coating dissolves before it can
kind of start to adjust the soil ph
so just keep that in mind now the option
options within limestone more than just
the type of kind of
pelletized or powdered we also have
options
here of dolomitic calcitic and hydrated
so many gross things there's just lime
but there's actually three main types
there's dolomitic limestone which is
calcium carbonate plus magnesium
carbonate
this is the most commonly found lime
contains elevated levels of magnesium
which can be an added bonus for some
growers then there's
calcitic lime which is which is a
calcium carbonate it's often called high
cal lime
and it lacks those high levels of
magnesium it's used if magnesium levels
are determined to already be at the
optimum
level then there's hydrated lime which
is calcium hydroxide
it's a very quick acting lime it may
change the ph quickly
but keep in mind that while it may do
that it does not have as long residual
and change and alteration of the ph as
the other lime options mentioned
also a hydrated lime is a mucous
membrane irritant so be careful if
you're applying it
it can really irritate your nose your
mouth anywhere and it's very
especially if it's powdered just be
mindful when you're going through and
apply it and that's why you'll typically
see the big label here
warning keypad reach of children and
read the label for cautions
now in the opposite case of the lime
we're now looking at we're going to
lower the soil's ph with that we need a
soil acidifier
which is typically sulfur or ferrous
sulfate
these are often recommended to lower ph
just as we saw with the limestone these
recommendations are usually offered
in tons per acre or pounds per hundred
or thousand square feet
so it's important to know your growing
space depending on what the soil
is made out of or what the components
are
it may alter the lowering ph the sulfur
recommendations
both of these compounds though do need
to react with the soil just like the
lime
does so it's important to incorporate it
into the soil profile
however you're not going to be
incorporating it the sulfur should be
applied no more than 400 pounds to the
acre so this
at the soil surface any one time uh to
establish plants
per year just to give you an idea sulfur
in that fair
sulfate so keep in mind that elemental
sulfur
spring applications and incorporation
work best since the acidification
process
is based on soil biology and not a
chemical reaction
soil temperatures should be above 55
degrees fahrenheit
and have good aeration so the bacteria
can be active and
cause that now reduction in ph if this
feels anaerobic or water logged
the sulfur gets converted into hydrogen
sulfide which actually can damage
plants that's why you want it to be
aerated and well drained now
ferrous sulfate is more costly to use in
sulfur
it's eight times uh you need eight times
more fair sulfa is needed in elemental
sulfur
however it is quicker acting than sulfur
so again pros and cons depending on what
type of
area you might be dealing with now you
want to avoid aluminum sulfate and
sulfuric acid because these seem like
they might be good options
but aluminum sulfate can be toxic to
certain plants for example blueberries
if high rates are applied irrigating
with dilute sulfuric acid can lower the
soil ph
but can damage plants and can corrode
metal pipes fittings
and irrigation systems so while these
sound like they would lower ph and
technically they will
there's some negative side effects that
don't allow them to really be made
recommended in an agricultural type
setting
lastly as i mentioned before you want to
follow the lab recommendations is
based on the lab that you select they're
going to take the ph they're going to
take your soil type they're going to
take buffering capacities
and they're going to go through and kind
of utilize all those factors
to give you a good recommendation if you
don't necessarily 100 agree with that
recommendation you might want to favor
maybe on the slightly lower side
or really use their recommendation as a
good starting point
and then see how your soil reacts over
time and base your repeated applications
on that so hopefully this was helpful
and allowing you to understand if you
want to raise or lower
your soil ph