for any products regarding cannabis that
you're looking at consuming
getting an analytical report is very
important
this video here in debaco university
though is going to provide you with uh
organized sequence of steps to go about
how to properly read as well as
understand
what those reports are actually able to
tell you
[Music]
all right so here we're going to go
about reading and understanding an
analytical report
for cannabis products it does apply to
a whole host of canvas products not just
dry flour
so what is this certificate of analysis
typically abbreviated
coa well cuas are a document generated
by
a licensed lab that shows the analytical
test results
on a cannabis sample these are used to
confirm the potency as well as the
purity
while also ensuring safety for
consumption and that's really important
be aware that some states may have
different testing requirements different
labs may have different layouts
but for the most part the generalness of
what i'll talk about here
will be applicable so first off why is
testing just
important just in general well it
provides the consumer
with a report that is transparent
unbiased
and ensures a safety safe product in the
end
so a lot of people will look at the
certificate of analysis go right to what
the cbd or tht levels are and forget
about
the rest sometimes look at the terpenes
but there's a lot more information than
just those
that's important to be able to recognize
so first off verifying an analytical lab
report
so calling the lab that the product was
tested by and provide them with a
certificate
id we see a client id we see
names we see license numbers we see that
sample id
all these little numbers and letters and
kind of all are important
so provide with that sample id kind of
like right here
as shown on the particular analysis
which they use to verify the lab report
is authentic
you give them their sample id and they
should be to tell you you know the
grower or the client id or the date that
was tested
avoid anything that's listed as what's
called an in-house test
as this has a high potential for bias if
they're testing their own product
companies are more likely to skew the
numbers in their favor
third-party lab reports usually have
special markings on it which does not
allow others to duplicate
and often will have signatures also also
associated with them
so third-party lab testing well what is
that kind of referring to why is that
important
third-party testing means that their
products are tested by labs that are not
affiliated with them
hence the term third party just because
the company mentions that it doesn't
mean you shouldn't look for the lab
report to analyze before purchasing
because any product
can just be tested so getting making
sure it's a third-party test
is important the whole purpose of
getting proc process
these products tested i should say by
third parties labs
is to show that the consistency of the
product contains the actual advertised
information
and also most of all the the
transparency is important
since growing a hemp and extracting cbd
is a complex process
it's critical to make sure that the
product of a consumer's purchasing is
safe for them to ingest
that's only possible with the
confirmatory results of a third
party test so with some common testing
terminology as i said different labs
might use different terminology
but you see the word the letters nd
typically refers to as non-detectable
this non-detectable means that it does
not mean it's not
present but it is not able to be
detected with the equipment being used
so it's kind of below detectable levels
now it could be zero
but it's below detectable levels a lot
of times you'll see a ppm that simply
stands for parts per million
blq is below level of quantification
denotes concentrations so small that
they do not meet the qualifying
threshold for cannabinoid content
then there's loq which is the limit of
quantification
this is the smallest concentration that
can be accurately quantified
lod is the limit of detection
and this is the smallest amount of
cannabinoid or cannabinoids that can be
detected by the instrument
unless we have loss on drawing that
might be stated and that simply tests
for the percentages of water content
in the final product so this gives you
some idea some of the terminology you
might see on these examples as well as
others
so let's get into the find the full
analytical report and this is on
the consumer's kind of shoulders there
many companies
post the coas of their products on their
website for all to see which is great
if a product does not have a coa
available it is advisable for consumers
to not buy that product and
is effectively untested usually the full
sale will not be on a product's label
but the potency testing will to view the
full coa consumers should be able to
find the qr code on the label
which should take them to the company's
website with the full coa and at the
very least if this is not possible
it should be available upon request any
consumers looking at purchasing anything
canvas related should request a coa and
it should be provided to them if it's
not
simply do i would not advise buying that
particular product
now the cannabinoid analysis again some
things that you might see well the
active ingredients in canvas should be
clearly labeled as it ensures that
growers can verify
the quality of their product so the
cannabinoid analysis that's where a lot
of growers will
consumers will look and that's great but
just keep in mind there is more than
just the cannabinoid analysis to take
into consideration
and again we're seeing some of those
levels uh those abbreviations mentioned
here they have microbial contaminations
so this uh is the bacteria mold and our
yeast
present in the sample predetermined
containment limits are established for
each
expressed in what's called cfu g which
stands for colony forming units per gram
colony forming units per gram
example limit would be less than 500 000
cfus per gram just as a random example
there
most test results simply list pass or
fail as a result meaning were they below
or above that threshold they're above
that threshold would be a failure
test and if they were below that
threshold they'd be getting a passing
mark there
and this keep in mind that just because
the sample may look clean
and looks moldy just because it looks
clean doesn't necessarily
mean it will still pass one of these
microbial tests or analyses
then there's aflatoxins which are very
concerning they're a type of mycotoxin
produced by certain types of molds and
fungi
they're very dangerous and have been are
potent carcinogens which you
uh which is why you want to identify to
ensure that your canvas has no
aflotoxins
in it to ensure that it's safe at least
for this particular category
then the terpene profile and analysis
and this is getting a lot of
popularity amongst consumers terpenes
are a set of simple organic molecules
present in
living organisms most of the flavors and
aromas of the plants derived from their
terpenes
you can find icing and diamond hops and
lemonade and citrus fruits as well as
other
terpenes are not unique to cannabis but
a lot of times provided in the cannabis
analytical report
plants produce terpenes naturally to
attract pollinators which is why it's
found in more than just cannabis
as well as to repair predators or
herbivores as well
so there are other advantages to the
plants producing these
in cannabis they've been selected for
the potential for different effects
or smells or aromas there's also heavy
metal testing analysis so cannabis can
be a bioaccumulator of heavy metals
these include but not limited to mercury
arsenic and cadmium and lead
any amounts of heavy metals present will
be listed here
and again just like the microbial test
these will simply reset at a pass
or a fail here so if it's below
detectable levels non-detectable
this status here would be a passing mark
for on the arsenic the cadmium the
mercury in the lead in this example
there's also pesticide analysis so this
is where the challenge with pesticide
residue or analysis in cannabis is the
concentration difference between the
pesticide residues and those
co-extracted cannabinoids and terpenes
here we're seeing units listed in the
ppb so ppm is parts per million
in this case there needs to be
sufficient sensitivity for these
uh pesticides to the detection to the
ppb or parts per
billion level so if they're going to be
present in really small
amounts here we're still seeing a
passing which is great but we have to be
mindful of using the parts per billion
unit when it comes to pesticide testing
analysis
and again now we see a great extensive
list provided here
simply can't test for every single
pesticide so a lot of the common ones
are provided here
but just keep that in mind that no lab
is testing for every single possible
pesticide
you want to see a comprehensive list and
of course a passing mark
for all of the pesticides tested or
listed
so they're all below the non-detectable
levels
to get a passing mark for the pesticide
test analysis