in this debaco university video we're
going to go out in the greenhouse and
we're going to show you how to recognize
a nitrogen deficiency in cannabis plants
now to correct this nitrogen deficiency
if you wanted one of the pure nitrogen
fertilizers
urea calcium nitrate or blood meal would
be great options there's other videos on
that within this channel as well as how
to calculate 100 parts per million to
feed your plants but this just shows
when you get a little bit on the skinny
side on nitrogen what the plant response
will be so you can recognize it quickly
and make corrections
[Music]
okay so after looking at these plants
here we can notice there is some
yellowing of those lower leaves and this
is characteristic of a nitrogen
deficiency you can see how
yellowing those lower leaves get the
newer upper growth stays green because
nitrogen is a mobile nutrient so when
we're looking at a plant and see those
lower leaves kind of get that yellow to
that limey green coloration that's the
sign we've got a mobile nutrient issue
those older leaves are sacrificing their
nutrients for the lush newer growth so
this is a good sign or an indication we
need to up our nitrogen fertilizer for
these plants
again as we can see here those lower
leaves get that yellowy to almost brown
but that newer upper growth maintains
that nice lush green growth which is
what we want to see that's simply that
nitrogen moving from the older leaves to
that newer leaves a good indication that
nitrogen fertilizer is a little bit
lacking in this particular grow so
they're upping their fertilizer and that
should help correct the problem
the
leaves that are this severe and
yellowing probably will not re-green but
those that are more of the limey green
color
compared to the darker green color so
this kind of this type of
lighter green compared to this green
those have a chance at greening out
that's saying they will but hopefully
will stop the progression of any more
yellowing throughout that plant and
throughout the other plants in this
entire greenhouse