ever look at your cannabis plant stigmas
and wonder if that can help you
determine
how ripe or when harvest should be for
your plants
well here i'm going to go over on this
debaco university video
recognizing how to look at those visual
cues of those stigmas
to try to give you some indication of
how close you are
to peak harvest
[Music]
all right let's get into recognizing the
visual cues of cannabis plants
stigmas related to harvesting so first
off
early development so stigmas start out
as white and this is when they are the
most receptive to
pollen this is when you definitely want
to keep any male plants or pollen away
from them
because this is when they're most
receptive to pollen they're the
stickiest
so to speak they're the most the
freshest so the most likely try to go
through and capture
any random pollen grains that are
existing around them and i say they
start out white
some cultivar some varieties will kind
of have more of a slight different
coloration in this case a little pinkish
hue
if you will a rosy glow so most will be
white
but keep in mind there are some
variabilities and that's a great thing
to see
with the diversity of different types of
cannabis plants but there'll be this
kind of
lighter coloration now as we get into
kind of the progression
of those stigmas as they age they will
start to turn a kind of a blonde
brownish kind of tannish color and here
we can see some that are still in white
in coloration
we're starting to see some getting those
kind of like tannish brownish
colorations as well and this is a sign
they don't all do not turn at once
this is a sign of that progression that
aging that's occurring
becoming less receptive to pollen at
this point they're kind of like drying
out
and this is where growers will probably
be shifting over to these structures
which are
trichomes and i have a separate video on
that if you want to learn more about
looking at determining the peak harvest
looking at trichomes
so getting into that near harvest kind
of stigma color there
well as harvest gets closer the
percentage of the brown stimulus will
increase
to the point of nearly 100 percent i say
nearly
might have a couple that just kind of
like to stay white for whatever reason
but nearly 100 percent while this may
not be the main visual signal used to
determine the point of harvest
it can be a valuable indication of the
overall plant progress
towards peak harvest reason being yes
you can look at the trichomes typically
you need to have a little bit of a
magnify and kind of zoom in on those
but the stigmas here kind of provide a
quick if you're walking down an area
looking quick in an
area uh usually a little bit more of a
predominant structure there
and help give you that indication of the
progression
of the development of that particular
flower so you can make a comparison with
on the same plant
or within multiple plants to ensure
you're trying to hit that peak
harvest without getting any degradation
of the valuable cannabinoids or terpenes
that your cannabis plant might be
producing