on this debaco university video we're
going to look at reducing fungus gnats
with the use of rice hulls we're going
to go out in the greenhouse take a look
at some of the plants take a look at the
rice holes themselves and then go
through and show you a plant that's
recently been watered and how quick it
wicks away the water as a way to add a
small little physical barrier on the
subscribing substrate to help you reduce
a common problem through a very easy way
[Music]
okay if you're looking for a great way
to reduce fungus gnats using rice holes
in your containers is one way to do that
literally as you can see in these
containers we have a thin coating of
these rice holes now these rice holes
what they simply do to reduce those
fungus gnats is by reducing the surface
moisture in and around the plants by
simply breaking that moisture from
what's in the growing substrate you're
reducing that pressure of those fungus
nets and therefore eliminating a problem
through a physical means that really is
quite easy so if you've never used rice
holes before you might be wondering
what's the consistency of them
well just as you would imagine they're
very thin they're very light i'm not
going to apply an outdoor on a really
windy day but it's this thin and light
property to them that allows them not to
hold a lot of water and then allows it
to be very dry you don't need to put a
ton of these around your plants
so just enough to cover that surface
because it's going to wick and dry and
then the area below that can be wet and
moist for the roots but this top area
being dry
really is what reduces your fungus gnats
so if we look here at our container you
can see we just put just enough to cover
that surface if you look at the plant
here you can see that's the soil
substrate right there just enough of
those rice holes to cover that to keep
it nice and dry and that is really
what's going to help
keep that moisture at a minimum and
directly reduce your fungus gnats from
getting on your plants even from the
early growings of the plant okay now
here we see a plant that was just
recently watered a little hand watering
of the small plant and we can already
see those rice holes starting to dry out
so there is some pockets here they're
still holding a little bit of moisture
but again this plant was just watered
and we're already seeing that water
allowed to percolate through drying out
those rice holes so this is a great way
to want to reduce your chance of getting
fungus gnats and it's a very simple way
simply adding rice holes