something that I feel is often
overlooked by growers is the reflective
hood options or just reflect the hoods
in general for their artificial lighting
setups you can see here at double end in
here we have to 315 watt lights and here
we have a single-ended light all with
slightly different reflectors but the
whole goal is the same to help increase
the amount of light it hits the plants
and there's not lost
so these reflective hoods and this is a
single-ended one here the main goal is
to disperse light evenly across the
plant canopy and minimize that light
loss a proper reflector can increase the
growing footprint under the same light
compared if there was no reflector
utilized only about 40% of the light
goes directly from the bulb to the plant
so without reflector about 60% would be
quote lost and that sense of loss
wouldn't be hitting the plant wouldn't
be captured like a plant for the
photosynthetic process it's commonly
made from thin metal so be careful not
to damage them especially when you're
taking the light or they reflect are out
of the initial packaging well when
you're looking at a reflector you look
for the stated percent reflectivity so
reflectors leaving industry I've got
three here ones like the Vita ones by
sunlight supply and ones by demo locks
we want to have the higher percentage
what that means is you're gonna get a
better reflection so we can see this has
a greater reflection we're able to see
more of the detail here in this water
here we have a little bit lower beef
left if 'ti you're gonna see the same
general whether these spire is here
where the green light is it see it's a
much blurred image to be a lower degree
of reflectivity we have that higher
percentage indicating we're losing less
of the light that were paying for with
these artificial light setups now
cleaning the hoods clean these
reflectors new out-of-the-box reflectors
are through peak of efficiency in
communist be sure to clean the hoods to
ensure the reflectors are able to do
their job well and consistently over a
growing season or year be careful though
when you're cleaning them not to scratch
them because I could do more long-term
harm so if they do get dusty and they
will get a little tarnished in you dirty
I do want to make sure you go through
and clean them
but be careful what you clean them with
because you could do more damage
ultimately I want to replace the
reflectors could often be purchased
separately and these can increase the
light you sufficiency if clean is not
able the reflector or if it's reached
condition or it's beyond the ability to
be cleaned
a typical reflector life you're looking
at about two to four years four years is
kind of a max reflector before we want
to go through and replace that so a lot
of girls replacing bulbs every year
replacing the reflectors every other
year depending on your conditions you
might District to four years but that's
really the maximum you want to run any
reflective or enclosed reflective hoods
you want to utilize glass between the
plant and the lights we see here this
reduces the heat transfer from the bulb
to the plant I need to have the cooling
system air or sometimes liquid to help
regulate heat buildup so the bulb in our
bowels to not burn up you can see here
carbon filter pulling air through
cooling that light and then exhausting
it at the top here these air cooled
that's another would just saw this an
example of air cooled here's another
example this pulls air through ducting
to provide cooling in a sealed hood
system inexpensive and easy to operate
keep in mind the lights need a proper
temperature to operate and pulling in
cold air from the outside may not be the
best option particularly the north east
people think we're doing a good job in
the winter by pulling directly in cold
air well lights need to operate at
certain temperatures you want to cool
them which I wanted to say chill them
and this glass or plastic here will seal
up to allow this to be a controlled
environment there's horizontal
reflective hoods we see with these two
overall the most efficient reflectors
that directs half of the light downward
towards the plant they didn't have a hot
spot directly below the light sometimes
as we see here there's also additional
reflectors plate in place and this helps
reduce the kind of the bulb on hot spots
and we kind of increases reflectivity
even more to prevent the potential for
burning the plants below there's also
vertical reflector hoods
these bulbs are hung vertically which is
less efficient as a light has to travel
further before being reflected remember
that universe square law so we're going
to keep those bulbs as close to the
plant as possible without
burning them companies with parabolic
reflectors they can act like an umbrella
to help direct light I present like the
vertical mounting even though this can
increase mobile life you know quite get
as great of the mount reflecting to the
plant so you are losing some and just a
general inefficiency of the mounting of
the direction of the bulb open any
reflective hoods that we see here allow
for extra airflow reduce a chance of
overheating aluminum will transfer heat
more efficiently but Steel's often more
efficiently I should say that its deal
but often will increase the cost this
steel a little bit cheaper than aluminum
but you got a way kind of what you're
using and some companies are making
aluminum very efficiently and they're
able to transfer those out at a much
reduced cost lastly if you don't use
reflector and just go with and they can
bulb as we see here not usually
fluttering at all this allows the lights
bulbs to run cooler as a result the
bulbs to be suspending the plants to
take advantage of the 360 degrees of
light being admitted because if you
mount above the plants which it's not
advised this can increase the risk of
damage to the bulb and also increase the
amount of light loss would be about 60%
when a reflector is not used this is why
it's advised to use not only a new
reflector but when you're changing out
about every two three at max four years
so you're maximizing the light that
you're paying for to hit the plant to be
able to use for the photosynthetic
process