okay here we're investigating how the
body goes about regulating blood glucose
levels how it has ways to both raise and
also lower these glucose levels to be
able to maintain homeostasis so we're
going to focus on the organ of the
pancreas the pancreas is located behind
the stomach it secretes a number of
digestive enzymes into the small
intestine to a narrow tube however we're
going to focus on the islets of
langerhans within the pancreas which
govern
blood glucose levels insulin is a
hormone that promotes the accumulation
of glucagon in liver in triglycerides in
fat cells also there's agon which
is causes the release of stored glucose
in fat breakdown so how does this look
well if we have too much glucose in our
blood after eating for example a high
sugar carbohydrate based diet insulin
will put Lucas into cells
so insulin puts insulin into cells
basically adipose cells take up the
sugar then we exercise we don't eat for
a while this will cause a decrease in
our blood sugar levels this will then
cause the pancreas to release glucagon
which will Stu may deliver to break down
the sugar and put it into glucose and
increase our blood sugar levels now then
we consume another sugar based diet here
that'll cause insulin to be produced to
put the glucose back into cells the
exercise for a while it's the how this
goes around and around yeah some ways
where this doesn't work properly it
would be diabetes it's affected
individuals cannot take up glucose in
the blood there's type 1 and type 2
diabetes type 1 is only about 5 to 10
percent of diabetics it's an autoimmune
disorder in which the immune system
attacks the islets of langerhans this
typically developed for the age of 22
often called juvenile onset diabetes is
treated by daily injections of insulin
so here's that normal condition where
boosting insulins being received glucose
uptake a metal cell here in type 1 we
have an autoimmune disorder where a
Technos outs of linked hands insulin is
not being produced even though it's a
fully functional receptor
so through those daily injections those
individuals can help correct correct
that deficiency
however type 2 diabetes which is the
vast majority is caused by abnormally
low number of insulin receptors this
develops typically after the age of 40
and as a result is called adult onset
diabetes typically you know piece
individuals this is treated usually by
diet or exercise because there's simply
a demand low number of insulin receptors
even though infants being produced at a
normal rate yeah there's too much
glucose in the blood insulin converts
some of them of it to my kitchen so we
see our glucose in the blood
lottie's gonna want to convert some of
that to the clock again so we have our
insulin being produced there's nothing
to take some of that and put it into
glycogen to be stored
just to see that again here's our
glucose in the blood very high levels
insulin is being released taking some of
that up and storing it as glycogen now
again the opposites occurred if there's
not enough glucose in the blood glycogen
converts some of that into glucose
here's our glycogen so our gluten that
actually looks like we're going to take
this break them down and it's going to
put them into the bloodstream so again
insulin is taking blood out of the blood
vessels been into storage and glucagon
is taking that and breaking it apart so
that there is some Lucas now how the
blood glucose level changes over time
we're looking at specifically a day here
we see during our meals we have this
insulin levels increasing increasing to
help reduce the keep our blood glucose
in a very tight range as the body tries
to maintain homeostasis so initially
well this may look like very large
spikes this is occurring in a very tight
range helping the body maintain
homeostasis you can see here again our
our blood to tarp increase here's our
liver we're having an increase in blood
sugar glue guns being released we have
that low blood sugar so what increase
our blood sugar here who then is
responsible for that that's causing the
breakdown here
then our insulin is put in our glucose
into storage so into those cells this is
a result of high blood sugar insulin
want to decrease our blood sugar it's
putting it into storage and the loop
goes around and around typically you
have to eat a high sugar diet to feel a
lot of candy you may have a lot of
energy I'm feel very energetic because
you have high blood sugar insulin will
be produced innocence typically can be
related to the sugar crash reason being
insulin may overshoot and may over
produce too much and causing it decrease
in your blood sugar causing you to lose
your energy
glucagon will then take a little while
to get started to help release some of
that blood sugar and this is kind of
going back before to help your body
maintain homeostasis