here on this tobacco university video
i'm going to go over regulating humidity
in a cannabis grow facility
[Music]
all right let's go over some of the
complexities and understand a little bit
better regulating humidity in a cannabis
grow facility
all right so humidity what is humidity
well humidity is the measure of water
vapor in the air
many viewers think it's unavoidable and
while this is true to some extent if
humidity goes unregulated the plants
could
become more likely to get powdery mildew
or bud rot if levels are too high
they could also suffer from leaf burn or
water stress if the levels become too
low so what's the optimum humidity well
it's going to actually depend on the
stage of growth of your plant
the clones and vegetative are typically
higher levels of humidity and as the
plant ages in the flowering and final
weeks of flowering
the humidity level or ideal humidity
levels begins to
decrease there for a cannabis plant
now to control humidity you need control
over the
environment so to gain better control
over the growing environment growers
need to isolate their grow rooms
but air circulation is also still
important so you want to create this
kind of sealed up bubble
you want to have a way of regulating
this and
a way to kind of monitor the air flow as
well
sealing off and insulating the grow area
is one way
to get isolation from the outside
environment but it's important
regardless of the outside conditions to
make sure you are still having
air movement within the facility
temperature regulation also impacts
humidity so when we're talking about
humidity that's important
we also want to look at how humidity and
air temp kind of play off one another
temperature regulation is important for
the plants in general
but how this is accomplished can impact
the humidity levels
for air conditioning units make sure the
unit is sized appropriately to reduce
the chance of large temperature swings
from a unit
that is either too large or too small
for the growing
area the goal is to have your unit run
for consistent cycles for longer
durations to moderate the temperature
changes
you don't want it to get too hot and get
too cold and get too hot and get too
cold you want to kind of keep it
at a even keel there avoid short on and
off cycles which will reduce the life
expectancy of your air conditioning unit
and it's also not beneficial to the
plants and i'm going to wear your unit
out quicker
but you're also not going to benefit the
plants in any way
and here we're seeing when we take our
air temperature and decrease
our air temperature going from 28
degrees celsius to 24
just that change in temperature can also
impact the humidity
and we see our relative humidity
acceptable range here changing
with the temperatures now that
temperature in humidity we're looking at
the
vapor pressure deficit here temperature
humidity are inversely proportional
when the temperature goes down the
humidity is
on the increase this is why swings in
temperature impact humidity as well
which will relate to potential disease
pressures so the goal for your facility
should be consistency
monitoring your levels and knowing what
levels are your target levels
so you can be aware that you are within
that acceptable
range as i said the importance of air
circulation
so oscillating fans are a good start but
a room with a dense canopy fluorophanes
may also be needed
the goals maintain consistency across
all portions of a fully grown plant
we just want to have good air
circulation in the bottom a good air
solution to the top we want to make sure
we're mixing that air in a vertical
sense as well
as in a horizontal test sense because
air circulation is still important at
all stages
of plant development if you are using
water tanks you want to make sure that
they are being covered
you also want to be checking your water
drains because to limit the amount of
water that may naturally enter growth
space to be sure to cover
any water reservoirs you may have you
don't want to have this artificially
increasing level of humidity
also make sure that the drains are
actually draining excess water
it's not just a large puddle on the
floor sure that water is getting to that
drain and going actually down
the drain both of these may seem obvious
but are still worth
mentioning and always worth that double
check to ensure that your
reservoirs if you have any are sealed
and your drains are draining properly
for additional help you might want to
use a dehumidifier
so dehumidifiers remove moisture from
the air these units may be needed
more during the mid to late portions of
the growing season because the increase
in plant matter that you should have in
your growing facility
make sure that it is a commercial grade
not a residential homeowner
a great dehumidifier residential models
while cheaper
are also electrically inefficient and do
not hold up under the workload of a grow
room with a lot of transpiration
occurring with your plants
a proper dehumidifier will save you
money in the long run
though proper humidity control and as a
result to reduce potential loss
from disease so really it's important if
you need a dehumidifier you get a
commercial one
one set or size for your facility
because it can really save you a lot in
the long run
so where does this humidity come from i
talked about and it's from the plants
well plants transpire about 97 percent
of the water they absorb so 90 of the
water comes up
and out the stomata of the leaves
growers are suggested to have multiple
units to properly regulate the humidity
you want to have one big unit in the
corner you want to have multiple units
to ensure that there's an
even distribution or control over the
humidity in
a growing room multiple units offer that
more even control
over this over a larger space and also
redundancy if one unit was to fail
the entire growth space does not fail
with it you have that kind of backup
and systems yes others might be a little
overworked but at least you won't lose
the entire crop
so if you're in the opposite situation
where you want to increase the humidity
levels you want to use a humidifier
and these can produce a constant flow of
water vapor for an indoor garden which
may be needed if natural air is
especially dry
this could be particularly to your
region it's because if you're using
heaters that could naturally dry out the
air
cool water is used to create a mist that
dissipates throughout the space and
increases those moisture levels
again to bring them up to your desired
target levels
lastly avoid competing systems
so getting both the temperature and
humidity in balance can be a difficult
task
however knowing the natural conditions
of your outside air may
help you want to adjust your light
cycles to be during the natural
night of the day to reduce the heat of
the lights compounding with the heat of
the day
so if you're going to completely indoor
space those plants are isolated from the
outside
just because the sun's out doesn't mean
your lights have to be on you can
help kind of absorb some of that heat
some of those differences by having your
plants essentially experiencing the
daytime
during what would be the natural
nighttime when it's cooler out so these
are different ways that growers can
manipulate
completely controlled indoor situations
to try to reduce the stress on the
equipment and systems
to try to maintain the target humidity
as well as temperature levels in their
growth space to help maximize
plant production