here we're going to look at how the body
goes about regulating blood glucose
levels in order to maintain homeostasis
how the body goes about doing this is
the pancreas is involved that's
responsible for monitoring blood glucose
levels specifically the islet of
Langerhans now when we say homeostasis
isn't mean everything's a complete
flatline there Kim you can do as
fluctuations but they will occur within
narrow limits for example when glucose
levels are high insulin will be released
when levels are low glucagon will be
released we see a nice graph here we're
looking at our blood glucose levels in
red and our insulin levels here in this
bluish purple color we can see that
there are fluctuations throughout the
day but overall this is kept in a very
tight range so our body can go about
maintaining homeostasis looking at this
in a pictorial sense we have our
pancreas here we have two situations one
could be low blood sugar that's gonna we
want our Vice want to increase our blood
sugar
glucagon will be released promoting
glycogen breakdown the liver in contrast
to that we have high blood sugar we're
gonna want to decrease that blood sugar
and we're gonna do that with insulin
insulin is going to do two things it's
gonna promote glycogen synthesis it's
also going to stimulate glucose uptake
in tissue cells and overall that will
lead to a decrease in our blood sugar
now when we have that high blood glucose
we call it hyperglycemia so here would
be our normal blood sugar levels and we
consume orange juice or something has a
lot of sugar and now we are in I bow my
Samiha state insulin is going to be
released by beta cells in the pancreas
so and that's gonna initiate three
things insulins effects first it's gonna
trigger body cells to take up glucose
from blood and utilize it in cellular
respiration it's also going to inhibit
two processes like a genesis is one
where glucose is removed from the blood
and stored in glycogen in the liver it's
going to inhibit that step it's also
going to inhibit amino acids and fully
glycerols that are not converted to
glucose in the ER you may remember
macromolecules rough smooth ER this is
gluten Genesis that will be also
inhibited in a hypoglycemic State
whew tonight we're trying to get rid of
some of this blood sugar we're trying to
store it so this is what we're gonna buy
is gonna go through and help trigger
these events to reduce blood glucose in
contrast to that we have our homeostasis
and I went low blood glucose well
glucagon is gonna be released by the
alpha cells in the pancreas and that's
basically going to do the opposite of
what we just saw in that hyperglycemia
state now where it stimulated or insulin
stimulates this is going to inhibit and
where insulin inhibited this is going to
stimulate so it's basically the reverse
that and the whole goal here is to a
blood glucose concentration increase to
get us up to this range here after our
hypoglycemic State looking at this where
we look at both parts together and see
that here where we have our stimulus of
blood glucose levels cupcake beta cells
in the pancreas release our insulin that
insulin signals the liver to take up
glucose and store it as mikage in our
body cells will also take up glucose as
a result blood glucose levels will
decline reaching homeostasis after a
period time a blood glucose levels fall
pink alpha cells in the pancreas will at
least glucagon and the liver will break
down the glucagon to release glucose
overall blood glucose levels will rise
helping us maintain this homeostasis so
hopefully this kind of feedback system
makes sense and helps develop a better
understanding how the body maintains
blood glucose levels to keep homeostasis
and allow the normal functions of the
body to continue