here I'm going to tell you a little bit
about reptiles success story and how
they've become so well adapted to the
terrestrial or land environment see some
sea turtles here recently hatched making
a run for the water here hopefully not
get picked up by any predators or
seagulls on their way there so let's
start with the history of reptiles the
origin and evolution well first off they
arose from in phidian's so the earliest
fossils is about 359 million years ago
small four-legged vertebrates with small
teeth now it's important to make the
distinction between a reptile and
amphibian so reptiles are cold-blooded
have a backbone scaly skin and lay eggs
in contrast to that amphibians pictured
here are cold blooded
it's a similarity they also have a
backbone but they have moist skin they
lay eggs near water and they go through
a metamorphosis during their life cycle
just remember we're gonna be focused
more on the reptiles here don't get them
confused with the Indians so success of
reptiles well there's four important
steps we're gonna focus on two in
particular one is the watertight skin
that keratin you know let's give them
their watertight abilities respiration
they develop lungs excretion actually is
uric acid which requires very little
water so they can conserve water so
they're not wasting a lot of that in the
in the Attic egg a little quote here
it's not the strongest of the species
that survives nor the most intelligent
but the one most adaptable to change if
that mind you look here at reptiles
so water retention wellin tipene's
sample frogs cannot be considered fully
terrestrial because they lose too much
water through their skin in Phoebe's
must stay moist to avoid dehydration and
their method of reproduction requires a
moist environment see that here it's
little toad swimming in the water
reptiles so have evolutionary
adaptations that free them from the
water be able to live much more on land
now of course they still require water
but they don't have to be living in
water they can hit all much harsher and
more arid environment so that water
tight skin terrestrial animals face
serious problems of water loss as water
evaporates through their skin my
reptiles have evolved the skin made of
light flexible scales that overlap
deform protective almost watertight skin
that minimizes water loss let me see
that here and if ever touched a snake
you might expect them to be slimy but
it's actually just this interlocking
kind of scales there and the main goal
is to reduce water loss here we're
adding the advantage of camouflage in
both these cases but really those
interlocking watertight skin allows them
to survive in these much drier regions
watertight eggs also without a watery
environment most firm and eggs will try
out a reptiles fertilized eggs need a
moist environment in which to develop
the amniotic egg cells is from a reptile
needing a moist environment to develop
so that harsh outer shell we have that
nice kind of watery environment on the
inside allowing for the embryo to
develop inside a dry sand here but in
its small micro environment inside the
egg it has the water that it needs to be
able to survive through its early stages
of development watertight eggs in ma
Iook Iike names both water supply and
food supply there's a key to a reptiles
success as a terrestrial animal the eggs
tough shell mix essentially watertight
does not dry out even in very dry
habitats most reptiles all birds and
three species of mammals actually
reproduced by the in the Attic eggs with
shells and the formation of amniotic egg
suggests that these three groups of
animals evolved from a common ancestor
now we say Emily attic eggs we might
think of the ones we buy in the store
but realize that there's many different
types some people may have been
fortunate enough to see like Robins eggs
right sometimes their nest or locating
areas in your houses or developments
that's another example of the amniotic
watertight egg but they come in all sort
of shapes colors and ways to camouflage
in those ways to stand out it's unique
based on individual species now the
amniotic egg reptiles considered the
first rest really depressed the amniotic
egg first evolved in reptiles but also
found as I said animals birds
I'm sorry mammals and birds protection
from the physical damage see hard outer
shell this limits the evaporation of
water but still able to diffuse oxygen
and carbon dioxide this
here on our profession or cladograms the
development of the amniotic egg being
fairly far along in the development
process here so relatively advanced
animals continuing with this we have the
internal structure of the amniotic egg
amnion which is the thin membrane that
encloses the fluid where the embryo
floats kate here by this kind of purply
grayish region the yolk sac which
encloses the yolk fat rich food supply
fitting in maryland's with the yolk is
we have the left two lists elect miss
which stores water produced by the
embryo and we have the chorion which
surrounds all other membranes we see
that located here's the chorion albumin
is the protein and water for the embryo
this is the albumin okay right here this
is in part which which makes eggs very
nutritious and why a lot of people eat
them is because they do contain a lot of
this protein and a lot of these good
supplies assuming they weren't
fertilized so the em yak egg the amnion
encloses the embryo with the watery
environment creating like a little ponds
is a way to think about it that watery
region within this hard protective shell
and this shell also protects the aching
being crushed up and in what environment
and maybe in animals may be sitting on
this it might be buried in sand burning
the nest that's offering protection
what's interesting about the egg is the
yolk sac and NZO which is the developing
food supply for that Union bail this
extras waste products from the arrest so
the left to us stores the waste products
because remember in a sealed environment
here so we just can't have a way just to
produce you know nutrients we also need
an area to put the waste products also
allowing gas exchange so while this is a
hard protective shell
there's also carbon dioxide able to
diffuse out and oxygen is able to
diffuse in and there is an airspace a
little bit there along the similar to be
able to basically breathe within a quote
sealed environment blood vessels and no
walls carry oxygen carbon oxide from the
embryo so Mars is a living developing
individual
the knack eggs surrounded by the element
yolk sac and a lot to us is the membrane
called the chorion the chorion allows
oxygen to enter the egg and carbon
dioxide to leave so that's a very
important portion to allow that
individual to be able to grow and
develop you ever seen a bird beak
breakthrough that's been really able to
breathe air and they didn't just kind of
get suffocated in that egg they're
allowed to exchange that carbon dioxide
and oxygen that last kind of picture
here and then find some of the key parts
where certain things are located a
little different image here just be able
to kind of identify the main parts and
also what their functions are for the
importance of the amniotic egg which led
to the success of reptiles being able to
make that jump from the watery
environment to the arid dry land in
there