okay here we're looking at resource
partitioning see just an example here of
a variant here where we have sunny dry
conditions on the left and shady moist
conditions on the right there's
different species are going to favor the
sunny and dry environment versus the
shady and moist environment so calls
research resource of partitioning this
is formally the principle of competitive
exclusion which states that no two
species but the same niche can coexist
so the principle this competitive
exclusion we see have an example of that
here can be restated as no two species
can occupy the same niche indefinitely
so here we have the yellow birds
occupying the ground the trunk of the
tree and the top portion then these red
birds move in there's competition and
we've noticed now that the yellow birds
are located at the very top of the tree
and also on the ground while the red
birds are occupying the trunk of the
tree it's an example of competitive
exclusion as part of resource
partitioning so let's look at specific
at this resource partitioning well this
is when it is overlap two outcomes are
possible one is that competitive
exclusion or really this resource
partitioning that we're seeing so we
have a tree here there's different bird
species that will occupy different
portions of the tree so we're going to
be looking at the very top or apical
meristem of the tree somebody closer to
the ground so I'm going to be on the mid
section towards the ends here the end of
the branches and in this case these bird
species are going to be located in that
center portion of the tree all these
Warbler species are warblers they occupy
the same tree but because of resource
partitioning they're occupying different
specific niches or different specific
areas within the tree you see here with
the lights lighting up on the different
areas these going to be examples of
different niches within the tree which
is the result of resource partitioning a
lot of different species that kind of
coexist without overlapping in a
particular physical space habitat the
actual tree so as we search partitioning
a persistent competition is rare in
natural communities either one species
drives the other to extinction or
natural selection reduces the
competition between them
so an example of this research
partitioning is we have hawks and owls
hawks and owls they both have the same
prey in this case it's mice so there's a
region of niche overlap that's occurring
between species one we'll just call them
the Hawks and species two the Owls both
overlap and competing for the same mice
here however due to researcher
partitioning we have this now separation
we producing this overlap how this
happened well we're still feeding on the
same species here Hawks now you're still
eating mice but the Hawks are hunting by
the day in the Owls at night this is a
way of separating out reducing the
direct competition of both hawks and
owls so they're not competing for the
same prey at the same time some Patrick
species occupy the same to you graphical
areas but they avoid competition by
personing resources so here we have two
different whale species and this the
Patrick species tend to exhibit greater
differences than the allopatric one
which we'll talk about in the next slide
species doe this is a resulting in
character displacement which facilitates
habitat partitioning and thus reduces
competition so what's an example of this
why don't have these pictures here well
we have the killer whales here which
have teeth the reason why they have
teeth is they're actively seeking in the
ocean they're actively seeking seals
here we have a different whale species
that has this filtration system they're
both living in the same ocean but these
are going through and straining out a
small little plankton so that they can
feed this is synthetic species they're
occupying the same geographical area for
avoiding competition by feeding on
different food items ones feeding on
very small almost micro organisms here
it happens feeding on large macros and
such as the seals as a result when its
teeth and one has a filtration system
that push out and strain out those from
the water this is an example of research
partitioning with synthetic sympatric
species in contrast to that with
research partitioning with allopatric
species these do not live in the same
geographic area and thus do not compete
so we have Costa Rica fishing we have
different fish species and
Caribbean versus that the Pacific Ocean
is the example of allopatric species
because they don't live in the same
geographic area and therefore do not
directly compete with one