on this debaco university video we're
going to look at
a study that was done on the response of
cannabis genotypes
related to concentrations of potassium
all right let's look at responsive
cannabis genotypes to potassium supply
so first off the research article that
i'll be pulling some information from
presented right here
welcome to take a look at it in more
detail to see
more of the materials and methods that
they used but i'm going to provide a
general summary here
so first off the plant material and this
is just what they had
used two medical cannabis cultivars
genotypes rural medic and desert queen
which are approved for commercial
medical use in israel were used as the
model system
in the study presented here both are
indica have indica characteristics and
were selected to represent
two distinct chemotypes rm contains
similar concentrations of thc and cbd
about five percent of each and dq desert
queen has high tea it's a high thc
cultivar plants were propagated from
cuttings from a single mother plant and
coconut fiber
plugs now the growing conditions for
these plants the plants were divided
into five
increasing potassium supply treatments
15 60 100 175 and 240 parts per million
and grown for 30 days under an 18 6 hour
light to dark photo period under
metal halide bulbs in a controlled
environment in a growing room
temperatures in growing room were 26 and
25 degrees celsius
for day night temperature and a relative
humidity of 54 and 50
respectively irrigation was supplied
via drippers with one dripper per pot
the volume of
irrigation in each irrigation pulse was
between 250 and 650 milliliters per pot
per day
set to allow 30 of drainage fertilizers
were supplied by
fertigation dissolved in the nutrient
solution at each irrigation
so this kind of gives you that great
background of the research and kind of
the conditions
that they were conducting their research
in and the
article even goes into more detail so
time after potassium treatment let's get
to some of the
results here we're looking at the
irrigation in solution and then the
leachate we're looking at the potassium
here
on the y-axis and then time after
treatment in days on the x-axis
and overall we can see an irrigation
solution the potassium stayed
relatively consistent as we would expect
and the leachate here
for the higher concentrations increased
over time
and that's basically in the 175 and the
240 parts per million treatments now the
potassium concentration the little
brackets here mean concentration
on the leaf so we're looking at here
kind of our leaves
are two different varieties and
potassium concentrations of 15
60 100 175 and 240 that changes
noticeably in their morphology images of
the youngest fully developed lee on the
main stem taken
26 days after the initiation
of the fertigation regime and we could
see that definitely the
low reading here definitely had a
different morphology but as we get to
the higher readings
a little harder to make a distinguishing
factor based on visual characteristics
between the various treatments and
concentrations given
so let's look at the potassium on the
overall plant development
and this is photographed 26 days after
the initiation of fertigation regime
much like we saw with the leaf
but now we're looking at the entire
plant still those 15
uh concentration per million definitely
suffering
higher levels a little harder to tell a
difference at least based on purely
visual characteristics so what were the
general results were they looking at
well 15 parchment of potassium was
insufficient for optimum growth and
function in both genotypes and elicit
visual deficiency symptoms
that we could clearly see on the images
provided 240 uh parchment of potassium
proved excessive and damaging to
development of genotypes
royal medic while desert queen it's
simulated rather than restricted shoot
and
root development so for the
royal medic the growth positive response
to increased potassium supply
up to 175 parts per million of potassium
increasing in leaves and root biomass
the stem diameter and internode
elongation rate but increased was
further
but decreased with further increasing to
that 240 parts per million of potassium
rendering 175 the optimum concentration
for this genotype
this is important to realize that adding
more fertilizer
in some cases once you get above that
optimum level will lead to a decrease
in your plant performance so for the
desert queen increasing potassium supply
in the range of 60 to 175 parts per
million
did not affect plant development
surprisingly further increasing case
supply to level of 240
stimulated rather than restricted growth
and development in this
genotype so this is again where you're
looking at different genotypes you can
have different fertilizer requirements
to maximize that growth
having these studies is great to be able
to act as a comparison
to be able to look at potentially some
varieties that you might be considering
i put here just soil test potassium
recommended potassium levels just in
general might be recommended
but here we're seeing a dialed into a
nutrient-specific
regime based on actual varieties
so take this into consideration if
you're not growing one of these
it looks like kind of i would say not
going over that 175 would be a good
starting point
and then see how the plants respond