in this video we look at some ways
respiration rates are affected looking
mainly at plants but I want you to
remember that this also occurs in
animals and our respiration rate we may
think of like our breaths per minute as
a way to measure respiration and that's
one way and you can see here by the age
of an individual in so looking at humans
the breaths per minute does change
newborns to 6 weeks have the highest
breast permit anywhere from 30 to 60 is
considered normal and as we age our
breast from and decrease with adults
being somewhere in the range of 12 to 20
we can see our dogs here one sitting
nice in the Sun Prarie their lower
respiration rate and this dog running
here in the track
so again respiration rate relate to
plants looking at three environmental
factors here first one being temperature
when air temperature goes from 68 86
degrees Fahrenheit the respiratory rate
can double this is biological system in
general temperatures above 104 degrees
Fahrenheit can activate most enzymes
remember there's specific proteins at
this spend that depend on a very
specific shape above 104 degrees
Fahrenheit those proteins can denature
refrigeration temperatures slow the
respiration process reducing sugar and
water loss unwanted micro isn't
microorganism growth can also be reduced
and overall survival time can be
increased since why we store food in the
refrigerator to help increase its shelf
life by reducing the temperature water
is another way can in depth aspiration
rate in living cells about ninety
percent water
remember those seeds are also living
they only contain about 10 percent water
they're still respiring but at a very
low rate so we want to think about their
rate of respiration can affect where a
plant may be in its stage and seeds are
aspiring even oats are very slow or low
rate flooding rich so as these trees
have experience can stun trees and kill
plants really reducing respiration rate
essentially choking out the plants roots
need to breathe need to exchange oxygen
with carbon dioxide when these tree
roots became flooded that was no longer
possible in these plants are these trees
actually suffocated
oxygen is our last factor we look at
when we talk about respiration rate
reducing the overall oxygen content 1 a
3% in increased storage time in a sealed
environment particularly for Apple's
oxygen gas can we place with nitrogen
gas as a way to reduce the respiration
rate and increase the shelf life of
apples apples it's possible to actually
keep them about a full calendar year
under these conditions that will reduce
their respiration rate the reason why
they tend not to do that is the fresh
apples are usually coming out and the
stored ones don't taste quite as good as
the fresh the victims