okay here I'm gonna go over some very
common respiratory diseases
starting with chronic pulmonary
obstructive disease or abbreviated
commonly COPD this is exemplified by
chronic bronchitis and obstructive
emphysema patients typically have a
history of smoking dyspnea coffee and
frequently I just mean again as labored
breathing occurs and the recipe gets
worse overall COPD victims develop
respiratory failure coming by headaches
toxemia carbon dioxide retention and
respiratory acidosis how does this
actually occur what's occurring in these
individuals if you look at normal lungs
and the alveoli we see a very high
amount of surface area which is
important to allow this gas exchange
those individuals with COPD we notice
those alveoli are destroyed forming
fewer but larger structures here this
limits or reduces the amount of
efficient the transfer of gases that can
occur as a result you can get all of
these negative symptoms that do sadly
plague this particular individual moving
on from COPD we have asthma something
you might be familiar with typically
more common in children than adults it's
characterized by shortness of breath
wheezing and chest tightness the cue
inflammation of Airways precedes the
bronchial spasms so what's actually
occurring in asthma is our normal
pathway for air it's quite large and as
when we have this constriction that's
occurring could be thickening of the
airway wall could be the destruction
could be the presence of mucus all of
these can lead to asthma like symptoms
this could be caused by an immune
response is airway inflammation caused
by the il-4 and il-5 which stimulate
antibodies and recruit implements and
inflammatory cells
I always thicken with inflammation mucus
and magnify the effect this is typically
thought of if people try to replicate
this or simulate this be like instead of
breathing to a normal airway to breeze
through a very thin a small straw which
restricting the ability for air to come
in and also for air to come out you see
the current asthma rate and prevalence
by age sex and race
Missa T so by age child is more likely
to become affected than adult females
for whatever reason are more likely than
males and compared whites blacks and
Hispanic races black is tends to be a
little bit higher than the Hispanic in
white inhalers are common ways to reduce
the short term effectiveness of having
this potential issue occur lung cancer
is another arm sadly respiratory disease
accounts for about one third of all
cancer deaths in the United States
90% of all patients with lung cancer
were at once smokers there's three
common types these all fall under the
category of lung cancer there's squamous
cell carcinoma there's aDNA carcinoma
small cell carcinomas I could get too
much in the specifics but simply what's
occurring here is we have our nice
healthy lungs and we have our sad they
are affected lungs with smoke it was
increasing the rate or the chance
dramatically of contracting lung cancer
if you look on the packets of cigarettes
they do warn you about smoking can cause
lung cancer in addition to the lung
cancer it's also heart disease and many
other it's having negative effects so
the question comes up commonly about
what about e-cigarettes so we all know
that the traditional smoking has those
warnings without a cigarettes
those are smokeless tobacco and water
pipes and may cause serious potential
health problems though this can include
cancer because of the chemicals and
toxins that they contained actually
currently an act of e-cigarette lawsuit
for a lack of a cancer warning because
of the potential health risk the US Food
and Drug Administration you know them as
the FDA has started regulating these
products like other tobacco products
such as cigarettes on August 8th of 2016
instead of burning tobacco they
generally are contained cartridges
filled with nicotine and other chemicals
and it's because it's not an actual
smoking or burning of a potential leaf
or other product there is cancer
associated risk you're welcome to check
out the links I provided you with they
kind of stressed some of the point of
some of the potential risks with me
cigarettes lastly looking at
the country a lung cancer incidence the
above map shows lung cancer incidence in
the United States you can see the region
here and the south tents have a little
bit higher incidence of lung cancer
there's a lack of uniform in the
population percentage that smoke in this
suggests there may be other
environmental factors to consider most
carcinogens are also mute engines so
while smoking can increase your lung
cancer chance there's not necessarily a
direct correlation there's some other
factors also playing into that however
when we look at this data looking at our
cigarette smoked in our lung cancer
deaths we do see a definite correlation
after the incidence of smoking began to
increase the United States so did the
instance of lung cancer cigarette smoke
contains these powerful mutant the gyms
benzo purine spine 2 3 sites at the p53
gene these mutations at these sites
activate the gene research has found
that the p53 gene is activating 70
percent of all lung cancers so this is
showing this correlation here and
nicotine in cigarette smoke is also a
very addictive drug so you can have
other negative side effects think the
important thing to look at this graph or
at least to kind of give hope for the
future is that while cigarette smoking
did increase ended lung cancer deaths
noticed a decrease in cigarettes being
smoked and a decrease in lung cancer
keep in mind that each cigarettes are
also have their potential cancer risks
so just because you're not smoking a
traditional cigars cigarette there's
also cancer risk associated with those