here we're going to be looking at
restriction enzymes
now enzymes as you may remember from our
previous units can break something apart
or put something together in this case
they're going to be separating something
and that something is DNA going to be
breaking apart nucleotides at very
specific sequences this is a restriction
enzyme doing mass so restriction enzymes
they bind to specific short sequences
only four to six bases long in the DNA
sequence and the nucleotide sequence
what's interesting in both DNA strands
is identical when read in opposite
directions so you can see here
g-a-a-t-t-c well we read it in this
direction G a TTC read the same in AI in
opposite directions there's different
restriction enzymes and they basically
look for different recognition sites
that they're gonna cut the DNA example
here we have our DNA our Hindi 3
restriction enzyme cutting it right here
resulting in two sections now of DNA
this is another example here for the eco
r1 restriction enzyme most restriction
enzymes DNA is staggered fashion this
causes of generates sticky ends what
this term sticky ends mazes they want to
kind of rejoin together they want to
rebind they want to be kind of left
hanging out there these ends pair with
any other DNA fragment and generate some
of the same enzymes when we're pairing
it together
DNA ligase again comes back and that is
what's linking our DNA together to form
our double-stranded back again sticky
ends versus blunt ends so sticky ends
have sections that overlap and have
bases attached which results in the
likelihood they will rejoin with
complementary base pairs so again think
about here this little green line if we
separated out here
my name is called sticky ends this ends
gonna kind of want to stick back to this
end contrary to that we call something
called blunt ends and these have limited
contact in the direct cuts just cutting
the DNA right here in this sequence here
these sticky ends a little bit more of
an area where we could be binding blunt
end they're just going to be like this
kind of an overview join it's a little
bit harder than or rejoin we're here
chickens have a larger area that wants
to bind and that's what's causing the
sticky part restriction enzymes are
specific this is an important fact here
if there's a change in just one of the
base pairs of an eco r1 site and again
it's just a restriction enzyme the codon
will be changed this can result in the
loss of a cut site along the DNA meaning
this eco r1 these four to six ish basis
depending on what restriction enzyme
we're looking at they are looking for a
very specific sequence if you don't get
that very specific sequence you get a
mutation in one of those you may lose a
cut site or generate a cut site in
somewhere else along the DNA strand so
this is where you do not want to have a
mutation occur restriction enzymes what
they're actually used for I mean they
defend against infectious agents like
viruses and limbs that cleaver cut up
teen air important.if
foreign DNA gets put into a Cell give
our bacterial genome or a viral genome
here being injected into the cell if the
virus well cells naturally generate
these restriction enzymes to go through
recognize it says off foreign DNA and
chop it up before it can reroute all the
machinery of that cell this is why it's
important to have these we're going to
talk about them in relation to how
they're used for biotechnology but they
are in the natural sense they're not
completely man-made and they are used to
chop up what would be invading DNA
examples of restriction enzymes you
don't have to memorize these are just
some ones that are very commonly used
with where they come from eco r1 in
hindi 3 and our very common I've used
those in the lab this is just these
specific sequences that they look for
can remember our five-prime and
three-prime regions we talked about DNA
this is orient yourself in the DNA and
they each have a very specific
recognition recognition sequence which
will be important for a where it's
specifically going to cut