for those considering retail sales of
cannabis in connecticut
this video is going to provide you with
some up-to-date information
as of july 2021
all right here on this tobacco
university video i'm going to help
provide you with some of the latest
information
provided by connecticut as of july 2021
regarding
retail sales so first off if you want to
go through and find the
information for yourself this is the
link all the information presented here
is based off canvas information is
provided by the state of connecticut
as of july 1st to july 8th 2021
this is only applicable for connecticut
and subject to change at any time so be
sure to check your local and current
regulations this is only intended to be
used as a point in time
general example if you're not from
connecticut this might give you some
ideas of some of the laws and
regulations
that might be applied to other states as
well so first off
as a retail sales person a lot of retail
sales are asking can i buy or sell
products with delta 8 thc or delta 10
thc
and specifically this question asked in
connecticut today
well the short answer is just simply no
you may not sell any product that
exceeds 0.3
thc on a dry weight basis these products
are considered cannabis and can be
only sold in the adult use market by a
licensed retailer
sales of cannabis products from a
licensed retailers are not expected to
begin in connecticut until late
2021. it was very recently adopting a
recreational program
but here we can see some of the details
as far as dates and times
aren't necessarily just because that law
was accepted and
is now setting in to affect things but
there
may not be happening as quickly as some
people had thought
if your product label states the total
thc or thc content of
less than 0.3 on a dry weight basis your
product likely complies with the law and
i stress the word
likely complies with the law here if the
label does not clearly specify the total
thc content
or you are unsure contact the
manufacturer named on the label to
confirm the product has
less than 0.3 percent total thc on a dry
weight basis
delta products with thc content greater
than 0.3 percent on a dry weight basis
will still be available to patients in
the medical marijuana program
at their approved dispensary facilities
it's just a little important distinction
to make right there another question
come that comes up is when purchasing
new products to sell in my store
how do i determine if they're legal
under the new law
so you want to check the label or
confirm with the manufacturer that the
product satisfies the 0.3
dry weight thc limit that's kind of the
number one there
for any product that does not meet that
0.3 percent
uh dry weight thc limit contact the
distributor or manufacturer to try and
cancel or return the sale
because that it would not be legal for
you to go through and
sell and distribute can i give my
inventory of delta eight products if
they have
uh i'm sorry can i give away my
inventory of delta 8 products if they
have no more than 0.3
thc and a dry weight basis another
question and again very simple answer
no the definition of sale under the
adult use cannabis and control
substances
law includes transfer without
compensation so no you can't just
give it away and give it as free that
doesn't count
it is illegal to give away delta 8
products as they have more than 0.3
thc on a dry weight basis in the state
of connecticut so be aware of that
so can i sell products labeled with less
than 0.3 percent thc without a license
well if your product label states the
total thc or thc content
less than that 0.3 percent on a dry
weight basis your
product likely complies with the law and
again likely contact the manufacturer on
the label to confirm that the thc
content is less than 0.3 percent on a
dry weight basis again looking at the
label
contact and manufacture all things you
should be doing anyway
are there packaging or labeling
standards for cbd and legal delta
products against focusing here
specifically
within the state of connecticut and for
products below 0.3 percent
dry weight of thc limit all federal and
state laws concerning labeling and
packaging
still apply to any food drugs dietary
supplements such as connecticut food
drug and cosmetics act states
i'm interested in starting a business or
working in the industry how can i
participate this is a lot of
people want to participate in this new
and emerging kind of industry
connecticut's marijuana market got some
good information here again showing a
lot of
positive aspects from revenue and this
is where a lot of people are considering
getting started in this
so more information on starting canvas
business will be coming from the
department of consumer protection
because
the recreational program is very
recently adopted
which will be responsible for licensing
any new businesses
given the anticipated volume of
applicants the department will conduct
periodic lotteries to determine which
applicants to consider first
these liars are expected to continue for
at least the first few years of the
market we'll get into a little bit more
of that detail
here half the licenses will be reserved
for social equity applicants which are
businesses
that are 65 owned and controlled by
individuals
who lived for five of the last 10 years
or
nine of their first 18 years of life in
a disproportionately impacted area and
have an average household income
of less than 300 percent of the state's
medium household income
over the last three years this is kind
of a constituent that was put in there
in the sense that trying to allow uh
people may not have had initial
advantage to the market
to allow them to have half of the
licenses will be reserved for those
particular applicants
you may find more information about
licensing costs and lottery process in
other articles we'll cover some of that
here
so what are the license fees that's like
the next obvious question is okay i have
a license what are the fees
there's a fee variability so be sure to
know what you're getting into
and this is looking at if you're the
non-social equity fees
or the social equity fees if you want a
cultivator
micro cultivator retailer product
manufacturer bud and beverage
delivery transport product packager or
hybrid there
we can see the lottery cost the
provisional and then the actual
license here being the most expensive
being a cultivator
with non-social equity fees is going to
be about 75
000 there the least expensive
would be the social equity fee category
for a micro cultivator
at 500 only 500 to find out more about
these
want to research within the laws of
connecticut
again this is just providing you with
that kind of a little bit of an idea at
least how connecticut's approaching it
so what's this lottery process we're
going to talk about applicants yes some
places
actually have gone through and it's
literally a lot of they put them in
there and they tumble them around and
pull one out uh connecticut the
department of consumer protection will
announce the total number of applicants
to be selected
and allocate fifty percent of them to
the social equity applicant lottery
an an application period for each
license type will be opened for a
specific period of time
to be determined by the department of
consumer protection
a list of all applicants received for
each lottery will be randomized and sent
to a third-party lottery processor
the third-party library processor will
randomize the list of applicants
and identify applicants selected through
the lottery process
the applicants will be reviewed and if
an applicant is denied the next
application in the list will then be
accepted until the total number of
applicants is selected or there are no
additional applicants
remaining these selected applicants will
have to complete provisional application
and submit
appropriate fees and the provisional
license has a 14 months to obtain
a full operational license there so keep
that in mind as
well we saw those previously as our
provisional versus our license here
so can i purchase hem products in a
dispensary facility without the medical
marijuana card and
very very clear and i think simple
answer is just
no nearly no more to say
other than that so how will cannabis be
taxed and this is part of the thing that
was holding it up a little bit from some
of the laws there
but there will be essentially three
taxes on retail sales cannabis
the state's usual six point three five
percent sales tax
a three percent uh sales tax dedicated
to the city or town where the sale
occurs
in a tax based on thc content that will
cost approximately
10 to 15 percent of the sale price in
total the tax rate is expected to be
approximately 20
of the retail price of cannabis in line
with the tax rates of a neighboring
state
massachusetts uh so lastly the
question is well when will retail sales
uh begin when we go through this process
well sales could begin in late
2022 in connecticut first the state
needs to form the new social equity
council
which will set guidance for adhering to
social equity provisions the state will
also need to hire new staff
issue new regulations and oversee
application and licensing processing
for new cannabis businesses further
these businesses
need to time to secure funding physical
locations
local zoning approval and all other
elements needed
to start a new business in a highly
regulated market
that simply just takes time the supply
chain must be
entirely licensed before sales can begin
and this includes stores testing labs
growers and there must be enough growing
capacity to supply the retail
market the governor the governor nick
lamont pictured here starting the actual
bill
has directed each state agency to work
to implement the law quickly
and in a responsible way so hopefully
this
goes into some of the details that you
might be wondering regarding retail
sales of cannabis in connecticut
at least current as of july 2021