here on debaco university i'm going to
provide a brief overview
of reverse osmosis
[Music]
let's look at reverse osmosis use for
cannabis production
well first off the basics of the reverse
osmosis
system well reverse osmosis is a
filtration system it's a method that can
remove
up to 95 to 99 of dissolved salts
in any water sample as a result is the
most common
option for desalinating water on a large
scale
reverse osmosis uses high pressure to
force water through
a semi-permeable membrane which results
in salts on one side of the membrane
and pure water on the other so as we can
see here normal osmosis would have water
kind of
working its way pure water would go try
to dissolve the contaminants or salt
particles here
reverse osmosis as a sane semi-permeable
membrane but takes applied pressure
and forces that water going backwards
the reverse process
and squeezes the water if you want to
think about it that way through this
semi-primal membrane only allowing pure
water to come out
at this far end however this process can
be wasteful
if access to water is limited because
there needs to be kind of a bypass of
water with the system
there's typically a six to one ratio
with six parts being fed into the system
for every one part of pure water that is
produced so while it can
is great producing pure water it can be
a little wasteful in that six to one
ratio so again
keep that in mind if water is a very
limited resource for you
why would you want to remove minerals
well arrow water reverse osmosis water
will essentially have no minerals this
allows growers to now control what is
added to the water
if our water is fed directly to plants
then calcium and magnesium deficiency
is likely so the reason why we have
water starting with basically nothing
is that allows whatever part per million
you're trying to desire
can be all of the elements or nutrients
that you're looking
to add to the water if you already have
high part per million water
it's going to limit the amount that you
can add to make sure your plants are
properly fed
reverse as well as this process in very
quick sense
there's typically a three or four stage
kind of filtration process
typically that first stage is a sediment
filter simply because we don't want to
clog any of the
downstream components then the important
carbon filter
then we have the impurities are removed
and then we have a post carbon filter
so there are two carbon filters a pre
and a post and there can be multiple
stages of
these filtrations the whole goal here
again is to produce that pure water
as close to that pure water as possible
but remind
reminder that there is that six to one
ratio of lost water
so you need to have a way to kind of
drain out that waste water
it's not harmful water it's just through
the reverse osmosis process it's need to
kind of flush the system continually
to ensure you're producing that as close
to possible
zero ec or zero part per million and
result water