in this debaco university video i'm
going to be going over
rockwell size options for indoor
cannabis plant production it may be just
more than what you're thinking of
a lot of growers use rockwool at the
early stages but did you know
it can be used throughout the full grow
cycle here we're going to go over
some of those options
[Music]
all right let's explore some of the
options regard for rockwool for your
indoor cannabis plant production
so first off grodan stonewall or
rockwool here
many brands but this is a very popular
one when both commercial and hobby
growers
rocco is made from molten rock spun into
a cotton candy-like fiber
is then compressed into cubes blocks or
slabs
because it's man-made it does allow for
the freedom to be made into a variety of
shapes
rockwell can absorb nutrient solution
and help maintain aeration
which are both beneficial to the plant
on both the small scale
and also the large scale growth
production
so we want to look at the propagation
stages where people may be your growers
might be made
most familiar with rockwool seedling
startings and cubes are easily
transferred into blocks
and then into slabs if desired so that
makes it very advantageous
seedlings or cuttings started in grodan
cubes can be transplanted into more
traditional planters
or also growing mediums this is why
people might be familiar with rockwool
at the starter stage and they might
progress to other substrates
grodin makes ok starter plugs macro
plugs
and aok starter plugs just to give some
examples
there of the variety that you have even
in just the propagation stage of
production
we get to growing blocks as we can see
here used quite a bit
and we see the clones here being grown
in the little starter plugs and then
they're placed directly into its form
fit
into the blocks here those seedlings or
cuttings started
in these larger growing blocks and once
rooted the blocks are then transferred
to long
a larger stonewall slab grow blocks can
also be planted directly into containers
for soil gardening
and this is a strip of four inch by four
inch grinding blocks each with
pre-formed holes in them
to accept those little starter plugs
there makes for a very easy transfer
makes for a very efficient transfer
and also a very time efficient transfer
as well with minimal root disturbance
now growing slabs growing slabs are used
in the final stage of planting these are
kind of the largest
these slabs come in clearly marked
uv-resistant poly sleeves for ease of
use
it's recommended for larger long-term
crops with extensive root structures
like cannabis peppers tomatoes or even
cucumbers typically seedlings and blocks
are
placed into the slabs as kind of the
next level of progression
in the grow cycle now lastly combining
the blocks in the slabs what does that
actually
kind of look like we can see some great
examples of that here
this allows for minimal root disturbance
as the two components naturally work
together
they're also the very similar material
so that's allowing those roots to kind
of go through and transfer from one to
the other
very easily
so the block can be placed directly on
the slab to allow the roots to continue
growing
from that block right into the slab we
see that here in the large production
we see that here kind of a zoomed in
version what does it look like from the
root standpoint well this is kind of a
great cutaway
we're seeing the roots that were
initially started in that block have now
progressed to and are starting to spread
throughout the slab they're allowing for
that expansion
this is why rockwell can be used from
the very start to the very end
because of the options that it provides
and the root friendly and plant
therefore
plant-friendly environment that it can
create
throughout the propagation stage all the
way to the final harvest stage