so you want to learn more about rockwell
for indoor cannabis production
we've come to the right place here on
tobacco university where we're going to
explain
just that
all right let's get into rockwell for
indoor cannabis production
first off there's many potential uses
for rockwool
it can be used at any stage of growth of
cannabis production not just clones like
a lot of people associate it with
some growers prefer to use it only in
the early stages but it can be used to
fill
for full term other growers will grow
plants in it for the entire grow cycle
so you may choose to use it for only a
portion you may choose it to use it for
the entire growth cycle
it's entirely up to you but i'm going to
provide you with some of the details
about it
so you can make an educated decision so
first off
are the basics of just kind of like what
is rockwool um in general
well rockwell is a lightweight substrate
made from spinning molten
uh balsic rock into fine fibers
it's commonly used in hydroponic growing
setups especially in commercial settings
it's formed into a range of cubes and
blocks and growing
slabs large blue slabs and also granular
products
so because it is kind of this uh
stonewool or rockwool kind of
insulation-like
material it can be made it's
manufactured it can be made into
different
shapes sizes to allow it to be utilized
for different parts of the growth cycle
so what are the properties of it why are
so many people using it
well rockwell can have good balance
between the ability to hold water
and still provide sufficient aeration
for the roots
hydroponic setups often use rockwell
because it has a slow drain time which
allows for feeding and watering
and it can be also be very specific here
we see a rockwool cube sitting on a bed
of perlite
with a cannabis clone in it so again all
these
are reasons why rockwool is so
popular with many growers so what are
some of the benefits you know
so we said look some of the properties
some of the advantages well that natural
balance between holding water and
aeration
aeration are conducive for root growth
in development and who doesn't want
bigger better
routes lightweight which can reduce the
shipping expense
and provides a sterile growing
environment so not only can it ship
fairly easily because it's lightweight
does take up some volume
but as far as the weight isn't a great
deal
it can also provide a sterile growing
environment works great to reduce the
chance of
implementing any sort of disease
especially on the early stages of growth
but really
for all stages that it's being utilized
in
however you do want to watch out for out
the algal growth here that can occur in
the sense of with water and holding
water and
light with grow lights or sunlight that
can also cause addly to grow
also disposal can be an issue due to the
fact that it really doesn't comp
decompose or break down all that well so
you want to be thinking about the kind
of full growth cycle there
of okay if i'm going to use it here
where is it all we're going to end up
and can i dispose of it properly
some options for rockwell they said it's
kind of a manufactured product so it can
be offered in a variety of
situations and sizes there's some small
little starter plugs
there's some slightly larger cubes
there's bigger blocks and then we get
into the slabs
so some of the companies start with
little starter plugs and we can see here
is a larger cube well that starter plug
will fit
very easily into that cube then that
cube can be placed on a block and that
block can be placed on the slabs that
can allow those roots to fully expand
and helps minimize root disturbance and
allow this product to be used for the
entire
grow cycle now how would you prepare
rockwolf is this something you are
considering
we want to always check with the
manufacturer but at the very least
rockwell will need to
have a pre-soak in water before going in
planting in it
some needs to be soaked in water to help
regulate the ph something can just be
soaked in regular water
it's still however a good idea to check
the soaking waters ph before
during and after the rock will soak to
help ensure that this will
not be an unexpected stress on the
plants and limit their nutrient
availability
lastly that water soaked targets so said
about soaking your water well what
should target should you be
well depending if you're using rockwell
for the propagation or growth cycle
the targets may vary slightly however in
general you should be shooting for a ph
around 5.3 to 5.5 a parts per million
content of around 400
at temperature around 65 to 70.
typically a soak time of two to five
minutes will help ensure the air bubbles
are removed
and full absorption has occurred we can
see that point of saturation here
in the grower here taking the ph reading
all good things that are shown in the
picture
and all good things you should be
implementing in the practice if you're
looking at
growing your plants in rockwool