this is intended to be a brief overview
of routing hormones its goal is to
produce you know clones and plans that
have a nice fibrous root system to allow
for nutrient water absorption and adding
hormones can help encourage this to
happen so first off breeding hormones
are typically oxen based the one here
and one will see is typically they could
be made from naa or IBA IBA send all
three butyric acid and that's a very
common one that's used in many routing
products so there is a difference
routine there's a gel-based and there's
also powder based essentially the
hormone is the same since this hormone
in this is clone X the both contain that
IBA and all three butyric acid or awful
often the gel could hear better to the
stems and the longer the hormone comes
in contact that can improve the odds of
rooting my experience clinics gels is
superior to most other ones that I've
used however when you're using it be
sure to store it in the refrigerator
around 40 degrees Fahrenheit so the
hormone the auxin does not degrade with
heat so again while these are both the
same hormone this powder tends to be a
little bit harder to stick onto some of
the stems this purple sticky gel adheres
a little bit better and I think that's
part of the reason why this one tends to
encourage a little bit more rooting
importance of roots Willers also these
things root hairs they are very thin
they're about one selfic their
structures allow for maximum absorption
of water and nutrients they create this
web which is a very high surface area to
volume ratio and while they're very
small they are visible to the naked eye
but they're more easily seen at the aid
of a light microscope careful protection
of root hairs from desiccation the
physical damage must be taken to ensure
that the plant is able to efficiently
and effectively absorb water in
nutrients hormones can help increase
this web that occurs whether we're
talking about clones or cuttings or even
ceilings to help encourage them to
produce this web