while many growers will tell you how to
root cutting successfully
very rarely do you see anyone that
relates it to scientific published
research
and hopefully you've come here to debaco
university for just that
that's what we intend to provide here of
the rooting success rate of cannabis
cuttings
research to give you the best methods to
increase your odds of success
at rooting new clones or vegetative
cuttings
from a cannabis plant
[Music]
all right let's get into the video here
so first off here is the article if you
want to find a little bit more
details or information uh we're going to
provide you here with kind of
some a brief overview of this particular
article
in this video lecture so first off
realize that there's many
variables here growers often wonder what
the impact would be of different rooting
conditions if conditions are favorable
there would be very likely to be some
degree of rooting however the goal
for growers is to maximize the
production that's the whole
intention here is to do some show you
some comparisons
but show you how to maximize your
routing potential there in your cannabis
clones
so first off looking at canvas plant
material and factors explained and this
is again a part of that study
so canvas was actually used as part of
the study so it's always hard to find
that let's try to provide
here cuttings were taken at the length
of about 13 centimeters with three fully
expanded leaves from stock plants
cuttings were taken at the ends of
axiary limbs and cut at a 45 degree
angle
each cutting was rooted in a 5.7
centimeter wide 5.7 centimeter tall
peat jiffy pot containing pro-mix a pg
organic growing
substrate so again this gives you just
some background for this
study full factorial complete randomized
design with four factors rooting hormone
leaf number
cutting position and leaf tip removal
two levels per factor in 10 replications
per factor combined
so this was a pretty extensive study
that really touched on many of the
things you hear growers say should i cut
the leaves not cut the leaves
how many leaves should i have this study
gets into that for leaf number cuttings
either had one fully expanded
leaf removed two leaves remaining or
were left with three total leaves for
cutting position cuttings from terminal
shoots were taken from either an apical
position basically node 10
or higher on the plant or from what was
determined to be a basal position which
is below
node 10 on the plant for a leaf tip
removal treatment the portion of the
leaf tips about one third of the leaf
area
was removed from fully expanded leaves
or the leaves were left
uncut and lastly for the rooting hormone
factor we're looking at the base about
five centimeters if each stem was dipped
into either
0.2 percent endo-3 butyric acid gel
or in zero two percent will extract
rooting gel
for another source of comparison so
again these are probably some things
you've heard from a lot of growers
let's look at some of the data provided
to get into what the results showed from
this study so it's also important
understand the propagation environment
so this can also play a large factor
into your
cloning and rooting success so trays
were randomly arranged in a walk in
a growth chamber and initially misted
relative humidity in the
first zero to four days was 95 percent
from five to eight days that was reduced
to eighty percent
and for nine to twelve days that was
reduced further to sixty percent
temperature was maintained about four 24
degrees celsius
for day and night for the entire period
fluorescent lighting was used to
maintain an 18-hour photo period
and the light intensity was slowly
increased the par readings from that
zero to five days again at 50
micro moles six day six to date nine
eighty and day 10 to day 12 115 of
poverty on those micro moles
in meters per second to give you an idea
of the conditions
the harvest determination so the bottom
of the trays was observed
a daily from seven days after
and onwards for for treating roots and
cuttings were harvested at
12 days when approximately 50 percent
or more of the cuttings showed visible
roots at the bottom of the tray so again
these are some of the parameters
that were set forth for the experiment
and the results then
are based off this so the rooting
assessment you know looking at how well
those plants
may have rooted or may not have rooted
well successful rooted cuttings were
assigned to either
two classifications based on the degree
of advantageous roots
a root quality index abbreviated in this
study rqi score of one
or two was assigned by a third party
without knowledge of applied treatments
based on visual reference
that's the top image right here so
here's a
one and here's a two but far before our
qi measurements the substrate was washed
and rude cuttings
with ro water to again allow for a good
visual inspection
because that's how the roots were
assessed visually and that's how the
study was conducted
reading success rate of cannabis
cuttings if we look start at some of the
data here
the rooting success rate of cannabis
cuttings with about 80 cuttings looked
at here
the cut leaves had about one third of
leaf tips removed to give you an idea
cuttings from terminal shoots either
april cuttings again greater than
node 10 and basal cuttings less than
node 10 and those apocalypse are equal
to or
greater than node 10. rooting hormones
there's a synthetic hormone
or an organic hormone which is
willow-based bars within each factor
bearing different letters
are significantly different at p less
than
0.05 using chi-squared contrast
so measured in a binomial scale in which
any visible advantageous root formation
was considered rooted to calculate
as percentage of cuttings with roots in
each treatment so what does this
background say about the data provided
right below me
well we can notice if we look at the
leaf number whether you use two leaves
or three leaves
statistically there was no difference
between those whether using a basal
cutting or an apogee cutting again
no statistic difference between those
however
with cutting the tips or not cutting the
leaf tips there was a significant
difference
and to get the increased rooting success
it is suggested here by the data
to not cut the leaves there in addition
to whether applying the organic or the
synthetic rooting hormone
in this case the synthetic hormone
definitely had a much greater
rooting success than the organic one so
again leaf number
where you took the cuttings from not
major difference at least statistically
based on this study
uncutting the leaves and using synthetic
hormone definitely did make a
statistically difference
improve improvement in rooting success
we're looking at the loop root quality
index of the cutting so again 80 were
used
looking at the cut and the uncut leaves
here we're looking at
the bars within each factor being
different letters anything different at
p
less than 0.05 using chi-squared
contrast we can see the
again same basic pattern here we're
looking at leaf number
and synthetic pattern here providing
definitely the greatest
difference there reading success rate
so where we're looking at where we took
those cuttings this is a
number of 40 individual plants here cut
leaves had about one third of these tips
removed
cuttings from the terminal shoots again
the apical
equal to or greater than node 10 basal
cuttings less
are under node 10. and again the same
statistical analysis applied there and
here we see the example
of looking at the basal or apical here
shoot tips
looking at whether you cut or uncut the
leaves as if the leaves were cut
in this case if you do cut the tips of
the leaves the apical
area did show an improvement in rooting
success
however if you leave them uncut it
doesn't matter where you take them from
statistically there is no difference in
the rooting success rate
so what's the research summary here what
have we learned from looking at all this
data and how can apply that to our own
potential cannabis clones well rooting
hormone of 0.2
iba gel delivered higher rooting success
rate than the 0.2 percent will extract
so that would be advised to use
cutting 30 of the leaf tips reduced
reading success rate so it is not
advised to cut those uh leaf tips
number of leaves three leaves had a
higher root quality compared to two
leaves without influencing rooting
success rate
and the position of cutting on the stock
plant did not influence either reading
success rate
or the root quality you might want to go
back to some of the previous slides or
pause the video
to look at those charts presented in a
little bit more detail
yourself but lastly to maximize rooting
success what's the quick general summary
here
we want to take plant material from
either the apical or basal positions
that doesn't matter you want to make
sure the cuttings have at least
three fully expanded leaves you do not
want to cut the tips of the leaves off
at any point that will again reduce your
rooting success
you might dip the cuttings in iba
reading hormone to help
increase your and maximize your rooting
success and quality cuttings
that you can produce and here it is
supported with scientific research doing
comparisons between different methods
growers may use and hopefully you found
this helpful
and it will improve your rooting success
on the clones that you take