now here we're going to look at rotary
hydroponics which is as the name implies
applies a wheel that rotates around a
central light source here
so there's nutrient solution in the
bottom and this rotates through very
slowly and allows the plants to get that
full exposure and doesn't need a
reflector on that light that's giving
that 360 degrees of light for the
operation now the ferris wheel concept
is kind of the idea to think about or
document these rotary systems the goal
is to maximize space in light use and a
very small footprint ideally get a big
yield while the speed rotation is slow
you can still see it and I try to show
that here where we can kind of see the
world turning but it's very slow in the
rotation that it does this is the same
concept here as the rotary form of
hydroponics overall this is not
well-suited for a large-scale production
it's not a good option for plants that
grow very tall because they're limited
and as a result sadly this isn't very
practical so let me look really cool
interesting we could see all the root
systems here going right around and
being picked up that nutrient solution
not very practical and if plants are
growing very tall well they're gonna run
into the light and get tangled and then
cause all sorts of issues so again very
limited on what it can be produced for
does look kind of neat and does allow to
maximize it footprint but again not
great for large scale operations and
really not widely used