so here we learned about the rough and
smooth endoplasmic reticulum typically
referred to as the rough and the smooth
er you kind of see comparison between
the two animals here i've having a very
rough textured skin
a very smooth texture so that rough what
makes it rough what makes it smooth well
it is based on the texture but really
what gives the rough
er that rough kind of texture is
the ribosomes that it is kind of like
studded on it's kind of like attached to
the outside
giving it that rough appearance the
smooth has very few
ribosomes giving it that much smoother
more consistent look
so within that endoplasmic reticulum
it's a system of membranes and channels
of saccules which are just these
flattened
kind of vesicles are continuous with the
outer membrane of the nuclear envelope
so we're kind of going from the nucleus
and we're just leaving the nucleus when
we hit the endoplasmic reticulum
in particular this rough er is started
with ribosomes on the
cytoplasmic side and this allows for
protein production
so this is the synthesizing or the
creation or making of
those proteins it also allows for
proteins to be modified and processed it
can be
sugars can be added resulting in
glycoproteins
so this rough er with these ribosomes is
especially abundant in cells that
secrete a lot of proteins which makes
sense because it's the site of protein
production as a polypeptide it's
synthesized in a ribosome attached to
the rough er
it's threaded into the systerial
space so what you'll notice in this
picture
is kind of this high degree of surface
here a lot of these folds
this allows for a lot of these ribosomes
to be packed in in a very small
area these folds kind of create its
shape
and this is a very efficient shape as
well
i mentioned these glycoproteins so
a protein with a glycogroup so proteins
with a carbohydrate
can think of like a protein with glucose
attached for example
it's an example of a carbohydrate these
proteins are packaged packaged into
transport
these kind of vesicles these curing
mediums
that can go to the next stage so while
information is coming out of the nucleus
going into the er not necessarily
finished when it leaves here it may have
one more step to finalize that and this
rough er
is a membrane factory as well these
membrane brown proteins are synthesized
directly into the membrane itself
so it's kind of like this system working
together
these enzymes in the rough er also
synthesized phospholipids from
precursors
in the cytosol of the cell now the
smooth er you can see kind of this
picture right here a little bit of a
contrast if you will
a very smooth in appearance but still
has a lot of folds
because there's basically no ribosomes
synthesis of lipids occurs
and it forms transport vesicles on the
site of various synthetic processes it
can also detoxify
and store things so the smoothie r does
have
vital functions specifically story
metabolizing
carbohydrates for the smooth er i could
synthesize and transport lipids which
are fats
and detoxify poisons in drugs such as
alcohol in the liver
so liver very important filter well it
contains a lot of this kind of smooth er
i can break down stored glucose and it
can help store calcium ions
in muscles so this er this smooth
er is found in a lot of cells and
performs a lot of
vital functions for our cell