okay here I'm gonna investigate the
plant hormone salicylic acid and if
you're wondering that this name sounds a
little familiar is a very similar to the
compound found in aspirin this is where
the rumors or focal airs come up with if
you add an aspirin to your watering can
when you go and water your plant how
that could be beneficial for that plant
that stems from this particular plant
hormone so salicylic acid impacts plant
growth in development the photosynthetic
pathway transpiration
I am uptake and transport so there's one
little hormone can involved as a lot of
plant processes involved in signaling
immediate planted defenses against
pathogens so these are all impacts at
this one single hormone can have on
plant growth now plays roles and
resistance to pathogens as well missus
where that benefit comes in that's
involved in the systemic acquired
resistance which pathogen attack on one
part of the plant induces resistance in
other parts so what does this mean well
this is involving if there's one area
that's seeing a point of infection this
hormone can be activated sent to other
parts of the plant to kind of up
regulate the defenses to help we make
the other plant more resistant to a
particular pathogen so that pathogen
having to infect different areas of the
plant having in one area up regulating
this particular hormone that signal can
be passed to the plant to make it better
to defend itself against that pathogen
exhibited one part odds are it's going
to want to spread to others now not only
can the silk signal impact the original
plant that becomes infected and that
includes different parts of that plant
the signal can also moved to nearby
plants this happens when a plant
converts the salicylic acid to volatile
compounds so it releases like a mist
year in the air so this is a great
advantage not to plants because if
there's one point in infection this is
one way one individual plant can get the
signal out to its neighbors that there's
a pathogen under attack hopefully
operating up regulating their defense
mechanisms to reduce the impact that
pathogen can have family on the original
plant that it infected but the
surrounding plants in that area