okay here we're going to be looking at
saturated in unsaturated fats as we see
from the initial picture here saturated
has very little linear organization and
unsaturated fats here have a presence of
a double bond creating this a little bit
more of a jagged appearance here so
we'll look at this more in a little bit
of a molecular scale this gives you this
is that quick comparison of the
saturated versus an unsaturated fat that
contains at least one double bond so
fatty acids can be saturated or
unsaturated there's our two main
classifications for saturated fats which
are mostly animal fats there's single
bonds between all carbon atoms so if one
way to remember saturated fats think of
it saturated with hydrogen's because
there's all single bonds here so there's
the maximum amount of hydrogen's located
on this molecule unsaturated fats are
typically oils we've mostly plant fats
may contain one or more double bond
between carbon atoms we see this line
here indicating a double bond this
double bond as compared to our saturated
fats women will be less total hydrogen's
here compared to saturated so
unsaturated fats have less total
hydrogens and have this double bond this
double bond causes a fixed point and
this can cause a change in the overall
shape of our fatty acid and I think this
picture kind of shows a nice
representation of that in saturated fats
you see saturated with hydrogen's
because it's all single bonds
however unsaturated fats only need one
double bond and that double bond can be
an assists orientation where we see both
hydrogens are located on the same side
and we have a trans orientation where
they're located on opposite sides here
so that double bond fixes those two
carbons and they're bonded together and
as a result we can have a cyst form but
they're both on the same side or we can
have a transform when we have one that
is below the other one there so keep in
mind saturates all look the same
unsaturated only needs one double bond
and that could be an ASIS or transform
those saturated fats are typically
solidifying they're cool cool they can
raise our cholesterol they're very
stable our unsaturated fats are
considered to be more of our good fats
they don't raise your cholesterol that
little unstable and they do not salute
asylum cool this is why these typically
are oils they're good fats the saturated
ones butters and things we may like the
ice creams tea cakes is are saturated
with hydrogen's and these are typically
have negative effects in the body where
we're raising our cholesterol that
saturated and unsaturated again here's
how our chains look highlighted the
unsaturated double bond here and the sis
form but this gives you an idea from
that first image of how our saturated
fats looks like a very nice tight line
and unsaturated fats had at least one
double bond in this case there's two
inside a little bit more of a notched
appearance located here comparing of fat
composition so oils they said have less
of those saturated fats and a greater
portion of those mono unsaturated
to one double bond or polyunsaturated
between multiple double bonds form their
dairy products could see a much higher
portion of saturated fats and little to
almost none of polyunsaturated fats and
there's some other meat products here
just to give you that kind of general
comparison look at some other
classifications here we have our nuts
sweetened baked goods and you can see
just on a quick comparison the change in
the amount of polyunsaturated fats and
same here butter very high percentage of
saturated fat so again just a good
comparison and a good resource to look
at and compare this is the cicero's
transforms cysteine on the same side
with that double bond trans being on
opposite sides here we get to see how
different those molecules look now
importantly remember these because trans
fats do not occur in nature so fats that
look like this where our hydrogens are
on opposite sides believe that do not
occur in nature we see a evidence here
of that trans fat so what they do exist
but they don't occur in nature
well they occur typically when we
process foods
so the cyst ruptures in your body is
able to process and
it's all structure right here trans are
not helpful for the body and linked to
cancer and heart disease so it's very
important of the structure of these
molecules and how it impacts our body
artificial trans fats are created in an
industrial process that adds hydrogen to
liquid vegetable oils making them more
solid so there's a advantage here in the
processing industry which is why some of
these have been created the primary
dietary source for trans fats is
processed foods and it's partially
hydrogenated oils as a result and now
we're seeing the negatives and linking
these negative effects to these trans
fats we're not seeing them required to
be on Nutrition Facts labels so foods
are required to state trans fat on the
label so take a look and know what
you're eating as a result of this
companies are now going about different
ways to achieve the same end result
without creating trans fats because of
their negative impacts in the body
however now with the label laws having
chemists required to state this you can
easily check to see if there's any trans
fats in the food you are consuming