okay we're gonna be looking at the
saturated media extract from soilless
media so I'd be wondering what this
exactly is the way you kind of think
about this is it's kind of like a soil
test for your soil less media so you
want to be taking your soilless media
and sending it to the lab and calling it
soil so you're not going to get really
that accurate or representative results
your soil less media because it contains
no soil needs to be treated differently
and the saturated media extract or SME
is the way to go to get accurate results
I've included a couple links down here
if you want some more information such
as from UConn soil testing lab and also
UMass again about this SME for soilless
media now this SMA is considered to be
the standard for testing the soilless
media and picture the pallets here kind
of that standard that gold standard it's
the one that is highly regarded in the
field
so this soilless media want to be
running to SME we don't want to be
sending this in as a soil sample again
because it's gonna use different
extraction fluids and not give us the
accurate results that you need
there's sample instructions so a little
different than that soil test if you
watch that lecture there I need to
provide a reputable and adequate sample
size for the lab the SMB through sample
directions independent fertilizer
regimen and method of production will
influence which we have so the pictures
of the legos here you don't wanted to
send them a bunch of random blocks gonna
have something that could mass together
and tell a good story or in this case
produced this Lego figure of Yoda to
tell a story of what your grow is going
to look like if you're kind of
haphazardly going through and sampling
and that really following the rules well
it's just like sending a bunch of blocks
you're not going to get some results
back is that really gonna help you you
send a quality sample and you can paint
a better picture of what's going on with
your plants the key is to be consistent
so birds need to be consistent with
their sampling and also consider the
following questions if comparing results
so if you take an example of a sample
early in the grow and it later I'm gonna
be able to compare those results
accurately you need to consider the age
or the stage of development of the plant
what the growing
you're using what's the fertilizer
program is there so release fertilizer
mixed in is there a plant problem going
on all of these factor into trying to be
consistent the sample you give the lab
and also allowing comparisons to be able
to occur if you're looking at the same
grow cycle and also the consider these
if you're comparing different grow
cycles or different plants on different
age groups lastly this SME procedure
what they do in the lab then what do you
think I miss the whole procedure here
they simply make a paste like tooth
paste here with soil and water and they
take the liquid portion which is the
extract they separate it from the solid
portion for pH disciple salts and
nutrient analysis so the procedure can
be very similar to a soil test but
exactly the details of how they go about
this is slightly different and therefore
you should be targeting the test in the
lab that matches the type of sample that
you're sending them so you get
representative results back so that
you're able to make informed decisions