you may have heard about the screen of
green method
of cannabis pruning well if you want to
learn more this debaco university video
is for you
all right let's go over the screen of
green pruning method
typically refer to scrog method for
cannabis production here we can see some
setups right here
and as the name implies it does involve
some sort of mesh screen
so first off the production for indoor
method shall we say screen of green or
scrog is very productive
and is an easy way to grow indoors when
the number of plants may be restricted
by
laws so it allows you really to take one
plant and kind of
maximize its area keep in mind that the
screen of green method
is not to be confused with the sea of
green method
which has more plants and does not
really involve training as this method
does
if you want to learn more about the sea
of green method check out debaco
university here
we have some detail on that method for
this method though
a screen is typically used to support
the plants and while it may not be
a natural pruning method it can maximize
single plant production and here's kind
of an example of five days of growth
here
of here on the left and five days later
what the plants can look like
i did mention this is showing indoor
this can also be done and not so
common but can also be done in an
outdoor situation as well
so the screen mesh and placement of that
mesh
so what is a scrog what's the screen of
green a screen that is the main
character of this method we can see made
of many different materials
but all those materials will be sturdy
materials it's commonly
has wire to support the plant canopy
there can be
mesh can be ropes here but we want to
have some sort of structure
there this the mesh of the screen should
be at least two inches by two inches
and up to four inches by four inches to
allow for ease of plant growth as well
as support
the placement of the screen is
determined by the lights used strain
being grown
and training design chosen by the grower
so again exactly where that's placed
will be grower dependent
you can also see the importance of air
circulation that's why you see the fan
down here as well as a monitor down in
this location
now the area many different styles of
screening materials some use
plastic netting or mesh other use
stronger material like wire
concrete wire is a good option versus
chicken wire chicken wire is a little
too fine
of an area there could be used but again
that wouldn't be my first choice
some growers used 50 watt hps per square
foot target for their screen to give you
an idea of the
leaf area to lighting watts coverage
but you want to see the following watts
to screen size and light distance
suggestions and again these are only
suggestions
so again if you're growing a typical
kind of thousand watt i'm going to keep
it about 24 inches away
plus and you want to have about a four
and a half by four and a half screen
size just to give you an
idea there of the wattage of lighting
you may have and the screen size you
might be looking at
instituting now the light dispersion so
we're looking at the light how are we
going to disperse that light
to maximize the space and dispersion of
the light to determine how close the
light can get to the canopy
also keep in mind as i pointed out
earlier do not forget about air
circulation
note that distances should be checked
with a par meter to ensure consistent
light intensities across the canopy
regardless of your chosen
light source so you want to make sure
that all of the areas here
are getting an even an equal amount of
light you don't have any hot spots
now the plant number so plant numbers
are based on how much space the borough
wants to train each plant to take up
however in general the goal is to limit
the plant number and maximize the space
east
each plant takes up with this method
kind of the complete opposite or
contrast of the sea of green methane
less plants do require a longer time
into vegetative stage
more plants allows for shorter
vegetative time that's again
characteristics of the sea of green this
is this
screen of green as growers become more
skilled they can often reduce the number
of plants to be grown in the same square
for
area because a lot of it comes down to
as we can see here the training
typical era for a plant is one to four
square feet depending on the duration of
veg
and experience of the grower this is
another reason why it's so popular if
growers are limited in number of plants
they can grow
these screen of green allows them to
cover more area for each plant
now timing is critical consider we say
more experienced growers
timing the flip to flower that 12 hours
of light 12 hours of dark is critical to
maximizing the area for each plant
the general lewis rule is to wait until
the screen areas about 70 to 80 percent
full
before grower decides to flip their
plants to that flowering photo period
exact timing can be partially strain
dependent since we're keeping records is
a good idea
now training the plants you want to
start typically allowing
four to six inches to grow above the
screen height this acts as the plant
material be trained by pulling the
branches back
under the screen in a horizontal
orientation going under the screen is
advised as this limits the need
for additional support to keep the
plants in place but is more difficult if
the
mesh is very fine screening material
i'll try that two to four inch
mesh screening is recommended this is an
ongoing process of
branch training to direct the plants
that take up the empty or gap spaces
so growers need to be aware of where
those gap spaces are and where they can
kind of direct those
branches to go so you don't have any
empty spaces because you're paying for
that light anyway
however you want to keep the pruning to
a minimum as you want to have as many
branches to fill the screen area as
possible
and this shows a great kind of under
canopy view here
of what kind of it looks like under the
screen where there's no leaves but you
can see a lot of branches a lot of
twisting turning to again to maximize
that screen coverage area
now we're pruning those leaves printed
leaves should be done
if the leaf is shaded a bud site since
the main goal is to increase the light
intensity on the actual buds which will
overall will help maximize plant
production
however do so in moderation especially
early in the trading process to not
further stress the plant
potentially stunt its growth so again
this is where timing comes into
play a little bit and this is again
where grower experience plays into it
now with this screen of green with
clones or seeds or or both
some growers believe that clones are the
only way to go with this pruning style
and while clones may be a little bit
more predictable it does not mean this
method isn't limited only to clone
starting material
due to the time investment with the
training process if you're using seeds
feminized seed would strongly be
encouraged but keep an eye out still for
that one in 100 that might be male
because you spend a lot of time pruning
and training that before you even see
the flowers
so you won't be wasting your time
pruning or training a male plant that
ultimately will just be discarded
do not forget about ventilation again
this is very important with this
method above the plants as well as below
the plants
because you're going to establish a leaf
canopy pretty tightly through that
screen
so it's important not to prevent about
the ventilation the screen will often
act as a physical barrier
so above and below the canopy
ventilation should be considered we can
see the fan here for above
also fans below or advised sometimes
this will require two separate fans
even in small spaces because you're
creating basically this physical barrier
lastly when you're looking at this
method looking at the plant hormone
influence well this does increase the
meristem regions and requires pruning of
the with the intention of maximizing
branching of the plant
you can see here one plant but a lot of
different branch points coming out
removing the apical meristem or pinching
reduces the natural auxin levels
resulting in elongation in increase in
side branching
so again that may be advised to help
increase the amount of branching so you
can get
maximum coverage area of your screen
and maximize the area that your plant
will take up
to limit the number of plants you can
grow and again a little pruning a little
advanced
placement of the screen this method can
be very productive and this is why it's
commonly used
but lastly don't forget about that
ventilation so you decrease the odds of
getting diseases
building up in your plants