have you heard about the sea of green
method of pruning
for cannabis production but want to
learn more this debaco university video
will provide you with some details
about just that learning more here about
the sea of green method of pruning to
see if it's a right fit for your growing
situation
[Music]
all right let's get into the sea of
greener sog pruning method
for cannabis production so first off
this method is really intended to
maximize speed
the sea of green method was developed to
maximize the speed of cannabis growth
especially if overall height is limited
and this is
commonly done in grow tents where you do
have that limiting of the plant height
it's also more commonly done with
starting material is clones versus seeds
however it can be performed with either
plants can be planted in
at densities that are as high as nine
plants per square foot
so this is really maximizing plant
number while decreasing overall plant
size
within a short time after being
established the lights will be switched
to a 12 hour dark period
inducing flowering so the plant height
itself the plants typically should reach
about 12 inches or
tall or so before you decide to flip
them and that's basically change the
photo period of your lights
from a vegetative photo period 18 plus
hours of light
to 12 hours of light here which is the
flowering photoperiod
they should finish around 18 to 20
inches tall as far as your plants are
concerned
the plants should be grown in three
gallon pots to maximize the density
with the limit of water stress however
some growers will choose to utilize this
method and grow their plants in only one
gallon containers
so simply they can pack more plants in
but the water frequency will have to be
increased so just keep that in mind the
goal of this method simply is to
maximize production we also utilize all
the space available
particularly when you're lighting it and
have to have those upfront costs
to maximize flower production so here we
can see all the containers literally
touching one another can't really get
any denser than that
and quick turnaround time for the
flowers
now the plant hormone influence with
this uh method uh this relatively quick
flip of the flowering photo period
12 12 12 hours of light 12 hours of
darkness flying duration limits the
plant's overall height how tall they're
going to get
which is great in grow tents this
induces flower quicker and allows for a
quicker time to harvest a faster
turnaround time
the plant density should be high because
while there is no alterations to the
normal hormone concentrations of the
plants
because this shift occurs sooner than it
is
normal overall yield per plant will be
reduced so growers need to make up the
difference by increasing the overall
plant numbers
simply you're going to get less per
plant with this pruning method
but by growing more plants you can make
up that difference and sometimes that
quicker turnaround time
is more advantageous and if it is this
might be a pruning method
you consider