on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over a very common method of
curing cannabis
and it's carrying cannabis in sealed
containers so if we can pick up some
of important information here to make
your occurring process as successful as
possible
[Music]
all right let's look at sealed container
curing of cannabis
we see an image of that right here one
example we have a humidity control pack
cannabis buds in a sealed container here
so first off we want to limit the size
of the container
so since containers are used will be of
limiting size the buds should be removed
from the branches this may have been
done during the trimming
stage but this may need some extra
attention to detail to ensure only the
chosen material
enters the curing process now i say
limited size of containers this doesn't
mean you want to have like a small
little micro size container
but if you have these giant large
containers it might sound really easy
i can just control the environment in
there it can be a lot harder
so typically using smaller size
containers trimming down the buds to
ensure only the
valuable materials placed in them is
something that is advised
now that chosen container what container
actually going to put the buds in well
wide mouth mason jars as pictured here
typically are the preferred option
a 32 ounce jar on average holds about an
ounce of dried bud plus or minus
the goal is to leave about 25 air
airspace within the container
you don't want to go through and pack
the full container you want to leave a
little bit of
space there to allow some movement of
those buds and they don't want to
compact and do any physical damage to
them
also bigger scent necessarily better as
the container gets large
larger the ability to ensure a
controlled drying process and curing
process becomes
more challenging simply because the
large volume of
the mold has an increased odds of
developing
now these wide mouth mason jars very
commonly used
used at great extent i've had some
people say that they don't want to use
these simply because they live in area
prone to earthquakes
i typically advise them you might want
to reconsider where you're living
because these are glass jar so keep that
in mind you probably other than the
photo here probably don't want to be
storing them in this particular
kind of orientation simply because you
don't want to have the risk of damage to
them or breaking
of that glass mason jar so we see here
we want to shake it up well
the idea comes here for to avoid the
buds from becoming a mass
and occasional shaking it may be advised
to keep each bud separate
that's part of the reason why we want to
leave that 25 percent gap there
you want to avoid over shaking to limit
the amount of physical damage that
occurs but kind of just a light general
shaking or even just turning of the
container can be enough just to ensure
that each bud
is consistently independent of one
another
and then where do you want to put these
well a dark place most containers should
used do not block light completely so be
sure to place your containers in a dark
cool environment you could see here a
dark room kind of like that wine
cellar-like
concept there where it can be a little
bit light and kind of reduced light as
far as intensity and duration goes
but overall want to keep them in a
relatively dark low light
environment and this is a process
that you don't want to set and forget
the curing process should be routinely
routinely checked on
this can be very important in the early
stages to the buds containing the
highest moisture content
here we can see three different
containers relatively similar
temperatures relatively same humidities
but definitely one is a little bit
different and this is something we do
want to be checking on because we want
to make sure we don't want to lose or
jeopardize the end harvest at this very
late stage
in the full process so this concept of
burping containers you may have heard
this burping the containers and valves
opening the container
a few times a day for the first week to
allow moisture to escape
and oxygen to replenish during this
process check for
follow odor as this can be a sign that
mold is starting to develop
so burning is just simply open the
container and then closing it back up
again
allow that gas exchange to occur rather
any moisture to kind of leave and allow
oxygen to replenish within the container
typically done daily at least during the
first week
expected humidity progression so there
will be a decrease overall
using a hydrometer should be used to
know the exact humidity level of the
curing environment
the target humidity range usually around
60 to 65 percent
sometimes you can get a little too low
sometimes you can get on the higher side
and we can see each one
of these individual containers has its
own kind of gauge there
so as we saw previously just because you
have it in one doesn't mean
every container is going to be exactly
the same
good to know if one's running a little
high one's running a little low
because it really can prevent long-range
problems or ultimately
loss of that particular container or
crop
so after that first week routine checks
can go down to twice daily
from twice daily i should say to
basically every day so checking them
morning and night and just checking them
once a day after that first week
as you get to that week's two you know
two and three you can decrease that the
drying process seems to be going good
drying process is progressing well you
can even go down to
uh in every other day routine check
every other two you know skip a day skip
two days if anything's going well there
as you get later in that process because
you'll have less and less variability
and closer to that ideal range
so how do you know when you've reached
the end of curing will some growers use
three weeks until final cure others up
to eight weeks into the final cure
kind of gauge cut the buds are looking
engage the humidity levels and then once
you've reached the end of your curing
process
keep in mind you're not quite done yet
you're almost there the next step after
caring is storing
there's other videos here in debacle
university that you're welcome to take a
look
at to ensure you have a quality storing
process
to keep all that hard work that you did
to keep it as long
as possible in peak condition