okay here we're gonna discuss season
extensions always to get a little bit
longer growing season there's many
different styles many different purposes
you could see just because you have a
structure doesn't mean you can't have
the structure within a structure tall
crops long crops all different styles so
I'm going to touch on just the main
points here just to give you an idea
what's available so first off for season
extensions there's small styles they can
adjust rows they are used to help
protect very small plantings here not
very tall low in a tight area areas you
might be switching or changing excellent
for that purpose still getting the
benefits of added heat and reduced
frost potential for damage but not
having to set up a very large or
elaborate structure and there's your
mid-sized caterpillar tunnels for
gaining massive popularity great if
you're considering the high tunnel but
are unsure if you want to commit to one
easy to set up I've set them up I really
don't take all that much time a little
prep work a little yes there's some
bolting and some measuring to do but
overall easily done in a weekend and
they say they said the great you're
considering a height élber not 100% sure
we're committed to that and you can set
multiple up and they give you an idea of
what it is like growing in a protective
structure and some of the benefits
that's what some of the challenges in
growing then caliper toes relatively
inexpensive not very wide but long great
for long areas of fields and as I said
instead of just committing yourself to
one you could easily do two and offers a
lot of flexibility that you're also
pretty easy to move if you wanted to do
crop rotations which is advised larger
styles is your true high tunnels do the
grants have become very popular
springing up all over the place if you
get more than one though I tried it to
the same size it makes it a lot easier
for management purposes they have
advantages but need to be taken care of
the plastic should be removed during the
winter and or the structure should be
able to be moved and it should be moved
it shouldn't be a permanent structure in
one solid location should have the
option of being moved
the reason being is you leaving that one
area can leave to the build-up of
nutrient
I don't get a lot of leaching I can also
have pest issues and problems so this is
why these aren't greenhouses they're
called high tunnels because they're able
to be moved so high tones versus a
greenhouse well high tones are temporary
they don't have an extra heat source so
you can see here they're just literally
tunnels that are tall greenhouses are
more permanent structures they can get
paved and solid floors high degree of
climate control heaters coolers sauce
fans a lot of electricity enough hanging
lights a lot more of a permanent
structures true high tunnels are just
that they're usually placed in fields
and there are tunnels that are high and
they're just aiding an extended net
growing season a very important part
where they have a small one a midsize or
a large one or even a greenhouse is
keeping these structure clean inside and
out is extremely important this can
often be overlooked especially when
they're brand new they look very nice
and they are but you got to maintain
that reduce the potential for disease
carryover it is the number one reason we
want to limit your local pest pressure
clean it sweeping up the floors making
sure there's not a lot of residue don't
using this storage for certain things
that letting crops die in there and then
just leaving them going through washing
the plastic even as you take it down the
inside the outside it's very important
to keep them clean in and out this is an
example of a relatively good size high
tunnel here showing you what it can look
like any season nice and clean here I
want to visit this farm it's the only
here a couple clippings here they're
doing some pruning but how clean it is
top bottom and plants they don't want to
have a micro environment here that can
increase your own pressure of pests
lastly extending your season you extend
it early as in the March April May time
frame or late September October November
it mage's early is that you can get a
jump on the season often get ahead of
pest pressure which is great late in the
season you can continue to Thanksgiving
meal if you're delivering that for
someone or the pests pressure can be
higher though later in the season so
just a word of caution that's starting a
little bit later in maintaining them
keeping them
for especially late season crops is
important ruin the season you need ten
that that has many problems but still
almost well I'll keep it cleaned and so
you don't have any issues and pushing
that season early and late can be great
hmm what if he do says your offseason so
keep that in mind