okay here I want to probably a brief
overview of some season extenders in the
different styles some growers use these
terms interchangeably but I want you to
understand what each of these different
titles refers to so we're just season
extenders all of these are performing
the same tasks so first off there's our
small style the season extenders and
they're just covering the rows and they
can help protect small plantings or
early plantings or plants that are going
to stay small initially great options
there to extend the season there to get
out a little bit earlier or to hold them
a little bit later in the season then
there's our mid-size season extender so
these are called caterpillar tunnels the
gray if you're considering a high tunnel
but are unsure if you want to commit to
a hotel they're easy to set up and set
one up easily over a weekend maybe a
date at least for the first one takes a
little bit time to get everything
oriented but offer a lot of the
advantage that high tunnel offers but a
little bit quicker easier and cheaper up
coming from our midsize we have our
large size and these would be our full
high tunnels this is it's kind of this
size here do the grants are becoming
very popular if you do get more than one
I do recommend you get two of the same
size because it makes management of them
a lot easier they have advantage but
they need to be taken care of especially
in the winter removing plastic is a
great option
I'd revenge them from caving in also
they can lead to build-up of nutrients
and pests again if you're not removing
the plastic so it's good to kind of
remove that plastic let some snow what
some winter rains come through to kind
of flush out some of the nutrients that
may be being accumulated in them over
the growing season
now hotels are different than
greenhouses high tunnels are temporary
and do not have extra heat sources
greenhouses are more of a permanent
structure typically a floor here and you
can see that evident here this would be
example of a hotel can technically be
moved pretty easily in not permanent
structures and on a tower of running to
them now season extensions no matter
what size or unit you're using be sure
to keep them clean inside and out is
very important this is often overlooked
we do seek to potential
for disease carryover limit the local
pest pressure this is also why I
recommend using insect netting to
eliminate insects but keeping them clean
both interior and exterior that's an
example of a farm I visited this is one
of the high tunnels that they have and
you can see it's very clean
this is even during the peak of tomato
season see in between the rows are all
nice and cleanly kept irrigation under
here nicely pruned nicely trained
keeping that I tunnel clean is very
important to reducing disease pressure
now season extension can be early such
as March April and May and they've
antecedent jump on this season can often
get ahead of pest pressure this is where
I think they're most advantageous late
in the season extended crops into
September October November it can
continue this season for a longer to get
closer to their Thanksgiving meal if
you're trying to supply that for maybe a
CSA but the pest pressure can be higher
so that's a little bit of precaution if
you want to go later in the season
typically its investigate that early
season jump because you're getting
beating out the pests must always keep
your structure clean