okay here we're looking at the three
secondary nutrients anyway so I have the
shifter here of the cars our primary
nutrients are needed first and then
secondary nutrients are kind of the ones
we would go to next as far as concern
when feeding our plants so looking first
at calcium represent ICA it's involved
with providing structural support to
cell walls and serves as a secondary
messenger in response to stress it does
not translate well in the plant so
that's in mindful they keep that in mind
as a grower that's hard to kind of get
that through the plant you can show
deficiency symptoms particularly in the
newer growth so looking up neutralize
acids when it's added there can be
commonly found in bones and again that
cell wall keep in mind that's a very
important component of plant cells
magnesium is the second one I want to go
over and it's essential component of
chlorophyll and also aids in the
activation of many plant enzymes is we
see the comparison here of plant
chlorophyll with it the magnesium there
in the center we notice if we look for
the quick these structures are very
similar
this is hemoglobin in the human body so
hemoglobin spining oxygen and we can see
magnesium here being that central
molecule being important for chlorophyll
production all the lower leaves will
typically show a deficiency by yellowing
first dolomitic limestone kind of that
limestone we used to correct pH is a
common source for magnesium for the
plants keep an eye out if you're using
cocoa quar is this media of choice and
supplementation is often needed so if
you're using cocoa car if that's the
media you're choosing these keep in mind
you may have to be adding more magnesium
in a grower choosing another media
source lhasa here we have sulfur it's
need for amino acid our protein or
enzyme production keep in mind amino
acids make up proteins and proteins are
our general category for enzymes a
sulfur also helps chlorophyll formation
an improved root growth and seed
production sulfur may be applied to soil
from rainwater via acid rain however
this is becoming less and less over time
as we're cleaning up the acid rain which
is a great thing because it's you know
degrading some of our forests and you
know our roading some of our monuments
that's a great thing but as a result
that acid rain was supplying
sulfur so girls may now need to add some
sulfur products the supplement what's
not coming free from the rain water if
you use gypsum or epsom salts this will
increase sulfur levels so if you're
looking at a way to add at epsom salts
and or gypsum are ways to do that so you
can find that is the third of the
secondary nutrients is another one to
keep an eye out for in your play in your
plants