on this tobacco university video going
to go over
sectioning a site for cannabis
production and how we might want to
allocate different areas within a large
field
and how small or what parameters would
be used for making different
ideas or sections within a large field
[Music]
just as we see the different sections of
pizza let's go into sectioning the site
for cannabis production so first off
during the evaluation process
is when you should kind of have an idea
of where you might want to have
different sections
so when evaluating a potential growth
site there may be different
differences noticed in one or many parts
of the process
growers should section out these into
subsections to provide specific analysis
of these areas differently
than the rest now again how small you
make these or what differences do you
notice
well here we're seeing these dark green
patches we're seeing these much yellow
margins is in these brown
areas as well now it could be very
difficult to
individually monitor each individual
little area
so we're looking at where the general
trends are we see this area here
for the most part fairly consistent and
we see areas over here
a little less consistent as well as over
in this region
so when in doubt if there's two sections
in particular that you're going through
and evaluating that appear to be
different
at the very least growers are advised to
take separate soil samples
for each and can you identify any of
these issues within your field as we see
here this kind of yellowing
banning that's occurring sometimes this
can be explained by visual differences
and other times it confirms
that the soil is the same and that
there's another reason for the
difference is noticed
so when we're comparing two sections
well it might be good to take a soil
test from here and here
if the results come back the same it
might be a water issue
it could be something else that's going
on could be a different kind of soil
a vein that runs through here but it's
good to know especially when you're
evaluating a new site
so at the very least which supposed to
be doing uh grocery
section should be defined as separate
fields even if
in very close proximity if separate soil
tests shows similar conditions
then a grower can know that to treat
these two fields in a similar manner
so here if we see these little driving
lanes here and we see these different
blocks
it would be advised at least initially
to sample these differently
now if these come back the same well now
we know in the future to manage those
very similarly however we're seeing an
elevation change and while they may look
very similar
there's the potential for for great
differences in the 20
soil test can really save a lot of money
in the long run
so how small the area should be section
can go through and how fine do we detail
something or how broad we detail
something
and really it comes down to the grower's
discretion however when first evaluating
an area these sections should be as
small as
reasonable to manage in the great scheme
of things soil tests are cheap
and in comparison you probably don't
have to go through this small little
detail level
but taking a couple more soil tests and
getting them analyzed just to confirm
something that would be a great point of
advisement
however if they do come back the same it
does not mean you have to keep sampling
that many times
but it could initially to get that kind
of idea together
especially if it's a new area now how do
we develop these
subsections well if the field is large
it can be broken into
subsections the boundary of subsections
is often based on past
practices for example as we see here
compost in a cover crop versus compost
only
and this might be the same field be good
to soil sample these separately
some fields also have multiple crops on
them that are rotated so that can also
be utilized as different subsections to
be sampling
the areas of rotation that have occurred
in the past may be within the same field
so subsectioning would be used to demark
these areas
and again gives the growers a little bit
more information
now as the grower it's important for to
go through the process of
label and documentation so getting a
printout of the area is important
to get before you go into an area this
will help you orient yourself and also
mark where you're taking soil samples
and what you're going to call each
sample when naming try to select names
that do not change
for example north middle if we're
talking we're in the northern area
and in the middle section of that
particular field
if you're labeling something called like
corn field this is not a great name
because it might be rotated and if
pepper's grown the next year and then
you might rotate back
into hemp and then go into corn so just
keep in mind you want to usually stay
away from crop names
if a farmer is currently using an area
you may want to also make note of what
they call the field
so if you have any questions you can use
their terminology
for example if you you may name it north
middle but if whatever reason the farmer
always calls it grams field
by current land owner that that might be
what you might want to call it simply
because
that current landowner might know oh
yeah on grandma's field
x y or z it can really just help you
learn it in the sense that you can
utilize some more of that history if
you're calling it by a different name
you might lose some of that background
or history that the previous land owner
or someone you're leasing the land from
might have so again just some
suggestions there
hopefully you find these helpful