in this video we're gonna look at seed
plants or plants that produce seeds and
I gave two representative samples here
it doesn't mean you just name only two
in this case this be the dandelion and
the pine tree so the evolution of seed
plants the seed is a critical adaptation
to life on land because it protects the
embryonic plant when it is at its most
vulnerable stage of its life seed has
produced two kinds of community it's
male and female which develop completely
within the sporophyte the milk
gametophyte is called the pollen grains
and this gives rise to the microspores
the female criminal fight contains the
egg within the ovule and this develops
into the megaspore kind of a way to try
to remember this is you think it's like
a sperm and an egg the sperm is very
small in comparison to the egg and the
sperm in this case represents the pollen
and that's the male portion that's a
very small region and the egg or the
ovules the metaphor here it's much
larger in comparison in size so
evolution of seed plants all same plants
are derived from a single common
ancestor and there's two main branch
points here we have gymnosperms and
angiosperms so gymnosperms the ovules
are not completely enclosed by the
sporophyte tissue at the time of
pollination sig evident by our pinecone
here microscopic female gametophyte n is
inside the ovulate cone and microscopic
male gametophyte n inside the pollen
cone here also so you see if you look
very carefully pine trees they yes they
have the cones they also produce these
male microspores here which is
containing the pollen angiosperms the
other case here are ones that produce
flowers they most recently evolved the
ovules are completely enclosed in the
sporophyte tissue called the carpel and
this is at the time of pollination and
they're the ones producing the true
flowers here microscopic female
gametophyte and inside the parts of the
flower and the microscopic male can we
fight inside these flower parts here
and it's this again the sporophyte the
2n and the pollen in is the end along
with the egg so what does the see the
evolution of the seed see has three
visible parts to it the endosperm is a
source of food that developed that the
developing embryo needs in some sense
the endosperm is used up by the embryo
and stored as food in structures called
cotyledons we're going to talk about
monocots and dicots dicot meaning dye
meaning to there's basically two seed
leaves monocot meaning one series the
embryo is the simple small little plant
lip and that's just kind of what's gonna
house the genetic information that's
going to develop into the full size plan
and the coat is a drought resistance
protective layer that's the outside here
so we see the comparison between a bean
seed in the corn seed and I'll have
another video that describes monocots
and dicots will be able to further
understand the difference between the
two but right now just looking at the
seeds you see they have a lot of the
same parts the key difference here is
the cotyledon we have cuddling here
putting the two binning dicots to seed
leaves in this being seen and the
cuddling in the corn is only one so
benefits of seeds will seeds out for a
lot of benefits the plants dispersal is
one facilitates the migration to new
habitats see here by the wind carrying
new seeds of vanillin dormancy this
permits plants have delayed the
development until conditions are
favorable plant doesn't necessarily
germinate in the fall it's not going to
be able to tolerate the harsh winter
particularly here in New England
germination controls when the plant
develops so that it can be synchronized
with critical aspects and the plants
habitat clearance might want to time the
germination and the lay their dormant
say so once most favourable for them to
actually grow in nourishment seeds
provide nourishment of the young plant
during the critical period just after
germination as we see here so relating
to drumming and germination this young
seedling here may want to wait till this
spring when the larger trees in shade
that it might be around it aren't fully
developed yet it is getting some
nutrients here to allow it to fully
expand its leaves
before it starts making its own sugars
from the Sun improve seed dispersal is
fruits fruits are a great way plants
have developed to be able to disperse
their seeds mature ovaries surrounds the
ovule becomes all or part of the fruit
in our angiosperms again our flower
producing plans they use fruits to
induce animals to disperse the seeds
although eaten by animals the seats
within the fruit are resistance -
chewing and digestion they passed out of
the animal in the feces ready to
germinate at a new location far from the
plant this is why typically farmers may
add manure to their fields because it
helps plants grow this could be a
potential reason why that occurs is
polenta used to be able to pass through
the digestive system and then grow in
the fertile manure
some fruits are dispersed by wind or
water see here the coconut water and our
data line again by wind but just because
a bird comes through and picks up a very
here doesn't mean it's a bad thing for
the plant it's being dispersed to
different regions us watermelons may
take them to picnics and the monkeys and
the squirrels here ways to disperse
things also the seeds can kind of attach
themselves in this case physically to
clothing or other animals through these
birds may be dispersed that way all
these are ways that plants have evolved
to help increase their ability to
disperse their seeds and take over and
be introduced to new locations