hey as we go along we're getting a
little bit more complex through our
plant evolution and we're at the point
of seedless vascular plants you may be
familiar with the most common example
here are ferns all to the category of
seedless vascular plants I want to use a
term vascular though you might be
wondering what what does this refer to
well vascular tissues are specialized
cylindrical or elongated cells that form
a network throughout the plant think of
it like the vessels going through the
plant there's two types of this vascular
tissue first type is called xylem and
this conducts water and minerals from
their roots or port to the rest of the
plant xylem works mainly in one
direction starting at the roots going up
to what we call the chutes and then
ultimately the leaves water will then
exit out the leaves through the stomata
the other vascular tissue is called
phloem this conducts carbohydrates
throughout the plant now phloem can work
both going from roots to chutes but it
can also go from shoots down to roots
phloem is ability to move up and down
the plant reason why that's important is
carbohydrates need to be moved
throughout the entire plant they grow in
a potato below ground that storage organ
the carbohydrates made in the leading to
be moved down to the potato here we have
an actively growing
apical meristem the growing tip we need
to move coverage from this leaf up to
the plant to here so phloem is ability
to go up and down this transporting
mainly sugars to describe a hydrates
xylem is conducting water in some
minerals is mainly working from the
roots upward in one direction to the top
of the plant now are believed to be the
oldest remaining group of the vascular
plants as meant to have been around 400
million years these if you've ever been
walking in the woods you see these
examples of a crown pine which are a
kind of a subset of club mosses and we
think they're going to get any taller
altered they're not this is their
typical fully grown size there's some
other types of club mosses you can see
they look very different and we're
progressing along our Colada gram here
we're working our way getting to
gymnosperms and angiosperms
what we see we've progressed from our
losses our hunger to our liver works and
this are all originated from our common
ancestor of green algae
now these seedless vascular plants ferns
as I said is the most common one you're
probably familiar with this sporophyte
generation is much larger and more
complex than the gametophyte when we
commute if I it's going to produce
gametes sporophyte is going to produce
the spores leaves on a sporophyte are
called fronds
so this gets into lists a little
terminology here and we're looking at
the seal is vascular plants in
particular ferns this entire isn't
called a leaf this is called a frond
this phylum also includes wisk ferns and
horsetails also fall into this category
the blade is the area here as we see we
have the frond being the entire portion
and the blade being where we would
typically say where the leaves are but
each one of these there are little
leaflets so this is kind of all one
continuous unit here and that is
referred to again as the frond for ferns
now the alternation of generations
I mentioned a little bit before as I
said you're most familiar with the large
sporophyte this is what it looks like
the haploid generation that's producing
the gametes here the comida fie it looks
very different and those spores are
coming together as sore on the other
side of the lead of the frontier that
are falling to the ground they're
producing the gametophyte so produces
both male and female committed fights
and to fertilize to develop the diploid
organism here it will then produce the
sporophyte lastly of the fern lifecycle
there's a rhizome which is a modified
underground stem the sources I mentioned
here is a collection of spore producing
sporangia and they're the little dots on
the underside of the lead if you've ever
looked at a frond of a fern that leaf
you may see some little dots under it
that's the sporangium and that's going
to produce the spores that ultimately
boost the comida fights that produced
the next generation in New England early
in the springtime may see something
called fiddleheads
these are young curled fronds in some
are edible they don't last for very long
early in the spring
typically once of April in May you may
see these kind of curled up things
starting to grow those are small little
curled up fronds of a fern and some
people really like them and there's
certain varieties that are edible and
you may see them as illicit as
restaurants as fresh plants if you can't