welcome to another debaco university
video
here we'll be looking at selecting a
male plant for cannabis breeding it's a
question often asked well how they go
about selecting the male plant
we're going to go through and breed two
cannabis plants so
hopefully this video will provide you
with a little bit more information
if you're looking at going down this
path
so first off there are some first off
there are some challenges with
male plants because often growers are
breeding for traits that are specific to
female plants
but there are there needs to be a
pollinator chosen
so selecting a quality pollinator that
may not exhibit the specific desired
traits
can be part of the challenge in the
breeding process however there are some
key aspects to look for
and document as part of your breeding
process and hopefully i'll be able to
provide you
with some information regarding that so
first off we want to consider the meal
plans morphology morphology to keep in
mind is the basic structure of the plant
morphology is important since the goal
is to maintain a plant structure that
can support itself
while producing the necessary compounds
if you have a plant that produces great
compounds
but is a very spindly weak kind of
structure or morphology
that can be a very negative when you're
looking at the breeding process so again
male plant morphology is definitely
something to document and to consider
i want to be considering the branching
and also the internode
spacing for how dense of a plant that it
might be producing or contributing to
the genetics of your breeding project
in addition male plants can still
produce terpenes and while they may not
end up in the flower
in great concentrations if you kind of
rub the stem
this can help indicate what terpene
profile
that plant may produce this can be used
to help the grower determine what
compounds the male plant may have
for the initial phase of selection again
if you're going through it's important
to kind of like isolate one
area rub the stem to begin the lower
part and you'll get an idea of what that
terpene profile
might be there's also plant vigor so
aggressively growing plants can help the
breeding process
and this help the growing in general can
have a really nice
healthy robust looking quick growing
highly vigorous plant so this is another
consideration
when looking at male plants then we have
the pollen production it's probably the
number one reason why we're considering
male plants is
they're pollen for breeding purposes
while pollen is needed selecting males
that are
high pollen producers can help increase
the overall usage of the plants
and limit the total number of male
plants needed to grow
so male male plants will produce pollen
but if you're selecting some that
produce higher rates of pollen
that can allow growers to grow less male
plants have
greater control so that is another trait
to kind of look for
that might be advantageous in the
breeding process
now male plants producing female flowers
and i put kind of a question mark there
and there is uh it is possible to kind
of go through with a reversal
epithelium induced feminization in male
plants of cannabis sativa by ethylene
antagonist
so interaction between f ephron
and two ethylene antagonist one silver
nitrate another cobalt chloride
applied exogenously meaning to the
exterior of the plant to the male
cannabis sativa plant
was studied the feminization effect was
caused by two sprays
of 960 milligrams per liter
of ephron can could be overcome by 100
micrograms
of that's silver nitrate or cobalt
chloride
however neither of the antagonists could
suppress the feminization effect
of 1920 milligrams per liter
of ephron sprayed twice this is again
a way that male plants can produce
female flowers this might be
advantageous
in your breeding process to kind of go
through and determine
where that might be advantageous if you
look in the description there should be
a
link to this particular research paper
that you're welcome to go
and investigate further if you're
looking at some of the details of this
study then there's also the requirement
of official
lab testing so testing promising male
plants via a professional lab is
important to get the cannabinoid and
terpene profiles
this should be a very targeted and
selective process
unless you have a very large budget you
want to be very selective on the plants
that you're choosing
to potentially breed further and send
those off
for independent lab testing and
independent plant testing
this can help you have a track record
and a great kind of documentation as far
as what that plant produced
for continuation of breeding or maybe
for elimination
of breeding if it did not produce what
you were considered to be desirable
and then lastly typically many people
grow male plants produce the pollen and
then cull them
you really want to let the male plants
complete their full growth cycle if
possible
do not simply cut them down once they
produce the pollen needed letting the
plants go through a natural growth style
can help provide some more information
on how these genes may perform at the
end of the growth cycle which could be
important
this can be important for female plant
production and harvest
and just something else to consider
instead of just chopping down that flour
does it get powdery mildew late does it
have other sort of issues later in the
growing cycle
other important notes that as a breeder
and grower if you're
looking at considering those genes to
continue them on
would be an important piece of
information can really help with your
breeding
process and overall success