now there are many different types of
containers when growing on selecting the
right one is important how do you go
about looking at the options that are
there and how you go about selecting the
right one for your situation well
there's many factors that come into play
as we see here looking at many different
colors for you want to consider what
else is in the room what sizes of the
room one of the other room colors just
the same thing comes in when it's a
latina container want to be thinking
about what type of plants we grow in
what size are they going to be what are
we looking at for convenience but
there's a cost with its availability
what's the size the shape the color
staging plants material and are we
growing in large beds so again all these
things come into play
this is why it's simply a little bit
more complex you may have originally
thought how the material is the first
thing to consider while the plant may
not being direct directly affected by
the material material that the container
is made out of to have many different
types and different properties
associated with that clay pots are kind
of the old old standard they're very
heavy they will wick moisture away
increasing the need for irrigation as a
result these are rarely used in
large-scale production anymore metal
pots can corrode over time wooden pots
sadly with wooden pots they can break
down over time or degrade they can also
Harbor disease and when used for
multiple cropping cycles as a result the
main focus here and most popular of
course is plastic pots due to their
lightweight ease of storage long life in
reduced moisture loss as a result this
will be the main focus of the discussion
from here on they have rigid and grow
bags both polymer the plastic category
just went to me to where of some of the
other pots but plastic by far is going
to be the main focus here so convenience
some growers use what they can easily
find out what's on the shelf what do I
have some extras of sometimes this is
what's free or what what they can wash
and clean the containers before use
however this leads to issues with
consistency having different pot sizes
and different shape pots reduce your
efficiency so overall cost savings is
minimal give the example if you have a
very small pot in a very large pot and
you're both trying to grow plant in
those they have very different watering
requirements you could miss one need to
overwater one
and this creates just that lack of
consistency that lack of efficiency in
your grow operation we also wanna be
looking at the cost of the container and
while the cost will depend on many
factors typically the thickness and size
of the containers are typically the
driving force behind the cost we can
reuse plastic pots after good rinse and
wash down so this can vastly impact your
long-term container budget if you're
able to reuse those keep in mind also
the cost of shipping when comparing
containers some people cause with a free
shipping sum if you order over a certain
amount so you want to keep the shipping
cost is also a factor in the total cost
of that container so you can see there's
a lot of little different puzzle pieces
when it comes to putting together the
final cost but all these must be
considered so you get the true accurate
assessment of the final cost the
availability what can you get now a lot
of girls kind of wait to the last minute
and then want to buy something and that
can run into some issues however you
should select a container that is the
best fit for your growing operation not
just what you can get now do not change
this because the one pot or the one
container that you're looking for is
backordered that's often back toward for
reasons difficult part and you want to
plan your grow around that just want to
do that ones backward I'll just go with
this one and I'll have a run of those
size pots or those type of pots again
keeping everything efficient keeping
everything consistent is very important
and get away from just kind of ordering
late and getting what is available now
and if backward or just a little bit it
potentially worth the wait to keep your
a grow operation efficient as possible
this size of the container so size
doesn't part relate to the age of the
plant most growers will simplify and use
three main sizes small pots at 4 inches
to one gallon are typically used for
clones medium pots are considered about
3 gallons and therefore the early part
with a vegetative stage then when you
transplant into flowering or into final
stages 5 to 10 gallon pots are for the
main grow and flower and phase to
maximize yields most girls are using
about 7 and 10 gallon pots some may even
go larger for mother plants somebody
believes 10 gallons or sometimes even
larger pots for that instance container
shape so taller pots are preferred over
wider window garden style containers so
kind of 100 pots
be taller and thinner than kind of this
long appearance here this allows to
easily pack in more plants under art
sometimes limited lighting area
container color so there are a lot of
theories or ideas behind color typically
white will be little less likely to
absorb heat
however standard black pot is by far the
most widely used some girls want to try
reds or blues because it increased gross
has been shown in reports with like
tomatoes or squash but this day is based
on plastic mulch and outdoor growing
situations as we see here these
containers do not really reflect that
much light to the plant canopy that's
why color doesn't matter that much here
in the outdoor grow situation we see the
sunlight coming down reflecting this
large area of light up at the plant
looking down at the light that may hit
the pot and reflect it up to the plant
well it's just basically the rim so that
color is going to have a very minimal
impact on the plant growth so even
though color can potentially have an
impact on large field growing operations
and plastic mulches container growing
the area is greatly reduced in much at
minimal so color is by far least
important here if you're growing in
large bed some girls choose to grow in
large beds here like the big boxes
filled with media or multiple plants may
be grown initially this may sound easier
than many of these little pots to move
around but the this design typically
wastes a lot of soil and you're
constantly changing after each grow
cycle it can be a lot of a greater
challenge here so typically raised beds
are not advised growing plants
individually in pots is the preferred
method to go with plastic pots that's
the by far the most efficient way so you
want to keep that in mind to keep your
grow operation as efficient and easy to
easy to maintain as possible