okay here I'm gonna go over how to
select the tomato seed or variety that
is best for you now this is not going to
be a whole list of variety names I'm
going to teach you how to think and go
about looking at your operation so you
can be able to determine the best
selection for your operation so the
first thing is what where are you
growing the first time we consider is
where you're growing the crop and what
growth habit you need if you looking at
an outdoor operation there's a lot of
options you're looking at being under
plastic typically determine source
emanated treatments will be used this be
a greenhouse a high teller caterpillar
tunnel as an example it may be more
limited on the size of the plant that
they can get to second thing to consider
is what your market is consider your
market who are you selling to and what
do they want
are they looking for the perfect look
would be more for hybrids on heirlooms
people ask for them by name large fruit
for sandwich Tomatoes different colors I
really haven't seen too many deep blues
and purples but they offer variety that
may not be found at some major chain
places so again you got a look at what
your market is because that might
dictate what variety or sway you in a
direction for what we're ready to grow
threaten to consider is well what are
you growing we're looking for a really
season looking for short days to harvest
kind of a quick turnaround time your
main season gonna be your core plantings
we're looking for late season growth for
may be considering greater disease
resistance because typically later in
the season there's more of that pressure
around fourth is to try new varieties
but always have a standard for
comparison I'll just try everything new
if you didn't have that kind of sense of
comparison then you might lose it how
effective or how better one variety may
be while experimenting is good you don't
have that control those trials are never
less meanings for me I use the better
boy tomato as my comparison variety to
determine whether something is truly
better or worse than something I've used