so welcome to this debaco university
video
here we're gonna be looking at selecting
the one cannabis plant
out of a million kind of like playing
the lottery here finding that one unique
individual
that would be warranted for going
through the process maybe of propagating
and cloning
and breeding out further so realize that
with plants there's some genetic
and inherent genetic variability when
growing a population of plants there's
some that
sometimes just one just stands out now
what causes that plant to stand out may
be
different for different growers that
stand out is basically at the discretion
of the grower standouts could be the
morphology is it a tall or
short plant does it produce a lot of cbd
or cbg for cannabinoids what type of
terpene profile does it have these are
things to consider as well as
the time that it flowers is it earlier
late flower does it does plant tend to
yield a lot of quantity
or is it a plant that is producing a lot
of quality
does it need a lot of pruning and is it
resistant to diseases
and if so which ones these are just some
topics we'll be covering
here in this video now the morphology is
the first one so keep in mind morphology
is looking at the structure of the plant
and tall plants be better suited for
larger yields per plant
while shorter plants are more
advantageous for the indoor market so a
lot of
growers may be breeding for those that
are growing in grow tents
that's a targeted audience so that could
be advantageous
internode spacing is what should be
measured and that's the space between
nodes
tighter internode spacing means it's
going to be a more compact plant
and greater internet spacing means it's
going to be a taller plant
however when you get those tight compact
plants that can also increase the
density and also increase the potential
for diseases or
insects to kind of hide within the plant
then there's the cannabinoids so thc and
cbd are what it's commonly
selected for but some breeders are
looking now into developing strains that
have greater concentrations of other
cannabinoids
in particular breeding for cbg has
gained some interest
for its potential uses so just another
consideration there
that just goes beyond the thc and the
cbd when we're looking at breeding and
finding a genetic standout addition
there's terpenes
so the now the cannabinoids important
but the effects of a given
product are receiving more attention
breeding for and selecting a unique
terpene profile can make a strain stand
out
and be sought after the difficult part
is that the terpene profiles can be
associated
with taste and effects which are going
to be interpreted differently
by different people this is why
typically the cannabinoids
and the percentage of those is given a
little bit more weight or a little bit
more kind of favoritism than the
terpenes because that's kind of flavors
what one person may like another person
may not like
then the flowering time so this can
relate to when
pre-flowers are first seen or when an
autoflower actually starts to get into
the flowering phase
early flowering can help reduce the
duration needed to complete the growth
cycle so that can be important for
growers
getting more generations in the same
duration of time
and delaying the flower time can
increase the time in the
required vegetative phase and this can
help build a bigger plant structure
which may be advantageous if you're
seeking to breed a high biomass
producing plant
so again you can see again the pros and
cons with each there
then we get into just general yield you
know how much is the plant
producing well regarding yields this can
be related to one of two
main factors one could be quantity those
are
for those looking to just the total
amount of plant product
how much product is produced by the
plant then there's also
quality and here the breeders looking
more for at the chemicals and compounds
produced
and not so much the total plant material
of course most growers would like both
high quality and a lot of and a lot of
product that is of high quality
but sometimes you may have to select one
over the other
some growers will sacrifice the total
quantity for improved quality
which can be directly related to the
terpenes produced for example there
then we get to plant behavior and this
is how much you want to fight with the
plant so to speak
how easy is the plant to grow this could
refer to how well the plant
supports itself on its own if it's a
strong plant or does it kind of require
or need staking
also consider how much pruning or what
pruning method might be a good fit for
the plant's
natural style weaker plants that require
staking should be considered more for
indoor applications
compared to those growing outdoor or
those that want to be a little more
hands-off
and production of their plants then
there is disease
resistance so this is often overlooked
but how resistant is a plant
strain to a certain diseases can be a
very important
to be bred into genetic lineages
very important trait to consider this
can become obvious in a large growing
area if all plants have a disease but
there is
one that disease quote missed in the
sense that it just simply has resistance
to that
because this doesn't happen like powdery
mildew for example would spread over the
whole area that means that one plant
that isn't
diseased has inherent resistance and
that can be very advantageous to any
breeding program
this can be a very desirable quality it
makes for a great addition to a breeding
program
if you can get some disease resistance
here we see in the images powdery mildew
but there's also bud rot to consider as
well
as well as a host of others different is
not always
better though so just because you're
growing a thousand plants and one of
them is different
mutations are often not beneficial but
in the case where they are
growers should consider propagating that
plant to preserve those genetics
often cloning is suggested to ensure the
exact same genetics are copied
and then multiplied that's just again
important mutations
typically not a good thing but in
certain cases they can be and you want
to make sure you have
methods of preserving recognizing that
number one and then preserving those
genetics
this is where attention to detail is
important you want to look carefully at
all plans keeping good records is an
important part of this process
if you happen to get lucky and find that
unique genetic kind of profile you want
to be able to capture
and preserve it and not lose it or lose
track of it
you want to make sure that you're able
to take advantage of that unique
situation
because it might be truly that one in a
million
now that selection process that you may
go through
can take a long time even longer if you
do not know what you're looking for so
keep that in mind even being very
selective and targeted
still can take a very long time either
select a standout plan continue to breed
it and select for
consistent repeatable qualities or
determine what you want to breed for
and then start to select for those
qualities so that's two
different routes you can kind of take
with the breeding process
so again being intentioned to detail
knowing what you're looking for finding
genetic standouts having good cloning
procedures
this is all ways that when you identify
that one in a million you can hopefully
capture that i wish you the best of luck
in this process
if you wish to go down this route
because it can be challenging
and take a lot of time but also very
rewarding in the
end