all right welcome to this tobacco
university video here we're going to be
investigating
self crosses compared to outcrossing in
cannabis plants
and this is a scientific research study
so i'm going to be presenting some data
as almost some pictures
to help you understand the differences
between these two
and how they impact cannabis so starting
with
the research article that i pulled the
information from we could see the
abstract listed here
a link and source is cited here and i'm
going to try to give you a general
summary of this article
so first off so i have to define what
kind of outcrossing and self-crossing is
and
sometimes self-crossing is simply
referred to as cellphone
so an outcross let's start there is when
two unrelated or at least
distantly related plants are bred or
crossed together
the outcrossing increases the genetic
variability and we can see that here we
have different individuals
mixing up the genes compared to
self-crossing
this is when the maternal and pollen
from the parents are the same
genotype the goal is to reduce the
potential for genetic variability
and this is different than cloning which
is an asexual form of vegetative
propagation so keep in mind that
cell thing or self-crossing is not the
same as cloning
it's reducing the genetic variability
where cloning is almost an identical
copy there are so little different
procedures
in this case we're just reducing the
chance at variability
so when is cell thing used in particular
well
for hemp feminized seed producers often
use sulfine to maintain a strained name
the process of selfing a cannabis plant
may lead to inferior plants for
cannabidiol or cbd production so that's
kind of what we're
looking at here is yes we're using this
maybe to maintain a strained name
but is that also going to reduce or
negatively impact cbd production
so when we're looking at the self versus
outcrossing
kind of examples here and here we can
see some great images
so the self progeny here were
significantly smaller than outcross
providing for all
measured traits and i think we just look
at the image here the letter a and
letter b being l crosses and
here letter c representing self crosses
we can see a stark difference
well the study goes on to say that the
self-progeny here
compared to the outcrossed was about
half of the height had fewer internodes
reduced internode length half the leaf
area half the total dry weight delayed
by seven days in flower development
36 percent less floral dry weight equal
cbd producers
both met the legal limit of 0.3 percent
thc
so just note that while there is these
stark differences is a limit with any
scientific study there's always some
sort of limit with this one it is that
the study was only looking at three
strains
and the primitive three crosses were
evaluated
now looking we saw the stark differences
there but now if we kind of look at the
numbers we're kind of looking at the
vegetative and flower growth in yield
these findings provide the phenotypic
and genotypic data to support that cell
thing in cannabis
induces inbreeding depression so while
there's a lot of numbers here and you're
welcome to pause the video and take a
look at it
i want to just make note that this first
column and the second comment represent
the outcrosses
and this last column represent the self
crosses
and with letters of the same name we're
having basically no
statistical difference so we can see the
outcrosses pretty much a's and just a
couple b's in there
for all the self crosses we see the
beasts and the seas indicating that
there is a significant
difference looking at this by the
fischer's least significant difference
with
a p-value less than or equal to 0.05 so
again looking
at some statistics supports what we saw
there with the large images or
phenotypes of the plants now what was
also noticed
in this research study is that all self
progeny exhibited
leaf variegation this is known to be a
recessive genetic trait in higher plants
so that again indicates that there's
probably an accumulation of these uh
recessive genes variation was first
evident at the catalina growth stage you
can see that here
cod leads remember are the seed leaves
for most plants the variation persisted
through day 35
and however three plants had variegated
leaves until the end of the study so it
might be a prolonged effect there
now self in cannabis looking at induces
inbreeding depression so evidence of
inbreeding depression
in self-cannabis well self-feminized
seed has less vigorous plants and
reduced yield
increased homo sagacity with negative
recessive traits such as variegation
observed which suggests inbreeding may
occur more rapidly in hemp
than other crops this just shows an
example here of potential corn plants
we're seeing that
reduced height there that inbreeding
depression does occur in plants but
this study at least indicates it may
occur a little quicker in hemp
crops so we're looking at crossing
different strains can increase yields
crossing two different strains to
maintain or increase heterozygosity
could be a strategy to increase yields
and plants may be more uniform
if crossing within a strain is necessary
growers should consider using two
different genotypes of the strain
to produce feminist seed and maintain
the strain name so just a little kind of
indication there
now what we're looking at for is like if
you're a grower how does this kind of
relate
how can you kind of apply this
information well hemp breeders may want
to consider developing inbred parental
lines to generate f1 feminized seed
which could produce plants that exhibit
improved crop uniformity and
hybrid vigor it may be beneficial for
feminized seed producers to use
outcrossing instead of selfing to
generate feminist seed
for cbd production so that's kind of
just a general overview here looking at
hemp
compared to self-crossing and
outcrossing