welcome to this debaco university video
here we're going to be looking at sexing
cannabis seedlings so you grow
plants from seeds that are diacious
where they could be male or female
how do you determine whether you have a
male plant or a female plant because a
lot of times i could determine if you're
looking for cannabinoids whether you
want to keep that plant or discard that
plant
so here follow along with this video
all right let's get into some of the
methods here so first off there are two
main options
one there's gender detection screening
using the pcr method or polymath
chain reaction method or there's the
quick cone clone and
flip method so both of these had
advantages and disadvantages
i'm going to cover both of these here
briefly giving you the pros and cons
and then you can make a decision on
which one you think is the best fit for
your growing environment
so first off using the gender detection
screening or pcr method
the advantage of this method is very
accurate it also offers very quick
results
and can be done early in plant
development so we're actually looking at
screening
some of the genetics of that plant
determine where it's male or female
and can be done basically at the very
early sealing stages
so again a lot of advantages with this
method the reason why everyone does not
use this method
is simply because of some of the key
disadvantages the first being of course
that it is costly
for the equipment to use to set up has
to be kind of a
lot of equipment that's needed a lot of
upfront cost associated with that
also requires individually testing each
plant material so organization and
labeling are also
very important and when i say
organization we're looking at at the
using these very small pcr tubes
to be able to analyze samples the
specialized equipment is needed or
material needs to be sent off to
site to a lab which again might be
prohibitive
for certain growing establishments so if
you look at the other method the clone
and flip method
the advance to this one and a big
advantage that's very easy
the results are clear and distinctive
female clones could be
providing an early indication of
chemical end products to be
produced what this simply involves is
taking vegetative cuttings from a plant
and putting them into a cloner typically
taking up a small space
and putting them under a flowering light
period so this can
induce flowering at a very early age and
that can determine
one whether you have a male or female
plant if it's a female you could keep it
going for a little bit longer and maybe
get some sort of idea of the chemical
end products
for that clone that it matches that
mother or stock plant that it matches
now are there also some disadvantage
with this method as it cannot be done
with autoflowers
and this does require labeling and a
dedicated space for 12 12
um hour 12 hours late for our start
photo period and it does take much
longer to get results than with the pcr
method so again each has its pros and
cons it's advanced and disadvantages
so you might want to review these and
then check out this channel for
continuing videos going into details
on whatever step or process you think is
the best fit
for your growing establishment