in this tobacco university video we'll
go over should cannabis clones be
purchased locally or
shipped in cases where growers cannot
produce their own
all right let's give you some of the
advantages and disadvantages of
purchasing clones locally or having them
shipped in
so first off it's important to
understand that the end product
should be the same there can be some
variability but purchasing clones can
save you the need
to create a propagation environment so
if you're limited on space or time
purchasing starting clones can be
advantageous
ideally whether they're purchased
locally or shipped in
the end product should be the same but
there are some advantages and
disadvantages to each
each method so first off if we're
looking at purchasing
local clones what are some of the
advantages to that well typically you
can see the end product before
you shut out the money to purchase it so
that's a great advantage
they can have some strains that are good
fit for your area in the sense that
they're produced there
for a reason you can also get the clones
right when you need them you might be
able to call up the person
and go pick it up that morning when you
can plant that afternoon
so that can be another advantage of
purchasing your clones
locally however there's also some
disadvantages
in the sense that a lot of times local
producers mainly have a limited select
and
selection of plant strains you may not
be to get the one do grew last year
one that you know works well for you so
that can be again a disadvantage
of local clones or local producers of
clones
the shipping of clones well so what's
the advantage why would someone go
through and
you know bring in and ship in clones
well typically the reason why people are
going that route
is they have a larger selection of
strain options so because they can be
shipped in from anywhere they can
compare
different producers and get exactly what
they want or get some unique
different strains do some comparisons so
this is why some growers
do select to ship in their clones then
we also have the disadvantages
of purchasing clones elsewhere and
since that may only get to select a
shipping window of time and not an exact
date so just because the weather is nice
and perfect
they might be coming in on that standard
date you may not be able to change that
clones also may be smaller in size than
you would purchase locally due to the
restrictions on
shipping to try to keep things in the
small shipping boxes as possible
that may cause you to get some smaller
clones if you're getting them shipped in
versus purchased locally
and then also there's the damage may
occur during the transportation process
no matter how diligent the growers may
be to protect the clones that they are
shipping out
so that's some disadvantages of the
shipping in process
so again end result should be the same
but there's some advantages
and disadvantages of purchasing your
clones locally or shipping your clones
in
if you choose not to produce them
yourself