okay here I'm going to go over at
sensimilla harvest for cannabis and we
see two buds here that fit this up quite
well
keep in mind sensimilla refers to not
being pollinated
if these alpha hours have been
pollinated they would shift their energy
into seed production and reduce the
resins and cannabinoids that were
typically seeking for growing cannabis
now this sense Mill harvest typically
occurs about six or twelve weeks after
plants have been exposed to an even 12
hour light to our dark photo period in
the ranges little broad because of
different cultivars keep in mind
autoflowering varieties will not
necessarily follow this because they are
not sensitive to changing photo periods
when we're looking at determining and
timing that harvest the tricone color is
what's going to determine the peak
ripeness the trichomes because they
produce the resins their color is a key
indicator when peak ripeness it does
occur the goal is to get a developed
translucent kind of feet white trichome
with a large bulb on top too early
these trichomes structures will be thin
and clear and not fully mature and too
late the structures of a brown tea and
orange coloration keep in mind though
some cultivars tend to produce more
darker trichomes at maturity so be
mindful of what cultivar you're actually
growing how do you determine this color
well it's my observation you want to
inspect those trichomes with a 30 X
looped as a strong LED light built in
this way you can expect and determine
exactly when to harvest I mean it takes
me a little getting used to here but it
really allows you to magnify those
trichomes to make it much easier to
determine exactly when they're ripe now
what are you looking for the goals to
harvest went about half of the observed
trichomes are faint white and
translucent color I kind of give the
idea of the jellyfish here that's that
faint white to translucent color now if
you're a small detailed operation you
can even select the individual buds for
harvest to ensure each one's you moved
at the exact correct day and this kind
of gives you a little bit that
real-world image of kind of how it
should look if you're a small operation
you can select the individual buds often
that's not the case so when it inspect
some representative sample buds that you
have
and you're looking for that translucent
the faint white color what about half of
the trichomes in the bud have that
that's when you can go through and
harvest and as you start to learn a
cultivar you'll start to know how many
days since you flipped the lights that
will produce this and allows for a more
efficient operation but the key part
here is to have a good magnifying loupe
use your observations watch the buds and
don't get don't harvest them too early
or too late
catch that peak ripeness so you get the
maximum yield for the effort that you've
put in