okay in the pictures here we see two
female flowers for Disney cannabis
what's unique about these flowers is
that there's no seeds sinsemilla
is what's called in cannabis when you
produce a flower that does not produce
any seeds that sinsemilla is pronounced
Erickson sawmill a is a female flower
that has not been pollinated this is the
most potent part of the plant or the
highest cannabinoid production and CBD
will be produced the goal is to have the
plant produce all of its energy and
reserves inter producing cannabinoids
and not producing seeds through this
process now why not pollinate a flower
will the lack of pollination signals in
the plant to produce more resin attempts
to increase the odds of capturing pollen
that may be in the air so it's the
plant's response to not being pollinated
initially it's trying to go through and
increasing the odds that it couldn't get
pollinated this same plant stressor also
increases the production of cannabinoids
which are present in the in the
structures we see here called trichomes
the pollen if pollen does reach the
female flower the energy will be on by
the plant allocated to producing seeds
and this will reduce the amount of
cannabinoids produced and this is in
part why it's so important to identify
male flowers early on so that you're not
getting this potential for pollination
which will vastly reduce your
cannabinoid production