looking at the title it should come as
no surprise that this is gonna pertain
to scale to muscle getting it to a
little bit more detail of the skeletal
muscle and exactly what's going on here
being able to recognize the microscopic
view here you keep in mind this is
involuntary controlled so we do have
control over where it goes and what we
do with it
so skeletal muscle overview each muscle
has a discrete organ composed of muscle
tissue blood vessels nerve fibers and
connective tissue again there's a bigger
image of the microscopic look it does
have neurons connecting it because we
need a way for our brain to tell that
muscle to contract because it is
voluntary controlled that's is why we
have the motor neuron so the three
connected tissue sheets are the endow
museum the parrot museum in the EPI
museum that is connected sheaths just
like our knife here the sharp blade of
the knife is stored in the sheath that's
a protective outer layer here that same
concept applies here so our museums our
skeletal muscle fibers the black circle
the endow museum is the red circle here
Paramecium is the green and the outer
thick area here is called the EPI museum
so that endomysium it see that pictured
here in this model Paramecium is the
area this she's protective layer here in
the EPI vision located right here so
looking at these a little bit more
detail that in the museum is the fine
sheath of connective tissue composed a
particular fiber surrounding each muscle
fiber keep in mind endo means in that is
the innermost portion here paradism are
fibrous connective tissues that surround
groups of muscle fibers called the
fascicles see that right here
there's our param and this is one zoomed
in area here this is the fascicle
located right here and in the overcoat
here the dense regular connective tissue
that surrounds the entire muscle is the
EPI in its iam think of it as like
epidermis is the outer most covering a
little bit more detail FF as iam allows
the muscle to contract and move
powerfully while maintaining its
structural integrity
this is the epic messy in here this epic
museum also separates muscle fiber from
other tissues allowing the muscle to
move independently so keep in mind these
muscles need to move and contract need
to be separate from what's surrounding
them within the body the epimysium helps
provide that barrier during a little
deeper here a Paramecium allows the
nervous system to trigger a specific
movement of a muscle that's the allowing
that connection of that and neuron to
come in in the innermost the endomysium
here connect contains the extracellular
fluid and nutrients to support the
muscle fiber as we'll learn it for these
muscles to contract a lot needs to go on
and this endomysium is providing that
fluid in nutrients to help allow our
muscle fibers to contract these
nutrients are supplied ultimately from
the blood to the muscle tissue and
that's when nutrients are brought in and
waste are brought out lastly here our
muscle fiber produced by the fusion of
several cells that their ends discretes
a very long muscle fiber that contains
all the original nuclei so keep in mind
that we're having this linking of a
bunch of these cells together this
multinucleated fiber essentially these
microfilaments are bunched together to
create myofilaments and that's what
we're noticing here skeletal muscle as a
reminder found involuntary muscles and
they produce powerful voluntary
contractions this would be something at
work having control over and moving and
able to have control over which we will
notice will be different compared to the
other two different types of muscles