all right here my attempt to give a
brief overview of the skeletal system so
you can see here hopefully you'll be
pondering wonderful thoughts about the
skeletal system and by the end you'll be
feeling like this so first off achlys
some videos to keep in mind in the
description there's a link to the slides
there's some YouTube videos you can
watch about when San Britain's Got
Talent show and someone who's very
flexible and ones here at looking at
neck stretching in Myanmar and some of
the changes that occur physiologically
reminder that remember about the
homologous analogous structures we see
this kind of the same picture here come
bearing homologous structures will they
have similar structure but different
function and analogous structures keep
in mind have different structure but
similar functions these Mulligan
structures comparing the function of the
phalanges in the human to the bat for
example this is just showing one here
we're looking at the Mong is just sort
up here
humans and the phalanges those are your
fingers what the uses were compared to
the bat again ours is for gripping and
grabbing and the bat would be for flying
now changes in the human skeleton that
do occur in embryos the skeleton is
primarily heileen cartilage during
development much of this cartilage is
replaced by a bone not all of it but
much of it there is cartilage it does
remain in the body and it's like for
example your ears your nose in your
throat region and also within your
ribcage so there's different areas also
within your joints you can still have
some remaining cartilage during the
development of the skeletal system at
birth this skull bones are not quite
complete I was actually kind of room for
them to move and there's actually
they're not quite fully fused yet the
adult human only has 206 bones that have
grown together from about 300 bones at
birth so within the skull just as an
example bones are joined by fibrous
membranes called
fontanelles these fontanelles are
completely replaced with bone within two
years after birth so if you have a very
early on newborn they'll actually be
little soft spots in their head those
are the fontanelle's that's the gap
between the plates within their skull
they haven't quite fused yet
help with the birthing process and also
allow the brain to grow and develop now
functions of the skeletal system in
general might be some of them might be
very obvious they support the framework
cradle the soft organs that you have it
helps provide them with protection case
of brain or spinal cord or vital organs
that spinal cord runs right down the
vertebrae all encased in a bone there
it's responsible for a movement it gives
them muscles something to pull on it's
kind of that lever system for muscles to
pull on also as it acts as a mineral
storage which is way the body can kind
of store minerals especially calcium and
phosphorus to be used to help regulate
other levels for example calcium there's
very little of it in the blood but it's
a very crucial amount and the body will
actually take it from the bones if it
needs to to help maintain that very
precise level in the skeletal system is
important for blood cell formation
because within the bone marrow as we'll
see is responsible for many of the
components of the circulatory system
talked about that cartilage bones in the
cartilage now there's different types of
cartilage so that's important to keep in
mind there's highly news of
fibrocartilage and there's no elastic
cartilage located in different areas the
Highland cartilage is for smooth surface
and gliding of particular joints as you
can see kind of in your ball and socket
joint elbow do we have elastic cartilage
is is very flexible makes up the the
exterior of the ear and also your
epiglottis in your fibro carlos is
resisting strong forces
it's very fibrous compression and
tension that would be very important to
have in your life in your vertebrae
between your vertebrae of your spinal
cord there's different classifications
of bones there's flat bones irregular
short bones long bones and sesamoid
bones and they're just helpful
classifications and a lot of them make
sense flat bones are flat regulars are
kind of those odd kind of shaped short
bones long bones and the sesamoid bones
here are kind of like your specialty
bones as we see in the patella or
kneecap the composition of bone in
general we have an organic component
which is your osteoblasts which is your
bone forming it cells your osteo sites
which are mature bone cells that
maintain
mineral concentrations in your
osteoclast which are large cells that
reabsorb or break down the bone matrix
so while these all kind of are all start
with osteo the last are bone forming
sites are the mature bone cells and
class or the large cells that reabsorb
or break down the bone matrix so these
four types of cells are found within the
bone tissue because you can have they're
all organized here these cells
osteogenic cells are on differentiate
and develop into osteoblasts we kind of
have this thing formation of these
different cells
however when osteoblasts get trapped
within the calcified matrix their
structure and function changes in to
come osteocytes so some of these have a
unique ability to change unless air
osteoclast develop from monocytes and
macrophages and differ in appearance
from other bone cells if you were to
look at them under a microscope then we
have our inorganic or our mineral
components to the bones there's 67% bone
by masses minerals mainly calcium and
phosphates so while a bone is composed
of thirty-nine percent calcium if you
take all the bones in your body it is 99
percent of the body's calcium that one
percent in the blood that's a very
important 1 percent to have minerals are
responsible for the bone hardness and
resistance to compression unless you can
again just see the comparison of what a
bones made out of and what percentage it
makes up of the body calcium and
phosphate being key ones while a bonus
17 percent phosphate it's again 99
percent of your total phosphate in your
system the grocery eye bones are in bone
textures the adult skeleton has 206
bones there's a compact bone which is
the dense outer layer which gives a lot
of really good strength and inside
there's a honeycomb which is a spongy
bone and this is to help reduce weight
and allow areas to be filled with bone
marrow and could be red or yellow
depending on your age but that stuff
compact bone on the outside really gives
bones a lot of their total strength
Mayr produces necessary components of
the circulatory system so that marrow
particularly have the long bones we see
kind of superimposed image here is
making your red blood cells white blood
cells and also your platelets all very
important for a fully functional
circulatory system red bone marrow is
soft spongy tissue at the center of
bones that produces red blood cells
white blood cells and also those
all-important platelets since the
production of red blood cells requires
iron the marrow is one of the places in
the body that normally stores a supply
of iron this kind of gives you a
real-world image of what it looks like
it's also contains stem cells and stem
cells or cells they can kind of be made
into anything here we're looking at
specifically cells that will go along
the path to help or aid in the
circulatory system in some way here we
see the outer surface of the bone we
have the red bone marrow and we have the
yellow bone marrow in the center here in
this particular image that yellow bone
marrow that I mentioned it's important
component and it will increase with age
so it contains the global American is
mostly fat and begins to replace red
bone marrow in long bones after about
five years old when were younger our
bones contain very little fat and as we
age the percentage of fat in the Amero
increases here's an infant less than one
year old completed mostly of that red
bone marrow then childhood one to ten
years old we see that yellow is starting
to occur adolescence ten to twenty years
old much more yellow bones kind of a
yellow marrow within the bones when your
adult considered to be 25 years plus in
this case see the vast majorities been
replaced with yellow bone marrow we
still have that vital a red bone marrow
to help keep producing some of those
vital components of the cell but you
could see not nearly as great percentage
as it was when you were in infant