okay this videos gonna look at skin
color and what kind of makes up the
pigmentation for the different skin
colors that we see depicted here so
looking first at skin color in the
pigments there's three main ones we want
to focus on first one is melanin and
this is the most important provides UV
protection now there's a delicate
balance between being protected from UV
light and being able to synthesize
vitamin D I have a separate video that
handles all light vs vitamin D my
welcome to check that out the second
type of skin pigment is keratin this is
provided from our diet carrots yellow
vegetables tomatoes these have a lot of
keratin in them carrots for example
beta-carotene you may have heard of
hemoglobins the last one it's the pink
of light-skinned Caucasian skin contains
little melanin and it's actually some of
the haemoglobin that's coming through
that's giving the skin its color or
appearance now we're looking at map of
the world here and we could see
different regions of the world tie in
with the skin color
well those areas that tend to be higher
intensities of sun where there's a large
population to have darker skin colors
than at the North Pole for example here
whether you tends to be less intense
sunlight so we could see if there's
definitely correlation here particularly
in Africa and Australia with the skin
tone the chromatic scale and the
relation to the equator or the intensity
of Sun reading this has a genetic and
things and we're looking at skin color
is genetic the intensity of the pigment
is based on the amount of melanin and
that's genetically controlled light
colored skin do the connective tissue in
hemoglobin giving it its light color and
we saw before geographic location and
has a set amount of UV radiation which
correlates with the indigenous skin
pigment in c-average skin pigment for
that region
I did say skin color is genetic which is
true we see that evident here where we
have a homozygous basically recessive
for all of the color genes here light
and then almost I guess down here for a
very dark and if yet are heterozygotes
here we breed those here
f2 generation and we get this kind of
effect here most out of resulting from
this cross will be kind of that medium
in this case a scale of three skin color
as there will be very as rare as number
six here and you see it kind of also
depicted here in a Punnett square like
for a high hybrid cross so again it's
genetic we kinda have the ideas here but
with the geographic location being an
influence on selecting for one skin type
or one pigmentation versus another so a
little comparison between what we see
the macroscopic view in the microscopic
view so the Photoshop 40 X magnification
and Caucasian skin here is a and may not
be able to see it here but these locator
is this is a microscopic version of the
skin and we see see here for East
Indians and then D is located here
ESO came here for african-americans and
then F here so if you're looking one of
these letters are located the B the D
and the F might be a little hard to pick
out initially if you note the
progression increase of melanin as skin
pigment darkens as is you check the
links here courtesy of someone who was
able to provide these pictures online
than that music here to show you guys
how the what we're noticing is the
melanin or pigmentation is darkening as
our skin color is darkening so what
provides this well the melanocyte
location this is what's producing the
actual melanin melanin production so
here's our skin this will kind of
towards the upper surface here we have
the dermis and dermal layers if we zoom
in that box it looks like this and this
is our specific zoom aid of the local on
the site can't hide altogether
i'm here's our milan site down here this
would be dark skin on the left and light
skin on the right and we notice that
there's a lot of these Malena somes that
are dark so melanin is the pigmentation
and these cells contain a lot of that
mess tends to be the darker skin here
the lighter skin we see a lot of those
basically left white or blank they don't
have that pigmentation and that will
show
ultimately as lighter skin allowing
hemoglobin and connective tissue to show
through here with our intense melanin
gritting that darker skin appearance
their few minuses our high epidermis
here this is the skin cells that will be
kind of leading off and getting broken
off and being shed and this is our layer
down here that's working its progression
up here hopefully this provides a little
bit of a background on the pigmentation
of different skin color