okay here we look at skin as we age this
kind of time-lapse shows kind of see the
progression of skin as we age and what
changes that occur you can see we start
young and youthful and slowly as we age
our skin becomes a less useful if that
less resilient a little more wrinkles
sadly develop and that's what happens as
we had written a little bit more about
this so first off skin as we age well
stratum basale is the mostly comprised
of keratinocytes these are responsible
for renewing this skin we're talking
down here in this deeper layer here
we're not talking right at the surface
these care in the sites produce keratin
as they mate as you may guess and this
is a protein that protects our skin from
chemical products and bacteria
now these migrated from the basal layer
up towards the skin's surface so this is
our skin surface and this is kind of
where they're being generated from and
again our orientation here's our dermal
layer here as we move upwards to the
skin surface they're dividing and
changing you'll notice since they
actually go these are younger cells and
these are our older cells and our dermis
cell turnover by age so as you get older
we notice that the cell turnover I'm an
infant is a 14 days you're getting cell
turnover - as you get older the amount
of days increases so infants and teens
you're talking about two weeks to three
weeks to four weeks about and as you get
older we're talking about forty five
eighty four days but much longer over a
month you're basically over the age of
40 and this is how our skin ages it's
generated down here we notice it's
changing and morphology and also
function as it works its way up towards
the surface before it eventually falls
off so again giving you that progression
as you age called
collagen production decreases and this
is reduces our skin's ability to repair
and it becomes less elastic see more of
a kind of a cartoon image here try more
of a real-world simulation here this
lost of that kind of elasticity of our
skin causes wrinkles
is because reduction of blood of blood
flow through the dermal capillaries
building in fewer nutrients well less
nutrients means less chance of renewal
less chance of rapid growth and division
this is the thinning of epidermis and
this is slowing the cell turnover rate
and reducing the barrier in function of
the epidermis
so the epidermis still provides
protection but as we age it starts to
provide less protection it's getting
thinner that barrier is becoming less
this gives you Indiana a little visual
representation and also some more
information on from your 20s to your 30s
or 40s to 50 plus at what kind of is
happening and progressing they draw your
attention just to kind of the shape you
could see in your twenties nice youthful
flat look to it 30s we're starting to
get a little bit of that movement here a
little bit of those wrinkles during the
form 40s a little bit worse you see 50
is more pronounced there and we have
this transition of reduction of collagen
and we have that seen a decrease in
moisture retention and slowing getting
that more kind of dry look that more
aged love those increasingly wrinkles so
not everything necessarily gets better
with age looking at the aging of the
skin to kind of give you some of these
major age-related changes that occurs in
a long list here sadly none of them
really great everything from injury and
infections to increase the immune system
starts to decrease sun protection
diminishes because again it's getting
thinner here and getting also drier skin
that's the last statistic to the skin
less resilience to the skin
he lost decreases it's slow to repair
and basically just showing harmful
effects of the environmental damage over
time so sadly again all not good things
that occur this is just one of your
body's abilities to provide a barrier
and again that decreases as you age just
couple fun facts here you shed the skin
cells continuously it's a couple facts
here human shed about a million dead
skin cells every 40 minutes so you
probably you know don't realize this
your number of skin cells that you're
shedding also the average person will
shed about 600 pounds to
seventy about kilograms of skin during
their lifetime so if you ever wonder
what you know you're dusting for and
what the dust bunnies are in the corner
of the room were down the hall that's
actually skin cells that's because
you're shedding so many of them so
rapidly
the more people you get in an area the
more life you die of those dust that
occurs and that's why I should go
through and make sure going through a
regularly including areas to remove
those skin cells that they were just a
normal body function of the shedding