okay this video electrician will get
smooth muscle and a little bit more
detail so smooth muscle this is how it
would look under a microscope now what
we're looking at here there's an insane
image
cells are long and spindle shaped they
each contain a single nucleus and Celer
microfilaments are loosely organized we
often call these sheets of cells so look
at this image it might be a little hard
to be able to tell that look at the kind
of representation image here we see
these distinctive features coming into
play now a relaxed smooth muscle cells
can all look like this say they're kind
of long spindle shape this is kind of
what we mean when they're contracted
they take on this kind of bunched up cut
parents they kind of take this kind of
clumsy look here versus their normal
relaxed spindle shaped so they're where
our squares smooth muscle found well
it's found in the walls of blood vessels
the stomach and the intestines and this
is if you were taking a cross-section
this is what it would look like now the
nucleus is one per cell and its central
looking centrally located in each cell
the smooth muscle cell is elongated
spindle shape and much smaller than a
skeletal muscle cell if you were to
compare the two directly that relaxed
shape that spindle shaped and then
here's that contracted that can bunched
look the advantage of smooth muscles
that provides powerful rhythmic
involuntary contractions this is helpful
to move food through the stomach through
the intestines to help blood go through
the vessels all these things are very
important and is involuntary means we
don't have to think about it they're
known for their slow sustained
contractions
there are Thomas meaning they're not
voluntary control they just happen they
do contain actin and myosin filaments
but lack the sarcomeres and predominant
locations are wall the GI tract
that's the gastro potential intestinal
tract walls of the arteries and veins
and around glands is typically where
you'll find these smooth muscles so even
though we don't have direct control over
them they do provide us with some very
necessary everyday functions of body