welcome to another video here on debaco
university
here we're going to be looking at
snell's law of refraction
now refraction keep in mind light
passing through difference in
mediums can cause bending of light
that's what kind of makes the spoon look
like an optical illusion here
looks like it's broken that's because of
the bending of the light through those
different mediums
now snell's law of reflect refraction
well snell's law describes the behavior
of light as it travels from one medium
into a different medium and snell's law
can be written as
n1 which referring to the refractive
index of substance one
times the sine of angle one equals
the refractive index n2 of substance two
times the sine of the angle of angle
number two
now both of these angles are measured
relative to the normal or line drawn
perpendicular
so you can see indicated here to the
surfaces where the two
mediums will meet now snell's law of
refraction
in order to calculate this on the
refractive index of materials is based
on the angle
the light hits and bends we can see that
depicted here the lights coming in at
this angle
passes through the means and it comes
out at this angle through the second
medium
here we can see all of the components
you can see all of them described
however to best understand this let's
apply some numbers to this
an actual mathematical equation
so looking at snell's law example number
one
light traveling in air which is
refractive index of one hits a piece of
glass
an angle of 30 degrees the light
refracts
in the glass at an angle of 15 degrees
the question is what is the
index of refraction of the glass
so what we first want to do is take the
components given to us
and apply them to the equation for what
we know
so how we would go about this is we'd
start with the substance one the
refractive index
is one that's going to be the air and
it's it's a piece of glass thing
of 30 degrees so we know the angle ends
substance one we know the refractive
index
then the light refracts in the glass an
angle of 15 degrees
so we know the angle what it's asking
for is what is the refractive index of
that glass what's n2
in this example so if we go back to that
equation we kind of plug everything
in well 1 times the sine of 30
equals refractive index of substance 2
times the sine of
15. so how does that look well 0.5 is
going to equal
0.2588 times n2
solving for n2 we get n2 has a
refractive index
of 1.93 so what is the index of
refraction of the glass
the answer would be 1.93
moving on to example 2 for snell's law
here
slightly different example given here
light traveling in air has a refractive
index of one hits a piece of glass at an
angle of 45 degrees
if the glass has a refractive index of
1.5
what angle should the light bend up so
in this example i'm giving you now the
refractive index of the class and i'm
asking you now to determine
that angle so just as we did before
you're going to go through you're going
to find out all the information that you
know we know
refractive index we know the angle in
substance 1.
we don't know the angle of the light
leaves but we do know the refractive
index
so same as always we plug everything in
here we're solving for the angle
we go through the same mathematical
process multiply those
leave that there factor that down to the
next step
get point four seven one four equals the
sine of angle two
going back and taking the inverse sine
there we're getting that the angle would
be 28
degrees so again here we're solving for
the
angle before we're solving through
refractive index this is kind of both
parts of the
calculating for snell's law now here we
have some snell's law practice
so i encourage you to pause the video
here take a look at these
grab a calculator and go through and
solve some of the
for some of these questions because the
answers appear on the next slide
and i will be reviewing them in a moment
so again here pause the video
work your way through these and then
compare your answers to the answers
provided
hopefully you've gone through and paused
the video at this time because here i'm
going to give you the answers
so here are your answers remember the
first two are referring to refractive
indexes
and the last two are looking at degrees
hopefully you got these
if not i suggest you go back and watch
the video again and hopefully
that will help you be able to answer any
of these questions that may show up in
the future