okay I'm gonna go over so quality and
the take-home quote here is treat your
soil soil well and it will return the
favor to you so you want to be careful
and mindful of your soil I don't want to
mess it up and ideally the crops you get
off it will be more than bountiful for
ya so obvious question is just what is
soil quality well it's a combination of
things it's often referred to as soil
health but really more properly called
soil quality in this soil health is kind
of the physical properties your soil the
chemical properties and the biological
properties and how they all interact and
overlap that little portion right here
in the middle would be your soil health
or so qualities we're going to call it
so first off what is soil well soil is
or should be about fifty percent mineral
25 percent air and 25 percent of water
just gives you hundred percent now
whether you have clay or silty clay or
silt loam or silt or sandy loam depends
on the percent clay the percent silt and
the percent sand that you have in your
soil you'll notice the percent clay has
a large bearing on what type of soil it
is clay is very small particles and they
influence the properties of soil quite a
bit now good for growing conditions that
they said here's the 50/25/25 split
compacted soil though you'll notice a
greater percentage of the solid and
poorly drained soil has more water and
also that same percentage solid but more
percentage of water and that's your
water a lot of your air percentage goes
down so these are some conditions you
may have experienced or have fields that
have this but ideally you're trying to
shoot for that 50/25/25 split if you get
the soil test free back and they say
silty loam well this gives you an idea
on this triangle of what percentage clay
silt and sand that you do have in your
soil balance is the key regardless of
soil you're talking about
so the key part of yours to be balanced
there's a lot of different things going
on not as simple as just one one kind of
leg here of the lever could be multiple
things going on so looking at the
results you get back from the lab it's
important to realize what's high value
somewhere are low values and the goals
to have a balanced soil so you want to
bring the low values up without adding
even greater amounts of nutrients to the
high values and is it difficult
balancing yeah and there's some
give-and-take within everything
so quality this is gives you an idea of
the complexities the Moltres chart
what's in antagonism or synergistic with
certain nutrients and how you affect one
and how it affects all the others
this is going to get very complex I can
be very hard to understand at least
initially there's micronutrients in
hearing there's some major nutrients and
how they all interact but as I showed in
the last minutes that balancing act that
you're trying to maintain you don't want
to just look at one and just raise one
by increasing one you're also going to
potentially affect some others so just
important to keep that in mind and when
in doubt start on the low end because
you can always add more so more is not
better as I said you want to turn the
low end excessive amounts of some
nutrients can restrict plant growth
negatively impact the environment and
basically cause you unnecessary expenses
we have a deficiency range here and a
critical arrange in that sufficiency
range so you wanna yours your yields are
increasing the certain point that
sufficient arranger doesn't change if
you keep adding nutrients at this point
you get to this toxic range you could
actually have a reduction in the elds so
your goal is to reach that critical
level that's at the point what we call
no fertilizers response is likely so up
to this point you keep that in
fertilizer your percent yield keeps
going up then there's a certain point
and this would be the exact point here
we're adding more fertilizer it does not
give you more yield just increases your
cost in your time and you're destined so
you want to try to be as close to here
as possible now if you overshoot a
little bit that's okay if you understood
a little bit that can be okay too if you
had some fertilize you can bring it back
up the key part is to know when you're
close or protein that critical level
because if you go too high could really
cause some issues so what do I add to my
soil there's liquid versions of some
nutrients there's wettable powders
there's granular which one do I choose
well they all have pros and cons to them
on the liquid the pro is it's really
easy to measure typically or run through
an injector easily and we'll see to talk
about drip irrigation and fertilizer
injectors however the downfall to
liquids is that they shouldn't feed it
any point in their life so storage of
them could be an issue they take up
large volumes to Neph gallons
five-gallon storage and often there's
just stabilized or in and that could
settle over time that's
you're saving a year-to-year a lot of
times you'll see a little bit of a layer
developing the bottom I want to try to
shake them and stir them it's midwinter
just to go through they're not settling
out so they don't lose that stabilizer
still over time it's hesitancy to drop
that a solution that can be an issue
multiple powders they don't sell over
time they're great small volume for
storage but the cons is it can be messy
and hard to measure often require
pre-mixing before tank mix and kind of
like making the chocolate milk should
put it in the container here shake it up
before you add it to the glass here so
it can be a little bit harder than next
I'll put the ranges they store small and
they don't settle over time then we get
to granular these are easily broadcast
no special equipment needed literally
can take a gloves and a pail and go and
spread them they can't be fed through an
irrigation system for the irrigation to
interfere again it's not possible as
granular there's different size we know
there's some larger particles are some
smaller particles think of it like
applying sand and that can be
advantageous I tend to be cheaper and
bought in larger quantities when you're
looking at soil health or so quality pH
should be your number-one concern
typically Connecticut ourselves acidic
and we have two types of lime
so all I'm is not treated the same just
assume the line needs to be added every
year I've had some fields that do need
to be lightened on every year somewhere
every other year summer every fifth year
some you fertilize once with lime and
you're kind of done I caution you about
using wood ash this can dress lee
increase your ph it's great at raising
your pH but it can add it to become too
high in two eyes just as bad as too low
we're shooting for just slightly acidic
6.8 for most crops 6.5 is our goal
most native soils we can be hovering
around five some cases a little bit low
or some case a little bit higher or
tsun4 around that neutral adding wood
ash I've seen soil approaching 10 which
causes all sorts of other issues when
we're adjusting our pH using lime the
two types are dolomitic which is
commonly called agricultural lime and
this is high in magnesium it's about 12%
magnesium and there's calcitic or garden
lime and this is a lower magna
seem content so if your magnesiums
already high you could be looking at
more of a calcitic or a garden lime to
be adding to your particular soil NPK
nitrogen phosphorus and potassium
nitrogen and put in parentheses here we
determined that with a nitrate test kind
of a little difficult special test to
kind of go through and follow do nitrate
tests that want to do to get true
analysis of your soil nitrate levels
phosphorus want a caution it's a
freshwater contaminant if you over add
phosphorus yes--it's will say it's
important for roots and getting them
growing with you over add phosphorus it
can contaminate fresh groundwater wells
in area ponds potassium K is commonly
needed can be pulled out of soil pretty
readily by some crops you show up as a
deficiency in some some areas some other
macronutrients calcium lime does contain
calcium but for the most part it's not
really plant available so it looks like
in the raw form it's kind of a silvery
look to it magnesium they talked about
can be an issue with Tomatoes epsom
salts is great for that for the
magnesium or dolomitic lime if your
soils low in it also epson salts gave
you some sulfur which may be more of a
concern
due to lack of acid rain were receiving
back we had a lot of acid rain coming
from some of the power plants out in the
Midwest they since have cleaned up their
stacks as we rose less sulfuric acid
because the acid rain was sulfuric acid
it was raining down and some fields were
getting quote free sulfur now that we're
getting that as much acid rain we're not
getting that free sulfur we can't took
for granted in some cases so certain
instances you may see low sulfur not
necessary in the large scale
micronutrients are also important not to
over add a lot of people get hung up in
the micronutrients your irons your
manganese your Boron's your coppers your
zinc your chlorides don't really focus
on days after you get your pH
straightened out in your macro
straightened out then you can move to
these they're typically bear deterrent I
a test of the leaves not to say a soil
and overall ation of your focus rarely
is a problem on their own I have seen
growers over add these and get into
issues I kind of use the association of
micronutrients consider them to be like
a spice
you can take a perfectly good steak and
over spice it and it will taste horrible
same thing here you can take a
micronutrient and over at it and it can
really cause havoc on the plants in soil
cell micronutrients while living in them
odds are very low this is a problem and
some growers are asking you all below
should I test for molybdenum
no it's such a small amount if it's in a
fertilizer it typically comes with a
warning to may be harmful of ruminant
animals for foraging grass where
applications have been made this I found
online here was the link on the
description to look in the resources
there this is what it would look like
but really it mimics a lot of other
things and in our area I have never seen
this really to be a problem microbiology
also getting a lot of talk driven by the
hobbyist gardeners stick to some of the
basics have some supporting evidence
more than just the manufacturers
brochures there's a lot of advertising
saying this is the best micronutrient if
you add this guaranteed to get bigger
crops not always the case so you want to
make sure your pH and your
macronutrients is straightened out
before you start moving to microbiology
some examples of some of her beneficial
bacteria actinovate Aizaz companion
there's some examples here
these tend have some a little bit more
supporting evidence and some other ones
i've heard about so these might be worth
an initial look if you feel everything
else is straightened out for fungi roots
shielding mycorrhizae root shield is
root shield plus mycorrhizae is being
found in potting mixes too so this could
be some good beneficial fungi to look at
and target however earthworms can't be
overlooked they have many benefits be
kind to them and you'll get their free
castings you have to go out and buy any
they'll just work their way through the
soil and if they're happy you'll be
happy coffee grounds can be great way to
encourage the initial population you can
actually even grow them over the winter
and a slightly heated basement if you're
looking at something to do over the
winter n-- want to get a head start and
getting some earthworms for the area you
plan on growing in the spring
tillage disturbing the soil as little as
possible
till with a purpose i always say there's
different types of tillage or zone
there's chisel plow want to maintain us
she's didn't pay for city with the soil
in the plant keep living roots in your
soil and keep the soil covered mentioned
this in a couple of other videos with
cover crops and weed management but
tillage you want to remember that you
are disturbing the soil this can be good
if you have a purpose but just just keep
going through and keep beating up less
soil can I'm negative effects over the
long term how to maintain high quality
that species diversity in soil in plants
people in roots all year keep the soil
covered this can be a non invasive way
it's called a broad work if you have a
very small area basically jab this in
the ground after you put it in the
ground your rock it back and you just
break necessarily get some aeration in
without really turning or flipping the
soil tissue testing turnaround time is
important if you do want to go through
new tissue testing to determine your
plant health increased cost reduced time
between sampling result is worth the
price so if someone will turn the
results back and under a week and you
have to pay a little bit more that's
worth it because tissue testing you're
typically looking at a quick result to
fix a problem here we see it tomato leaf
on a bean leaf here exhibiting some of
these symptoms this is a nutrient this
is potassium in particular and you're
able to go through and have that be an
issue correct that with some liquid feed
again can save your crop so turnaround
time is important for the leaf analysis
if you do want to go this route again
start with the pH looking at that your
macronutrients once you get those in
line a lot of other things will come
together but there are other options the
key part is treat your soil well and
it'll treat you well