okay here we're gonna be looking at soil
pH so there's no difference between the
PHS soil there's a pH of water it's all
following the same zero to fourteen
scale and we're talking specifically
about soil pH we're looking at assessing
the pH of the actual media or substrate
that the plants are going to be growing
in so while it is the soil we're going
to looking at if you're having a problem
with pH it's a good idea to test your
irrigation water
this testing the pH of your irrigation
waters a good idea is this can impact
plant growth in soil quality so here for
example this is your irrigation water
and it has a pH of four point nine six
this could vastly be impacting the pH of
your soil and again depending on what
media might be growing in what and why
it's so acidic in part test your water
to start the page scale is the same zero
to fourteen scale it's a logarithmic
because as you can see here it's a
tenfold increase per each pH unit that
it goes up and this is important so if
we said I'm only a couple points off
well that's like tenfold increase so
that I can get exponentially off there
and this reason why we want to maintain
that pH is affects the availability of
nutrients for our plants so how do we
test it well it's easy to do pH meters
only can test liquid not dry soil so we
have to go through and develop a liquid
medium or slurry from your soil be sure
the tester you're using is calibrated
and the probe doesn't dry out there's a
term called when it dries it dies this
is why you'll see in labs pH probes are
kept and usually distilled water at all
times even when not in use
now how do you go about testing soil
well you wanna start at the clean probes
don't want to have any interaction or
contaminants when I add distilled water
to the soil to create a slurry and then
test the pH especially before you can't
just kind of take the probe and put it
in the pot put it in the soil and get an
accurate reading for pH need to kind of
create this slurry solution here to
again get that accurate reading and
that's why you want to use distilled
water so the water you're adding isn't
influencing the total pH so I'm so I'm
pH testing best done as part of a
complete soil test that's carried out
with consistent protocols in a
professional lab I'd much rather send my
solar media
to LabVIEW professionally done they do
make these kits we kind of add solutions
and they kind of look at the color these
can give you very results it's best to
get it done professional lab with a set
of protocols that target pH is what you
should be shooting for and that's
usually around six and a half to seven
or so six eight is usually kind of the
ideal or the sweet spot know if you're
growing hydroponically it could be
better
you might target might be a little bit
more acidic that five point eight to six
point eight or six point three being the
ideal pH again acidic is pH is below
seven those hydroponic setup stead also
to have reduce buffering capacity if
it's just pure water this would cause
rapid swings in the pH and this can
result in very poor plant performance so
if you are growing hydroponically you
want to make sure you just buffers in
place to help resist change in pH so I
do want to maintain it slightly more
acidic but you kind of want to prevent
that pH and jumping around a lot there's
really going to affect and negatively
impact your plant's growth
now if correcting or rising the soil pH
that's very common for New England soils
which is typically looking at five and a
half to six so often this needs to be
raised can even be less than this
limestone is the most common method for
raising soil pH this is a general term
there's many different types of lime
build my say on liming the soil well
looking look more specifically the
options you have within the broad
category of limestone
so there's dolomitic lime this is the
cheapest and easiest to find I see even
here dolomitic limestone the concert is
very high in magnesium so if you have a
soil test that comes high in magnesium
well odds are you might be looking at
another lime alternative but this is the
cheapest and typically easiest to find
then there's something called calcitic
lime and this is very effective at
raising the soils pH it's mainly just
calcium it's not very high in magnesium
so again for high magnesium soils
calcitic lime might be the way to go
cons are typically harder to find and
can be more costly when you do find it
the other third main category of lime is
what's called hydrated lime this is a
quick way to change pH often though it's
not a long term pH to change its
solution and for conditions that require
high doses there can be taxes and B
issues lastly
mucous membrane irritant and typically
why with this line they'll see keep out
of reach of children it's a very usually
a finding dusty product and if you do
breathe any of that in it will feel kind
of that burning sensation of your mucous
membranes
there's also that's love lowering soil
pH this is a condition where your pH
would be seven or even a little bit
above that common Rocky Mountains in
West where the pH is a little higher
then the desired amount for plant growth
typically ultimately adding sulfur iron
sulfate or aluminum sulfate these are
all ways to kind of help lower the pH of
your soil to help get it again to that
sweet spot that target range of being
slightly acidic for maximum nutrient
elderly and for the best plant growth