okay human goers some basics of soil and
wellness you may think this is an area
where kind of worms live keep in mind
that there is an organic mineral matter
that composes 75% typically five percent
organic matter which contains
microorganisms and macro organisms then
50 percent of it is actually defined as
air and water this is what makes up soil
so again what is soil well it's mineral
based material that also contains air
water inorganic matter
times people I think it hung upon the
organic matter keep in mind air and
water are also a vital components
they're good for growing plant
conditions 25 percent air 25 percent
water 50 percent solid compacted soil
this is where we're kind of squeezing
out some of that air still retaining 25
percent water but increasing that solid
percentage poorly drained soils we also
have that 5 percent air they've
increased that water amount quite a bit
so while the salad is still 50 percent
here that matches the good growing
conditions in this case we have an
excessive amount of water
suffocating those roots reducing plant
performance a particle size so the size
of particles determines the
classification to the impact and open
space between those particles most soils
are a mixture of different particle
sizes Clay's defined as less than point
zero zero two millimeters it's the
smallest of the particles gravels told
artists to mills - about 75 millimetres
sand and silt and clay are going to be
the three we're going to kind of focus
on here
silt is that point zero zero two so I'm
basically clay up to 0.05 millimeters
and sand would be larger that 105 to
about that two millimeters could see
just in comparison well we may think of
sand particles being very small it is
clay there's actually the smallest again
how do those look well we have clay
soils sandy soils we have baloney soils
here so clay being comprised of those
smallest particles and then alone kind
of being in the middle and sand being
the largest well clay soils contain the
small so particles they have a tendency
to pack together reducing air spaces
greatest amount of surface area and have
a great impact on soil properties this
soil will crack when dry and tendency to
stick to equipment and if you've ever
worked with clay like a pottery class it
has a very
a similar consistency in extreme cases
to something like that and kind of see
here were we having that stickiness
appearance here that sheeting that
occurs this would be very indicative of
a clay or very very small particle based
in soil field test to determine clay I
simply take a sample of the soil in your
hand at little water and try to form a
ball as we see here and then attempt to
squeeze the ball into a flat ribbon the
ribbon reaches about two inches long or
more before breaking this is a sign you
have clay soil because those small
particles are able to hold themselves
together and this is kind of one quick
way you're not a 100 percent accurate
way we could play to give you an idea of
does that soil contain a lot of clay
based particles sandy soils there's a
largest of the soil particles it's very
easy to cultivate and sand however they
tend to dry out quickly it can be easily
flushed in nutrients so while they can
support plants because of their large
particle size typically water can drain
through them in soak in nutrients so
there's white if you don't see a lot of
plants being grown in desert regions
where it's all sand simply because of
the low rainfall and the tendency for
this soil to dry out anyway loamy soil
that's a combination of particles about
equal parts which is about 40% of sand
40% of silt offers many properties that
supports plant growth it can hold
nutrients which is great while still on
water to percolate through and air to
infiltrate which is great however
there's a large range of lonely soils
kind of see three different subsurface
areas of loam here the dark brown is the
fine kind of sandy loam subsurface layer
is kind of this pale brown is I guess
it's kind of also along those sandy loam
lines and the red clay is a red clay
loam so you kind of see some variability
that does occur but in general loamy
soils do favor crop development the soil
triangle so it's important to try to be
able to read this just on an initial
kind of overview take you can see that
clay is a great influence but you'll
notice there's of course three sides of
this triangle but how we'd go about
reading that is if we had soil had 30%
clay and 30% scene
so we take that 30% line go over here
see where intersects our 30% line right
here so 30 and 30 here and 34 33 60 40%
would have to be still to see this line
it comes down here all three intersect
right at this point here indicating that
soil would be a clay loam so again you
take your three percentages of clay silt
sand sand and wherever those intersect
would give you the soil type and you'll
notice that clay again because it's
small particles high surface area has a
great influence on the type of soil may
be classified as sand very difficult be
considered a fully ZN soil and you can
see those lonely soils are kind of here
there's a true loam clay loam sandy loam
sandy clay loam all these different
forms of classification but you can see
how I can kind of eat this soil triangle
a lot so you don't want to use soil if
you're growing in containers you want to
go out and dig a bunch of soil put it
containers and go grow in it this isn't
advised it's often heavy in mineral base
which can lead to issues utilized in
indoor operations the water holding
properties are not conducive to
container growing outdoors oil is great
for outdoor operations just because
plants may grow good outdoors doesn't
mean that will translate into the high
stress environment of indoor container
garden