here we're gonna look at soil fertility
and what kind of defines a soil is being
fertile a lot of times you may hear that
it's very fertile soil well what's that
actually mean here we'll look at some
more of the details behind that so in
particular the definition of sir
fertility is the building the soils to
sustain agricultural plant growth this
is by supplying essential plant
nutrients in water to allow that lay the
plant to grow but also reach
reproduction reach its full lifecycle
this conduct has to occur also in the
absence of toxic substances which mean
hit it plant growth so the higher is
soil is in soil fertility not only is it
allowing for plant growth it's allowing
it to be just phase of reproduction but
there's also an absence of harmful
substances now through several
conditions that contribute to soil
fertility such as root depth training
soil moisture proper pH and nutrients
this gives you just a little bit so
profile the horizons Oh organic is at
the very top a is very near the surface
the B is the subsoil which is pretty
much the extent in which the roots will
reach see the substrate name is where
roots are not going to reach and then
our we have as bedrock here now looking
particularly at root depth sufficient
soil depth for adequate root growth and
water retention so I want to make sure
that the soil is not just you know very
shallow that can cause some issues with
plants as they develop their roots see
kind of a profile here of a soil this is
a tree and we can kind of see that they
that root depth not doesn't quite go as
far as some may think is definite a
couple large area allowing for adequate
nutrient and water absorption as well as
anchoring this plant in the ground then
there's drainage a good drainage to
providing carburation roots here we see
a pitchfork being plunged into the soil
here we can kind of break the soil here
and help increase duration roots need to
respire they need to take it oxidant to
breathe to grow properly so you don't
want them soaking in water for a long
periods of time for most plants that's
not going to be good results that's
gonna be evidence of poor soil fertility
we have soil moisture so we do need to
have some moisture in the soil and that
is so the root zone needs to maintain a
proper moisture this means it's not one
logged or it's not too dry it's kind of
that nice even about the physical
properties of the soil
can impact this such as the particle
size here
how many large or small particles that
have kind of sandy that clay gravel
based that can really impact the ability
for a soil to maintain moisture levels
we have the proper soil pH so soil pH in
the range of 6 to 7 in fevering that
slightly acidic to neutral is preferred
and this is again speaking for most
plants there are a couple plants for
example like blueberries you for growing
in there looking at much more of the
acidic range here this various compiler
8 sales above 7 so we're just looking at
this pH range typically right around
neutral most nutrients are available to
class so that's where most are going to
prefer 6 to 7 the nutrients to support
plant growth we want the optimum rates
of nutrients that our plant available so
what this term plant-available means is
that the plant can take them up some
soils for different properties or
different issues may have a high amount
of nutrients in them but they may be
here the term called they're locked up
nutrients there are nutrients that
aren't able to be pulled out by the
plant so we want to have that kind of
that maximum growth maximum yield want
to have those nutrients being highly
plants available which often is provided
through a proper pH of the soil so just
a couple things that help contribute to
the term soil fertility