in this debaco university video hope to
try
to reduce some of the complications
when looking at nitrogen as a fertilizer
when trying to grow plants
[Music]
so nitrogen may just be one nutrient but
it can perform
a lot of different kind of transitions
it can as
can become very complex in the different
forms that it takes
the hope here is to try to reduce some
of those complexities
we're going to look at soil nitrogen
complexities to better understood with a
nitrate test
and at the end some fertilizer
recommendations will be provided at
least
in general to act as a general summary
here
so the impact of nitrogen on plants
nitrogen is an important nutrient to be
looking at
it's because it's part of all living
cells nitrogen promotes green leaf
growth
and lack of nitrogen commonly can limit
plant growth
plants uptake nitrogen in the form of
nitrate no3 or ammonium
nh4 with the nitrate form being
preferred
by many garden plants so it's not only
just the nutrient it's also the
molecule that comes in to help impact
and change how it might be open to
uptake by a plant
so again why focus on nitrogen well even
if levels of all other nutrients are
sufficient
you may still need to add nitrogen each
year
despite the many different nutrients in
the soil nitrogen is likely to be
deficient
if not managed properly nitrogen is
variable so understanding and managing
it can be a challenge
proper management of nitrogen will help
ensure optimum crop performance
and minimize minimizes potential
negative environmental impacts
and the reason why you need to
continually usually fertilize with
nitrogen
is because it has a tendency to leach
from the soil while other minerals be
tend to hold in the soil a little bit
longer nitrogen has a tendency to leach
out from year to year so we're looking
at nitrogen recommendations related to a
soil test
keep in mind that since nitrogen levels
can fluctuate widely depending on
environmental conditions
and can change during the shipping
process of that soil test as it goes
from where you sampled it
to the lab this element is not measured
in a routine
soil test this is why there is this
thing called a june
nitrate test which tested specifically
and only
for nitrogen the nitrogen
recommendations are based on crop
needs as an estimate by field studies
combined with presumptives
of the presumption that little available
nitrogen remains in the soil
at the end of the growing season and
here we just see some examples of
looking at nitrogen recommendations
looking at cotton
and ancient removal and pounds per
bushel of corn and soybeans
so again it's good that you have some
sort of crop to match this up with
but hopefully with all these can kind of
develop that general sense
of what's a good target level when we're
taking
a june nitrate test so the nitrogen
cycle now nitrogen has many different
chemical forms
and it changes as part of the full
nitrogen cycle
some are more pla available than others
that's an important consideration
not all nitrogen can be uptaken by
plants nitrogen makes up the vast
majority of the air about 78 percent
but this is only usable by legumes which
can fix this form into other plant
available forms
so even though plants are constantly
exposed to atmospheric nitrogen
which is the vast majority 78 of the air
around them most plants other than
legumes cannot utilize that form of
nitrogen
you're looking at mainly the nitrates
being what's being able to be absorbed
by plants here also some ammonia as well
but others can be leeched out and not
uptaken by plants so not only do we need
nitrogen in the soil
and around the plant we need it in the
proper form for uptake
so what are some commercial nitrogen
fertilizers we have the ammonia
which includes anhydrous ammonia and at
room temperature ammonia is a colorless
pungent smelling gas that is lighter
than air
at minus 28 degrees fahrenheit ammonia
is stored as a liquid
and ammonia easily dissolves in water
this makes it an efficient form
of delivery to plants but it must be
injected below the soil surface to be
delivered to plants so it's
not commonly done in rocky soils need to
literally be
injected below the soil surface and it's
going right along we're going to go
through and inject it below the soil
surface and cover it up
if you have rocky soils the kind of the
point of injection can break
and therefore it's typically not used in
soils that tend to be very rocky or
regions of the country that tend to be
rocky
calcium nitrate of 1500 is water-soluble
and
fast-acting form of nitrogen fertilizer
urea is very potent it's 46.00 46
nitrogen it's a very efficient source of
nitrogen but requires soil microbes to
change its form of nitrogen
to become plant available it's best if
incorporated into the soil or watered in
shortly after application
to avoid nitrogen being lost to
volatilization where it becomes a gas
and goes into the atmosphere
and not uptaken by the plant there's
also organic forms of nitrogen
fertilizer such as manures
they can have high levels of plant
available amounts of nitrogen
but you want to watch the type of
bedding that may come with the manure
for example if it's sawdust or other
fine wood products this will reduce the
amount of plant available nitrogen
because it should be uptaken as part of
the decomposition process
of that sawdust then there's soil
organic matter
and nitrogen is released in the process
of mineralization
as organic matter as soil microbes break
down
that organic matter we kind of have this
kind of process going on
the soil when it gets to a proper
temperature then there's a blood meal
here this has a 12 1
0 12 nitrogen it's a high nitrogen
content
organic fertilizer now changing forms of
nitrogen as you see we have
nitrification which is the biological
process of converting ammonia just nh4
plus
to nitrates the nitrate n is negatively
charged as we can see right here
in ion that is not attracted to soil
particles or soil organic matter
like the ammonium is so it's more
commonly easy to leach
you have two negative particles they're
going to kind of repel one another as a
result that's going to have a tendency
to leach
out of the soil then there's
denitrification which is bacteria
converting no3 to no2 gas
and that would kind of the no2 gas would
be lost to the atmosphere
that'd be through the process here of
volatilization
then with immobilization this is when
nitrogen is assembled into compounds
or materials that is not available such
as plant residues it's another way we
can quote
lose nitrogen or have nitrogen that
cannot be
of benefit to the crop we're trying to
grow
now how can nitrogen be lost and i say
lost in the sense that
we know where it goes but loss in the
sense it cannot be uptaked
or utilized by the plant we're intending
to grow
there can be leaching and this is
physically loss of nitrogen due
excess water additions it's most likely
to occur in sandier soils
that denitrification is typical loss of
nitrate forms when soil is saturated
with water for two to three days
particularly prolonged rain events
volatilization is when the surface
applied nitrogen is not incorporated
into the soil which is applied on top
because this can lead to nitrogen being
lost to the air conditions that
increase the rate of volatilization is a
soil ph higher than 7.3
also hot air temperatures and a moist
soil surface if you're in the hot of
summer
on a basic soil with just after a rain
it's going to improve the efficiency to
be volatile volatilized
and not uptaken by the plant there's
also crop removal we must take into
consideration
this is simply removing plant material
that has nitrogen in it will naturally
reduce nitrogen in the soil
this is actually how the majority of
nitrogen leaves the soil system
when the crop is harvested and taken off
site the nitrogen that's in that plant
is also removed with it then there's
soil erosion
and runoff and these should be minimized
for the reasons in addition to nitrogen
loss but also don't want to be losing
your soil
this is why cover crops are highly
recommended in open fields
now there's two key forms of nitrogen as
i said that ammonium and that
nitrate form while there are many forms
and nitrogen clean both organic and
inorganic forms
plants can only use these two forms
plants only take up
inorganic nitrogen in the form of no3
nitrate
or nh4 plus in the ammonium
so all other forms of nitrogen are
intermediate forms
and cannot be directly utilized by the
plant they might be important in the
cycle
but as far as what the plant can uptake
these are the only two forms that the
plant can uptake
so which one is better well in short
neither
just remember that nitrate is always
present in the soil solution
and will move with soil water so again
keep that in mind that
it's not like oh i want to choose one
versus another they both can be utilized
by the plants we're looking at those
conversion forms of nitrogen
inhibiting the conversion of our
ammonium
to nitrate can result in less nitrogen
loss
in more plant uptake because the whole
goal through this entire process
is this important part here of plant
uptake
you can see we see here the nitrate form
the ammonium form can both be uptaken by
the plant they're the only forms
our goal here is to limit the chance of
this being converted or leeched
or this being kind of immobilized or
this kind of being leached out of the
soil or part of the soil runoff or
volatilized
we want to make sure we're having its
greatest percentage that we can
going through plant so we're not losing
a whole bunch we're not wasting a lot of
that fertilizer
as how can we reduce the waste of
nitrogen fertilizer well
growers can work on ideally the timing
of that fertilizer
if plants are fertilized too early the
risk for lost
nitrogen does increase growers should
try in timely application with plant
uptake
so what does that mean well here we have
a corn plant as just an example
we fertilize very early we're going to
lose a lot because the roots are going
to be small
and also the demand for nitrogen is
reduced
when we're looking at the corn again as
another example
3 7 of nitrogen taken up by post-post
flowering
66 nitrogen taken up by a flowering
phase so we're looking at fertilizing
we want to time that for a little bit
later in the growth cycle when the
demand goes up
because what that's going to do is allow
our nitrogen in the soil
to be uptaken by the plant at a greater
efficiency simply because the plant is
demanding greater amounts of it
so as promised were some common for
nitrogen fertilizer
recommendations you know what would i
kind of in general kind of recommend
and just some common fertilizers calcium
nitrate
is great to use when soils are colder
for more plant available form
but it's only 15 percent nitrogen you
have to take that into consideration
that calcium nitrate is very plant
available but only 15
nitrogen compared to some of the others
urea is great when the soils are warmer
but be sure to water it in to avoid
potential volatization
and this is 48 nitrogen i make that
distinction
because if you're adding a pound of
calcium nitrate
in a pound of urea and think they're oh
they're both nitrogen fertilizer
that pound of calcium is 15 percent and
and that penetrates 48
in if we can scale this up to 100 pounds
of calcium nitrate
of that hundred pounds of fertilizer
only 15 of that would be nitrogen
comparing that to urea 100 pounds of
urea
48 almost half of that is going to be
nitrogen
so keep in mind that there is no best
form of nitrogen
trying to better understand this taking
a june nitrate test
there's other videos on that here on
this channel that you're welcome to take
a look at
to try to better understand nitrogen why
because you typically need to add it
every year and it does change quite
frequently so being able to best
understand the conditions and the
process and cycle of nitrogen
will help you make a better grower and
help improve your plant performance