this debacco University video we're
going to go onsite at the CBG guru's uh
establishment here to see their soil
preparation and also their planting and
see the methods they imply to grow their
[Music]
hemp so it's great to allow for sea and
Jacob to allow me out on their field and
hopefully teach you a little bit about
what they do um in their uh hemp
production so first off who are they uh
well we've got Sean here we've got Jacob
of the CBG gurus their go goal is to
produce quality product um manufactured
in stability and alignment with nature
they use as we'll see a layer of wood
chips uh to help uh maintain and improve
soil structure and quality and they also
work with Korean natural farming methods
and this kind of idea and concept is to
kind of use kind of some of the modern
science allowing for sustainable and
abundant cultivation of crops worldwide
so this can be applied more to than just
hemp provide some of their contact
information here and their website if
you want to take a look at them further
uh that microbial solution they're using
and we'll hear a little bit about that
described it's called the jadam
microbial solution or abbreviated JMS
and that's looking at bringing back
bring farming back to Farmers restoring
Farmers sovereignty and Technology speed
up the ultra lowcost farming and
ultimately open new world where Farmers
consumers and Mother Nature are all in
harmony provide some good links here if
you want to take a look at it a little
bit further as well as the basic recipe
here um so you can get a little bit of
an idea if you want to explore that
further take a look at these information
provided here as well as in the
description but let's go out to the
field and see exactly uh Sean and Jacob
in action at the CBG
gurus as we uh we prepare our field uh
with cardboard which decomposes first
and kills the sod covered in wood chips
which will decompose second um kind of
over time we get this really rich
organic matter heavy and kind of very
worm casting heavy uh top soil and you
can see if I hunt through a little bit
I'm sure we'll find some
worms right there's
one
so yeah we're trying to disturb them as
little as possible ideally um but that's
one of the big advantages to like the
back to eeden style farming um is over
time you're building really really
organic matter Rich top soil and really
like helping the worm population grow um
a lot of other like microbes and and
insects as well
so see
I'm excited as time progresses all
really turns into that
rich top soy like it's only been 3 years
um at this
point I think this is probably an old
row
we had some really crazy increases in
organic matter um from our first year to
the second year doing the Back to Eden
style um and it was
like more than more than like I think it
was like two
2.3% organic matter increase um in the
soil
um and with a cardboard that we used to
kill the sad we kind of uh
figured that like and it seemed as we
were preparing the holes the sad
decomposes really quickly because it's
still pretty alive has some nitrogen
stored in it um and that gives you like
an immediate kind of boost so if you do
have like grass you know lawn or um hay
field can work quite
well
so the jadam microbial solution um which
is really incredible for soil building
and just like soil Health in your lower
soil layers and the Anor robic layers um
one thing we
learned at a from Young Sun Cho at his
he's the founder of jadam um is that the
only the top two inches or so of your
soil is actually an aerobic environment
so under that is really Anor robic um
and a lot of like you're know the miza
can thrive in a system like ours with
all the wood chips available for them to
eat
but um it's also really important for
soil Health to have your Anor robic
microbes deep down in the soil breaking
apart those minerals and rocks and
everything so uh he created a recipe
just using boiled potatoes uh salt water
and then some soil leaf mold um you can
look it up online the JMS uh jadam or
the jadam microbial solution
um and you let it ferment in like a
bucket or a barrel a tank
um for about you know 24 to 36 hours
watching as these kind of rings of
bubbles accumulate on top and once they
are kind of concentric circles in the
tank you can dilute it with water and uh
pour it over your whole field um and you
can do it when they're plants in the
ground but it's a great soil soil prep
um and soil building Technique we heard
we uh heard Preston Smith speak about
how he built 2 in of top soil in 3
months using just jadam microbial
solution and wood chips um cuz there's
just such a it's just such an efficient
way of fermenting indigenous microbes
um that you could really just get like
insane levels of decomposition so it's
really amazing too for like remediation
can be done totally
cheaply uh pretty easily anywhere in the
world
so pretty
[Applause]
amazing
t
yeah so Sean has drilled with the auger
these nice uh deep holes hopefully about
like 2 and 1/2 ft or so deep um and then
I'm going to come back in with the
Pitchfork and uh so the holes are about
8 in wide I'm just going to stick the
Pitchfork about 45° on the edge of the
holes kick it down and really just try
to loosen up some of that soil down
there on each on all four corners all
four sides so I'll go around it like
that
um really trying to get like underneath
the wood chips and not really pull any
of the wood chips into the hole um so
they don't sap any of the nutrients any
the
nitrogen
so then once I kind of get around it I
want to go back in and really loosen
that soil
up uh with the
Pitchfork
and see
it's pretty nice big loose hole Little
Rock in there so a lot of
[Applause]
worms
ready to
go looks
nice got the dunk
Bucket over here so we make made a big
concoction of uh the base of it was the
Korean natural farming um seed soak
solution um so it's the the base four
parts
um which okay I could try I can think I
can
uh remember what we got going on here in
this bucket so we have the um the bone
Char in vinegar uh which is water
soluble uh calcium um in addition to
some vinegar as like a cleanser um and
to to
um pH balance has some has a scobby in
it too as well um so some microbes um
then there's the food element which is
the fermented plant juice which we just
extract from fresh live local uh foraged
plants with uh like a raw sugar we use
demarara sugar um and then finally the
last component is the Oriental herbal
nutrient which is a tincture of the five
Chinese medicinal herbs so we had
licorish um ginger garlic um Angelica
and
cinnamon um tinctured with uh vodka two
parts and jelica um and you keep them
separate but when you do a dunk or spray
or mix it up and dilute it um you
combine them together um or you can
combine them you know for about a month
ideally before um that's what uh Master
Cho says so um we
have some other beneficial microbes we
got like a biota from uh biosafe systems
who's nice organic company out of
Connecticut that does like IPM
Solutions
um and a couple other like microbial
things mixed in
there the air pruning on the sides I
think those nice thing maybe um and
they're just a little bigger so they the
plants uh and deeper that's the other
thing that we found with like the 5in
versus the 4in pots um the depth U just
like really stunted the growth they were
grown together for like two two and a
half weeks but then by week three like
you could see the tap rout would hit the
bottom of the small pot and then it
would like slow down whereas like the
other one keep sending that tap rout so
I think the deeper the pot
um the more
ideal but yeah so we're going to take
this plant here with the
flip loosen that pot up slide right out
you can see here
the like root growth is perfect on these
cuz they're not wrapping around the pot
they're going straight down um and
they're looking pretty white and
nice so I'm just going to take her
and dip her in here for a couple seconds
get
some
and There She
Goes what a beauty sour Tangy number
three I really like we love these big
pots they're
rocking the plant just grows so fast it
it
uh especially these clones we've got
definitely some good genetics this one
was
uh some very tall tall plants very
quickly and I'm just going to wrap W up
around here give a little wood chip
mulch
in a little circle around
her to try to keep the wood chips a
little bit away from the beast but she's
also pretty big
so don't really have to worry about that
nice and
Woody
o bag him and tag him that's it that
Tang number
three