here on this tobacco university video
we're going to go over soil test report
target values
to get you an idea of what this actually
[Music]
means
so if you've got a soil test report back
you might see this kind of green area
here
that is usually your target area some
people call it some labs we'll call it
medium some will call
optimum but that's kind of the target we
don't want to be up here and we'll
explain why you don't want to be over
that or under that
why that's the goal area to be well the
goal as i said there
is to be in the optimum area so some
growers think excessive is the target
but this is false optimum is the best
having excess amounts of certain
nutrients can impact the availability of
others and result in reduced growth
balanced nutrients allow for the optimum
growth of a plant
now the example or picture here of a
mountain if you think about climbing up
the mountain you're getting more and
more yields
people think it's going to go on forever
but if you keep going
reach that optimal or that peak that's
where you want to be but if you keep
walking you're going to go down this
other way
and start to reduce your yields when you
get into toxicities or
conflicting levels with other nutrients
so common misconception here if you look
at this nice
graph here i think it helps explain this
the sense that if there are more
nutrients than the plant needs
it can just take what it needs and
that's a false statement
now this is a common misconception that
growers just want to like i'll give it
some more and it doesn't need that much
it'll just ignore that and plants really
don't have that option
plants are not a kind of buffet nutrient
concentrations they
impact many chemicals reactions over
adding
what will offset this balance so also
too much
nutrients can cause potential
environmental contamination
not to mention wasted time and money
so it's not just kind of like ah give it
a bunch of nutrients a buffet and it'll
kind of like pick out what it needs
now you want to be fertilizing your
crops and your plants to be in this
optimum range
if you go in this above optimum range
well you're not getting any more yield
you're wasting time you're wasting money
and potentially you could be reducing
yields
and also increasing the odds of
environmental contamination
all not good things so adding more
and getting less i kind of like this
general concept i think this graph kind
of shows it for
when you're adding over adding
fertilizer can have
detrimental impacts in addition to just
increasing cost to the grower
it also increases the chance for
environmental contamination and
can also reduce yields and here we see
the soil test
levels and the theoretical yields and we
see very low low medium high here
going through we're getting to that kind
of maximum yield this is we're applying
maintenance fertilizer basically we're
fertilizing the plants with the plants
are removing
previous to this stage we're kind of
adding a little bit more than the plants
can uptake because we're trying to
build up that concentration in the soil
however
then we get to a point we want to apply
no fertilizer if we go much beyond that
to the excessive range
well we start to get detrimental effects
we start to get toxicity issues we start
to get reduction in yield
for adding more fertilizer so again this
optimum rate is what makes growing a
little bit of a challenge in the sense
how close can you be
within that range lastly the target
should be the critical level
so you might hear gross talk about
critical level and this is basically
indicated here
and also generally basically right here
the critical level is the level at which
adding more fertilizer will not increase
yield at that point you've now crossed
over the sterile test value going above
that
you're not going to get any more yield
now the optimum range
is a range not a number the critical
level is more so a number
the optimum range here will be a little
bit above that critical level and just
in case
you can overshoot by a little bit that's
fine but if you get above optimum one
i've overshot
too far and if you get excessive you
could get into toxicity levels so again
there's this optimum range where you're
basically
applying maintenance fertilizer you're
if you get into that kind of above
optimum you're applying no fertilizer
because you just have excessive amounts
of nutrients
so it's important for growers to realize
when they're at the very low low and
medium categories adding more fertilizer
will increase their yields
but it's not a linear line forever once
you reach that critical soil target
level
getting the optimum range you're then
shifting to only applying maintenance
fertilizer
keep realizing at the rate you were
you'll get into that very high toxicity
levels
and potentially reduce your yields and
potentially contaminate the environment
both negative things you can avoid by
realizing and
knowing these target levels