you're gonna look at soil testing
provides analysis of the soil so what
you do is you take a representative
sample from the field you sent it to a
lab and they work on extracting certain
nutrients from the soil and report back
to you I want a sheep you email and they
can mail it to you and it's a great way
for you to find out information about
what's going on in your field but it's
kind of hard to see
definitely observe it can save you a lot
of time so often I get asked the
question is it worth $20 you know it
worth the cost and that's $20 just an
average the information you can't see
and my opinion one of the best twenty
dollars you can spend on a field the
benefits are great and the cost are low
so that's why I highly recommend soil
testing even if you're looking at an
area for pH you may not have to go
through and do the complete soil
analysis but sometimes I'll even tested
field multiple times during the year
typically in the spring and also again
in the fall how many sample locations
well you can take three different
samples in various fields it might be a
good field a bad field in average field
you I didn't want to sample these
separately at least for the initial test
here the example is we have a wooded
area a vegetable garden a low-lying area
some green grass but you want to sample
an area that's fairly consistent so you
could see in this low-lying area
low-lying area there's some yellow spots
well those sample locations are outside
of those yellow spots I would test those
separately just to get an idea what
would be going on there could be a pH
issue could be something else the
vegetable garden set is sampled
separately than the wooded area then the
green grass has many different locations
at least to start with and then if you
determine all these to a very similar
these two are the same in the future you
could reduce your number of samples but
initially just trying to get an idea as
many different areas as you think
possible your goal is to get a
representative sample so this is your
population you want your sample to be
within that population in the soil lab
is only as good as a sample that you
send them so proper sampling technique
is your responsibility and take time
with it there's many different ways they
can still get
accurate results with not just one way
it's a spade shovel I can do a soil
auger a soil tube doesn't really matter
as long as you're consistent and able to
get that sample within your population
in this cases to be your field so how
does sample well pop your sampling
technique and equipment it's not really
all that complicated you want to take
out random I always say six to nine
samples per area that's about six to
nine inches deep pretty easy to remember
six nine samples six to nine inches deep
the goal is you don't want to go much
deeper or much shallower than that this
is the root zone this is where your
roots are going to be exposed to so
tools of the trade official stainless
steel probe you can use I've used those
in the past they make it really easy if
you're doing a lot of samples
particularly walking on large corn
fields or I use sometimes inch and 1/2
PVC pipe and sledgehammer and a pail and
a bag you take the PVC pipe you want
straight ideally take your sledgehammer
put the plastic bag in the pail I pound
the PVC pipe into the soil I knock out
soil I take another walk pound on the
ground again another six to nine inches
put it back in the bag take that bag out
when I'm done with that field label the
tie take another bag out of my pocket
but it back in the pail go through do it
from another field mix it pretty quick
and easy to do so it doesn't have to be
all that complicated
I like inch and a half because the soil
comes out of this pretty easy if you go
much smaller especially if it's a little
bit rained recently or it's a wetter
soil might get really jammed in there
pretty good inch and a half I can wrap
it a couple times with a sledgehammer
and usually it falls right out so we're
to test there's many different labs more
cost does not necessarily mean better
tests universities provide great quality
results I've tested at multiple labs and
they all give pretty consistent results
I know certain people that spend a lot
more than I do on soil tests and I've
looked at their results and they give
you some more information some more
ratios and a little bit different
information as far as details based on
the results but pretty much I just want
to see the numbers and results that we
can work on balance in the soil from
there so just because you're spending
more in this case does not always mean
it's it better
test for the results tell you remember
it's not the total nutrients I think
it's a big misconception
it's an estimation of the plant
available nutrients soil test results
provide the extractable nutrients you
don't care how much potassium is in the
soil you want to know how much is
available to the plants and that's what
soil tests try to do this is why if you
send two samples from the same field to
the same lab - and I test them to see
and they come back with different
numbers and you think that they're
giving you wrong results well they're
not there's a certain amount of
variability that occurs it'll be very
close about that but they won't be the
exact same number we're getting an
estimation they're trying to knock off
these nutrients from the soil and
determine what's available to the plant
because the soil test for plants doesn't
matter how much you have in the soil and
wants another portion of that nutrient
that's extractable and ideally available
to the plant a lot of vast majorities to
here of the potassium phosphorus is
bound up in the soil not available to
the plant so that's not what's a soil
test measure to measuring extractable
nutrients nitrogen why is it so
difficult to test whether sometimes not
test for it why do some ones used to
test for and don't anymore well to get
an accurate result need to do nitrate
test measuring is in constant flux it's
constantly changing I keep in mind the
lab will test and generate an accurate
result for the lab but if this doesn't
represent Muirfield it's not valuable or
worthwhile if you want to have a
estimation of the nitrogen that's in
your field and the Jun nitrate test is
the best way to do that it's taken in
June you want to sample down 12 inches a
little deeper and you don't want to put
in a plastic bag I'm gonna put it in a
paper bag so it breathes you want to get
to lab as soon as possible typically
people will sample and drive it directly
to the lab to get the most accurate
results that represent their field
conditions as possible