if you're thinking about using soilless
mix for your indoor cannabis production
here in tobacco university i want to
provide you with some specifics and some
tips
to help you with that process
all right let's get into some soils mix
suggestions for indoor cannabis
plant production so first off i want to
understand that there are as i'm sure
you are well aware
many soilless mix options this category
has many options within this broad
title here growers will find one brand
and stick with this and different
growers have different favorites
however remember that manufacturers can
change unexpectedly
modify the recipe or discontinue a
soil's mix
line at any time so you want to be well
aware and well diversified
so you are not have to relearn
everything just because the manufacturer
decide to make a change
most general purpose soilless mixes will
work out just fine for cannabis plant
productions i don't think you need to
have necessarily only one
and there's some common brands pro-mix
bx botanic care mix online
fox farm for example the happy frog
listed are shown right above me here
these are just some examples of some
common ones that you may be familiar
with
or may have seen now there's a soil mix
recipe for cannabis so at the in the
description to provide with some links
to some references you're welcome to
check those out
so i got some of the information here as
well as i cite a source at the very last
slide
you're welcome to check out as well for
more specifics
but the following here is listed for
about one cubic foot volume for easy
scaling up to match your volume
as far as kind of what you should be
kind of mixing in there
again directed more towards the cannabis
plant production and please take this as
only a suggestion there are many
uh different other options out there
this one is very simple that's why i
like it 50 percent peat
fifty percent vermiculite five grams of
dolomitic limestone to counterbalance
some of the acidity that the peat may be
bringing in
and ten percent uh ten grams of gypsum
there to help
uh supply some calcium uh to the plant
properties of this medium mix allows for
greater balance in aeration and also
water retention
a lot of growers will supplement the
vermiculite for perlite but vermiculite
can potentially supply some silicate for
the plant
as well now which i like that one as i
said very easy
fifty percent fifty percent vermiculite
50 grams dolomitic limestone 10 grams
gypsum for that one cubic foot
you'll notice there are others that go a
little bit more in detail
some develop these super soil recipes
they list all these ingredients
in the actuality as far as the plant's
concerned many of these details may not
be needed or may not be really
benefiting the plant
starting with this very basic formula
and building from there would be my
suggestion
now that vermiculite that i mentioned
you know what's it kind of what's it
look like well it's kind of got this
um kind of that goldish kind of brownish
kind of look to it
uh what's so great about it well it has
a lot of water holding capacity
in cec which stands for cation exchange
capacity
which has silica in it and it's likely
to benefit cannabis unlike other
substrate products particularly perlite
which i know is commonly used
however vaguely use if you haven't heard
of it is actually becoming used
less and less mainly due to its
increasing in
its cost and many growers and
manufacturers are utilizing perlite as a
substitute
so if given the option for a better kind
of
material to add a vermiculite would be
better than perlite but it might be a
little harder to find when you do find
it
you might find it to be a little more
costly
now the peat moss example here has
properties that are conducive to
supporting
plant growth however some are looking
for alternatives in
supplements with some turning to
shredded wood and other products
coconut coir is a good additive as well
but has slightly different properties
so again looking at a good kind of base
property use this peat moss
this is a picture i've taken myself
these are the ones that i've used and
quite a good
product here very easy to apply very
consistent
and usually easy to get overall but
again there could be some environmental
concerns by some people
so optimizing the ph so in that mix
there what's very important is that you
have a good
uh optimized ph some peat can have a
natural
ph of around 3.8 which is very acidic
however when mixed with the vermiculite
it usually will end up around 4.5
but remember our target peach is around
6.0
6.0 6.3 6.5 typically somewhere in that
range
to achieve this dolomitic limestone
which is naturally high in magnesium it
needs to be added to raise the ph
that dolmetic lime would be advised over
calcitic or um hydrated lime
adding gypsum will add some calcium and
sulfur in a slow release rate and it's a
good kind of general additive there
that's why it was mentioned
in the previous recipe if you're looking
for that reference not only in the
description but here i've provided you
another youtube video
link that you're welcome to again take a
look at there but this is intended to be
that quick little summary
kind of of giving you that quick little
rundown of if you're looking at going
through and kind of using a soilless mix
hopefully this gives you a quick recipe
to get started with that process