when it comes to sorting cannabis some
buds are just destined for extraction
and this debaco university video can
provide you with a little bit more
detail
and buds that go into this particular
[Music]
category
all right let's look at sorting canvas
buds destined for extraction
all right so in this case buds for
extraction the goal is not to focus on
high quality looking flower
since the end product will essentially
be the same the extract
so we're not looking so much at the
aesthetics of the actual bud
this is more common for outdoor
production simply because the buds
produce tend to be more variable
and not visually as appealing as those
with indoor operations
so initially we might be going through
and selecting out maybe the high grade
buds
mid grade we could potentially go either
way but low grade
typically is going to be for extraction
we're basing that on the visual
aspect and if they don't kind of look
like they're going to be that high
quality
looking or high quality aesthetics then
a lot of times those buds will go into
the category
to be extracted now why would you go
through extraction well in mass
production situations for extraction
there is less need
for this time-consuming art of trimming
to make those buds look
as good as they possibly can this can
also be important if you're looking to
produce
certain compounds and not a final showy
dry flower as an end product
looking for a certain terpene profile
certain terpenes
specifically or just a cannabinoid
extract there's no sense in kind of
going through the
delicate process of producing the dry
flour if you're looking at really
isolating that particular compound
that's why you'd go through this
extraction process
also as a grower you need to know what
you can produce if you have a process
dialed
in the odds of producing high quality
dry flour are greater
however if this would be a struggle an
extraction might be the way to go if you
know the quality of buds that you're
going to produce
are not going to be that great visually
looking not going to be that kind of
super a grade you might want to go
through and just
have a plan to go through the process of
extraction
to produce that end product that way
instead of a final
dry flower product so if you're looking
at
targeting a compound while extraction
will be able to remove individual
components
you may want to try and target one and
select a variety
or cultivar that is known to produce
high amounts of that material
to maximize the extract concentrate that
you look at producing
since the extracts again can have some
variable whether you're looking at dry
flour being the bud
going to raw oil refined distillate or
isolate
you can see the different levels here
there's a certain
end product that you're really looking
at trying to determine
that's what i want to produce well try
to pick a
cultivar try to pick a variety that is
known to produce a little bit higher
value
of that particular goal product in the
sense that the
whole growing process ideally you'll get
more
yield on your investment simply because
you'll have a greater amount of extract
in the end
this is where it comes in not looking at
producing a high quality visual looking
dry flower
looking at producing high quality
chemicals and components
within the plant