so if you're choosing to sort your
cannabis buds based on their size and
in density this debaco university video
is for you because we're going to go
into some of the details
with this process and give you some
hopeful helpful advice
[Music]
all right let's get into sorting chemist
buds based on size and
density so first off bud density
blood densities is essential because the
more dense basically the more yield here
we see a very dense
uh flattened flower here we see one is a
lot less density
more density simply means more target
plant material is produced and also the
denser buds has improved
visual appeal increasing the price
consumers are willing to pay
so even if these quote weighed the same
this would be one that would
drive a higher dollar value which should
be the goal of any grower
now we're maximizing density so genetics
do play a role so make a wise selection
at the very early part of the process
when growing keep the environment under
continual control and
document the conditions daily if you
want to have good records of your
growing area
provide the plants but specifically with
good light intensity
and the proper spectrum if you're
growing indoors growing outdoors
limited with the sun make sure that
you're trying to prune them and make
sure you're getting as much light
exposure to the bud regions as possible
this applies in both indoor and outdoor
and you want to have good
trimming and pruning style pruning style
the actual plant trimming of the actual
final buds
and do not harvest too early wait until
you get definitely that level of
maturity
with your buds so you're able to get the
maximum cannabinoids and terpenes
and have a good visual on end product
so we're starting buds by their size
this can be automated which is advised
for larger scale operations
there's two main commercial options um
here both kind of
serve the same purpose the goal is to
take a collection of plant material
collection of plant material and sort
them into different containers or
categories
this one kind of does it with different
hole sizes and kind of
kind of move them around and just
section them out here we're looking
they're all kind of passed down this
area here and as it gets progressively
wider
the smaller buds will fall through here
and be sorted here and the larger buds
will make it further
down and be sorted down here so this
automation is a great way to speed up
this process
now what's the importance of sorting
when we go through this kind of process
well
bud size can directly correlate to price
on the extreme case
the popcorn or kind of the small buds
are classified as seconds or kind of b
grade with indoor production buds will
be more consistent on the plant from the
top to the bottom
with the top buds still being the
highest concentrations of cannabinoids
and terpenes
going to be very similar to those in the
lower end but definitely higher
with that greater light exposure and
there's other studies here on this
channel that will kind of go into some
more detail on that
for outdoor growing there tends to be
more variability among buds
based on the location on the plant
location within the field how it might
be shaded
other branches might be blocking it so
again keep that in mind but this is
able to take whether it has consistent
or inconsistent original starting
product maybe
it does allow it to be sorted so you
have a lot of
consistency in your packaging then it
leads us to the last point here would be
second cut flower in the sense that
often these are smaller sized buds
but if from an indoor grower the potency
will be very similar to the larger
typically more expensive buds this can
be advantaged for someone who wants to
try a new variety
but it's important to kind of sort that
kind of popcorn to the a grade
simply because it's what a lot of
consumers are looking for particularly
purchasing dry flour they want those
eight grade
second b grades you can still get some
value in those for sure
sometimes they are sent to make
pre-rolls or extraction in extreme cases
but you definitely want to select out
your a grade because ideally
the a grade quality is going to get you
an a grade price