okay this videos will cut the source and
sync relationship that plants have to go
through so a source being mainly leaves
the sync in this case being the
developing blackberry and how these
interrelate we look at plants so first
defining source ankles so our sore
portions of the plant that are producing
more energy particularly sugars than
they are consuming sinks our net
consumers of energy so here's our source
in this case a leaf young leaves can be
a sink acorns in this case can be a sink
our roots can be a sink and leaves our
main areas of source remember fully
mature leaves our source tissue the
young leaves can actually be a sink
themselves so they can be net consumers
of energy before they mature then they
can be net producers so looking again at
some sources these are typically green
areas going through the process of
converting light energy to sugars this
is an transport via the xylem these
carbohydrates are assimilated into
storage and they can go to roots shoots
and fruits and all other components
they're never entering the phloem that
can go up and down being transported to
where it's needed so that transportation
process here on carbohydrate transport
is through the process what we call
translocation this is the movement of
products of synthesis by phloem so just
put the picture of the Train here to get
the idea of moving products we need a
lot of products throughout the plant
so how translocation works well we have
our source leaf here produce some soup
sucrose companion cells are loading it
into the phloem within our sieve tube
elements and then that is transported
and moving towards a sink cell where
these companion cells are picking up
those sucrose molecules and adding them
to the sink cell we also notice when we
increase our concentration of sugar
water will move across and we decrease
our concentration of sugar water will
move back to this eylem the basic
equation for the entire post synthetic
process can reckon spend a lot of time
on that now that's coming up in future
and other videos you'd like to watch
those photosynthesis is carbon dioxide
plus water
utilizing light energy to form sugar and
oxygen now the reason why it's six co2
plus 602 and light producing a c6 h-12
o-6
sugar molecule plus six oxygens is this
balances the equation so there's the
same number of carbons hydrogen's and
oxygens on this side as there are on
this side this is why the coefficients
are necessary here who did this six
carbon complex sugar the process of
emitting the light energy to produce
chemical energy in this case sugar and
that's what we're seeing here it is
refined sugars cubes but you kind of get
the idea of what's going on here most of
the system generals that capture of
light energy we notice that that can go
through and form starch or sugar storage
organs and sense of our tubers I can be
used for starch which is sugar storage
in an organ on a tomato in this case so
we can see there's a lot of things going
on here and this how this source sync
relationship plays into the plant it's
not just going from one area to another
on there's a lot of factors in play here
so in general sucrose is typically used
for a long distance transport
long-distance transport of carbohydrates
it's mainly in the phloem it's been in
the form of sucrose sucrose is a
disaccharide of glucose and fructose
being linked together in long distance
transport a source cell all the way to
some sort of sink cell so the strength
of sugar traction the ability of an
organ to unload sugar from the phloem
determines the sinks strength so here's
a sig cell the root sync strength is how
aggressive is that going to be at
grabbing sugars and pulling them from
the phloem in this case different
sources are six different cells I should
say or sinks and the sink strength
refers to the ability or the
aggressiveness of grabbing those sugars
and pulling them towards themselves
meristems are the say of actually
dividing cells from a new tissue and
typically found in the growing tips of
roots and shoots
there's apical and lateral meristems
they should look familiar from some of
the future or some of the previous
videos and repeats discussing the noun
into the future and these are examples
of beara stones
require a lot of energy so typically
sources of sink areas so cell division
drives the same strength cell division
will increase the sink size the source
sink relationship will affect the entire
plant you kind of show here with our
little output our big apple on a little
plant here so you have a lot of sink
strength and that's gonna drive a lot of
the processes that the plant goes
through so again remember our xylem and
phloem there are vascular connections I
was moving water from the roots to the
shoots then phloem is moving mainly
carbohydrates up and down in close
proximity to contain themselves the
phloem the vascular tissue is transport
sugars to other medibot and other
metabolic products it can move materials
up and down the plant so again as we see
here our sieve tube elements and our
companion cells these are all involved
in the phloem in the movement of
carbohydrates and other metabolic
products the pressure flow model well
sugar enters the phloem via active
transport were actively adding their
sucrose molecules as the sugar
concentration increases water will enter
the sip tube cells from the xylem by
osmosis then the pressure will increase
inside this area and push the sugars
through the phloem and sugar will move
from the phloem to a sink by the process
of active transport you notice now that
we're removing our sugar the waters
moving back across
remember our xylem contains more than
just water there's also minerals in the
xylem and that's what is helping drive
the water movement through the process
of osmosis
so phloem loading this this is the
process where sugars enter the phloem at
a source point so in some plant sugar
moves on sugar producing cells into
companion cells in the sieve tube
elements via plasmodesmata where these
are holes in the actual cell wall you
see that here companion cell moving it
through the plasma is another so called
sim classic phloem load this is
partially apple plastic phloem loading
in some plants this is her sugar moves
from sugar producing cells in the into
the apple class
ATP is required we see that right here
for an active transport into the
companions
sugar moves into this sieve-tube cell
elements via transporter proteins via
the plasmodesmata so here we're having
those energy required that ATP being
broke down ADP to allow this to occur so
both are accomplishing the same end
result where we're getting our sugars
into the flow now certain insects will
take advantage of this Athens in
particular and a Taurus
for using a stylet which is this kind of
long piercing mouth part as we see here
to tap into the phloem the if it cuts
into the phloem a lot and SAP to easily
be consumed they're trying to consume
the sugars that are within the plant so
that's why they're specific they have
mouth parts that penetrate the phloem
and then what's call of insects they are
flown with feeders just referring back
remember sugars carbohydrates
carbohydrates or saccharides there are
many different types of sugars sucrose
is mostly used in the transport of
implants sucrose is formed when monomer
of glucose and monomer approaches are
joined together through the process of
dehydration synthesis dehydration is the
removal of water we see a hydroxide
group and hydrogen ion o H and H come
together to form water
dehydration that's losing the water
molecule and creating this bond here and
that's what's allowing these two
monomers to be joined together to form
sucrose which is a disaccharide lastly I
think this image is pretty interesting
or noticing that cell growth is a
consequence of sugar import from the
common simulate pool according to the
source sync concept so what does this
mean well cell growth is a consequence
of the sugar import so we have this
radiograph here what this image shows is
labeled sugar molecules so a
concentration two and a half hours after
tracer molecules were fed to older
leaves in the plant so we went to
initially the scientists added on sugar
molecules to older leaves red areas
indicate an area of high concentration
so you see that here the red color
indicates high level of beta particles
in those sugars in the radio activity
again this doesn't mean that all plants
are radioactive this is
an example of scientists labeling
certain sugar molecules to be able to
help trace them and see where they end
up the key your take-home message here
is that the concentration of in young
leaves the image indicates that these
are fast-growing young leaves drew the
radioactive sugars from the older leaves
so this indicates young leaves are
actually a sink cell there are pulling
sugars from the older leaves so just
because it's elite does it mean it's
always a source cell young leaves into
developing they're actually consuming
more sugars than they're initially
producing ultimately when these beech
maturity they will produce more and
become a source for the plant to allow
it to be able to store it in different
sink cells and those could be tubers
those could be fruits or other regions
in the plant but initially young leaves
are actually a sink before they fully
developed