so you want to add carbon dioxide to
your grow space
well there's a variety of sources of
that carbon monoxide that you can add
in here on debacle university i'll
provide you with some quick advantages
and disadvantages of each and then go
into more detail
on each of the sources described here in
other videos that can be found
on this channel
[Music]
all right let's get into sources of
carbon dioxide for cannabis plant
production
now just keep in mind that carbon
dioxide is a non-flammable colorless
odorless gas
it can be in a solid or liquid state or
gas estate
used across various industries including
welding food beverages manufacturing
as well as water treatment that's very
commonly found
now one of the options when we're
looking at enrichment we have compressed
bottles
the advantage of utilizing compressed
bottles are typically easy to get
they're easy to find at most grow shops
as well as many air suppliers
and they're also a pure form of carbon
dioxide meaning
just carbon dioxide is purified and
compressed in the bottle
you're not getting any sort of
by-products the disadvantage of using a
compressed bottle though
is the transport and or refilling of the
bottles can be a hassle especially as
you get to the larger
sizes so compressed bottles aren't
looking like something you want to
implement there is also a liquid carbon
dioxide to consider
now liquid carbon dioxide is a very
dense and pure form of carbon dioxide
it's one of the
densest purest forms it's a great great
source in that regards
however the disadvantage is it's
difficult to get and can require special
holding equipment
and refrigeration on site so typically
liquid carbon dioxide is
reserved for larger operations where
they need the density of carbon dioxide
they don't want to store they want to
have limited storage areas but there are
additional equipments that that is
required
now there's propane as a carbon dioxide
source now utilizing propane this can
also provide heat as a source when it's
burned it's going to give you some heat
and additionally enrich your area with
carbon dioxide
however the disadvantages is that this
will also increase humidity
and also potential byproducts of other
gases
also consider the questions what if heat
is not needed in your grow space
particularly in the summer
and what if the heat is only needed at
night or the lights off
period carbon dioxide can only
efficiently be utilized by plants during
the
lights on uh period or during the when
sunlight exposure occurs
so if you're adding carbon dioxide or
burning propane as heat then you're
adding carbon dioxide you are
but the plants really are not able to
take advantage of it
which can also cause considerations if
you're needing uh to supplement
carboxylate in the summer months
where heat is not needed and lastly
there are biological carbon dioxide
generation sources as well
the advantage is it's a passive form of
carbon carbon dioxide
generation tends to be pretty easy
uh the disadvantages though is it's an
incandescent inconsistent production
meaning these are biologically generated
so they're biological systems that need
to be
fed and they might produce more one day
and less another day and also
temperature dependent
it's also a not regulated form of carbon
dioxide meaning you could get a lot in
one area
and not a lot the next day so keep these
in mind
if you want to learn more about any of
them check out other videos on this
channel where you can learn more about
the details
to determine the best source of carbon
dioxide for your growing operation