so when we're irrigating our crops we
want to be considering what source of
water we're gonna utilize then some of
the common ones are rain water pond
water city or tap water in well water to
cover each of these sources briefly just
to give you some background on them so
first off rain water can be easily
collected by simply having a rain barrel
or collecting it off a roof
sadly this can be an unreliable source
and most of the time when it rains a lot
especially for outdoor operations you
don't need to irrigate a lot then when
it doesn't rain you don't have a lot of
water reserves and your plants need
irrigation so sometimes you can kind of
be working against yourself there also
it's not necessary this is easiest
setting up a rain barrel there's
actually 12 states that regulate the
collection of rainwater that I've listed
here so I've chosen to highlight
Colorado here because it is unique
I put the source right down here at the
bottom in 2009 Colorado where the
legislation session lasts a bill that
allows limited rainwater collection for
properties supplied by a well even then
that residents must apply for a permit
to do so this is why I just looked to
know that it's an illegal ought to
collect rainwater but sometimes in
certain states there are certain
processes to follow and that is simply
hooking up some pipes to it a rooftop
gutter system here and collecting it
let's go into pond water so pond water
now the pond water can be variable we're
looking at kind of more of a natural
surroundings to this pond and here a
little bit more of an urban setup
caution should be used when using this
type of water because especially in the
urban type setup you're looking at could
contain pesticides from weed weed
management in the local area also
sometimes pesticides or herbicides can
be added to the water itself to help
reduce some unwanted plant growth
it should be filtered regardless of what
type or physical and microbial
contaminants there should be a
mechanical filter that removes
particulate and that's just could be
sand could be mud could be just floating
debris and also it's recommend a UV
light pond filters used because it can
sterilize the water but this can have
some restriction on the flow rates so
while this wouldn't be a very efficient
method shown here this gives you an idea
of water is basically passed by a UV
light making
sterilize it and only the chance of
contaminating your plants in your soil
or your container growing media with
naturally occurring microbes that might
be present in pond water tap or city
water actual contents depend on the
physical location even town to town this
can relate to what they're adding to
that to help reduce you know potentially
eliminate hopefully the microbes that
would be growing in the water so this
could be chlorine Clarett amide there's
a whole bunch of different types of
basically sterilants that are used
that's why it can vary from town to town
likely contains some form of chlorine
and salts get your water tested or call
your water Trent for current report
they're very good about reporting and
providing it with that information it's
advised to check the tap water during
the year to see if changes occur and
this could be areas if there's a lot of
tourists that come in higher demands on
water or summertime versus winter it's
good to just get an idea to see if there
are changes that do occur over the year
well water all of its e-minor should be
applied to tap water there's a
likelihood of greater changes is
possible with low water coming
classified as hard water and it contains
a lot of minerals temperatures and other
factors it can be a cold shock to plants
and may need to be heated before it's
applied this is a particular importance
for very deep wells also with all wells
you should watch the flow rate and the
well replenish rate how quick will that
well replenish the water that's in it
and I say well typically they're not
open wells like this so you have ten of
the Bukit on the rope they're typically
drilled and this is one that was
recently drilled in the area here you
can see the sand around it with their
drill down and just be mindful to not
run your well dry be mindful of the flow
rate that it can support and also the
rate you can replenish itself so that
you're able to keep that well and as a
reliable water source