on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over spectrum comparisons
and photon efficacy for cannabis
production
so we're going to try to give you some
comparisons between
different spectrum produced by common
light sources
all right let's get into spectrum
comparisons and if we look just at the
title slide here
looking at our regular day dawn midday
and dusk we can see how
the overall wavelengths and intensities
can change
throughout just a single day but here
we're going to focus a little bit
something a little more consistent
indoor lighting so first off i have a
good reference article here if you're
interested in want some more information
definitely recommend you check this out
provided with some links and the proper
citations here
so you can go through and read the
details if you want for yourself
i'm going to provide a summary so we're
looking at photon
efficacy here note that photon efficacy
of hps lights is about 1.7 to allow you
for that
general comparison um here to the
numbers provided compare that to the red
led chips which are 2.6
times the efficiency so if we look our
led kind of red here at 4.5
and hbs lights are only about 1.7 for
that comparison
the conversion of efficiency of photons
efficacy depends on spectral
distribution
i want to be aware of exactly what
wavelengths are being produced by that
particular
light source so plant action spectrum
so plant action spectra associated with
the primary classes
of photosynthesis photosensitive
molecules in plants
action spectrum for the cryptochromes
are not yet well established
so just be aware we have chlorophyll a
and chlorophyll b i think most people
are probably familiar with at least
hearing those terms
and we could see here we can have a very
strong absorbance down
in that bluish kind of wavelength and
then another peak over here where we're
getting closer to that orange or red
areas there and these are measured in
wavelengths which we'll see in
future slides here on this presentation
so first off we're talking about light
in general i thought this picture was
kind of interesting just to show light
pollution on a soybean crop so if we're
looking at the kind of soybean field
here
we're seeing a roadway we're noticing
these like dark green kind of like
little
almost like bubble areas and we'll
notice those correlate
with street lights so this shows a great
visual of how light pollution or light
can
impact plants here and we see this again
on a soybean field
with just the street light's impact on
some of the green coloration we see
in this crop so looking at metal halides
to hps
flip for cannabis some people will grow
in a metal halide at the veg and then
flip over
when they go to the flowering stage go
to high pressure sodiums
and that's usually a metal halide for 18
hour days and high pressure sodium flour
for 12 hours
metal halides have about 30 blue to keep
plants short with tight internodes
hps only has about four percent blue but
is still a very efficient light because
of the red orange spectrum it produces
green photons are important for visual
disease diagnosis
and as a source of comparison sunlight
does have about 30
blue light in it as well so as i
mentioned those kind of pictures
uh graphs that we'll see here here we're
looking at a
sunlight spectrum just to kind of give
you an idea looking at mainly that par
range uvb uva far red
and kind of the roy g biv spectrum here
for light frequency produced
and it's a one to thirty uvba ratio
for uh sunlight spectrum if we go to
high pressure sodium spectrum we're
noticing just if we go back and forth
for just a couple seconds sunlight
here's high pressure sodium back and
forth we're seeing a massive change here
in the amount of light frequency that's
produced by the high pressure sodium
spectrum
then we also have some grow light
spectrum these are white leds producing
3500 kelvin again to give you this that
comparison
of what what spectrum is being produced
by some of these lights
but you should always be checking with
your specific light
bulb or manufacturer should be able to
provide you with one of these
spectrum graphs so also in addition
we if you're not aware of there's
something called the dlc which is the
design
light consortium for light efficiency
it's an independent company that lists
many lights from different manufacturers
and published
test results for the efficiencies of
lights 2.5
and greater micro moles per joule is
considered to be a very efficient light
and this is kind of a non-profit
organization that can help kind of
provide you with some more
details and information potentially
about lights that you might be
considering purchasing
so you make the best selection for your
grow area
and again as always if you want to learn
more i've provided you with some great
names here to go through
take a look special thanks to them in
the research of course that they've done
to contribute to the information
presented here
and research all over so you can
hopefully become an
informed consumer when you're looking at
purchasing lights