here I'm going to provide just a brief
overview of four different types of
speciation this is kind of the quick
general overview good way to kind of go
back and review hello Patrick Perry
Patrick parapatric and sympatric
speciation so we have the quick easy
definitions here and will provide you
with some visuals to help allow you to
understand these a little bit better
which will help you describe certain
situations so so it's the first one
allopatric speciation this is a result
of a geographic isolation or a
geographic barrier that results in
complete reproductive isolation and
creates no gene flow so we have this
very predominant physical structure it
could be a geographical isolation to be
a mountain range for example causing
reproductive isolation causing different
species in this case because of no gene
flow crossing between these we have the
green and blue species developing
completely separate from one another
with no gene flow interacting between
those two then we have the parapatric
speciation this is a geographic
isolation results in reproductive
isolation of only peripheral populations
which does result in isolated gene flow
so here we have a subset of this
population that then kind of separated
out and we see that's developing its own
with isolated gene flow to the original
population this geographic isolation
occurs only for these kind of peripheral
populations it's kind of broke off and
here we see development the blue and the
green species moving on we have a
parapatric speciation which is a result
of geographic isolation resulting in
partial reproductive isolation which
results in limited gene flow so we see
the original population streaming are
crossed kind of combination with the
ingredient almost developing we see a
favoritism here for the blue jeans and
here for the green and we had this
limited gene flows to result in our two
different species here the blue and the
green lastly here we have sympatric
speciation which is junik overlap
results
and no reproductive isolation which does
result in gene flow
so we have our original population we
have our population within a population
as a result gene flow is easily able to
happen with no reproductive isolation so
we can get the development of these
species but this population originated
within the original and there is gene
flow because there is overlap that is
occurring between these two different
species well that gives you just a quick
general rundown of speciation and allow
you to explain what may occur in certain
situations