okay while you think there may only be
one or a few general types of stems it's
a couple specialized structures that are
relate to stems I'm going to run through
five different specialized stem
structures and give you some indication
on how they're different and where you
may have seen them before so starting
with the first one our specialized
temperature something called rhizomes
these are horizontal stems that grow
below the surface of the soil we see
that here we're seeing that roots are
coming off them and this structure right
here is called a rhizome these are
horizontal stems and they're growing
below the soil surface so you might
assume one area here hops is a plant
that does this then all of a sudden we
see another plant that pops up over here
well those two might be connected by a
rhizome witnesses contributes to how
certain plants can spread very quickly
through an area another form of
specialized stems runners and stolons
there's some other items but they grow
above ground if you ever been strawberry
picking can you look at one plant very
closely you kind of don't get distracted
by all the wonderful strawberries that
may be in the area you'll know sir
actually it looks like they're like
connected also clipped with a wire well
these are similar to our rhizomes these
stolons
are above-ground stems that link these
plants together may help allow
strawberry plants to kind of spread and
grow out so next time your strawberry
picking you look at the strawberry yes
that's great but you can also look and
find the wonders of the stolons and
point them out and show the connections
between certain plants another type of
specialized stem is tubers they swell in
size from the accumulation of food pry
the most notable example here would be
potatoes this is what potato plants look
like above-ground you've never seen them
before or recognize them we're referring
to the tubers which are these swollen
areas that accumulate food located below
ground so again this shows the potato
plant above ground and these are the
tubers below ground so all your french
fries and potato chips come from these
specialized stems which is the plant
accumulating food below the soil surface
we see here they're held up and then in
this Hill is where all the potatoes
ideally will be developing and accusing
the sugars the cute
from the leaves through the
photosynthetic process another type of
specialized stem is bulbs there's small
stem located at the base surrounded by
fleshy leaves so if you ever had to
plant bulbs you might have to plant them
at various depths based on what point it
is and you'll notice here our daffodils
are very commonly seen in the springtime
same thing with our crocuses both of
these are very early plants and they
grow in the early spring when there's
not a lot of kind of energy or
competition and because they have this
kind of stored area this kind of energy
stored in the bulb region they
specialized them they're able to grow
early and take advantage of some of the
Sun before some of the larger trees make
shade out in the area
crocuses my people with some of the
first things you see a lot of times they
made Germany even before a recent
snowstorm getting closer to springtime
and daffodils are these large yellow
flowers typically in a clump here which
you may see last type is called a quorum
and on a quick look they look very
similar to bulbs but they contain almost
all stem tissue so again go back for a
second just for that source of
comparison it's your small stems looking
at a basis run by fleshy leaves so kind
of all these leaves located here if we
take the cross section the bulbs do that
same cross section with a quorum we
noticed in this instance there's some of
the bulbs on the exterior look but they
contain almost all Staten tissue and if
you ever eaten garlic or familiar with
garlic garlic is a prime example of a
quorum and again if you take the cross
section it's all just about all stem
tissue here it looks like on the outside
hopefully this is helpful and going over
some of the specialized stems that do
exist