in this short video I'm going to cover
three specialized plant epidermal cells
remember epidermal cells referring to on
the exterior or outside portion of the
plant it'll help it for protection each
of these cells have very specialized
functions the first specialized
epidermal cell are called guard cells
these are paired cells that protect the
open and called the stomata so as we saw
in a previous video we saw the stomata
opening and closing well that's because
guard cells help regulate the passage of
oxygen carbon dioxide and water vapor
across the epidermis remembered while
these are holes technically they're
pores because they're regulated these
openings called stomata allow the plant
to take up carbon dioxide and release
oxygen and water vapor the column the
colorized scanning electron micrograph
shows the close to amount of a dicot in
each dama is flanked by two guard cells
when they swell it helps it close and
they're allowed to open and this is
what's allowing these pores to be opened
the guard cells sit within the layer of
the epidermis you could see them right
here so are close to mount of here to
seal up the area here's the open stomata
you can see the guard cells located
right here when they swell up indicating
there's a lot of water they begin to
open and that is what allows things to
go through the air in the water vapor
and when the plant wants to condense or
conserve water they will close up so
those are the guard cells in addition to
guard cells another specialized
epidermal cells called trichomes these
are the outgrowth of the epidermis that
occur on the chute and give it the fuzzy
appearance tried to show some good
images here they play a role in
insulating and effect heat and water
balance so they can help reduce water
loss because we're just kind of creating
this more of a furry like fuzzy surface
and this is what they look like in a
kind of zoomed in look and they are
white and they are little protrusions
there these are two plants that have a
lot of trichomes and they kind of stand
out and very distinctive here and
they're outgrowth from the epidermis the
last type is called a root hairs so last
we talked about it we talked about the
mycorrhizae which is a fungus
associate with roots also root here's
these are small extensions that come
from the central root and they occur
below ground in the hill keep the root
in direct contact with soil particles
who hairs play an important role in
reabsorption by increasing the surface
area of the root now from the root we
can have mycorrhizae that binds to that
which is a beneficial symbiotic fungus
and that can further enhance water and
nutrient absorption now a short
description of the three specialized
epidermal cells in plants