this is going to be a quick overview of
the spinal cord basics keep in mind we
can't forget about how we label our
vertebrae such as cervical regions our
thoracic region our lumbar and our
pelvic because those same terms apply to
different regions in the spinal cord in
addition we have sensory or ascending
efferent pathways in blue here and those
are areas of the spinal cord that will
send a signal so we touch a hot beaker
that sense of heat and burning will go
is going to go through the sensory
pathway then our brain will process
information and savingly to remove our
hand from the very hot beaker and our
motor or decent and efferent pathways
indicated in red here shows where those
signals from the brain will pass through
the spinal cord continuing on with our
central nervous system looking
specifically again at the spinal cord
region well the spinal cord simply put
is a column of nerves from the brain to
the tailbone predicted by the vertebrae
of the spine it's responsible for the
conducting the impulses between the
brain and the rest of the body
there's impulses can come from a variety
of senses so can we hear from our skin
cater from a variety of our organs our
glands all these kind of feed into being
helping the body maintain homeostasis
and also having the body being able to
sense it's both external as well as its
internal environment and we see the
terms like t1 t2 that's referring to a
thoracic one thoracic to l1 refer to a
lumbar region what an interesting fact
about the nervous system in the spinal
cord that we talk about all these nerve
impulses moving they move very quickly
they actually travel at about 268 miles
per hours how quick these impulses are
being transferred so it's very quick
within the spinal cord there's two
regions there's gray matter and there's
white matter and the gray matter
indicated here by the yellowish region
is the neuron cell bodies located in the
centre the white matter and give it's
kind of steerage region here our axons
in dendrites on the outside you see here
this sectional organization of the
spinal
or also what a cross-section stain would
look like and we still see those
distinctive regions and all three of
these images much clearer and here even
in a cross-section that's been stained
you can clearly tell the difference
between gray and white matter