tobacco university video if you're
looking at using sprays to control
odors with cannabis plants this will
help you
ensure you're using it in the most
effective way possible
all right let's get into sprays for odor
control in cannabis production
so first off keep in mind that no matter
what spray or what product they're
really not
good stand alone absorbing gels and
sprays will only do so much to reduce
odors because these items mask the odor
more than eliminate it so that's an
important
point to keep in mind installing an
adequate ventilation system with a
carbon filter
is usually the preferred option sprays
and gels should only be used in addition
to other methods of odor control
and should really not be relied upon as
the sole source
of odor control especially as plants get
later in their growth stages
particularly the flowering stage
now you also want to keep the plants a
safe distance away from any sprays that
you might be applying because when using
odor absorbing gels or sprays
make sure plants are a safe distance
away
to not only reduce the chance of
physical damage but to reduce the risk
of unwanted scent absorption
that can negatively impact the taste or
smell of the buds
that you're looking at producing on your
cannabis plant
also where are you going to place these
sprays or gels is
important we want to look when using
absorbing gels they should be placed in
your ventilation ducting
so if you don't have a ventilation
system in place the use of sprays is a
quick kind of way to help control odors
is
definitely not going to be nearly as
effective this is where the odors are
concentrated within the ducting
and the risk of the plants is minimized
so it's really helping maximize the
effectiveness
of these particular odor absorbing gels
and also sprays
because you know that odor is going to
be carried through that ducting
by concentrating the gels and sprays in
that
area that'll help ensure the greatest
amount of contact with the odors you're
trying to reduce
while minimizing any potential risk to
your plants
which will help again get you the effect
that you want by minimizing any sort of
damage that might occur