in this debaco university video i'm
going to be looking at the sterile
seed bed technique which is a technique
used
to manage weeds on a large scale field
as we can see here in practice
all right let's get into the sterile
seed bed technique to manage weeds in a
cannabis field
so first off what does this technique
involve well this technique is based on
allowing weed seeds just below the soil
surface to germinate
and then are killed prior to planting
the cash crop while minimizing
soil disturbance weeds which germinate
and emerge before the crop is planted
are simply easier to manage while this
process can be overlooked it can be
very effective so what you're seeing
here is we have our seed bread
preparation we're allowing some certain
weed seeds then to kind of germinate we
kill those off
and then by not tilling the soil that
mixing everything up we're
keeping our weed seeds down below where
they can germinate and that's allowing
our
intended crop to go through and be the
one to grow
with less weed pressure now this basic
process
is cultivating the soil promotes weed
seed germination
of the total amount of weed seeds
present a small percentage
are non-dormant and able to germinate
really at any given time
this can quickly and be the fir these
can be the quick ones and the first ones
to emerge
most weeds only emerge from seeds in the
top kind of shallow layer
about top two and a half inches or so of
soil and most typically emerge only in
significant numbers from the top
one inch of soil cereal seed bed
technique works by targeting weed seeds
in this
shallow layer reason why seeds can
germinate in this shallow area
is some of them are actually have
photoreceptors they're actually light
sensitive
so they know if they're in that top inch
they're getting some sunlight exposure
that's going to signal them to germinate
they're down below that where it's
completely dark all the time they're
going to remain dormant
if you go through and till them up well
then it will start to emerge
so how are the weeds killed
well ideally practices that minimize
soil disturbance because deep tilling
the weeds
will not only bring up more weed seeds
to the surface and essentially go
against the basis for this technique
examples include often preferred will be
herbicide application
a weed flamer which can be very
effective shallow rotary cultivation or
simply a hoe
so we can see all of these methods can
all be incorporated
as part of the sterile seed bed small
manual operation
a loop or sterpo can be great larger
scale we can see these utilized
herbicides might be possible and also
flame leaders can also be a possible
technique utilized again with caution
so why not use this technique after
talking about all the good things about
it
well while this technique can be
effective if you're have the following
conditions the weed control percentage
may not be as high as you would like
the weeds are lengthy emergent periods
they germinate over a long period of
time if the soil conditions such as
moisture and temperature impacting weed
emergence particularly dry conditions
may not allow for weeds
to germinate as an example unable to
implement weed control when crop is
growing as this can restrict multiple
weed germination periods
and also control so if you have these
particular situations this may not be
the best method
so again want to caution you to just
commit to this if you look at these
conditions they're very common in your
area
may not be the best method timing the
state the
sterile seed bed technique so again
timing is kind of uh important with this
method
the stale seabed technique can be
initiated several days
weeks or months prior to seeding or
transplanting the crop
simply put the goal is to kind of let
those
weeds germinate that are in the surface
kind of kill those weeds off let a
couple more germinate kills weeds off
without doing a massive disturbance and
the further ahead you can do this ahead
of the crop
the more likely you are to germinate the
weed seeds and remove those
to give your chosen crop a little bit of
a head start before it starts shading
out hopefully the soil there
so this gives you just a little
background here of the sterile seabed
technique