in this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at stemophilium gray
leaf spot in tomatoes in great detail
not only through images as we can see
here we're actually going to go into a
high tunnel here from the grower see
what they're experiencing also go on the
microscopic levels you can see what this
disease actually looks like under the
microscope and lastly some new
scientific research looking at the
genetics and how we may be able to breed
resistant varieties going forward
[Music]
all right so let's look at stemophilium
great leaf spot in tomatoes here so as i
said multiple views we're going to look
at description of the disease actual
images and video of a known case
comparison to a common look-alike a
microscopic view as well as a genetic
investigation regarding the virulence
factor so let's start with just the
basics here you know what are we dealing
with here about stemophilium well while
it may seem like a new problem gray leaf
tomato was first reported actually way
back in 1930. there are four different
type of helium species here all provided
here we're going to kind of cover them
in more of a general case here
what does cause then is there is high
humidity or free water on leaf surfaces
that's what's required for the spore
germination as well as infection
spots on leaves are small light brown
and somewhat circular to irregular in
shape some larger spots can be seen that
are cracked symptoms do start to appear
within two to five days of infection as
you get an idea of the rate of spread
now the dispersal of this particular
fungal pathogen is via air currents or
wind also splashing of water it can also
be seed borne and it also survives on
crop debris as a saprophyte so you want
to make sure you're cleaning your fields
and removing those of any cases that you
think you might have had
this is kind of a zoomed in version here
of what the different leaves kind of
look like and we have the upper portion
and then that same leaf i turned around
and you can see the under portion of
that same leaf and what you're kind of
not seeing here is a lot of yellow
haloing keep that in mind seeing this
brown coloration and almost the centers
are tan
so that tan kind of coloration in the
center with that darker brown region
can be an indication that you may have a
case of stemophilium
now here's just another look here
showing a little bit more of advanced
symptoms again upper and lower leaf
surface
this more advanced progression is
evident by this large kind of browning
area and the larger lesions located
under side of the leaf here so a little
different we just saw before those are
earlier symptoms these are a little bit
later stages see an idea of what it
might progress to if you're looking at
it on a leaf yourself
now full leaf view here
so just a little leaflets there the
images uh shown lower leaves here just
above the pruning point for this
particular grower they are exhibiting
more advanced advanced symptoms and we
can clearly see that evident um right
there and this where i was pruning the
lower leaves so you were just above
those and these are a little bit higher
up showing those early signs when you
want to actually catch it
now looking here if you do look at the
in the detailed view at the radius of
the petioles here this is when
inspecting these areas closely look for
potentially small rectangular legion
these can be difficult to find but
something else to be aware of when
you're looking at the leaf you can see
that they're here
and there's clearly an evident of one
right there again not widespread but
just something else to look for when
you're doing that field diagnosis
now here i'm going to go through a high
tunnel video now it is this is recorded
and uploaded in 4k so i would recommend
that you do pause the video if you need
to and i'm kind of bring up that hd so
you can see the details this was this
case was officially lab confirmed case
of stemophilium the first symptoms did
occur around mid-july which is about
four weeks prior about a month prior to
the video being taken at this point it
does typically start in the older leaves
and works its way up the plant and
different varieties will have different
levels of severity so hopefully like the
quick little video here of the high
tunnel we get to hear from the actual
grower
all right so here we are in the high
tunnel we're going to take a look at
this demophelium now what we really can
see is that browning of the tomato leaf
here and we notice that there's the
small browning area but also the larger
browning area notice how there's no
yellowing or haloing effect of that
yellow around any of those spots now as
you look our way up the plant we'll
notice that the upper portions tend to
be a normal green coloration with no
spotting and we notice those spottings
are more prevalent on the lower ends of
those leafs now we're noticing here
again a lower look we know the bottom
branches have all been pruned out and
removed so keep that in mind we're
looking at that distinctive brown
coloration and that kind of tan center
with no yellow hailing is the key part
here to the visual indication that you
might have a stemothelium
that browning again as as far as goes
this doesn't really form circles it
tends to form more of a irregular
pattern looking at the upper portion of
the leaf a little bit more advanced
symptoms there as i flip the leaf over
you can see the under side of the leaf
as well there some of those are very
advanced cases others are just starting
another last look here
showing you kind of that early starting
again this plant was officially
diagnosed so this is a sample was taken
to the lab brought here back now we're
able to look and identify this is
exactly the cause this is the early
stages of it so this would be when it
would be important to go through and
identify it or have a reason of concern
to bring a sample to the lab yourself
now we can see those browning again that
can expand out and cover a portion of
the leaf but we'll really just have that
browning to tanning so let's now go to
the grower and hear what they have to
say i noticed there was spotting
um
throughout the plants i had noticed some
i thought was botrytis as well it was
all looked like alternary but sprinkled
throughout the plants and i think it's
botrytis never seen that before but the
spotting was throughout the plants
um some varieties it this is there and
it doesn't seem to have any effect on
yields or plant health in some varieties
it was almost like septoria would work
its way up the plant you're looking at
it right now mar noir which is a high
loom from johnny's
uh it's uh i i'm doing it because it's
leaf mold resistant because we had awful
leaf mold last year
so if you liked that little grower
interview there where they got to
explain what they were seeing now do
keep in mind that fact sheets tend to
report that cherry and grape tomatoes
are more susceptible than other types
but based on the observation here we saw
it did that show on i did show on all
the cherry varieties so keep that in
mind but it did not really seem to have
much negative impacts in regard to
overall plant performance in the
all-important yield does most commonly
occur or at least is first seen in high
tunnels with higher temperatures and
humidity being favorable for the disease
development
now we also heard in uh the kind of
grower talk there uh that they thought
it initially looked like septoria so
this is kind of like a look-alike to
that symmetrium is often mistaken for
the septoria leaf spot listen early on
keep in mind that simofilian this leaf
right here has more irregular lesions
with brown margins and tan centers the
leaves tend to remain green in areas
that are unaffected and in contrast that
to septoria this tends to be more
circular spots with in the inner circle
a lighter shade of brown in addition the
leaf will typically yellow there so a
little comparison there between a common
look-alike
now when you look at under the
microscope if you are fortunate to be
able to do that we have the canadian
here on the left and the canadian floors
here
on the right giving you the idea of the
size and kind of their structure
now the kinetic fours here are
specialized hyphal branches of some
fungi that produce canadia so this is
kind of the regular kind of spacing that
we see here and just gives you a really
good zoomed in and clear image of those
now the canadia they have two great
images here the one these are the
asexuals were producing on the connect
four of certain fungi they have the
surface fume we can see that nice
textured
surface view here of the canadian of
stemophilium
then the section view here we're looking
at kind of getting away from that
surface area what it looks like here on
this section of view so another
good visual identification if you are
fortunate to be able to look at this
under a microscope
and i promise going to get into some of
the genetics here so a recently
published research article here looks at
the nlp gene which does encode for
necrosis and ethylene-inducing peptide
one abbreviate np1 like proteins called
nlp
now when we're looking at all the data
here you might want to pause the video
i'm just going to cover over the
brief overview of this we have the wild
type here so that's kind of what it
would look like under normal conditions
and then we have gene knockouts and we
have over expressing here if we look at
the graphs here that kind of represent
the same leaves that were grown on the
plant and then removed only for the
image you see the wild type the gene
knockouts here showing less or smaller
lesion sizes than those that were up
regulated there looking at this
particular gene there
now what are the study findings again i
know they found out quite a bit so it's
great to look at some of the details
this was not particularly from the study
but just kind of highlight some of the
lesions they were talking about and
through their analysis of the nlp gene
which remember encodes for necrosis and
ethylene inducing peptide one like
proteins it was found that targeted
disruption of the nlp gene in
stemophilium significantly compromised
its virulence in tomato the nlp
suppressed the production of reactive
oxygen species abbreviate ros and tomato
leaves during stemophilum infection
expressing the fungal nlp in tomato
resulted in constitutive
transcription of immune response genes
and inhibited plant growth so this is a
great kind of target area when we're
looking at developing potential
resistant varieties as far as we got it
down to the actual gene that is defining
potentially the virulence factor for
this disease in tomato
and just kind of the last little bit
right here nlp might contribute to the
virulence of stemophilium by suppressing
the rms immediate immunity in tomatoes
large-scale functional genomic studies
are required to further dissect the
pathogenicity of stemithelium so this is
kind of an early indication but shows
promise as a way we might be able to
suppress this disease going forward but
at least now you've got a little bit of
an idea of what to look for in the field
as well as under the microscope
if you think you potentially have this
fungal disease on your tomatoes