okay continuing with the macromolecule
of lipids we're look specifically here
at steroids in cholesterol and how they
relate to the body so starting first
with steroids are composed of four rings
of carbon as we see them labeled here a
B C and D examples are cholesterol found
in most animal cell membranes and female
and male sex hormones are also fall into
the category of steroids which is one of
the three forms of lipids keep in mind
the other two our fats and phospholipids
so looking specifically at cluster all
here it's a fatty substance found only
in animal foods it's also produced by
our bodies small amounts are needed by
the body for essential functions so we
want to think that cholesterol is
entirely a bad thing the small nuts are
still needed by the body where the issue
comes in is where we have excessive
amounts of cholesterol and it can form
this fatty plaque which sticks to the
inside of our arteries and this can
cause heart disease so we need our red
blood cells to easily flow through our
veins and our arteries here we have this
build with these plaques now think about
if we have blood flow going through here
everything that's well inside however if
we restrict it down to here you can have
some serious issues so we get heart
attacks where's heart disease by even
extreme cases death can occur
now cholesterol we have HDL which is
considered good cholesterol and LDL tis
considered bad cholesterol so LDL stands
for low density lipoproteins his carries
cholesterol around in the blood and it
confirmed those plaques they talked
about in your arteries as a result that
can increase the risk for heart disease
so negative things with the LDL pathway
here
HDL so considered the good cholesterol
so these are the high density
lipoproteins in these carry cholesterol
to the liver and also out of the body
for processing so the liver can process
it synthesized by the liver picks up
cluster on the tissues and can allow it
to be excreted from the body this helps
avoid plaques and heart disease so when
we talk about cholesterol the broad term
please realize if there's low density
and high density
while forms of cholesterol any
high-density consider the beneficial
ones for the body while the lower LDL
the low-density lipoproteins have
negative effects
now trick try glyceride level in the
blood is a fat that circulates the blood
it increases risk of heart disease it
looks like once if you melted butter
stick with four fists gallon of water
produce a milky kind of looking liquid
so these triglycerides have that kind of
milky look to them now having none of
them is not necessarily the goal under
150 milligrams per deciliter is the
normal or level of low concern
borderline high is 150 to 199 C high in
very high levels so having a certain
amount is in sidered normal but when we
start getting into higher numbers that's
where we may get concerned in the reason
why we typically have blood work done to
be able to assess of these levels now as
a result our normal blood levels of
total cholesterol sort of kind of
shooting for that under 200 borderline
is over over 200 to 239 and high risk is
over 240 and it's milligrams per
deciliter we can break down that
cholesterol instead of just that total
we can look at the high density and low
density in the triglyceride level so
remember the high densities are the
beneficial ones we want to see that
number
ideally 60 or above LDL want to be under
100 and triglycerides under 150 would be
the goal this is why we get blood work
done that reason why there might be
these ranges or these gold amounts is
we're trying to stay within that
accepted kind of average or normal
levels of distribution that isn't true
for everyone and they may be changing
some of these levels but it gives you
just an idea of that total cholesterol
under 200 but breaking it down further
into the different types of cholesterol
so hopefully get a better understanding
for the difference between these two now
risk factors occur low so if you do have
a family history of high low density
lipoproteins which is sorry negative
cluster
there can be increased by if you're
overweight and obesity your diet can
also impact that your sedentary
lifestyle your family tree or history
you're a cigarette smoker hypertension
diabetes type 2 can also contribute to
this especially the combination of these
factors can really increase the odds of
you having a cholesterol problem so if
you have a family history and a
sedentary lifestyle and an unhealthy
diet that can really help contribute to
developing this high cholesterol and
negative effects seen by the body
management or eating a healthy diet
exercising keeping weight in the normal
range hyper sensitive diabetics better
control don't smoke and get your
cholesterol checked at least once a year
if you have risk factors so just various
good practices in general in both diet
and in health that helps you be able to
manage if you are at risk for
cholesterol lastly exercise what we
considered exercise will can help boost
your HDL or good cholesterol this
reduces the risk of heart disease helps
control your weight and helps control
diabetes and hypertension and I say
exercise it doesn't just run up the
stairs this exercise for at least 30
minutes daily you can choose from a
variety of exercise it should help to
enjoy and you can keep it up so don't
pick something that you can have to do
try to incorporate 30 minutes some form
of exercise daily that you might enjoy
doing so for some people that's running
for some people that could be swimming
that could be jogging find something
that works for you this exercise here is
defined as 30 minutes of daily active
work