okay I'm Gor proper technique to streak
plate so yeah beautiful place that look
like this we're trying to isolate and/or
grow bacteria for example so a goal
plate streaking if done properly you'll
be able to take a small sample and
either multiply it or separated isolated
samples so here we're just looking at
multiplying it and you're looking at
trying to isolate individual colonies
and you look a little closer here you
can see these counties are definitely
different than these you might be at a
pic one of these and then go through and
multiply that on a separate plate so
that's the goals of plate streaking
required tools or a petri dish
agar the culture you're dealing with
inoculating loop and also a flame then
we're going to through in flaming the
not flitting loop here we're using a
Bunsen burner so it's important to keep
in mind that the top of that middle cone
is the hottest portion you want to be
way up here when you're sterilizing you
know want to be way down here that very
top portion of that center cone is the
best and hottest part when you're
looking at sterilizing your inoculating
loop transfer the culture when i
sterilize the loop as I showed in a
previous slide let it cool so you don't
want to just go directly from the hot
flames of the culture because you'll
burn and kill them all then after it
cools I'm gonna pick up the culture from
the stock plate spread the culture using
a zig zag pattern and only one portion
of the petri dishes you see here kind of
this back and forth motion well that's
gonna do is it's gonna allow through
friction cultures to be transferred to
the media on that petri dish then we can
get spreading that culture you know what
sterilized a loop a lot to cool in a
cooling that can't stress that enough
streak through the original area and
spread cultures using that same zig-zag
pattern on only one portion of the petri
dish repeat this process dragging
through for most recent streak as you
left off on what does that mean well
here was our initial Street well you can
see our next when we drag through that
initial one and there's exact pattern
again stopped reenact it we sorry we
sterilized the loop cleaned it put it
back down here went through that initial
streak and again back and forth back and
forth and this is kind of a way to help
ensure we're spraying that bacteria and
spreading it out well this is gonna be
gone into what's called
T Street which is kind of a formal term
for this it's a very common pattern used
in microbiology labs because it looks
like a tea you'll start here you'll
zigzag back and forth you'll end here
and then you'll go through and you'll
drag through that you'll kind of go
through another area we sterilize the
loop and do a third time so you could
see here's our initial we drag through
that another spreading and then a third
and if it comes out properly it'll look
like this and this is great milking it
isolating bacteria individual colonies
and this and then allows you to pick
those colonies and then transfer it and
multiply it on another plate at a later
date