you might be familiar with dna structure
being this double helix
we're going to get into a little bit
more detail of just explaining the
structure
or what this is actually what are some
of the components that give dna
this double helical structure so
starting with the discovery of the
structure well
dna specifically is made of nucleotides
each nucleotide has a five carbon sugar
as we see here
there's a phosphate group which has a
negative charge and then an organic
base in this case based on nitrogen now
discovering the structure of dna there's
two main types or two classifications
of these nucleotides we have the large
bases the purines they're known as
adenine and guanine abbreviated with the
letter a and g
and we have acrymidines these are
smaller bases you notice these only have
one ring
and the purines have two the permians
only have one ring
there's cytosine and thymine
assuming we're talking about dna for rna
we've got to remember uracil is only
found
in rna and thymine is only found in dna
cysteine is found in both now what's
important to remember is that a purine
will always bind with a pyrimidine
and we're going to see exactly how that
occurs
so our purine binding with this
pyrimidine how does this look
well here's an adenine with a thymine a
binds with t they have two hydrogen
bonds
between them g and c will bind together
guanine and
cytosine have three hydrogen bonds so
they hold their structure just a little
bit stronger
than between a and t how i try to
remember it is g and c both have these
kind of
semi-circle curves to them so they would
fit together very nicely
they have a stronger bond because they
have three hydrogen bonds
versus adenine and thymine only having
two keep in mind this is about dna so if
you look back for a second
adenine binding with thymine well adding
would bind with uracil if we were
talking a double-stranded
rna which does occur now ribose compared
to deoxyribose so
look at the second carbon for h and oh
well this is kind of the area we're
looking at comparing
ribose with deoxyribose
so deoxys simply means without oxygen it
has just a hydrogen
ribose has an oh group now ribose stands
for
is responsible for rna which is
ribonucleic acid
deoxyribose dna deoxyribonucleic acid
so here with dna we see that kind of
second carbon there
deoxy without oxygen here's ribose with
oxygen we can see that oxygen
atom right here in the structure
now key observations about dna of
rosalind franklin uses x-ray diffraction
experiments to reveal that dna
had the shape of a coiled spring or a
helix this is kind of looking top
down at it you could see kind of that
coiled appearance we kind of put it in
that 3d rotation
but this image is kind of looking down
and this kind of gave the first
indication
that dna may be this spring look or this
kind of helical
shape watson and crick at the
al the accolades for kind of developing
the double helix official structure
though they based a lot of it off of
rosin franklin's
research so watson and crick kind of
came up with this idea and they used
kind of
finger toy models to kind of develop
this structure
that it was this helical shape this
double helix component
now two strands of dna are held together
by weak hydrogen bonds
and they have complementary pairs so as
you mentioned
appearing in a pyrimidine binding
together those are examples of
complementary base pairs a binds with t
and g binds with c those are
complements to one another we see that
here g binding with c and a binding with
t
two bonds and three hydrogen bonds now
when i talk about that
complement we're talking about the
original sequence and the other sequence
well it is not an identical sequence
it's a complement a binds with t
t binds with a a minor t g and c this is
what i mean by when i say a complement
e chain is complementary or a mirror
image of one another
so either can be used as a template when
a dna goes to
produce itself again to replicate that
process of
replication now working with dna there's
many different ways
scientists will work with dna just a
couple there's pcr plus chain reaction
amplification where
we're up regulating a small section of
dna to be used and run through
potentially a gel
and dna fingerprinting used to identify
particular individuals or specific
sequences
within a genome