welcome to this tobacco university video
if you're going to be looking at the cut
and stick method you need to choose what
substrate
you're going to stick your clone into in
here we're going to cover some of the
most common options
to help you make an educated decision
[Music]
all right let's get into substrate
options for the cut and stick method of
cannabis cloning
so first off options to use that i'll be
covering in this video
rockwell oasis and foam all kind of fall
into a similar category
sand as well as soilless media will be
covered
here so you can choose the best option
that fits
your growing situation so first off
let's talk about
oasis and this is a foam that's inert
and designed to provide
a soilless growing medium for plant
roots that's capable of supplying water
in a steady basis without affecting ph
or the growing
environment so those are all great
attributes or positive attributes to
oasis
may look like rockwell cubes but they
are made from a different material and
i'll talk about rockwell in the next
slide
there's also capillary action which is
kind of like like a sponge effect
through the foam that ensures a constant
supply of water the plant roots or seeds
if you're germinating seeds
that is advantageous for the propagation
of cannabis seeds
the lower density foam keeps the top of
the cubes sheet drier which reduces
algae growth and increases root zone
aeration i'm going to say reduces algae
growth if you over saturate it we can
see in the picture here
you still can get some algae growth but
definitely a reduced
level if you're keeping the moisture the
proper amount
so that rockwell that i had mentioned
sometimes referred to as
stonewool it's manufactured so it can be
made to fit specific applications
the material is inert and holds water
while still providing aeration to the
roots great benefits
also growers near complete control over
the dial in
feeding program which can help maximize
plant growth in production
for that grower that can feed the plant
exactly what it needs in the exact
quantities
they would talk about sand here briefly
it's uh it's possible but not really the
best option because it can have some
inconsistent moisture levels in the root
zone it can have little dry pockets or
some nice little wet pockets
it's also very heavy material if you're
looking at transporting or having on a
grow bench
it can also but it can be easily
acquired by growers and typically place
sand would be used
clean sterile not a lot of weeds other
advantages of using sand
then we get to lastly here soilless
media here
has similar general properties to soil
but is much more favorable for container
growing
it also does have some buffering
capacity unlike some of the ones that i
mentioned before
many different blends and manufacturers
to fit a wide variety of growing
situations i don't think there's just
one soilless media
and growers can buy once and be done
there's no need to mix or blend
or kind of do anything else on their own
they can open the bag
and immediately start using it so if
you're choosing the cut and stick method
hopefully this
provides you with some information on
selecting the best substrate
for it to fit your conditions