here on this tobacco university video
i'm going to talk about
sun grown cannabis
[Music]
if you're looking to learn more about
sun grow cannabis let's get into the
video lecture here
and really sun grown cannabis is really
just outdoor grown it's just a term
that's been given
to the outdoor grown cannabis that's
being produced
however sun grown is intended to imply
that there's a greater focus on
sustainable practices
somehow does not have an exact
definition though and it implies that
the sun is the main source of light or
energy
in not electrical power the idea behind
this term
is that the cannabis has been farmed
sustainably healthy
and in natural environments so that's
kind of what this term is meant to mean
even though there's not an exact current
definition for it
so why indoor grown in the first place
you know why why is there such a thing
as inter-grown cannabis and that's
because
indoor cultivation of cannabis is simply
due to the prohibition of cannabis
forcing growers
to grow in isolated private locations
that were typically
in an indoor area this caused
technologies to be developed to allow
for this type of propagation
which increase the dependency on
electricity
so an estimated three percent of
california's household
energy use is due simply to the indoor
cannabis cultivation
so again sun grown we're utilizing that
sun reducing the amount of energy needed
particularly for
lights they can also relate to heat as
well
cost of replicating the sun's energy so
in a national level in 2011 it was
estimated
that the energy consumption for indoor
cannabis consumes 1
of the national electric usage or about
billion per year according to the source
located right there
this equates to the production of carbon
emissions equal to that of three
million average u.s cars for every one
kilogram of indoor cannabis
produced so as a result this is what
caused the outdoor or sun-grown
movement to try to reduce some of this
production of energy
when we have the natural sun so
sometimes energy savings is that with
outdoor production this can nearly
eliminate the energy needed
for the growing of cannabis which
reduces the environmental impacts and
also the cost
to the grower so it's a great thing
where you can utilize natural resources
and when we have access to the sun well
that's a great savings there and
also environmentally friendly in
addition to savings growers
often use organic products local water
in that natural sunlight there so
reducing cost while hopefully
maintaining good yields
the sun grown advantage states that
potencies can be achieved when best
practices are used
and there's the source you can find in
the description this is supported by
this statement
that sun-grown diverges from outdoor
because it adheres to the use of organic
practices
and fertilizers so sun-grown chemist
also carries a myriad of environmental
benefits
due to avoiding the use of harsh and
artificial additives
so this is where that term sun grown is
being utilized
to distinguish it just from outdoor
growing even though the plants are grown
outdoors that sun-grown label is
implying that there's a more
focus by the grower to sustainable
practices
so what are the limitations of sun-grown
cannabis well with the variability of
the outdoor environment
these variable conditions can cause
stresses on the plant and reduce overall
production
equipment used to reduce some of these
impacts can reduce the overall carbon
footprint
efficiency of a growing operation
but often will help increase yields so
growers can be caught in that
kind of limbo where if they're going to
implement some
kind of practices that may help reduce
or buffer some of these stresses
they may be also adding more carbon
which is what they're trying to reduce
with the idea behind sun grown
in addition the seasonality of different
regions can also limit the amount of
growing cycles that can be completed
within a calendar
year so that can be limiting as well
now some grown anecdotal accounts so
people will say
well sun grown will produce increased
potency
improve plant health more aromas wider
terpene profiles but again these are
more anecdotal
and not necessarily confirmed on
scientific lab tests
the sun spectrum advantage this is one
thing that we can agree on is that there
has been lighting studies that
demonstrate that there's improved plant
performance with uv
light and also far red light wavelengths
as these do contribute to the
photosynthetic process and both of these
are products
produced naturally in the environment
while this may be
true other stresses that typically
reduce the overall quality of the buds
so while we're getting a better spectrum
that full kind of sun spectrum
there could be other stresses such as
temperature humidity rain events
fluctuations in inconsistencies and kind
of moderation of temperature as well
over time the duration of sun all those
can be kind of play into the
reduction in the overall quality of the
buds so lastly what's the goal
of for sun grown growers is that the
goal of those growers is selecting the
follow the practices of sun ground will
have less overall cost compared to
indoor production
however the final product quality may be
a battle and not often won compared to
indoor operations
so sun ground growers goals should be
focused on sustainable
practices and total biomass production
due to the reduced cost per plant
growers can often grow more plants
and win the biomass production game
compared to those indoor growers
however growing a product for final dry
flour will meet stiff competition
from the indoor market so growers should
be considering some form of extraction
for their product
if you're looking at growing the sun
ground route simply with the lack of
need of energy inputs for example for
lighting for the photosynthetic process
typically these growers if they have the
land can produce more biomass and
produce more plants
because of the reduced cost overall and
hopefully
make up the difference with extraction
simply by the increased number of plants
compared to those indoor growers which
need to have
maximum yield because they have a lot of
inputs and upfront costs
hopefully this provides you just a
little idea of what sun grown cannabis
is all about