so we have probably all heard someone
saying I need to go outside and get some
sunlight to get my vitamin D well we're
gonna kind of learn about some of the
science that's behind this I think some
people do this conception that vitamin D
is kind of reigns from the Sun it just
kind of sends down vitamin D to us is
that necessary 100% the case but learn
about what the Sun does give us and what
we do absorb here and how it does relate
to our vitamin D production so you can
see here our sunlight shining down and
all these people on the nice beach here
and many of them are getting exposed to
the Rays and making a vitamin D so what
is vitamin D actually d3 is the Pacific
vitamin there's foods high in vitamin D
so it's not the old sunlight is not the
only source of this it is an important
nutrient for maintaining a healthy
skeleton and it forms in an integral
part of bone metabolism calcium and
phosphorus homeostasis the most natural
way to get vitamin D is of course by
exposing your bare skin to sunlight
ultrafine be raised in particular I
stressed the point bare skin if you're
just outside and you're all kind of
bundled up and covered up with jackets
and hats and gloves you're not really
getting the vitamin D production 1000 IU
which is international units is what's
considered what people need as far as a
sufficient vitamin D ml see so we're
gonna relate to the Sun now remember the
Sun produces a visible light but also
we're going to be focusing here on the
ultraviolet lights
UVC UVB and UVA in particular so
starting with our UV rays and exposure
alfe remember UVC is filtered out
actually by the atmosphere so while the
Sun does produce UV see rays they're
filtered out well above our heads in the
stratosphere and into the ozone UVB rays
kind of this wavelength here considered
burning they enter the surface of the
epidermal layer and remember that's our
top layer of the skin UVA are considered
aging our UV wavelengths because they
penetrate deep into the dermis and the
sub-q days are hypodermis just well the
hypodermis kind of layer there or these
we cannot see this is our visible light
spectrum our ultraviolet here
in less than approximately 400
nanometers so that 200 ish to 400 is
nanometers in wavelength that we can't
say so which I mentioned those UV bytes
is you may have seen sunglasses and they
offer UV protection filters out 100% of
all UV a B and C and harmful blue light
up to 400 nanometers are polarized great
marketing but to filter out a hundred
percent of UVC rays it may sound great
there's one kind of major flaw with this
well the atmosphere actually filters out
the UVC rays so you're not really
exposed to those wavelengths
unless you're kind of taking your
sunglasses up above the ozone layer so
they are maybe maybe right there you
filtering out those UVC rays but you're
probably not being exposed to them in
the first place so just kind of watch
the marketing on certain things when you
understand the science I can kind of see
through some of the things that they are
offering up in their kind of
advertisements to you so skin type does
impact this ability to process vitamin D
some people you know burn easily they
start individuals here on the beach
summer probably soon as Ohio burn very
easily some people more likely to tan
and some you'll have an innate
protections so remember that this you
have more than just your skin type you
could also use sunscreen or simply
covering your skin can reduce UV light
exposure here in Saudi Arabia there's a
lot of Sun there's not a lot of shade
simply covering yourself can help reduce
your exposure and we're looking at the
UVA rays linked to tanning and here's
our visible light and then our UV being
related to vitamin D so how does the
skin type what's the point of going over
this even well this guy table below
shows different types of skin types
they're just labels can take one two
three four five and six and here's their
skin colors a little description and
some characteristics you're probably
most familiar to characteristics if you
know someone always burns never tans
they're kind of that skin type one their
very fair red or blond hair blue eyes
freckles and get into kind of type three
here sometimes a mild burn gradually
tans fair
in the eye or hair color very common
skin type and all the way here is six
black hair dark brown eyes may never
burn tans very easily it's important to
understand your skin type because you're
gonna see how that relates to your
amount of light exposure so you may have
heard I need ten minutes of sunlight and
I don't get my vitamin D well that's not
always the case it's kind of what's son
doing need an F is not ten minutes well
specific recommendations to reset one
thousand international units of vitamin
D or not that easy to figure out skin
types are different depending on the day
of year in place and time of day the
recommendations all vary so here's two
examples here both at noon one here in
Miami and one near in Boston so starting
this to Miami bright sunny Miami if you
have skin type three you'll probably
need about six minutes of exposure to
Sun in summer and 15 minutes in the
winter we're in the winter in the
northern hemisphere that kind of angle
of the sun's going to be a little less
in the winter or less intense that's how
you need a greater amount of time
however if your skin type of five still
in Miami at noon
probably need about 15 minutes in the
summer and thirty minutes in the winter
it's a little different there risk in
type five your skin type five again it's
at darker brown color versus fair skin
color for that skin type three if you're
in Boston now at noon someone with skin
type three will probably need about an
hour of exposure of the Sun in the
summer and someone in the summer with
skin type five oh I need about two hours
of exposure in the summer if you
anywhere I got these numbers from the
link is located here at the bottom now
during winter which is interesting about
Boston that's in winter months it's
really not possible for anyone to make
vitamin D in the Sun no matter the skin
type
the sunning those very reduced also
might be typically Boston is very cold
it might be covered up very hard to get
any vitamin D from the Sun this is why
it's important also to consume vitamin D
in the diet but this hopefully gives you
a little bit of the idea of it's not
just as easy as only ten minutes of Sun
depends on your skin type depends on
your location and also depends on the
season so hopefully this gets you a
greater under
four bodies and you're able to
manufacture and make vitamin D from the
Sun and realize it's not as easy as that
simple yeah ten minutes and I'm good