interested in learning more about super
cropping your cannabis plants
well this debacle university video will
give you some details
if you're looking at learning more about
this pruning method
let's get into super cropping pruning
method for cannabis production
so first off the quick and simple of it
well super cropping can be quick and
simple way to prune trained
plants to run if they run out of height
in the growing space
so it's kind of like when you're getting
that area getting too close to the area
the roof or the ceiling limited or
lights
you can super crop them it's a technique
where you're bending the stem close to a
90 degree angle that involves breaking
the internal fibers of the plant in the
process
but not breaking the entire top off this
can be done
in flour although it's usually performed
in the vegetative stage of growth
now when i say this kind of bending here
looks pretty aggressive and it is
but we're not breaking this it's not
completely falling off
this top part will continue to be able
to grow
now because of that because you don't
want to break that plant off you have to
learn the feel of the plant
squeezing pinching the stem where you
want to bend it
you will feel the plant's tissue start
to crush a little bit you can kind of
see right here
and then you want to lay the upper part
of the branch over at a right angle
and that goal is to crush but not break
the plant tissue
do not perform this on the top two to
three nodes as you want to be sure that
there is some plant material above
to crush the plant if you do it when
it's too young you won't have any of
those really kind of developed
fibers with thinner or woodier stems
that are harder to crush
but it is possible if they're um get a
little bit more of that technique and it
just comes with some feel
this stem eventually will form a callus
or kind of swell
at that bending point after a period of
time
now the advantages of super cropping why
would someone want to be implementing
this
well the most obvious reason is to keep
the plant canopy at the same
level especially in height limited
growing operations
the bending of the main stem will also
increase light exposure to lower buds
which can help increase the number of
larger buds the plant produces
all of these are good things and this is
where that timing comes in and learning
your particular strain
note that does not work well plants have
been aggressively lollipopped as well
so you can sometimes combine pruning
methods if you're super cropping
and lollipopping those two are really
kind of a little bit more of a conflict
to one another
however super cropping can help maximize
the horizontal space in the growing area
and fill in empty gaps
both between plants and also in the
within the same plant we talk about
having multiple tops
this is just one example here of a plant
that counted uh
59 different uh tops there from a single
plant
so again a great method to kind of
implement there we can just see how many
tops we can get
from one plant now when do you actually
super crop when's the kind of the
perfect timing
what's typically performed in early
flower or so
as this can increase the size of the bud
in the end branches
and also lower buds that will now be
getting greater light intensity
some do it in late veg some early flower
again it's not like a set
day the general recommendation though is
about three to
three to seven days a week before
growers decide to flip that photo period
to help allow plants sometimes to
recover from the stress of this method
before they go into flower
so some girls will do it right after
they float in the flower to give a
little time to adjust
other girls like to do it just before
they flip in the flower to allow some of
that longer
photo period to penetrate the canopy and
encourage those buds to start
forming now the basic process super
cropping is to make room for
more super cropping and some examples
here it can be done multiple times
this example here the branches bent that
has
no lower branches growing up so here we
have initial bending point here
what does that allow when we take that
wrench and bend it this way now
this makes room now for this branch now
be bent going this way to fill in that
empty space
this allows for a different branch that
does not have lower branches to be moved
into this
area and this is how you can really
maximize production
looking at your plant and kind of like
okay if i take this one i kind of bend
this one outward going this way now
well that gives me an empty space here
that maybe i take when it's over here
and kind of bend it that way
you're starting to maximize that canopy
from still a single plant
particularly important if you're ceiling
height limited or also if you're plant
number
limited now what's happening when you're
super cropping you know there's a plant
hormone shift that's occurring
and the bending of the plant does not
remove the apical portion we still see
that here
of the plant but it does increase the
light intensity to the
inner and also the lower leaves this can
help induce further development of these
lower portions of the plant
without this pruning without this the
pruning style
in this areas these leaves would be
shaded so we're
maximizing the light penetration we're
maximizing the coverage
area we're really allowing the plants
to perform and to produce the highest
percentage or greatest efficiency
that we can and this is why growers like
to utilize this pruning method