okay I'm gonna describe a little bit
about what this concept of super soil is
and the picture here of Superman because
the idea is to create the superior soil
that's really going to help plants take
off and produce maximum yields so this
term super soil is very common in the
cannabis industry it's typically used to
define a quality based material growing
material that is both beneficial fungi
bacteria night macronutrients
micronutrients good porosity it's kind
of like the best of everything for
plants to grow in it can be a
combination of
recipes here to create the ideally the
best growing media for plants now the
advantage of super soil is that allows
the growers to dial in the soil type in
exact nutrient ratios
however with great control comes great
responsibility it's kind of like the
mixing table here all these little
adjustments you can go through and do
that may or may not make a great impact
at the end but that super soil allows
growers to have all of this availability
and control over some very minimal
conditions to very large conditions so
making your own super soil well skilled
growers will incorporate your precise
mixture of a wide range of components
they can be a combination of composted
manures and cocoa fibers perlite peat
moss and line
these sales often need a cure time and
we've a very labor intensive so it's
kind of like cooking I can have all
these ingredients at your disposal you
have this entire pantry you're trying to
go through and make the purpose dish
perfect super soil here and requires
when you're building from scratch all of
the necessary components in very precise
and pre measured quantities just like
putting something in the oven that needs
to bake
sometimes super soil needs time to cure
and making your own super soil it's
often a good surrealist mix will provide
the base material kind of like the
foundation that grows will then add some
materials to to kind of create the house
and then they'll add some specialty
sometimes what they like to think of
secret materials to kind of create the
final touches here to the room this
often takes a lot of time and sense of
letting it sit letting it cure and this
entire process is very labor intensive
super
complex recipes growers are posted as
examples all over the Internet
included two links down here to take a
look at you can think of creating a
super story like a recipe I want to look
behind what makes the best super soil or
what someone's considers to be the best
at super soil as a result many are based
and more field in actual science it's
kind of like thinking that adding this
and this can have a synergistic effect
and then they're going to add another
product and that's going to give them
this benefit it kind of sometimes get
out of control based on some of the
recipes that I've even seen also many of
these super soil recipes are a sellers
dream because growers are buying a wide
variety of products two examples as I
said links provided here just so
something you can take a look at what an
example of a recipe or that someone says
for a super soil may be that super soil
recipe example some growers swear by
prepackaged products such as happy fraud
and pro mix and these can often add a
good base material that can be modified
from there but they take a lot of that
incorporation and building of that
simple core porosity and those core
components out of the mix there it's
kind of starting with a good base
material that you can tweak or modify
from there now the whole reason why
people come up with these super soil
recipes is to have soil not to be a
limiting factor so we're looking at
yield can think about filling up this
barrel of water there's always going to
be a lower slat here and that's gonna be
the largest your plants can get because
that's the most restrictive so if you
have good light intensity temperature
co2 then odds becomes of consideration
of the next limiting factor so for
example of light is appear and
temperature is maximized and co2 is
great well if this soil is the limiting
factor creating a super soil will bring
that up increasing your overall yields
so the super soil can have a super price
rest of these get very expensive and in
the end products may be added that are
not needed or are repeated by another
product so you kind of get this kind of
diamond ring approach where something
looks nice and sparkly but it's
extremely expensive it's kind of like
planting money and sometimes
it's often wasting money which again
it's not good at increasing yields and
also increasing costs there when I keep
yields as high as possible with cost as
low as possible so it begs the question
is super soil worth it
while soil is important adding 20-plus
different amendments can be overkill
getting into the time versus money here
there's no perfect soil or product
everything has pros and cons so you want
to focus on a few key ingredients and
having your soil balanced and as
super-soul is not necessarily going to
produce a superb plan more often I see
people who over add amendments to try to
get into more problems then essentially
that they have created themselves so
that's why I said starting with the base
materials especially if you're a new
grower and tweaking or modifying that is
probably a great option starting
completely from scratch maybe if you're
seeing or trying to grow something very
particular that might be worth it but
just starting off and saying I'm going
to build a whole super soil can really
cause some issues so start with a good
base material add some nutrients to it
as the plants respond to it learn that
base material and go from there and then
determine if you want to go into
developing your own recipe for super
soil I do not recommend you starting out
with that because you can create more
problems than it's worth