when discussing cells surface area to
volume ratio is a very important concept
to get an understanding of so first
looking at surface area and volume
length is simply just a distance between
two points area is a squared term
typically length times width and our
volume here is a cubic term length times
width times height or could be depth
different shapes will give you different
basically surface areas and volumes
depending on their size and you can see
here the the comparison of area to
volume the area to volume and how these
different shapes create these different
ratios and that's we're going to look at
a little bit here so first off why are
cells so small since a basic question
how come we're not just one big cell
I'll put a link to both of these YouTube
videos this first one here is a great
job of explaining certain things and it
goes over the agar cube experiment which
has to do with the diffusion of certain
components in different size cubes or
blocks here so for soft cell size cell
sizes range from 1 millimeter down to 1
micrometer either way they're still very
small
the reason why this is it cells need a
large surface area of a membrane to
adequately exchange materials so what we
see here is in our small intestine we
have these villi these kind of finger
like structures you can kind of see and
what that allows is a lot of surface
area this is important because this
helps and aids in the ability for
nutrients to be able to diffuse across
the membrane so I have the picture up
here of a paper it's just flat and a
paper that becomes more and more folded
we're increasing the surface area here
allowing for easier to exchange
materials so you could think I've just
had a solid area very limited area you
can have contact with you take that same
area and I put all my fingers up now now
we have all these areas here and that
allows for a lot more surface area this
diffusion process reason why this is
important is our cells in this case red
blood cells example here
taking in oxygen releasing carbon
dioxide diffusion is spontaneous I mean
there's no energy investment that's
required for the net movement of
particles down a concentration gradient
so just as we put a drop of food dye
here it diffuses throughout all the
water simply using the molecular motion
of the water molecules here it diffuses
or moves across the food dye same thing
here in our cells with diffusion oxygens
freely had to come in ch is freely able
to leave there's no energy required very
important for cells so if they have this
great surface area to volume ratio this
can occur spontaneously no energy
required which means that life can
continue because there's not a lot of
demand for energy for this purpose we
call this a surface area to volume ratio
and this is because of this require
cells to be small so again here's our
small intestine and we see these kind of
finger like projections now these are
all cells all lining these entire of
peaks and valleys but we see zoomed in
here of our villi which we have micro
villi so we have increased surface area
even with on the cells and this is
really what helps us absorb our food
much more efficiently large cells
surface area relative defying ratio
decreases volume of the living cytoplasm
that's the inner portion of the cells
which demands nutrients and produces
waste and kind of exchange those two
cells specialize in absorption
unutilized membrane modifications such
as micro villi example here to greatly
increase the surface area to volume
ratio the picture the feather here
because the feather is very high surface
area to volume ratio a lot of fine fine
hairs here it's kind of the same concept
trying to get to understand here on our
micro villi so example here at the same
surface area but we're changing the
volume as we take that paper and we're
folding it we're increasing the volume
so we're changing that ratio of surface
area to volume
starting off our surface area if the
beginning and end is actually the same
but our volume is changing dramatically
and this is what's affecting the ability
for cells to exchange nutrients so
what's this look like mathematically so
I have three cubes here one
Huber's just a solid block this one we
could see our individual cubes here
there's basically eight of them here we
have many more I want you to think about
each of these individual cubes is having
their own independent kind of surface
air in volume yes they're all stacked up
together here but thinking is
independent so looking at comparison all
three of these initially if we take the
volume which is simply the height times
the width times the length number of
cubes we come with the same number so
all three of these are the same volume
what you're noticing is different here
is those the surface area this is one
big block as a result as a relatively
small surface area in this case 96
centimeters cubed this one has eight two
centimeter cubes and this is 192
centimeters squared as soon as the mini
blocks was actually 64 pick animal here
and they're only 1 centimeter cubes this
has a surface area total surface area of
363 hundred 84 centimeters squared when
we do the ratio out which is surface
area over volume we're noticing our
surface area divided by our volume we
can move the one point five to one ratio
here it's a three to one ratio in here
it's a six to one ratio the higher the
number here six to one be the highest
the greatest chance that diffusion can
occur throughout the entire cell here
our surface area of diffusion I'm going
to be very limited looking at the entire
volume of the cell here to be much more
extensive this is why cells are small to
put this in perspective of a high
surface area to volume ratio nothing
biologically elephant's ears or in this
case the rabbits ears used for cooling
high surface area ratio meaning heats
very easy to exchange you may know the
heat sink curve at air foils here on
computers or in certain mechanics this
is increasing the surface area to allow
heat to escape rady or in a car does the
same thing all of these four examples
have a very high surface area to volume
ratio in contrast to that times they
have a very low surface area to volume
ratio used for heat retention well
pretty large structure not a lot of
folds very smooth and limiting the
amount of contact they have polar bears
kneeling in cold environment in penguins
all huddling together here reducing the
total amount of exposed surface area to
kind of keep that key in and more
efficiently last days a couple links
here again looking at some other
available resources for you it all comes
back to cells being small to allow them
to be able to fuse nutrients and that
occurs through a very high surface area
to volume ratio