this is a nice short and brief
description of the three survivorship
curves we can see them evident here we
have a type 1 type 2 and type 3 type 1
is exhibited by humans type 2 typically
by birds and type 3 by trees look at the
percentage of maximum life expectancy a
number of individuals surviving based on
a log scale so the survivorship curves
they provide a way to express age
distribution characteristics of the
population survivorship is a percentage
of an original population that survives
to a given age you know they said we had
these three different types type 1 is
mortality rises in post reproductive
years or individuals died later in life
and that the example of the human humans
type 2 survivorship curves mortality is
consistent throughout life which is
consistent with many bird species and
then there's type 3 more Telly's low
after establishment which means that
there's a large decline in the young so
not many survived to older age but once
you get to know that mid age many will
survive how does that look graphically
well as we can see here I'll hang out
with the humans appear type 1 is for
humans where you can see that the death
rate increases later in life down here
so further in time is when you're more
likely sadly to die some birds is a
pretty consistent year-to-year and frogs
on in this example many diver early in
life but then once it establish itself
then those two individuals that do
survive to this midpoint many of those
will survive it until the end there's a
steep drop-off early on at meet type 3
type 2 is that consistent or linear
decrease in type 1 is humans where we
having that kind of plateau you're very
likely survive to mid to older age I
want to reach that then the survivorship
curve will decline rapidly to there
towards the end although it gives you
just that quick organization explanation
of the 3 some Earthship curves and the
tapes and how that they look graphically
and also an explanation of each of them