here we're looking at symbiosis and
predator-prey relationship here's an
example of symbiosis we've got the bee
pollinating this flower and predator and
prey there's always a bigger fish here's
a barracuda feeding on some sort of
baitfish here now we have something
called coevolution it's a term that
describes the long term evolutionary
adjustments of a species to one another
so it's two or more species that exert
selective pressures on each other in the
evolved in response to each other so our
example here's our hummingbird in our
flower home bird is a very long beak
flower on the nectar is located very
deep in the flower so this is selecting
for this hummingbird to feed and
pollinate this particular flower so both
of these are adapting the kind of meet
the needs of each other
because each species is evolved in
response to each other one important
feature of coevolution is that selective
environment is constantly changing both
in coloration here in the depth of the
flower is really into that coevolution
that also the hummingbird is adjusting
to so how do we study coevolution
well coalition cited in several
different levels we have adaptions of
the individual to investigate on
interactions between the species and
broad evolutionary patterns this is
different than Co adaptation which is
referring to adaptations of certain
species much shorter term this could
refer to species adaptation processes
process by individuals genotypes and etc
I'll post a link in the description to
this video here helps to explain a
little bit more to us hosts and
pathogens co-evolved in together it's
constant competition that's occurring
co-adaptation now we have caterpillars
that secrete honeydew so hundreds a
sticky substance that ants like to drink
so sugary substance the ants defend the
caterpillars against parasitic wasps
added the honeydew secretion in defense
arco adaptations so the fact that the
caterpillars producing ideas at the ants
favour or like all
the answer addicted caterpillars I'm
getting attacked by these parasitic
wasps that literally lay eggs inside
them and cause the caterpillars to be
eaten from the inside out so the
honeydew that the ants like is
protecting the caterpillars from the
wasps pretty complex system welcome to
biology
how does co-adaptation
demonstrate coevolution so ballast have
a strict definition for coevolution in
its parallel evolution between taxes
required so we have the example here of
the hawk the bat and the dragonfly all
having developed some form of flight and
this is looking at parallel evolution
they're all developing the fact that
they can fly symbiosis this is a
condition which two or more kinds of
organisms live together in close
association just one another there's
three different types which we're going
to go into more detail mutualism
parasitism and communalism so we have
our example we could have our reefs here
with our fish and coral living together
mutualism both be both participating
species benefit parasitism one species
balance while the other is harmed
communalism one species benefits and the
other is neither harmed nor has any
benefit so one of these in more detail
starting to lism mutualism is a
relationship in which both species
benefit we have our answer Athens here
Athens provide the answer with food in
the form of continuous excreted honeydew
they're piercing the plant in giving the
ant very easy play-do access the ants
transport the agents to protect them
from predators
so the aphids can be attacked the ants
are protecting those aphids because
they're the ones giving them the
honeydew does sugar so this is why both
are benefiting because the ants getting
the honeydew and a fizzer given
protection ants defending aphids from
lady beetles ladybugs love to eat aphids
so the ant will actually help protect
that this case both species are
benefitting mutualism another example
here our ants
providing food ballads these kind of
large kind of structures here answer
provided organic nutrients of protecting
these flower regions these plant regions
from herbivores and shading from other
plants they're eliminating competition
and it is a result the plants able to do
better so the plants benefit benefit in
in the ants in this case they're getting
a benefit also so when both species are
benefiting again a both doing work but
in this case both are through the
relationship benefiting from the process
they are called mutualism ideally in
class you would be working together both
you and your lab partner would be
sharing ideas this would be the example
of mutualism both of you are working
towards a common goal both you may be
doing a slightly different things but in
the end both of you are benefitting in
contrast that with care to sit so a
parasite I mean I want to remember
parasites different in a predator so
parasitism symbiotic relationship in the
form of predation so the predator
parasite is much smaller than the prey
the prey does not necessarily need to
die prime example will be the mosquito
mosquito basically attaches to your skin
pierces your skin takes in the blood
from your body and then leaves this is a
parasite we have example here leeches on
a fish parasite a true predator here we
have the Lions consuming their food prey
they're actually killing it completely
yes in this case a predator or parasite
i'm parasitism is much smaller here's
about equal size the prison messes I
need to die a case of us we may not
necessarily die from mosquito bite
assume those are carrying any harmful
diseases leeches do not want to kill
their hosts but in some cases they do
but it's not necessary for them we have
two different types of parasites there's
external parasites such as we call those
ectoparasites and they feed on the
exterior surface or an organism prime
example would be a tick and we have
different types of ticks but they all
are ectoparasites
we're feeding on the surface of your
skin parasitoids our insects or lofts
that lay eggs on living hosts we hear
homeroom that meets aliens our hormone
hornworm here that feeds on tomatoes is
getting attacked here here's our
parasitic wasp attacking 1/8 it these
are examples of parasites and
parasitoids and ectoparasites living
purely on the surface of the organism in
contrast to that there's something
called endo parasites and these live
within the bodies of vertebrates and
invertebrates marked by much more
extreme specialization than external
parasites due to parasite specifically
can live inside doing your specific body
system as an example here these are
endoparasites living within the bodies
inside and no meaning in brood parasites
are birds an example laying eggs in the
nest of other species so the cowbird and
its Eastern Phoebe
these aren't phoebe eggs are all this
nice kind of like almost pinkish tannish
color and then we have the cowbird this
speckled egg what happens here is the
Phoebe species creates a nest place it
takes in it and this cow bird this brood
parasite comes in lays one egg with any
other eggs of this other bird species
this poor Phoebe then takes care of all
the eggs raising all the young and isn't
inverting hidden care of this other
species this caliber this parasite
species that basically didn't build the
nest doesn't feed the young comes in
laying and then leaves this example
again parasite one organisms benefiting
one is clearly not comunism
is a symbiotic relationship that
benefits one species but neither harms
nor benefits the other coefficient sea
anemones are the prime example clownfish
gained protection by remaining among the
enemy's tentacles
their stinging tentacles to most other
species they also are green scraps from
the enemies food but the enemies really
not getting much of a benefit in this
case the clownfish is getting a benefit
but it's not like the accomplishes
feeding on
it's not reducing its ability to survive
at all
but there's no benefit for it other
examples would be cow I'm sorry cattle
egrets in the African cape buffalo this
species here the egrets of the birds may
eat insects off the Buffalo see them
located here here's one back here a
couple here on the hippo they're eating
the insects but there's no clear
distinction between communism and mutual
mutualism remember communalism is
reiationship that benefits one but
neither harms never the benefits the
other it's difficult to determine
determine if the second partner benefits
at all in this case indeed relationships
may sometimes parasitic but in this case
the insects that the egrets eating
really not doing any harm to the cape
buffalo here but really not often to
benefit by removing them printed or prey
interactions this predation is a
consuming of one organism by another
this is a clear distinction here the
predator prey predation is conceding
that other animal here here we have the
praying mantis in the fly we have a bird
here eating a fish again it's going to
be it's one way the poor fish isn't a
survive and that poor flies not going to
survive this is a great blue herring
eating a sunfish in particular under
simple laboratory conditions
predation often exterminates the prey
then it becomes extinct itself because
it runs out of food so if these great
blue herring ate all the sunfish they
themselves would become extinct because
they eliminate their own food source
typically this doesn't happen in nature
what tends to happen in nature is the
example here we have of our North
American snowshoe hare a rabbit and we
have the Lynx that feeds on it the preys
the rabbit you notice as the rabbit
population increases there's a slight
delay but in the Lynx population
increasing and that will drop as the
rabbit population drops and it kind of
goes through this cycle the rabbits
population depends on the presence of
what it eats in this case it's a willow
or birch branch
is the Lynx is dependent on the presence
of the actual rabbit you can see it's
this transition that's occurring hi in
one case followed by peak here in the
predator-prey drops predator drops so on
and so forth this interaction occurs
this predator prey interactions hers
something called keystone species so
these interactions are essential for the
maintenance of species diversity in
communities the Predators can be greatly
reduced competition competitive
exclusion by reducing the individuals
for competing species so how does this
look at us in a real example
well keystone species here we have
feeding on kelp so we have our kelp
forests that exist and an enemies here
these sea stars are bivalves and they're
downing the habitats here they are the
feet on the kelp so when there's only a
couple then the kelp was able to grow
there's able to these protective forests
and everything is well I'm good however
when you take out the key species here
the one that's eating these particular
sea stars now we get a plethora of sea
stars our kelp basically goes down to
almost nothing now as a result we don't
have this protective kelp forest to
allow fish species to occur to protect
them for other bigger fish so this
keystone species is a very important
species that can vastly affect the
ecosystem keystone where gets his name
from is the cue stone in a archway the
stringers are the stones here that
keystone is that Center one another
example the keystone species would be a
beaver they treat these beaver dams and
help can block up rivers if you know of
any people that live near these ways
beavers are very persistent in putting
up these beaver dams that can really
change an ecosystem
therefore these beavers would be a
keystone species because they vastly
impact the environment around them
looking at this beaver I don't know if I
trust him 100% he looks like he's up to
no good
still he's a keystone species and can
vastly affect the environment
physically here by building
damn and he may also be able to affect
it intellectually because it looks like
he's plotting something