here we're looking at symbiosis and this
is a prime example of the title image
right here we have the Rhino as a
symbiotic relationship with the
red-billed ops tech are here we can see
that right here so the somatic
relationship between these two different
species so it's going to a little bit
more what this actually means so as we
look at this well Samantha fine at first
it's the condition in which two or more
kinds of organisms live together in
close associations with one another
there's major times I try to this kind
of image gives you a good tennis
comparison between the two we have a
communalism where one species benefits
and the other neither benefits nor is
harmed can have that here we have one
it's benefitting and when it's not
harmed but really doesn't benefit either
from the relationship then with
parasitism we're one species benefits
while the other is harmed so here we
have the species benefiting and the
other one is actually harmed in this
case in mutualism both participating
species have a benefit so that's the
third type of symbiosis and this can
occur in aquatic environments as well as
terrestrial ones so I want to be mindful
that this occurring not just on land
let's look more specifically at
mutualism here it's in that relationship
in which both species of benefits so
here's an example with ants we have
eight heads well if it's provide the
ants with food in the form of
continuously excreted honeydew that's
what I do from the leaves or piercing
the leaf parts and sugars coming out and
it's at the ants feeding off the ants
transport the aphids and protect them
from predators
so Athens typically are fed on by lady
beetles and as a result the ant offers
protection for the aphids in exchange
for the Clady that it will provide from
the plant this is a mutual benefit the
agent as an event being moved around and
protected and gets the benefit of the
honeydew ants and our kids so our kids
provide the ants with food in the form
of belton bodies hands provide these
archaeans with organic nutrients and
predict them from herbivores and shading
from other plants so again mutualistic
both species are benefiting in this case
parasitism so it's a little different
it's a symbiotic relationship and that
is the form of predation so the predator
or parasite is much smaller than the
prey and the prey does not necessarily
die
so in parasitism we have the example of
the mosquito and the human here we have
one benefiting and one has a negative
effect here so we have the mosquito in
the human we have the sea lamprey in the
fish we have the lion in the wildebeest
here so parasitism well external
parasites is an example ectoparasites
feed on the exterior surface of an
organism so an example of this is the
ticks shooting at us
they are ectoparasites because they're
feeding on the surface of us there's two
toys or insects or wasps that lay eggs
on a living host so a parasitic wasp
will lay eggs inside of an insect and
then they'll grow multiply and divide
within an insect a prime example is here
horn worms that feed on tomato plants
could be infected with a parasitic wasp
we see here on the offspring here and
it's basically eating the horn room from
the inside out include a little bit of a
video here if you want to check that out
remember the link to the slides is in
the description we have here with this
horns here and fed from the inside out
that will stop its feeding so I only
saved the tomato plant but it also
caused more parasitic wasps to be in the
local area we have something called endo
parasites which lived within the bodies
and domain inside within the bodies of
vertebrates and invertebrates marked by
much more extensive specialization than
external parasites so external pairs
have to kind of like grazers here in the
parasites Nina's very specific match
they might be in a specific area of the
body would be turning certain organs so
they're much more specialized but
endoparasites referring to parasites and
the inside of a organism brood parasites
are birds they lay eggs in the nest of
other species so bird species reduce the
reproductive success of the foster
parent host so his example here we have
all these eggs and one looks like it
doesn't belong well this is actually a
cow bird it's a brood parasite meaning
female cowbird lays its eggs in the nest
of in this case the eastern TV season TV
can I take care of all the young all the
eggs I just like they were their own but
there's gonna be this one that is
actually a cow bird it'll be taken care
of so this is an example of a parasite
because this Eastern Phoebe I said do
that much more work to feed another
individual even though it's not the same
species communalism somatic relationship
that benefits one species in either
harm's nor benefits the other our
example here is the clownfish in see
enemies contain protection by remaining
among me and then these tentacles here
can be able to hide and they're also
immune to these stinging this that they
may produce and they also glean scraps
off from the anemones food so again not
really harming or benefiting either or
but these are typically seen in close
proximity to one another so another
example of that is a cattle egrets in
African cape buffalo
so egrets eat the insects off the
Buffalo but there's no clear distinction
between comunism
in mutualism difficult to to rent the
second printer benefits at all so while
the Egret here is eating the insects
they haven't ate Buffalo not really a
direct kind of benefit nor a direct kind
of harm to that one there so this kind
of relationship may even be parasitic in
some cases but this is just one example
of communalism we're having the
symbiotic relationship we often see the
Buffalo you'll see the birds the birds
are benefiting by eating the insects and
the Buffalo is really neither harmed
normative from this relationship same
thing here with our sea enemies and
remember we can occur in aquatic and
terrestrial ecosystems and there's just
some examples of symbiosis that does
occur