here on tobacco university i'm going to
go over tap water use
for cannabis production
[Music]
when it comes to tap water or city water
a lot of growers won't utilize it for
cannabis
but however it can be a viable resource
to use for irrigating your plants and
could potentially can cause no harm
however the basics of tap water or city
water is that it's
the easiest form of water as it comes
directly from the tap so many growers
this is what they mainly have access to
however it should be tested to know what
is in the water
this will vary based on your location
and even within your town
so if you're getting town or city water
you can call up the water company
and typically they're doing testing
anyway on a regular basis
it's good to know what is in your water
because one town or one location of town
might have different levels in another
location
so it's important to know what actually
is in your tap water or city water
can tap water be used for cannabis
production and in some cases
yes and it can produce quality yields so
a lot of growers will often want to shy
away from this want to grow
these massive purification processes
some
conditions that's justified but other
conditions it's not
and other cases potentially could cause
plant damage so it's knowing again
what is in your tap water so it's a
general term that we give
to a variable source of water now when
it comes to cleaning your tap water
depending on what your tap water
contains different filter options
may be utilized to purify the water to
make it usable
for cannabis production and you don't
need to use everything here in the
picture but these are just a sampling
of some filtration methods mainly used
for kind of house filters
that can easily be implemented to help
purify that water
that you have coming from the tap now
which filter is best
i put best there in quotes because
filter selection should be based on what
the grower wants to filter out of the
water
different filters have different target
substances so the best filter is one
that matches the substances the best
just because it looks clear doesn't mean
it's free of contaminants just because
it looks dirty doesn't mean it's
absolutely horrible
looking at these two water sources will
require different methods of filtration
and lastly some filter options there's
carbon filters which remove chemicals
and heavy metals
and then there are sediment filters
which capture and moves particulate
matters such as soil and debris from the
water
if you want to learn more about either
carbon filters or sediment filters
check out other videos here on debaco
university