here we're gonna look at your sentences
of taste and smell in a little more
detail so grab the popcorn in the end
and joy sensing chemicals for taste so
the taste receptors if you have are
important for sensing chemicals your
taste buds are located in raised areas
called papillae food chemicals dissolve
in saliva and contact the taste cells
the dissolving of those chemicals in the
watery secretions of your salivary
glands are important to help it enhance
some of the taste we're really hard to
taste something that's completely dry
this is another reason why your bias
secretes so much saliva to help your
taste buds work properly there's
different taste buds locating different
regions of your tongue but in general
the taste buds are those found those
raised portions and they're detecting
the sweetness or sourness of particular
food items that you're consuming smell
is also called olfactory receptors these
are cells that are embedded in the
epithelium of the nasal passage your
turn a tail passage and if we look in a
little more detail we see these sensors
here reaching out the olfactory bulbs
the key part we have our bone area we
have are basically olfactory receptor
cells here located number six the
produce this intense network this is a
causing this nice network of cells here
they're able then to pick up or sense
for the taste of the sense of smell now
the smell is all factory receptors are
far more sensitive in dogs we compared
to our own in humans ingredients for the
basic chemical families of explosives
such as various powders camels dynamite
TNT c4 are placed in random containers
and dogs are able to learn these types
of what they smell like then they can be
used at airports as a way to detect if
something's located in a bag or in a
region that shouldn't be these odors are
imprinted on the dog's brains via
consistent repetition and reward this is
called Pavlov style of training the dogs
what Pavlov did was here we see dogs his
food MIT salivates the dog
sibel this year zobelle doesn't
recognize anything but then what the
pavlof did as part of the experiment was
ring a bell and present food causing the
dog to salivate ultimately they trained
the dog that when the bell rang they
would automatically increase its
salaries and secretions so same thing
here when a dog in training is detected
to find TNT or c4 dynamite Sri lured
with food therefore what's gone through
in this case the airport here it knows
what it's searching for it's well if it
does find that it'll be rewarded with
food with food or a treat the reason why
is put in random containers it so the
dogs is not randomly searching and never
finds anything it's getting that
continual reinforcement there's a way to
kind of show with the olfactory
receptors do look like it's this intense
Network here's a factory bulb and this
is kind of what's when we take in air
particles this intense network here is
sensing our sense of smell transferring
that to the brain allowing us to
recognize certain sense hopefully this
is helpful me adding a little bit more
to your understanding of taste and smell
senses