okay here we're gonna be looking at the
attack Sonic classification system and
it's a way that we simply develop and
able to organize certain species
determine how they may be related and
which ones are more closely related than
others so aerosol system is one of the
first one he developed the first widely
accepted system this is about two
thousand four hundred years ago there
are two main groups he divided them into
plants and animals plants are based on
the size stem animals based on where
they lived so if you were a plant did
you have a soft stem or woody stem or we
like a shrub for animals did you tend to
live in the air did you live in the
water or were you and land dweller where
did you basically live so this is the
very first of the texts animated way of
classifying group things so now to name
organisms biologists use multi-level
grouping of individuals called
classification so why is it important to
place things into categories
well those later groups to be formed
refer to as genre or similar genus this
allows us to better organize or see what
organisms might be closer related for
comparative purposes so by organizing
them into seem to regions it can help us
draw conclusions can help us find some
information out we figure out one
particular on subspecies can help us
explain or look for solutions in other
regions the invention of the mail system
so soft referred to as the father of
taxonomy his basic concept for naming
ranking in hospital classifying
organisms is still in wide use today
each level is included in the level
above it level gets increasingly
specific from Kingdom to species so the
kingdom is very broad in this case it's
like animals here we've got breaking it
down to mammals and are getting all the
way down here and you'll notice the
grizzly bears the species very specific
well the grizzly bear pairs in all of
the prior levels above it however as you
work your way up animals aren't
that are more distantly related we see
here in animals we got dogs who got
snakes who got Birds of it insects all
considered animals along with the
grizzly bear but in the genus which is
just above the species there's only the
grizzly bear in the black bear very
closely related compared to these other
organisms so you can't leave like a
funnel a group of organisms at a
particular level in classification
system are called taxon put taxa
taxonomy is the branch of biology that
identifies the names of the organisms
species again meeting the most specific
here we see Arvin Fox I'm just like the
lab that we did domain is liver is the
broadest it contains a lot we worked our
way to kingdom phylum class order family
genus all the way on the specific
species so species names are important
organs are named using Latin in such a
way that no two have the same name
common names can be very misleading both
of these are called dolphin so don't
this is dolphin the flipper you know the
one you may initially associate with
this fish is also called a dolphin so in
this case here is a mammal being called
a dolphin and here's a fish being called
a dolphin mahi-mahi is what this may
also go by but technically both these
are dolphin we went into this prominent
restaurants you see dolphin on the menu
it's not the mammal it's the mahi-mahi
or the fish species so that can be kind
of misleading there that's why we use
our scientific names because common
names are make poor labels all these and
these are both bears so whether it's a
grizzly bear polar bear koala bear or
black bear they're all bears so we want
to be specific with our names so we know
were talking about when we're paying
this to others so the modern system each
Kingdom Plantae and Animalia was divided
into phylum each file into smaller
groups called the class classified into
order order divided into families
families right into genus in each chance
to divide into species so again in our
life is Novartis category we take a
subset of that River domain a subset
that's kingdom phylum class order family
genus and species being them
specific so we can see that diagrammed
here with our domain is the broadest
category or kingdom phylum class order
family genus species name is the point
of subspecies where there's individuals
that can break down even more
all of these build on one another and
get more and more specific in this case
we're building it as we go up others as
we go down as we see here
same pattern repeats itself though
kingdom phylum class order family genus
and species the order is important to
know so how do we try to memorize that
we get a new on ik device domain is the
broadest category kingdom a little bit
more specific down the phylum class
order family genus and species could
have subspecies so if you wanna come up
with your own kind of pictures here with
just the letters one example is does
King Phillip come over for grape soda
domain kingdom phylum class order family
genus and species and the fun gets
smaller here indicating it's hitting a
more specific because it's working way
down the funnel so that pneumonic device
may help you so what does species we're
talking about we're going the way down
to the species level so approach to
define what a species actually is well a
species is a group of individuals that
can breed with one another and produce
fertile offspring that and is very
important because a horse and a donkey
produce a mule but the mule cannot
produce fertile offspring so the reason
being horse has basically its gametes
divided you know 64 is deployed 60 to
donkey a mule through the combination of
these produces 63 which means it can't
produce gametes because it already has
an odd number so when you have a horse
and a donkey crossed together you can
get a mule and this is evidence when the
horse is the female and the donkey is
the male when that street roles are
reversed in the horse here again is the
male and the donkeys the female is
Nicola honey
horse bred at the horse horse
the donkey again a donkey but it's
important that in order to get a mule to
begin with even though they aren't
technically a species because they're
sterile the horse needs to be a female
and the donkey needs to be a male and I
take it a mule the henna is the opposite
when the horse is the male and the
donkey is the female interesting looks
can be deceiving so we're looking the
basic things I'm phenotype we have to be
very careful the willow wobbler and the
sheriff are almost identical in
appearance but do not interbreed so in
this she had a quick look to us that
these pictures look very similar but
they're actually very different so
what's the species was about 1.5 million
species that have been named how however
scientists estimate that at least 10
million species exist and at least
two-thirds of these occur in the tropics
so we see our world map encoded for
density other vertebrates species most a
lot dense here in this region this is
there's a very distinctive line here
with like all of a sudden nothing do you
know anything about this northern region
of Africa a lot of desert not very
conducive here a tropical rainforest
here we have a much moderate climate
very warm and that's what's allowing
these species to occur such a high
number our extinction rate versus our
number of species
there's an equilibrium that will adjust
this is true for all environments if you
know it may shift slightly there's
always give me that convergence point of
the extinction rate in the new species
rate so they're our last little
comparison here of classifying hierarchy
of organisms tecsound split species into
subsets called varieties peaches and
nectarines are different varieties of
the peach tree so main difference is the
presence of fuzz and the skin and
disease resistance peaches
pitted here are more disease-resistant
and have fuzz and the nectarines are
actually a little less resistant disease
resistant and are that's very smooth
kind of shiny texture blue as it looks
here these are called subsets or
varieties these are different varieties
of the peach tree so again these are
going to share a lot of similarities but
there's also some of those slight
differences the presence of
doesn't necessarily mean that it's
disease resistance if something's fuzzy
doesn't mean more disease-resistant but
in this case with peaches they're
evident by that fuzz and they also have
slightly more seeds resistance to them
versus a nectarine they're that shiner
kind of cooked to it and a little less
disease resistant hopefully they helped
explain some of the taxonomy and
classification of organisms