here on this tobacco university video
we're going to go
over the terpene mercy
[Music]
all right welcome to the chirping guide
to mercene
well what's the scent location and
properties of this particular terpene
well mercedes a monoterpene found in the
most abundant terpene in
cannabis that's kind of interesting the
scent is earthy sweet and musky
and foods that you might be familiar
with that containing of course
occurs in more than just cannabis plants
mango hops lemongrass thyme
wild melon as well as that lemongrass
has that kind of mercene
concentration which you might be
familiar with some of these sweet
earthy musky smells you might be very
familiar with
so what are some of the benefits of
mercin is that it does have
anti-inflammatory and anti-immunogenic
which inhibits
cell mutation including cancer cell
properties so kind of important for
reducing
inflammation as well as a potential uh
chance at reducing cells from mutating
which could be
related to cancer research going forward
does suppress muscle spasms
sleep aid and also has antibacterial
properties as well
studies show that mercy may take thc
more effective which is why it said that
consuming fresh mango
or other fruits that are high in
concentrations of immersing prior to
consuming cannabis will increase the
effects of the cannabinoids so we have
that chance that this might be having
that effect
additive effect with some other
cannabinoids
now going through information this is
one thing i did find i did
cite the source uh down here is that
there's inaccurate information i've read
about
mercenaries raising is important as they
state because
presence determines whether the strain
is indica or sativa
and that is not true they're looking
at indi um classifying indica
or sativa based on the effects so
they're saying anything with less than
0.5
mercy and produces sativa-like effects
so
keep in mind that sativa and indica the
only true
indication of sativa versus indica is
the morphology
or how the plant actually looks it has
nothing to do with indica-like effects
sativa-like effects
indica sativa is really only referring
to the morphology of how the plant looks
is it tall with thin leaves or is it
shorter with wider leaves
that's a that's an indica versus sativa
comparison
not these uh kind of made up effects
because
different terpene concentrations
cannabinoid concentrations
can change the chemical profile which
can change some of the properties and
effects
of the plant indica sativa not directly
correlated it's an old myth that goes
way back
so if you're looking for some strains to
kind of look at that might be high in
mercy now here's kind of a little bit of
a list here here's also a great summary
slide
to provide you some more information
about the terpene
mercy