on this debaco university video we're
going to cover the terpene
lemony
[Music]
all right let's get into your terpene
guide to lemony
so first off the scent location in
properties well
it is a citrus so it's commonly found in
kind of oranges grapefruit
lemon limes and other citrus fruits
giving it that kind of citrusy like
scent
lemony is one of the substances that
penny
forms so it's kind of an interesting
connection to one of the other terpenes
discussed
lemony is commonly used as a fragrant
additive to cosmetics as well as
cleaning supplies
because of the pleasant scent that a lot
of people associate with this
the medical benefits though it goes
beyond just pleasant scent lemony is
easily absorbed through inhalation and
even improves absorption of other
terpenes through the skin and body
tissue like mucous membranes
and also the epithelial tissue of the
digestive tract
it's an antidepressant mood elevator and
may help be helpful for acid reflux and
into indigestion
lemony is known for its powerful
antifungal and antibacterial properties
as well lemon is a natural insecticide
in the cannabis plant
which is the original reason why the
plant goes on to produce it
but here we can see a lot of benefits to
us
now if you're looking for what strains
potentially to be looking for
when we're looking at higher
concentrations of this particular
entropy
here are a list here so limiting again
those great benefits that it does have
this is kind of a nice little summary
slide there and best of luck if you're
looking at kind of
producing more of this particular
terpene the plant wants to for as an
insecticidal properties we're looking
for it for the kind of
citrus scent as well as the potential
for medical benefits