this debaco university video is going to
get into some of the details of the
terpene
pinning
[Music]
all right let's get into the turpin
guide for our pinning here
so looking at the scent location and
properties
of this particular terpene now as the
name kind of
implies we kind of can see it in the
term uh that kind of says that pine or
woody opening kind of like a scent to it
it's found in basil and parsley pine
nuts citrus fruits can also be found in
pine needles
and can be seeped in hot water and
consumed as a tea
so this is not just unique to a cannabis
plant because it is commonly found in
pine trees as well
painting actually comes in two isomers
or types an alpha
and a beta and the alpha which smells
like pine needles and is the most
commonly found terpene in nature kind of
important fact there
and then beta which smells like rosemary
basil dill or parsley
some herbs you might be familiar with so
just a slight change you can see the
double bond is located right here in the
alpha
double bond is located up here in the
beta and that does
change the scent properties scent as
well as other properties
so medical benefits just in general here
nice little summary
it is an antioxidant so it prevents
oxidation damage from other molecules in
the body
an important aspect opinion is also
powerful
bronchodilator which helps improve air
flow of the lungs
for those that might be suffering with
asthma it also has anti-inflammatory and
pain-relieving antimicrobial
antibacterial
properties pain also crosses the blood
brain
barrier improving memory and alertness
it also may counteract some negative
qualities
typically found with thc now if you're
looking for what strains might be
a little bit higher in this particular
terpene well here is in general
a kind of list here as far as to provide
you with a starting point as far as some
strains to look at
as well as another little summary slide
here if you're looking at learning more
about the terpene
pinning