this debaco university video is going to
highlight the terpene
linaloe so hopefully you can learn a
little bit more information about this
all right let's get into the terpene
guide for linaloo
so first off where is it located it's
sent in its basic
properties well as a floral uh terpene
and used in many perfumes it's something
you might be familiar with
that's found in a whole host of
different foods such as cinnamon celery
lavender
rosewood sweet basil and thyme as well
lanalu is commonly found in lavender
and its aroma is light and floral and
that's why you might be familiar with
this particular
scent it does differ from other terpenes
commonly found in cannabis and then it
has an o-h
or hydroxyl group attached to it making
it a terpene alcohol so it kind of
might change some of the various
properties when you're looking at
combining it with different things
now the medical benefits of lanaolu is
that it has been shown to be helpful in
treating mental disorders such as
depression as well
as anxiety lanalo may even be used as a
sedative sleep aid
as well as in anti-conversant so kind of
an
interesting kind of properties here for
this particular
terpene some studies even have reported
the anti-inflammatory effects
of this essential oil and it is found in
other things other than just
cannabis it's widely known for the
ability to reduce stress
and it's used as an anti-anxiety
antidepressant and also a sedative
lonely is also used to relieve seizure
symptoms provide relief from those
suffering from psychosis
has a relaxing effect it can help you
sleep better so a lot of
great benefits with this particular
terpene if you're looking at potentially
where to find it
well this kind of gives you a general
idea of some strains
that might have this terpene in a little
bit higher concentration
however cannabis strains with purple
leaves and flowers tend to have higher
concentrations of this lanalo
however the specific phenotype of each
plant will be have different levels
of this terpene that are actually
present always good to get a test done
now the reason why i stress the purple
leaves anthocyanins is another kind of
plant pigment that's produced and we
notice a lot of purple coloration
associated with this particular terpene
so that is just a slight indication that
if you're seeing something
that has higher anthocyanin production a
little more of purple leaves there's a
chance
or maybe odds that it will also have a
higher concentration of
linalool best of luck if you're looking
for this particular terpene