okay here we're look at terrestrial
vertebrates and the type of gas exchange
that they go about doing keeping mine
cells of animals are going to respire
think they're gonna require oxygen and
they're going to produce carbon dioxide
so it needs to be an efficient way to
exchange those two gases to allow those
cells to continue to live and survive so
looking at gas exchange in the general
sense most primitive phyla of organisms
obtain oxygen directly from the
diffusion of seawater again those are
all your ocean based organisms not that
main focus of this lecture and keeping
in mind here the picture of the carp
aquatic animals possess the special
respiratory organs called gills this
focus though is on those our little Dan
based such as the B here
these arthropods use a network of air
ducts called trachea and we use special
organs called lungs to allow an
efficient transfer of gases so our first
group of organs that we're going to look
at are in fib Ian's and they are
land-based and are able to respire
through moist skin in addition to their
lungs so while the main root of their
respiration is the lungs they are able
to respire through their skin as well
there is a sack with convoluted internal
membranes here the help increases their
surface area at least somewhat and this
is allowing for gas exchange to occur
keeping in mind that they can also
respond through their skin and that's
why they're typically found in moist
environments the image down here shows a
cross-section of the frogs and just give
me an appreciation of what that does
actually look like moving on to our
reptiles they are more active and as a
result need more oxygen they cannot
respond through their skin because that
watertight skin so allows them to live
in more of a land-based environment
instead their lung contains many more
small chambers which greatly increases
the overall surface area over our
exhibits they need that increase in
surface air because they're solely
dependent on their lungs and cannot
aspire through their skin lastly our
mammals we have even a greater oxygen
demand than the reptiles or the
amphibians merely because we maintain
this constant body temperature this
requires our cell
be very active we increase our surface
area even more through two specialized
structures we see here the alveoli are
small chambers interior of the lung they
like these kind of great like structures
the bronchioles are short passageways
that connect a bunch of these clusters
what this does is this vastly increases
the surface area in our lungs allowing a
very efficient transfer of oxygen and
carbon dioxide so that our cells which
are we could aspire and a great rate
we're able to maintain that degree of
homeostasis