on this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at when you test
candidate plant material for potency and
it results in a number
what are some of the specifics that go
along with that
all right let's look at testing cannabis
plants potency resulting in a number
so first off when we're looking at
providing that exact number
to provide a reliable number the dried
canvas flower material needs to be
ground up
mixed together into a homogenized sample
this helps to ensure that all of the
individual flower variability
is easily averaged in the final tested
product
overall this results in a consistent
sample and allows for an accurate number
to be provided now with that homogenized
samples we suggest a representative
example
here however while this sample is great
for consistency in the analysis
this is often not how people want to or
are accustomed to
consuming their cannabis they may want
to have that
original solid dry flower they don't
want to deal with some sort of
diced up small subsample
they want the actual original basically
dry flower
but there can be flower to flower
inconsistencies that do not allow for a
consistent number to be given
it technically should be an expected
range i have another video on this if
you want to search the channel
to look for that if you're looking at
providing that consistent single number
in order to provide accurate results you
need a homogenized sample to provide a
number
for the potency of that exact sample
now that blended flour the results in a
number on a homogenized product
that most people do not want to purchase
you can see here
also encapsulated form here this can be
great for other cannabis end products
that number particularly concentrates
and also like pre-rolls but this is not
for a single dry flower which typically
brings the highest price
so if you're getting a consistent you
know purchasing an exact flower
with an exact number realize that the
really expected might be a slight range
from
that number because as you know
individual flowers will have slight
individual variabilities in uniqueness
to each flower so that's why it's hard
to have an exact number that correlates
even though we do see it with dry flour
it really needs to be performed to be an
accurate result on a homogenized sample