so in this debaco university video i'm
going to go into
testing chemist plant material for the
all-important cannabinoids
looking at some of the analytical
procedures that are done and the
importance of doing this
on plant cannabis plant material
[Music]
all right let's look at testing chemist
plant material for cannabinoids
well first off here's the research
article where a lot of the information
is pulled from so you're welcome to look
at this
in more detail if this is of great
interest to you
so one reason why growers would test for
cannabinoids
well growers want to know how potent
their plant material is because the
composition of certain chemical
compounds
can largely impact the value expected
price paid
for their produced end product this is
how you can start to see some
different values here different amounts
different costs because it can relate to
the potential
of the concentration of cannabinoids and
also potentially the terpene profile
present
so why is testing for grammars important
just in general you know we talked
there's other testing that goes on keep
in mind you don't want to forget about
microbial testing and mycotoxin testing
heavy metal testing as well but why is
cannabinoids important
well there's increasing evidence that
the ratios of cbd relative to other
cannabinoids
as well as endo androidiz chemicals such
as terpenes and flavonoids
exhibit desirable entourage effect so
this is important as far as looking at
the potential
benefits to this plant material the
synergistic interactions between
cannabinoids and other chemicals
may be responsible for the medical
benefits in the actual individual
this is why in part it's important to
test for these not just to claim the
highest or
particular numbers so canvas testing and
the
pharmaceutical testing practices is kind
of like merger between the two
so here we've talked about all the
importance here we see a simplified
version
now we're looking at kind of what an
analytical analytical report can look
like
and cannabis has cannabinoid percentages
that are relatively high
compared to other pharmaceutical
compounds that may use
bio analytical trace analysis
since it's common to dilute cannabis or
hemp plants extracts by a hundred or a
thousand fold or more
to reduce the concentration of targeted
cannabinoids
the to the levels appropriate for the
analytical quantitative
determination so that means chemists
relatively speaking
to other pharmaceutical products has
relatively concentrated requiring it to
be diluted down
to be able to perform with some of the
improper analytical tests
these analytical procedures need to be
amended for from current protocols to
maximize the information
content that is obtained to ensure the
information you're getting as a consumer
is accurate and representative of the
actual plant material
now current popular technique when
determining potency is hplc
high pressure liquid chromatography
using a photodiode
array detector is commonly used in the
cannabis industry because it's
relatively easy
and inexpensive to employ and the
different peaks will represent in
different
compounds and there's different columns
that can be used column sizes mobile
phase buffer solution
a lot of information goes into those
proper analytical techniques
now the sim lcms technique which is the
selective ion monitoring
liquid chromatography mass spec
technique can reduce the potential for
unknown interferences
due to co-illusion which can cause
go unnoticed with the hplc techniques
that are used
this is simply providing a little bit
more of a precision
way of analyzing those particular
compounds
now this liquid chromatography uv
chromatography compared to this
different analysis we can see a little
comparison here and this is some of the
data presented in that research article
this analysis of the sample shows much
improved selectivity
and absence of interfering
chromatography components
this is that when we go back here that
selective ion monitoring
liquid chromatography analysis this is
due to the increased
selectivity techniques where only the
protonated molecules of the targeted
cannabinoids
are monitored so we're getting a higher
degree of
specificity here we're seeing this
standard method
right here and then here we're seeing
the
selective ion method employed here and
this is the
analysis of the same extract in
comparison
where in a the protonate molecules of
the targeted cannabinoids cbda and cbd
along with thc and thca were monitored
we see a greater degree of precision
hopefully a little bit more accurate
results to get rid of some of what's
called the data
noise that could be employed and lastly
just looking at hplc compared to the two
here again important to kind of like
research and kind of have an idea of
the testing methods available and what
the lab that you're getting tested
from results from might be utilizing and
in contrast to the hplc method
if either the lc or the lc-ms which is
liquid chromatography mass spec analysis
of the same sample as performed
the considerably higher selectivity of
either of these techniques
could facilitate qualitative
identification of unknown compounds as
well as
mitigate the potential for unexpected
chemical interferences
for the quantitative determination of
the targeted compound
great summary basically it's more
precise at looking at
very specific compounds which can be
very beneficial
when we're dealing with a plant material
that can have a whole host
of potential other chemicals or
background noise there we want to be
very selective in a sense ensure we're
getting a
quality result a targeted result and a
very selective
result so while this might seem a little
complicated studying you know all the
analytical equipment
it's just part of you being an informed
consumer
for typical products that you may look
at purchasing or as a grower are looking
at getting submitted to a lab
for analysis