here in this tobacco university video
i'm going to go over testing chemist
plant material from mycotoxins
so you can be a better and informed
consumer as to just what these are
and why they are of concern and should
be tested for
on any analytical report
[Music]
all right let's go over testing cannabis
plant material for mycotoxins
well as always here's the research
article that the summary
will be provided for if you want to
learn more about some of the details
you're welcome to take a look at this
for yourself so mycotoxins come
from mold they are toxic secondary
metabolites of mold that can proliferate
in the same environment that is
supportive for cannabis growth
mycotoxins are known risk within the
food
safety industry in general they are a
concern in cannabis plants because of
the suspected carcinogens causing acute
and chronic toxicity however those
mycotoxins aren't limited just to
cannabis
they are products of mold and molds can
grow just about anywhere on walls on
couches and fabrics so again be aware of
this is not just a cannabis problem
this is something in general that's
important for it to be tested in
cannabis
but keep in mind that those mycotoxins
are not visible odorless chemical
released by mold and spore
formations and that's what makes them
such a concern
so what's the health threat you know
when we talk about mycotoxins so they've
been linked to kidney and liver damage
reproductive disorders and immune
suppression
canis material can also be contained
with mycotoxins during transport storage
as well as processing given the known
health risks
associated with exposure to these
mycotoxins testings
is an important safety measure for
consumers
and it's not just cannabis it's been
tested for
other crops as well other food related
crops is a real major
concern because of the damage it can do
to
human health in general so very
important is included with cannabis
testing
now there's also aflotoxins as well as
others well
particularly dangerous are the
aflotoxins a type of mycotoxin produced
by aspergillus
a flagellus a fungal species with
which is a potent carcinogen it's kind
of an example of how it looks and we can
see this highly branched appearance
allows these like spores to kind of
break off very easily get airborne
and be basically transported that way
it does produce aflatoxins in warm and
humid conditions
typically around that 33 degrees celsius
91.4 degrees fahrenheit
and 0.99 water activity so those are the
ideal conditions but it can of course
produce these outside of those
conditions even acute exposure can be
life-threatening if the dose of
aflotoxin is large enough
as the result in alpha toxins could
cause severe
liver failure a major concern there's
different aflotoxins so b1 is considered
the most toxic but
b2 g1 and g2 must also be considered as
they have result from decaying
vegetation in soils when warm
most moist conditions exist there are
regulations now that set limits on
allowable levels of toxins in foods
because of the great concern so the
world health organization the who
according to food safety digest from who
consumption of food
or product containing more than one
milligram per kilogram
and basically essentially one part per
million of aflotoxin can be enough to
lead to life-threatening
aflotoxosis and liver failure so
one part remember a very very small dose
alternately sustained exposure to lower
doses on the order of
20 to 120 micrograms per kilogram
daily for a period of one or three weeks
of aflatoxin b1 specifically
can cause acute toxicity and also be
potentially lethal
so as we can see the reason why there's
such a great concern
it takes a very low dose to get a
potential
lethal end result so we want to screen
our cannabis
for mycotoxins so both recreational and
medical cannabis
must now be screened for mycotoxins
derived from microbial contamination
this can be done in a number of
analytical techniques but due to
chemical complexities of the sample
extracts and the polar
and or reliable nature of some
mycotoxins they're good candidates for
lc-ms or lc-mssms
which is looking for that kind of liquid
chromatography and microspecs there this
is of course an extreme example we're
looking at mold developing
on the bud here but realize microtoxins
can be deadly at a very small level so
even though the product may look clean
we want to make sure we're still getting
it tested because even something that
looks clean
could still contain harmful levels of
mycotoxins
so lastly those safety requirements do
you know that cannabis is susceptible to
microtoxins and this kind of gives you
some information here
more than 40 years ago a paper was
published
that discussed the unfavorable condition
to these and produce
aflotoxins within cannabis and they can
occur also in
other plant material as well state
testing though
regulations typically have a maximum
allowable limit
of micro toxin detection on the sample
however there is variation in exactly
how the limit is applied between states
so keep that in mind
as an example the illinois department of
agriculture requires each of the five
main mycotoxins to be separately
separated under the limit of less than
the 28 micrograms
per kilogram but in nevada in california
the total sum of detectable alpha toxins
which include b1 b2
g1 and g2 combined must be under that
theoretical
limit so this is important consideration
so we're looking at the individual
microtoxins we're looking at the sum
total so keep that in mind look at your
state's regulations
for example new mexico's department of
health enforces one of the tightest
restrictions
of mycotoxin presence requiring the
collective amounts of all five
microtoxins
to sum to be less than the 20 micrograms
per kilogram
so important to know the regulations
understand the regulations and realize
the potential severe implications
of presence of mycotoxins as a continued
part to be
a well-informed and educated consumer