in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over some of the specifics
of looking at microbial analysis
of cannabis plant material which is an
important test to look at
here you're going to learn about the
details
[Music]
all right let's get into testing
cannabis plant material for microbial
analysis
so first off here is a research article
where some of the information was pulled
from
again a summary here but you can go
through and research this yourself if
you're looking at
learning a little bit more about the
details that were presented here
we're going to use this study to focus
on the microbes but in addition they
also talk about heavy metals
and pesticides other important tests
that are mentioned on
other videos on this channel so first
off cannabis
diseases so at least 88 fungal species
cause disease in cannabis as do eight
uh patho varieties of plant pathogenic
bacteria
so there's a lot of diseases that
cannabis plants can acquire
the most threatening disease of
flowering tops are caused by the
inquitous fungi botrytis scenario
typically referred as gray mold as we
can see here botrytis
and we also have alternaria that can
cause issues with the plants that tend
to produce kind of
brown uh looks like little brown circles
uh
starts using the lower leaves can work
its way up but these are just two
macroscopic examples but remember
there's also fungal species that can be
microscopically involved that can still
cause contamination
and that pro bed end product
so pathogenic threat to humans well
phytopathogens cannot infect humans
except perhaps immunocompromised
individuals
so there are some different types of
pathogens that may not be of direct
infection to humans however there
there's opportunistic infections by
alternaria as you can see here as a
microscopic view
they've been reported in patients
receiving chemotherapy recent organ
transplants
patients as well as people with aids
also airborne canadia which are
basically spores
of of scenario and alton area cause mold
allergies and asthma particularly in
greenhouse workers
so don't think that you're completely
immune just because that pathogen may
not be a direct
human infection agent it can cause other
potential
symptoms as well so indoor and outdoor
problem when we're looking at these
pathogens it's not just an indoor grower
it's not just an outdoor grower
asperger aspergillus and penicillium
predominant indoors
and cladosporium predominant outdoors
so if you're growing in an indoor or
outdoor location you may have different
microbes that you'd be of greater
concern but just because you're going in
one environment versus another does not
mean your canvas is completely immune to
the other
clattisporium may be an emerging problem
this fungus also infests
hemp mills as well so even not growing
the crop even storing the crop
can be an area where these microbes
could get hold
and start to proliferate about one
percent of cannabis supplies received
in harborside medical cannabis
dispensary in oakland california
were returned or basically rejected to
vendors because
unacceptable levels of aspergillium
contamination
so this is kind of what it looks like on
a kind of a zoomed in
level here's what it looks like a zoomed
in level is canadian these little spores
that break off
and it looks like it grows on a plate so
it doesn't like this on the actual
cannabis plant
might be hard to see without proper
microscope technology
but one percent of the supplies received
were rejected because of just
this is one uh microbial contaminant so
it is a real problem
now the american herbal of pharmacopoeia
our ahp protocols here they have theirs
listed
they have based on tests of commodity
for food products issued by the epa and
food and drug administration as well as
assays for cannabis used in holland for
orally consumed cannabis to hp
recommends
four tests total yeast and mold counts
total chloroforms
e coli and salmonella testing in
addition they recommend
immunochemical methods screen for
aflotoxins as well
for production to be inhaled the
astringent tests were recommended again
total yeast
total aerobic accounts bile tolerant and
gram negative bacteria e coli salmonella
and alpha toxin assays
the hp proposed specific limits in cfu
which is california units per gram
counts but emphasize that these values
do not represent the past fail criteria
rather they are recommended levels when
plants are cultivated and harvested
under
normal circumstances so it is important
to know europe
local regulations in the sense of what
they expect you to test what levels do
they set at the pass fail line
this is this is just providing one
example
looking at colorado as another example
here in 2015 color did update their
testing regimen
their total yeast or salmonella values
limited here
so this does not mean it contains no
someone or no yeast
they just set the limit here you to be
under this
theoretical limit here also there's
recommendations to test for different
for the three species of asp asperger
gillis here
although it was never implemented so
this is another thing you need to look
at
is what's proposed what's implemented
and what is
required and realize that these may
change from year to year so you have to
stay current
with whatever testing is required by the
state or agency you're looking at now
species detection
so for example with aspergillus it's a
large genus with 250 species and
separating three specific species from
the others
is not easy due to the challenges
associated with
species specific detection color changed
their testing requirements again in 2016
after they had just updated them
to a 10 000 cfu per gram total yeast in
mold test
but left in place to single cfu testing
for e coli and salmonella
so again important as a consumer also to
be aware of the testing
testing changes that may occur and going
back and looking
at the actual analytical report to be
that informed consumer is advised
here looking at the cfu's california
units basically do they grow on a plate
and we can see here they have a count
and they base that count per gram to
determine
whether or not it is above or below that
set
threshold level now we're also looking
at
pcr so this is polymerase chain reaction
as
is a very specific test here very
precise test
to accelerate the testing turnaround
time some labs are now using what's
called quantitative
pulmonary chain reaction or qpcr assays
which detects dna sequences in
cannabis samples the drawback of this
method
is that it's indifferent whether the
material is living
or non-living dna is testing dna if it's
present or not
to accommodate this an enrichment step
is performed
where the canvas samples are incubated
overnight in tbs broth
which is just a nutrient broth prior to
the pcr detection being run
overnight growth ensures that only
living organisms are measured
but raises questions of the overall
preferential cultural conditions
for broader total yeast in mold tests
to address this conundrum this kind of
challenge of like caught in between
some labs perform the pcr test on total
yeast and molds
and a positive result are confirmed with
an additional test extracted 24 hours
later
to ensure the signal from the
pre-incubated test
was in fact from live organisms
so again testing lab to try to figure
this out so that they're not getting
false results not giving false positives
or false negatives providing
quality results to consumers so you can
trust the test results that you're able
to get
and then lastly just figured i should
mention gamma radiation we're talking
about removing contaminants microbial
contaminants
using gaming radiation has been used uh
to basically
radiate microbial contaminations however
this doesn't mean counter
controversial and it may destroy
terpenes and does not destroy
mycotoxins important note there
microtoxins are unaffected by gamma
radiation
there's a study that was done that
looked at 10 000 grays of
in four cultivars for thc and cbd
dominant cannabis plants
levels of total thc and or cbd were not
altered by radiation treatments
in any of the cultivars tested compared
to controls
they did notice some degradation of
terpenes as kind of presented here
but they compared those reductions to
similar decreases arising from
short-term storage in a paper bag
as part of their general method of
testing so while there was
decreases compared to the known storage
conditions
they may not have been as bad as once
thought
that may just be a normal degradation
during the protocol
of testing process so just another
option even though controversial
figured i would mention it just to keep
you an informed consumer