in this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at testing chemist
plant material for the all-important
terpenes a lot of growers are looking at
producing unique terpene profiles
because a lot of
consumers are looking for very specific
or unique terpene profiles
so we're going to go and study a little
bit more about the testing in this
debaco university video
all right let's get into testing canvas
plant material for terpenes
well first off uh looking at the
terpenes in general they're not unique
to cannabis and are often responsible
for the odor
of the plant you can see a sweet
smelling a sour smelling and earthy or
spicy
you can see some of the terpenes listed
here on this kind of displayed wheel
different cannabis varieties produce
unique terpene profiles which
in combination with the unique ratios of
cannabinoids
may determine some of the preferred
medical benefits
by certain uh end users so here we can
see kind of just kind of summary here
and kind of look through and pause the
video and look at that in a little bit
more detail
but just to show some of the
classifications of these terpenes
kind of where they fall on this kind of
general
kind of classification and what kind of
effects they may
result in where their flashpoint and
boil points are
just to give you some more information
and hopefully an organized format
now the importance of terpenes just in
general is that since terpenes
are not cannabinoids some feel they are
not important constituents
of the cannabis plant or product however
there is
increasing evidence that other chemicals
in the plant work synergistically with
the cannabinoids
that produce the therapeutic response so
even though the cannabinoids thc
cbd get a lot of the attention these
terpenes and some of them the profiles
may have this synergistic effect so
there might be of greater importance
despite their varied and sometimes lower
concentrations there is some evidence
that shows these effects can include
lowering inflammation and regulation of
blood glucose
to protecting to protection of neurons
as well as gastric
cells so we're still studying and
learning more about these
but it seems like early indications that
their importance is only going to be of
increase so it's important to get a good
analysis and a test
of that included within the plant
material so how do we
analyze those terpenes so chemical
analysis has generally been done by
capillary
gc ms sources gas chromatography mass
spec
for this complex mixture of over 200
different terpene compounds
however there's recent reports that
employing a liquid chromatography mass
spec technique
with atmospheric pressure chemical
ionization apci
may not have been the optimum
chromatography separation efficiencies
compared to capillary gc columns but
when combined with the mixture analysis
capabilities of tandem
mass spec this may produce the results
needed
while also being admirable to some of
the other
important cannabis compounds in the same
sample
there's some evolution in the an
improvement hopefully in the analysis of
terpenes
because of their determined importance
being able to make sure that the
analytical report is presenting those
terpenes
in the most accurate way possible so
what's the suggestion for ankle
uh analytical techniques when it comes
to terpenes
well this quantitative determination of
terpenes and
substituent terpenes is often desired
and perhaps best done by either gcms
or lcm sms instead of some of the
earlier reported techniques
and why is this important to understand
well if you're a grower you want to make
sure that your plant material is getting
tested properly
if you're a consumer looking at the end
report you want to know what techniques
were used
to make sure it's the most efficient and
most accurate techniques
to ensure you can trust results provided
so we'll look at lastly these terpene
profiles
often consumers will seek out specific
terpenes or profiles that may have
improved relief
for their particular condition growers
also like to showcase their dripping
profiles and provide a selling point for
the product
so you can see both consumers as well as
growers have a vested
interest in analyzing studying
and making public the terpene profile
it all comes together with a quality
test with accurate results
so that consumers can make an informed
decision and growers can know what their
plant is actually producing