on this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at testing canvas
plants potency with the resulting data
provided as
a range while this may not typically be
seen
we're going to go over why that might be
important to be considering the potency
of canvas plants in a range
and not necessarily a single defined
number
[Music]
all right let's get into testing canvas
plants potency resulting in a range and
we kind of see that represented here
we're looking at
percentage weight over total weight for
thca to
see in total here we see all these
little data points
we can see that while the hard line here
might be the
number provided we could see the
variability that might exist
and that's why we need to be considering
this final product as
a range and not necessarily just one
single defined chemical number
so providing that range well with actual
plant
product material that's tested a range
is to be really
expected as there's no two flowers that
are exactly alike
even if they come from the same plant
grown in the exact same conditions
this seems to be logical when it comes
to understanding the plant but a range
can make
regulation as well as compliance with
laws and standards
much more challenging this is why
there's such a push for the results to
be expressed as a single number
if you want to learn more about that i
have another video on describing
the single number idea but here we see
thc of 19.7 to 22.2
range provided cbd provided as a range
because this is a
plant product it is as has some slight
degree of
variation hopefully that range will not
be very broad
but it is kind of unfair to represent it
as an exact
number and we're particularly looking at
dry flour
so the premium canvas end product is dry
flour
most people like this because of the
unique properties of each and the fact
that they often get to select the one
the ones here that they exactly want
however
this variability makes providing a
consistent number a challenge
in regards to potency there's a reason
why numbers provided should be expressed
as a general range
no two flowers would be exactly like
they're grown in slightly different
portions of the plant
different light exposure the difference
between them
should be minimal but there still will
be a difference
which is the advocation for the
expression of cannabis plant potency
as a range instead of a number but as
mentioned
that does make regulations very
challenging and laws
that want to have a set fixed point so
you need that number to kind of go
line and match that set of regulation or
law
so that's part of the challenges here
but just want you to understand here as
part of your cannabis education
that dry flower probably well maybe
expressed as a number
might be more accurately represented as
a range