so Growers have been asking in this
debacco University video will provide
the answer for how to go about properly
testing and screening for hop latent
viroid in cannabis plants
[Music]
all right let's go over the testing and
screening protocol for hopolate and
viroid
so first off this is another great
resource to kind of look at provide a
link in the description on the
references and we're excited if you want
to go to this podcast interview style
information there I'm going to provide a
summary of this as well as some other
resources
so leaves was the standard when we're
looking at taking a sample take the
leaves and this does still work so I
want to think that that was null and
void does still work petioles of the
leaf which again is this kind of portion
right here are slightly better than the
actual just Leaf portions there so you
want to get really specific just those
actual portions there that's from the
node to the leaves that petiole is
probably the better portion of the leaf
however the latest data does indicate an
early accumulation in The Roots before
it saturates the plant and will show up
with reliability in the leaves and
throughout the plant and as this kind of
shows here on the diagram here we see
the success rate you know we're still
seeing you know upper success rates in
older growth petals upper clone stem but
look at those upper and lower root areas
near 100 there so particularly in early
areas if you can send a root sample to
your standard Testing Lab might be
worthwhile because it does seem to
accumulate at least early on they are in
a high degree
now mother plants if you're talking two
months or older four leaf or petal
samples at different areas of the plant
can work systematic sampling throughout
the canopy should be performed root
samples can be hard to get and do
physical damage so Leaf impedials are
preferred for the stage of plant
development not only to reduce the
damage but also because at this point
two months or older
probably got very good saturation
throughout the plant it takes about six
weeks for that hot plate and hard based
on the research I've seen to kind of
saturate that plant and they kind of
become systemically over the entire
plant so at this point if you have that
plant that's over two months old a leaf
or definitely a petiole sample uh can at
least including the petiole would be
advised because usually you have more
roots to worry about might be doing more
physical damage and you're still going
to get a reliable result
in contrast if you have a two month or
younger plant this is where you want to
go and Target a root sample this is
because the early accumulation is in
this location the viroid Lloyd load will
be elevated improving the odds for
detection on a younger plant in typical
younger plants easier to get at the
roots there might be less of them in
total but easier to get at them easier
to get a sample and it's going to
provide you with a more accurate result
now how often should you be doing this
what frequency well if you're going to
keep and or clone the plant that's
something to consider the ideal window
is about every two to four weeks to
ensure continual screening to catch
something early just because a plant
tests negative it may be below
detectable levels or it might be a very
small viral load pick early on we get to
flowering that's where you can kind of
see these thyroid plant stress and that
already become more prevalent two weeks
is best for actively growing plants four
weeks best for established plants as
long as they're strict quarantine
protocols in place you're limiting
access particularly to your mother
plants or your mother room
now that plant quarantine this is if you
bring plants in there should be at least
a 30-day quarantine to allow for proper
evaluation and screening but when I take
a screen sample when it first comes in
and then send another sample off even
after that initial one
this may be requires multiple screenings
to ensure the plants are clean and are
brought in as to part of the growing
operation the last thing I'm going to do
is take one plate that's infected bring
it into your operation and have it go
through and infect your entire operation
good month 30 days is a good quarantine
period
now if you get a positive uh isolate the
plant remove it a full plant tag bag and
dispose is advised and when you kind of
put that bag over you want to limit your
own contact With It cover over basically
seal it up put it all in the bag and
then discard it to the uh for this
dumpster remember this is transmitted by
physical damage and trap and sap
transfer so when you are transferring it
into the bag you want to eliminate any
contact you do have with that if you're
wearing gloves put those gloves in the
bag and discard everything together also
the roots can have some of the highest
thyroid loads so avoid transfer or
contact with these as well a lot of
people just think of the plant the
petiole yes but the roots as well the
substrate they're growing and you
definitely want to be treating that
because that is where some of the
highest amount of irates can be located
it's going to be treating that with
diligent care and making sure disposing
of that as well with your plant