now on this debaco university video
we're going to go over some testing
cannabis plants potency
and kind of looking at the debate
whether we should be providing
a number or a range when we're looking
at potency
related to cannabis
[Music]
now it is important to test cannabis for
its potency
we're looking at more of an analytical
report and kind of this kind of
coloration difference because it can be
difficult to determine well is this uh
where does this exactly fall what
percentage
so we'll look at this in more detail
however looking at the general trends
of potency of cannabis samples
percentage thc and cbd in cannabis
samples seized by the
da from 1995 to 2019
and we can see that there is generally a
trend of an increase in thc
and overall generally a decrease here in
cbd
percentage of those seized by the dea
from
environmental agencies now when we're
looking at the percentages here these
are ones that are seized on the street
we are seeing some of course medical
benefits from the cbd
but the fact that it may lack that
psychoactive high may make it less of
a street desirable end product so
looking at this research article here
and again brief summary will only be
provided but the role of nasa spec
looking at
the cannabis industry to get some of
this detail of testing
so there's five cannabinoids here
presented
and in canvas potency typically refers
to the percentage of thc
and or the cbd cannabidiol in the plant
material
however at least three other
cannabinoids are between
routinely monitored including thca cbda
and cbn so just remember that there are
more than just the thc in the cbd
that tends to get a lot of the highlight
or the attention
so companies may offer a mini test
actually this is a good thing
while the main interest is typically the
cannabinoids and terpenes remember
the contaminant testing is required and
the product needs to pass
all of those categories as well so i'm
just caught up in oh looking at thc cbd
and cannabinoids
uh maybe some terpenes we're also
looking at kind of passing
all of the contaminant testing such as
heavy metal testing mycotoxin testing
microbial analysis and so on
also when we're looking at cannabinoids
it's more than just thc and cbd there's
a list here
of what some companies will test for so
it's good to have that
full kind of understanding of all the
cannabinoids present
in that final plant material now sample
size
does vary so depending on what end
product is being tested
will require a different amount of a
minimum sample
keep in mind that the number of tests
performed should correlate with the size
total lot size of the product produced
for example while two grams of plant
material is required if you're
harvesting
10 plants versus a thousand plants there
should be different number of samples
even though each sample only requires
two grams
here's something provided with some
general guidelines from us companies
waters and drinks should be looking at
10 milliliters or provide the full
finished product for disturbing
determining the fill weight on
analytical scale plant material looking
at about 2 grams concentrates only need
about 1 gram
infused products about 4 units of those
infused products
just to give you an idea of the sample
size with the different testing that
occurs
now the testing instruments high
performance liquid chromatography or
hplc
with diode ray detection allows us to
determine run spectral analysis
for confirmed end results good to know
what your lab is utilizing
for testing equipment to generate those
important numbers
on the analytical report now there are
testing compliance standards
a testing laboratory should meet gmp
standards glp standards and fda
compliant pharma practices
this is just kind of looking at good
manufacturing practices good labor
practices
and meeting those pharmaceutical
standards all other additional things to
be looking for
if you're especially comparing or
looking at determining what lab you want
to get your plant material tested at
so there's a great debate here should
the test results be expressed as a
number
or a range for example asking what is
your age
and providing it with how many years old
you are or what is your age based on you
know general ranges here
this is a great debate in the cannabis
industry should be looking at quoting an
exact number
or should be cutting the potency in a
range
so if we're looking at kind of looking
at expressed as a single number
the advantage is that it is just an
exact single number as we see here 38.61
percent
uh this is uh known uh with certainties
that's a great thing
however the disadvantages is really to
get that known
number that precise number it does
require a homogenized
sample so this cannot be done with just
a single dry flower
it has to be sold as kind of that
homogenized
sample so with that homogenized sample
you can't just test one single dry
flower you have to take multiple dry
flowers cut them all up
kind of get a kind of a mixture of that
and then test that to get that kind of
exact
number because different flowers as you
know are going to have slightly
different
variables than where they're located on
the plant and just inherent
in variability of that harvest
now when we're looking at a range the
advantage of having the
range expressed is that it gives you the
expected
range to from that product it can be
formed as a lot of
dry flour harvest for testing multiple
flowers you can say oh the lowest flower
was here the highest flower is here
after the expected range of this harvest
slot would be
this the disadvantage is it does not
give a single fixed number due to the
variability
and it's harder for regulatory agencies
to handle this pharmaceutical grade
material
that have a request a number
and not a range it's important to
realize that we are dealing with plant
material and it's expected to have some
variability
looking at different tomatoes or apples
and there's going to be different
variability from one to another
hopefully that range will be very small
but it's very hard to pinpoint an exact
number so this is kind of the great
debate should it be
expressed as a range or a number
whichever one you
agree with when you feel that should be
the accepted
put on a label there are different
videos here so you can explore
the advantages and kind of more details
of the uh
range kind of predict production of the
analog analytical report
or you could explore another video that
will look at the number as far as
provided on
a little political report hopefully this
provides you with some good information
and kind of this comparison that you may
not have thought of
to again help improve your education
regarding cannabis
at all stages including growing as well
as the end product and testing
all provided here on debaco university