on this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at testing cannabis
plant material for heavy metals
and some research articles surrounding
this particular topic
[Music]
all right let's get into testing canvas
plant material for heavy metals
so as always we have one scientific
article here
uh providing a brief summary on the
following slides as well as a couple
other
research articles we provided in this
video lecture
so starting with the basics here of
cannabis being used for
phytoremediation this fight over
mediation refers to the
procedures which employ plants to
scavenge heavy metals from the
environment
so we have soil that's contaminated with
heavy metals using plants phyto
to remediate or remove some of those
heavy metals this technique depends on
the ability of certain plant to
sequester
heavy metals from the soil so that when
food producing crops are planted
there ideally be no heavy metals in that
particular crop
so this kind of picture here kind of
simplifies it
metal embolization and toxicity is
reduced we're then taking up those heavy
metals
assembling them in the plant then
cutting down and removing this
particular plant
with an efficient way to kind of pull
the heavy metals out of the soil
heavy metals can be very difficult to
extract in the soil with other means
plants can be efficient at uptaking that
by removing this plant and discarding
that
essentially we've fight over mediated
we've used plants to remediate the soil
remove those heavy metals
take this plant material cut that off
site and that can allow us to
utilize this soil to be used for food
crops with very low chance of any heavy
metals accumulating
in those subsequent crops so we're
looking at heavy metal accumulation in
particular
so however this does lead to
concentration of heavy metals in
cannabis plants material
where they can later reside in products
derived from the cannabis plant
so that means that if we're using fiber
remediation with cannabis
which can be effective it is taking up
those heavy metals taking up those
pollutants
but can accumulate them not only in the
plant material but potentially
in end products that could be used it is
important to understand that some metals
are beneficial
essential for life others are highly
toxic and have negative effects on good
health
plants do need certain metals but
typically not the heavy metals like
zinc or high amounts of zinc i should
say cadmium
lead things like that cannabis has
good phyto-remediation properties
because they can remove heavy metals
from the soil
with minimal adverse effects so that's
what makes it great as a potential use
or potential good plant
to utilize in a phytoremediation process
we need to be cautious
because it can great at pulling those
out of the soil but it can accumulate
those in potential
beneficial plant parts so user exposure
to
heavy metals why are we so concerned
about heavy metals the user may be
exposed to unhealthy levels of
potentially toxic heavy metals by
smoking or other
produced cannabis products from
contaminated plant material
for other for user safety it has become
standard practice
to analyze cannabis plant material as
well as products derived from them
for a number of heavy metals we just see
here just heavy metals
in general where they could be generated
from industrial products
electronic waste could be direct contact
could be plants could be aquatic animals
could affect adults children and also
unborn
children in this case so what are the
heavy metals tested for
in typical uh most commonly they're
tested for is lead
cadmium mercury as well as arsenic
however depending upon which state is
involved this
this testing list of heavy metals might
be longer
so just keep that in mind these aren't
the only heavy metals these are the
typical common four
others may have more stringent standards
so what's the analysis
techniques we're looking at heavy metals
icp
either the oes or the ms are techniques
capable of measuring
multiple elements simultaneously and are
this preferred methods where multiple
or multi-heavy metal measurements are
desired and is regarded to have the best
sensitivity and is the method used in
many
modern laboratories so this is a good
thing we're not just testing just for
arsenic or just for lead we want to test
multiple these so the icp is a great
method
for that the food and drug
administration fda and
the usp united states of pharmacopia
have standardized methods for heavy
metal analysis which are very useful
resources
in the emerging cannabis industry where
regulation has been a bit slow
to kind of catch up so we're kind of
getting into the regulations of heavy
metal testing and
cannabis products because we want to
make sure the test we're getting is an
accurate representation of what is or is
not
in that plant so this is looking at
another
research article but really just at the
abstract because only the abstract was
publicly available
but again welcome to look at this
looking at the mycorrhizae comparison
and metal accumulation changes in
cannabis
so what did the study investigate well
the effect of mycorrhizae on heavy metal
uptake and translocation was
investigated in
cannabis plants hemp has grown in the
presence and absence
of 100 micrograms of cadmium
and nickel and 300 micrograms of
chromium
sex here and inoculated or with the
fungus glomerulus mosaics so what is
mycorrhizae just in general as a quick
summary
well here we have our plant here we have
our roots
not no colonization no mycorrhizae we
just see the roots
kind of being able to produce certain
extra dates being able to uptake
whatever is immediately surrounding them
the advantage of mycorrhizae
associations with those roots is it
expands
the net or the network that these roots
have
they're able to get basically water more
efficiently
as well as other nutrients more
simply because there's a greater
exposure of surface area
to the soil environment to that root
zone
compared to those that are not they do
not have an association with mycorrhizae
so we look at mycorrhizae colonization
hemp growth was
reduced in inoculated plants and the
reduction was related to the degree
of microvisit colonization the
percentage of microscopination was 42
and 9 and plants grown in
non-contaminated and contaminated soils
this suggests a significant negative
effect of high metal concentrations on
plant infections
by the mycorrhizae fungus keep in mind
soil ph
metal bioavailability and plant metal
uptake were not influenced
by the presence of this mycorrhizae
association
now when i say this is a fungus it is a
very small fungus well it looks very
large on the pictures here
it does work with the plants
you can visually see it here we as we're
stained but we can visually see the
vesicles in the hyphae of the fungus
it's a symbiotic relationship so the
fungus is getting more nutrients
and in this case metals for the plant in
exchange the plant provides sugars
so the fungus can more easily grow and
have a food source
so microarrays enhances translocations
more of the specifics of that study
plants grown in artificially
contaminated soil accumulated most metal
in the root organ
so the root region in this soil
microzations significantly enhance
though the translocation of all three
metals from the root
to the chute so that's a very important
point that microsay
is great at accessing different parts of
the soil
accumulating those metals but what they
noticed was that
the in the soil that had the
microorganism added to it
there was enhanced or improved more
translocation more movement of all three
metals from just the root environment
up into the shoot in upper portions of
the plant
the possibility to increase metal
accumulation in shoe is very interesting
for phyto
extraction purposes since most high
producing biomass plants
such as non-mycorrhized hemp retain most
of the heavy metals in the roots
limiting their application so this
translocation is a very
important kind of discovery here as far
as being able to move
those nutrients from just the root
environment up into the upper portions
of the plant
and we see that here on this diagram
where we're seeing kind of the heavy
metals and we're seeing them being
translocated up here
and transported to upper portions of the
plant now here's another research
article a little more current than
the last one that looks at the
non-essential heavy metal contaminants
in industrial chemist
bioeconomy so they looked at kind of
mitigation of heavy metal uptake
suggestions how to kind of reduce the
ability
for heavy metals to be uptaken and
translocated through the plant
they recommended avoiding the use of
mycorrhizae the previous study shown
which i just discussed
showed enhanced translocation of cadmium
nickel
and chromium-6 from the roots to the
shoot of cannabis
so it helps move those heavy metals into
the upper portions of the plant
which is something ideally we really
would not want to have happen
and keep it in the roots remove that
plant perfectly fine but as it gets into
those upper portions
can get into other vital plant
components
other suggestions that they provided
here was
they avoid the use of echo of bacteria
which is another trigger
for increased uptake of cannabis
associated with this strain has been
shown to
committedly enhance plant growth
accumulation of cadmium in zinc and
fiber plants
this is another additive another
bacteria that can help
increase the uptake and translocation of
heavy metals
in the soil so avoid inoculation of that
also want to be monitoring the field so
the farmer must perform a robust soil
test
as well as monitoring field conditions
such as field soil ph
weather conditions related to rain water
or irrigation water
irrigation water ph's and things like
that are also things
that should be monitored and carefully
monitored
and as i mentioned those ph
modifications for
injection in irrigation water cannabis
is acephilic
and basically in the uptake of
lead and mercury and plants occurred at
ph below the level of six
thus ensuring that the ph stays above a
6.5 level
and all chemo injection practices can
mitigate lead
and also mercury absorption in the soil
so when we say chemo injection this is
like growers who are looking at
fertilizing with water fertilizing with
water that has
fertilizer added to it the suggestion
here is to keep that ph above
6.5 to reduce the uptake and absorption
of lead in mercury by cannabis plants
and then the last mitigation heavy metal
uptake that they suggested
would be coupling ozone water treatment
with water softener system
ozone water treatment could help oxidize
these heavy metals in irrigation water
and coupled i ionized system with
a water softener system could help
remove oxidized forms of heavy metals
before they're delivered to the cannabis
crops so just another way to mitigate or
reduce the amount of heavy metal uptake
so heavy metals are a great concern
cannabis is a great
potential use for phyto remediation we
have to keep
in mind of the factors that cause the
translocation of these heavy metals
and limit the use of those upper
portions of the plant
as well as any plant material grown
indoors or outdoors
making sure we're getting proper
analytical tests that test for the
presence of these
heavy metals and making sure we're
staying below any thresholds that are
set