in this debaco university video we'll be
covering
thc and thca cannabinoids to provide you
with a little bit more detail
on these so you can develop a better
appreciation for this particular
cannabinoid
[Music]
so you might be wondering what the
difference between thc and thc a is well
here we see them
in the basic chemical structure and thc
a basically has this
additional group added on here so again
that's the
chemical difference at the molecular
level so this is a great research
article here
where we're looking at it goes into a
lot of detail on many cannabinoids
this video lecture i'm going to focus on
thc
so t ythc well it's the famous one
it is one of the most recognized
cannabinoids ever to be
discovered kind of like the taj mahal
show a picture everyone knows what that
is
while there are multiple compounds in
cannabis that offer
medicinal benefits and many more that
modulate the impact of thc
there are none with such psychoactive
impact as
thc and that's why it's kind of the most
famous one because it has such
a unique effect so what does that affect
well kind of the effect with rthc
after consuming decarboxylated thca or
thc
in high doses can cause near
halluciations for some
although the effect is not technically
intoxicating it is certainly
abbreviating and of very often
psychedelic
so some effects of acute marijuana
intoxication we could see some of the
after effects
of consuming a cannabis bud here that
has a high amount of thc
now here it says consuming decarboxylate
thca when it's decarboxylated it goes to
the delta 9 t2 many people are familiar
with
so the molecule that started the war it
is the cannabinoid
that is the target of now fading drug
war
which characterized canvas as a
dangerous and addictive
drug in the absence of thca there may
never have been a
drug war against cannabis so it's just
kind of an interesting
component of that it was really the
molecule that the plant produced that
really caused a lot of this
drug war kind of developing companies
such as the farmer and the felon
things like that dea going after plants
and the federal level being set at what
it is for the specific thc molecule
so what's the original source well tc
believe it or not the original source is
cbga
thca likes cbda as synthesized from cbga
in the apple plastic space of the
secretory vesicle within
the trichome structure the enzyme that
does the work is
thcaas or thca synthase
again there is a peroxide byproduct
which is toxic to the cell therefore
thcas
or thca synthase biosynthesis must occur
in the trichome of the secretory vesicle
so we're looking kind of a visual of
this well here's our cbga
and then it's thca and also cbg is being
derived
from that single molecule kind of like
the original molecule the stem cell
molecule
that through enzymatic actions and other
plant functions can then
be made to produce these various
compounds
all occurring within the trichome so thc
and regulations when we're looking at
current regulations that require all cbd
hemp flowers with a thc content greater
than 0.3 percent
thereby classified as marijuana and must
be destroyed
there are a few exceptions to the rule
of thcaase producing thca
and cbdas producing cbda
so a couple exceptions but pretty much
all cannabis hemp
uh equal to or less than 0.3 percent thc
marijuana greater than 0.3 percent
thc tht being that molecule that causes
the category the categorization
of that plant material so we get into
biological expectations versus
regulations well research from oregon
cbd company has shown
that in vitro cbdas will produce
one part thca for every 20 parts of
cbda why is that important well because
with the cannabinoid content of hemp
exceeding 20 percent
it may be totally unreasonable to have
the thca content requirement
set to 0.3 or less simply because we can
biologically expect a minimum
of one percent thca for every 20
of cbda produced by the cbda synthase
the required synthase for cbda
production
so because of this this means that if
we're getting these cannabis so high
the plant has to convert a certain
percentage so for exceeding 20 percent
cannabinoids in hemp we are expected
biologically biological expectations to
get
a minimum of one percent thca so
therefore setting the
federal limit at 0.3 percent or less
really limits the amount of cannabinoids
that this plant can theoretically
produce
overall so again that regulations versus
the biological expectations of the plant
again don't really match up so the
interactions
we're looking specifically at thc um in
its interactions
and in the human receptors particularly
interacts with the cb
1 receptor in the endocannabinoid system
for the majority of these receptors are
found in the nervous system tissues
and when bound by thc they modulate the
electrochemical systems that allow us to
perceive the world
presumably resulting in that
psychoactive effect
and here's just a little comparison here
and some studies have been done on thc
found in that article so lastly just
want to leave you with a thc
thc comparison to aspirin this is also
explains the
logistic muscle relaxant
and antiplasmic properties thc has been
shown to have
20 20 times the anti-inflammatory power
of aspirin
and twice that of hydrocortisone and
well so here we're seeing kind of that
potential medical benefits of thc
of other cannabinoids in related to the
cannabis plant
hopefully this gave you a little bit
more detail than you may not have
originally realized
about the cannabinoid thc in thca
produced by cannabis plants