on this debaco university video we're
going to go over thcv
and thcva cannabinoid and give you kind
of some insights into the potential
future
because we're not exactly sure where
this one might be going so hopefully you
find this video lecture interesting
[Music]
all right let's get into thcv and thcva
cannabinoids
now if you're really interested in
cannabinoids and want to learn more this
is a great research article you're
welcome to check out with some more
details
for this cannabinoid as well as others
you might find on this channel but this
is a great kind of information
with the citation here in reference so
you can go through and
learn all about the cannabinoids that
you want so first off looking at thcv
the active form of thcva has been shown
to have
psychoactive effect and an impact on
modulating the cb1
receptors but it has shown to be a
fraction of the strength of thc
so while it does have some similarities
to thc
it's clearly not as strong so it does
have some of those psychoactive effects
which
is looking in the future will this be
regulated is something to consider
if this is shown to have psychoactive
effects even though it may not be as
strong
as those found in the thc molecule
so thtv and diabetes so there are some
benefits it has been shown
to kind of ameliorate insulin
sensitivity in
at least mouse models indicating that it
may prove to be an effective treatment
for diabetes or at least a contributing
factor to reducing the negative effects
of diabetes
additionally it's been found to be both
a stimulant and an appetite
suppressant so again just other things
to kind of look at we can see some
things
listed right here and this does warrant
further research
however looking at the future uh
particularly with uh
thcv uh and other variant type
cannabinoids are being eagerly studied
currently
oregon cbd has currently released a
variety of polyploid hemp
that will express the varying type
cannabinoids but they are focused on
cbdv production it is difficult to
predict whether or not
thcv will be tightly regulated or not
as it does have some psychoactive
potential not as strong as thc but some
psychoactive potential
may cause it to be regulated going
forward
and that's why it should be cautiously
studied and look at the true medical
benefits
but again having the psychoactive makes
some researchers and some breeders a
little wary
that it might be regulated in the future
so this is
might limit some of the initial breeding
that occurs but it should not limit
any potential chance for beneficial
clinical trials