looking at the title it should come as
no surprise at this video lecture series
will cover the skull we're gonna be
identifying some of the bones within the
skull and also some of the functions
that this allows us to have so
specifically the skull what does it do
well some of its functions is protection
eye protects the brain in particular it
also acts as an entrance for the
respiratory system and also the
digestive system there's 22 bones or now
I'm not going to make you memorize them
all I'm going to present them all to you
and even a couple more in some greater
detail but on the highlight some of the
key ones that I want you to know we
can't forget within the skull there's
also something called sinus cavities the
goal of these is it decrease the weight
of the skull and they're also lined with
mucous membranes and they protect the
entrance to the respiratory system so
we've covered the respiratory system it
comes back a little bit to the sciences
and the entrance point here is in the
skull so there's two sets of bones we
have our cranium and our facial bones
and the bones are joined by what's
called a sutures and you kind of see
them here as we're rotating around only
the mandible is attached by a freely
movable joint remember the mandible is
this portion right here this is our
mandible highlighted in green in this
image here and the skull bones here of
the cranium are kind of sutured or
stitched away think about it together
here so of the cranial bones just highly
the couple here are occipital or
temporal or parental frontal and
stephannie leg bone so we have these
different bone regions which should be
able to identify these now this is one
orientation of the skull as you'll see
in other slides and images these same
bones may appear but we may have a
different view of the skull so it's
important to identify these bones based
on different orientations of the skull
here's the 14 facial bones now you may
count these up initially and the same
thing goes right here say there's not a
listed here there's not 14 listed here
well remember that some are there's
actually two of them for example there's
two nasal bones or just going to look at
the
- I want you to be able to identify
right here then mandible as I mentioned
just kind of the lower jaw and the
maxilla there's two of them on the left
and right side but I want to lose is the
maxilla bones and this is the mandible
being able to distinguish the difference
between these is important inferior view
of the skull so remember back from some
of our anatomical positions inferior
view we're looking kind of from the
bottom up and we see that and then here
with the maxilla here here's our
temporal bone where it's located here's
our occipital bone here
from the inferior review so there's a
lot of other bones I'm not going to get
into but we're kind of keeping track of
these two in particular from a different
viewpoint so we have here's another
viewpoint superior view this is from
kind of the top looking straight down on
the frontal bone here the temporal bone
the parental bone in the occipital bone
again from the superior view again don't
focus on the ones that I didn't
highlight at least for the purposes of
my class but you can see the degree of
complexity that occurred within a
relatively small region called the skull
paranasal sinuses these are hollow
portions of Bones surrounding the nasal
cavity you can see where they're located
you may have sinus pressure and that's
usually because of the sinuses that are
located right within the front of your
skull there for my purposes in Beckenham
you can learn all the different science
sinuses by name that could make sense
that the frontal is kind of near the
frontal bone the maxillary sinuses were
that maxilla bone is so you could see
that there's names to intervene late the
functions of these sinus cavities are
delighting the skull and they also give
resonance and amplification to the two
voice so because they're hollow it's a
loud voice to kind of resonate and
amplify a little bit better again from
my purpose is not going to make you
learn them all but you can see where
they're located so particularly if you
have allergies or sinus pressure
depending where it's located
maybe it'll identify the specific name
of the sciences that is has pressure or
might be inflamed
the hyoid bone this is an important bone
that kind of be able to identify it's
the only bone that does not articulate
with another bone as you see here in our
slowly worked in a skeleton kind of see
it's like it's floating unless because
it isn't articulate with any other bone
and this is true for the entire body
here this is the only one that's kind of
like free-floating it serves as a
moveable base for the tongue so that's
its purpose how do you begin and idea
where that is located about right here
it's the only one does not articulate in
the entire body
with another bone ah the fetal skull the
fuel skull is large compared to the
infant's total body length so if I see
in this image here in the amber seven
weeks after conception there's kind of a
disproportionality here the fetal skull
is large in relation to the rest of the
body length this is one thing that's a
little bit different though that that
fetal level you're having that change or
that disproportionality of the skull
being slightly larger in proportion to
the rest of the body now this individual
continues to grow and develop and become
more proportional but initially at the
fetal stage the skull is actually
disproportionate to the body weight
lastly remember one of the previous
lectures talked about fontanelles these
are those fibrous membranes connecting
the cranial bones they allow the brain
of the brain to grow and they convert to
bone within 24 months after birth these
are the soft spots on the baby's head
you can see a graph here of the
percentage of infants with open
fontanelles over time our massive
decrease from 3 months old to 24 months
old or 2 years old and we can see that
de Gration that mean time for closure of
the anterior fontanelle so after about 2
years in most cases is always one case
here in most cases by two years after
birth 24 months these fundamentals have
closed up and if we come ossified