welcome to this debaco University video
where we're heading out to the botanist
this is a dispensary facility and we'll
be conducting an interview with the
pharmacist usma zakar we've got Kira
long to help some of the interviews so
hope you enjoy
[Music]
hi it's Kia and today we're at the
botanist so that we could interview the
pharmacist osma Zakir we're going to ask
her a little bit about herself about
questions about the botanist their
educational Outreach some misconceptions
that people may have and just other
general information about being a
medical patient over at the botanist
so good morning thank you so much for
joining us today for an interview to
start just introduce yourself give us a
background tell us what you do here sure
thank you so much for having me my name
is azma zakar and I'm a pharmacist and
I've been a dispensary pharmacist since
2015.
um where we get to treat patients using
marijuana as their medicine it's been a
very very rewarding experience and it's
amazing to be a part of something that's
evolving and progressing so quickly
at the botanist we really pride
ourselves in our education department
where we do keep up to date with the
current cannabinoid research really
keeping close relationships with the
Growers and understanding their products
and then putting that together to really
see how much this plant can do for us
and it's been such a remarkable
experience to see how much patients
improve when they do get their medical
marijuana card and work with us thing so
how would somebody get started in the
process of becoming a medical patient at
the bottom so it is a two-step process
so first your doctor has to determine
that you have one of the 38 qualifying
conditions and then your doctor will
enter your certification into the state
system then the patient completes an
online application where your Val you
need a valid government-issued ID as
well as well as proof of residency and
that can be a little complicated so we
do help patients by appointment to help
them complete that part of the
application that's great of you guys to
do is there anything that patients
should keep in mind while going through
this process yeah there is a hundred
dollar fee to the state that we
currently reimburse to our patients can
you describe the different delivery
methods and how someone could best
utilize each of them yeah absolutely
it's really great that we have such a
wide range of Delivery Systems because
it can really the program can really get
tailored for a patient's individual
needs so there's of course flour to
smoke and there is vaping products after
that there's so many choices which is
great because many patients come to us
they don't want to smoke or vape and
they can still get the full benefit of
the program using things like oral
Solutions which are like dropper bottles
tablets capsules there's baked goods
there's even topicals which can help
with a whole range of conditions it's so
great that there's so many different
ways to go about that it is really great
because everyone has their own
individual needs and really
understanding and I think my favorite
part about what I do is just talking to
patients understanding their lifestyle
and really getting an idea of what's
going to work for them to empower them
and just give them the right Tools in
their toolbox and Delivery Systems are
really important because also the
delivery system determines how quickly a
medication is going to take effect and
also how long the duration of action is
how long it's going to last so it's
really nice to to tailor very
specifically for each patient
what are cannabinoids and how do they
differ from turkeys so cannabinoids and
terpenes are from two different families
of molecules so cannabinoids are the
molecular components of the cannabis
plant that actually makes cannabis
medicine so it works physiologically in
our body with our endocannabinoid system
terpenes are aromatic compounds that
actually exist in all plants fruits and
vegetables so for example Lavender is
very high in linole which sort of makes
lavender very relaxing the most common
terpenes found in the cannabis plant are
betamercine beta-cariathylene linole
limonene and pinene and in Connecticut
they're measured and they're on they're
on the product labels and that really
help us give us an idea of how a
particular Harvest is going to make a
patient feel
what are some general precautions and
warnings that you would give to your
patients prior to coming here and
ordering yeah I would definitely say
make that consultation with your
pharmacist so all of our locations have
really great medical cannabis
pharmacists that are here to help you
and assist you because we're pharmacists
we also understand your medications from
your from your regular doctor and your
pharmaceutical medication so we can go
through your regular medication list
make sure that there's no drug
interactions and then introduce cannabis
safely into your medic medication regime
if you have never used cannabis before
that's totally okay we have lots of
different products that have no
psychoactive effect if that's what
you're looking for but you're still
looking for that relief and so really
starting off with low doses speaking to
your pharmacist on how to safely titrate
up and explore different options and
different regimens so that's what makes
medical cannabis unique is that you have
a guide and that's what I love doing the
most is getting to know the patients
getting to know what they need and what
they're looking for and then being able
to set them up on something to empower
them on on getting better
hi everyone it's Kiara
um I'm here to talk about my story being
a medical patient at the botanist so
when I first qualified to get my med
card I thought it was pretty difficult
to find really a home base for a
dispensary because a lot of places are
pretty variable with their products with
their customer service hours but I find
that the botanist is very consistent and
that's what I really like about this
place is that there's always great
customer service I'm in and out pretty
quickly you know it's quick but not
hurried a lot of these products here you
can see that they have lab testing for
microbiology micro toxins having Metals
pesticides which of course are not
things that you want to be consuming and
so it's really great to know right on
the bottle that you're not getting any
of that in your product in my opinion
one thing that really sets the botanist
apart from other dispensaries is how
informative they are to their customers
you don't have to worry when you come to
the bottom cause they will let you know
exactly what you're going to get
yourself into there's no confusion they
have so many options here and I just
really love how transparent they are
with everything and how helpful they are
as a dispensary in general so that's why
I always come back to the botanists no
matter where I go it seems
so here at the botanist we really
understand the endocannabinoid system
and the science behind cannabis's
medicine so the endocannabinoid system I
really like to take the time out to
explain to patients why we're why
cannabis works as medicine and it's
really amazing to see patients when they
realize that just like we have a
cardiovascular system or an endocrine
system we also have an endocannabinoid
system that the molecules in the
cannabis plant that make cannabis
medicine are called cannabinoids and we
call them phytocannabinoids because they
come from a plant but lo and behold the
human body actually makes its own
versions of these cannabinoids and
they're called endogenous cannabinoids
because they come from the inside so the
two most prominent are anandamide and
2ag and anandamide was actually named
after the Sanskrit word for Bliss or
Supreme Joy
so how do these work in the body well
they work like a lock and key on our
cannabinoid receptors CB1 and CB2 so the
cannabinoid one receptor is actually the
most prevalent receptor in our central
nervous system that means you have more
receptors for cannabinoids in your
central nervous system than for anything
else that's a really phenomenal
statement and the cannabinoid two
receptors are mostly found on your
immune system your tissue cells your
organs and even in your skin so what all
what are all these compounds doing we've
got these receptors and we even have
enzymes that work on the endocannabinoid
system and we have our endogenous
cannabinoids well scientists put it all
together they named it the
endocannabinoid system and it is really
a complex molecular signaling system
that really helps to regulate almost
every physiological function in the
human body and that's why when you look
at a state qualifying conditions list
there's so many different types of
illnesses so you're looking at something
like ALS which is neurodegenerative or
neuroinflammatory but then there's also
PTSD on the list there's also Crohn's
disease on the list so how this explains
the endocannabinoid system explains why
one plant is good for so many different
disease States
so the cannabinoid two receptors on our
immune system is really what helps
modulate inflammation and why
cannabinoids are such potent
anti-inflammatories and then with the
cannabinoid one receptors if we just
look for an example of like pain for
example in our central nervous system
it's actually been shown in studies that
are cannabinoids actually modulate every
step of the pain processing pathway in
the human body so that's ascending
Pathways descending Pathways and the
cannabinoids are there playing a part in
all of it so again it's just so much
potential for the plant the more you
learn the more you want to help people
you know I work with patients who have
who suffer from fatigue because of some
of their illnesses so it could be an
autoimmune arthritis it could be
fibromyalgia but fatigue is a top
symptom or cheat complaint for them and
what's really remarkable is when you
start working with patients and you get
them to sleep properly through the night
you get them on the right cannabinoids
maybe CBD during the day you really
start fighting that inflammation they
start relieving their symptoms they're
in better mood and then lo and behold
they have more energy patients have come
back to and said to me well I didn't
think getting something from the pot
place would give me more energy but it
has and that's really fighting that
stereotype that people who use marijuana
are going to be sitting on the couch
ordering pizza I mean our patients are
getting back into the gym they're
getting back to work they're walking
their dogs again and they're they're
loving more parts of their life or more
parts of their day
okay so I do believe that all illness
right you have to include the Mind Body
and the spirit and I feel that that's
why cannabis has helped so many people
is that not only does it relieve your
pain it also puts you in a better mood
and that is one of the reasons why in a
lot of studies cannabis is a more
successful pain reliever than opioids
it's because of that mood component
understanding that patients have gone
through a lot in their health Journey
before they have even come through our
door and we really like to focus on
being sympathetic and compassionate and
completely non-judgmental we have
patients that have been using cannabis
for years or decades we have many
patients who've never used it before we
welcome everyone the same way we have
something for everybody and we really
like to tailor our services to to
everyone for their uniqueness as an
individual
so when we look at our products and one
thing that's great about Connecticut is
that we do have a lot of information on
the label so we have the cannabinoid
potency so how how much THC or CBD and
as well as the terpenes now terpenes are
really important because we like to put
together the strain the cannabinoid
potency as well as the terpene profile
to really give a good kind of estimate
on how that particular Harvest is going
to make a patient feel
so you may have a classic Indica strain
that's maybe very high in THC and then
we look at the terpene profile and it
has maybe it's very high in pinine and
limonene will patients have come back
and told us well that's really good for
focus and energy and so we'll say okay
well you know perhaps that particular
Harvest is going to hit more like a
hybrid and not just be an Indica that's
going to put you to sleep so when
patients call or come in and they're
looking for a recommendation my advice
is tell me what delivery system you want
to use and how you want to feel and let
us do the rest
so there's some common misconceptions
that I'd like to clear up because I
think it's intimidating right and
patients might not want to get their car
to come to the dispensary they're
missing out on on so much potential
benefit a really common thing that I
hear is I don't want to get high I don't
want to get high and I say you know what
that is no problem whatsoever we can
cover your symptoms from morning to
night with cannabinoids that are not
going to give you a psychoactive effect
and you never have to smoke or vape some
patients do not feel comfortable with
that and that's completely okay because
we have so many different types of
Delivery Systems so you never have to
smoke or vape and you can still get that
full benefit from the program one of the
favorite things about my job is hosting
the monthly can of convos so we have
monthly virtual sessions where patients
can join general population and even
providers from other states have joined
and we talk about insomnia and terpenes
we talk about chronic illness and PTSD
and I like to share the current
cannabinoid research that is going on
how I implement it and how our
pharmacists because we also do staff
education as well so we share our
knowledge and how we can really use the
current research in treating our
patients every single day with the
products in Connecticut so that can look
like targeted cannabinoid therapy that
can look like not using THC all the time
or not using just CBD all the time
there's other minor cannabinoids right
there's thca there's CBN that we have in
the program and really understanding how
you can use different Delivery Systems
different cannabinoids at different
times of day to get 24-hour relief of
your symptoms it's really just having
those right Tools in your toolbox to
really get back control of your life and
it becomes a beautiful cannabis
community and our patients have even
given us feedback saying my favorite
part about these events is that I feel
like I belong to a community because
really it's also about
removing the stigma from using marijuana
as medicine we have patients that are
even judged by their our own family
members for how they choose to medicate
and treat their symptoms and we wanted
them to know that we're here for them we
understand we're all in on this together
and really getting sharing the knowledge
of why cannabis medicine using
scientific evidence is so empowering for
us and it really helps patients feel
more comfortable and strong in their
decision to use cannabis as their
medicine so the monthly events are
definitely one of my favorite parts of
the job and so coming up I'm going to be
doing cannabis and Pain Management which
is a huge topic and then for Valentine's
Day in February we're going to do PTSD
and relationships I'm looking forward to
that as well what we also do for our
education department is spend time with
certifiers providers and doctors so
really getting them to understand what
we're doing here at the dispensary again
talking about how we do the
consultations how we review patients
medication lists all other diagnoses
that they may have because the body is
just one body it's all connected and
that's what's amazing about the
endocannabinoid system it helps regulate
all of the physiological functions in
the body so you really have to
understand what's going on everywhere
and I like to really push for the
potential of the plant to see what this
plant can do and that is that really
kind of keeps me going all right so my
name is Osman I'm the director of
Outreach for our three dispensaries here
in Connecticut the botanist in Montville
the botanist in Danbury and Prime
Wellness of Connecticut and South
Windsor you can visit us at our website
shopbotness.com or
primewellnessofconnecticut.com and on
Instagram the botanist.ct you could also
contact me on Instagram the Cannabis
soul