okay we're going to do a brief overview
of the lymphatic system which we look at
this image it does have a lot of at
least visual similarities to the general
circulatory system of our body and it
does work in close proximity with our
circulatory system as well as our immune
system so moving on so lymphatic system
recovering the lost fluid so what is
kind of referring to well the
cardiovascular system is actually very
leaky the process of moving blood going
through capillaries actually creates
some loss of some fluid so the goal of
the lymphatic system is to collect and
recycle leaked fluid the body uses the
secondary the circulatory system called
the lymphatic system so you can think of
the reason why it looks so similar to
the circulatory system and as we can see
with our capillaries here it's in very
close proximity to that circulatory
system as a way to kind of recycle and
collect LEEP fluid there's three main
functions of the lymphatic system and
here's one of them
this is returns proteins to circulation
so while we're moving things through our
capillaries and things are diffusing the
cross want to make sure returning
proteins are not lost outside the
circulatory system we want to bring them
back in because if proteins are not
returned to the blood the conditions
here this is kind of stage 1 stage 2
stage 3 and extreme stage 4 here called
edema and this is body swelling will
ultimately result if we have this
accumulation of proteins and not
returning them via the lymphatic system
blood pressure forces fluid out of the
capillary so why does this occur well
most of the interstitial fluid returns
by as Moses however excessive fluid is
drained into the lymphatic system
capillaries in the lymphatic system this
fluid is called lymph so the lymph nodes
the lymphatic system transport limp and
the vessels here contain a series of
one-way valves when they permit movement
only in one direction now here's a kind
of our arteries and our veins or
interstitial space we can see things
moving out things moving in this shows
the actual change in pressure gradient
at the Kapler
level the numbers represent the pressure
of the vesicles in millimeters of
mercury mm of HD so that's what the unit
is for these numbers in the errors in
the diagram show the magnitude in the
direction of the net movement and you
could take a look at that and clearly
see our artery pressures 37 mm of
mercury and the venule here is 17
millimeters of mercury go ahead and the
second function here the lymphatic
system transports fats absorbed from the
intestines will lymph capillaries so you
hear typically in the green color here
or called electives this absorbed fats
from the small intestine remember back
remember that our intestines have a very
high surface area they do this with our
villi manases increasing the surface
here for nutrient exchange particularly
for the intestines nutrient absorption
we see here our lymphatic system is
working in close proximity they're
absorbing fats from the small intestine
number three or a last function of the
lymphatic system that we're gonna focus
on is aids in the body's defenses which
is the immune system so lymph nodes are
filled with white blood cells three
particular areas of importance are
tonsils we up here they contain many P
in b-cells and inflamed in response to
and infection the spleen located here
contains T cells B cells and macrophages
in our thalamus right here in the center
it's important during field development
in childhood and by the time you reach
puberty the immune system is mature and
the role of the thalamus is reduced and
not to zero but it is reduced at that
later stages in life now a tough
elective you may have had this may be
wondering or a little concerned going
back for one second that if tonsils
contain TB cells and is important may
inflame in response to an infection if
it had those removed would that be a
negative impact on us well the
connecting these two with the immune
system it's reasonable to say that there
is enough evidence to conclude that time
fluffiness has no clinical significant
negative effect on the immune system
provided a link to the article here this
is what infected
or in flames tonsils will look like they
have henna that those whitish spots
there here's the representative image of
a normal and our abnormal our unplaned
here this quote in this article was
based on a total of marine thirty-five
articles including almost two thousand
patients so they came the conclusion
that there's no clinical significant
negative effects on the immune system if
you've had your tonsils removed this is
a brief overview of the lymphatic system
here if you want to look at another
video this is a crash course video they
tie in the lymphatic system to airport
screening analogy also goes over a
regulating blood valium volumes
maintaining blood pressure improvement
with the immune system and is the
appendix really useless so welcome to
check that out edition hopefully you
found this video helpful