so here we're gonna be looking at the
cytoskeleton in non membranous
structures within the cell kind of a
cool picture here showing some of the
interior structures that occur within a
cell so first off we have ribosomes so
kind of an important component to cells
in this site in the sense that they are
the site of protein synthesis within the
cell they're composed of our RNA that's
ribosomal RNA and they have a large and
small subunit we can see here the large
and the red and the small in the blue
these subunits are made in the nucleolus
of the salad sends me the little dark
circle you see within the nucleus now
one large and one small subunits make a
functional ribosome you need both
components there to be functional to
allow those proteins to be made so we
kind of look at the image here
remember that brightest tones are
three-dimensional so that's why I kind
of show this kind of three-dimensional
shape here and they're important shape
allows them to perform their very
important function so you have their
messenger RNA that comes out of the
nucleus then there's two subunits of the
ribosome come together and they allow
that translation process to occur to
allow messenger RNA to essentially be
translated into a polypeptide chain
which ultimately will form a protein now
these ribosomes
may be located either in the endoplasmic
reticulum there when they can get rough
we can see here these little purple
circles here would be the rough the
rough would be the ribosomes and the
rough ER and they're also free in the
cytoplasm making current small groups or
they can kind of be free-floating so
we're not just attached to the
endoplasmic reticulum they can also be
free-floating no matter where they're
located they're doing this same basic
function now ribosomes are RNA protein
complex is composed of two subunits
joined in attaching that messenger RNA
in the center here there's a site of
that protein synthesis and they're
assembled in that nucleoli and we see
here the mRNA coming through and our
newly born protein which is those
linking of all those amino acids that
are brought together by the transfer RNA
here and the sequence is very important
for their function going into the
cytoskeleton in eukaryotic skeleton is
in
or of filaments and tubes that extend
from the nucleus to the plasma membrane
that support the cell shape and anchor
organelles it's kind of like the
interior webbing to the cell helps it
maintain its shape and assist its
movement of the cell and organelles
within it it's assembled and
disassembled as needed depending on the
particular functions that the cell needs
to be carrying out now within that set
of skeleton there are three types of Mac
of macro molecular fibers actin
intermediate in microtubules so you'll
see here they both have kind of this
very interesting hair like kind of
structural component view to them within
those actin filaments they're stress
fibers that within the cytoskeleton and
they help with the cell move with
motility they're extremely fine and they
twist like pearl necklace here I get
help give them some strength the dense
web just under the plasma membrane that
maintains the cell shape and they
support the micro villi and I've also
found in intestinal cells and we have
also have with the cytoskeleton as I
said in the small intestine
so this Interceptor traffic control from
moving components around within the cell
also cell is plasma streaming these kind
of a red lines represent the actin
filaments and their whole point is to
kind of keep these villi apart we don't
want them all together we want to
maintain this high surface area to
volume ratio and actin filaments help
that within those actin filaments they
can pinch mother cell into two after
animal mitosis so it's important
component in muscle cells also for
contraction other than myosin these are
indications these are very strong
filaments able to kind of pull those
cells apart during the mitotic process
also important for your muscles when
you're having contractions to occur
allowing that sliding filament theory to
occur those have to be very strong to
endure the stresses that those cells are
under we also have intermediate
filaments and to get their name because
their intermediate in size between actin
and microtubules and the Rope like
assembly of fibrous polypeptides again
this twisting action can help increase
their strength without necessarily
causing a large increase in bulk so they
vary in nature they
from tissue the tissue from time to time
so these intermediate ones can kind of
change a little bit they do function to
support the nuclear envelope cell uh
cell junctions like those holding the
skin cells tightly together so do some
vital components but they are not kind
of one particularly set thing they can
vary a little bit from tissue to tissue
in the time to time as well keratin we
might be familiar with the structure of
our hair has composed of a lot of
intermediate filaments nuclear plasma
membrane connections and gives you that
idea of how something can be very thin
but yet also very strong keratin is
composed those intermediate filaments to
be a little bit there they also have
your braids right here you know it can
be stronger in that ways and that's kind
of what these can do on the molecular
level these microtubules
these are intracellular transport
chromosome segregation and these are
like microtubules are like little tubes
on their hollow cylinders and made up of
two globular proteins alpha and beta
tubulin kind of here's a cross-section
to kind of show you that kind of like
two but that they do have in their
appearance their assembly they're under
control of microtubules in the organ
organization Center most important is
the centrosome when we're looking at
kind of dividing a cell you see here
interact with other proteins and cause
the movement of organelles within a cell
so we want to just think about cell
dividing that's one but also organelles
need to be moving within a cell in
microtubules help with that they're
important for motor proteins so it's a
motor protein will lives helped use
energy from ATP hydrolysis to move
proteins along the substrate helping
that movement we've talked about sliding
filament theory you're seeing that
movement that's occurring in
microtubules are an important component
for that there's centrioles there's
hollow cylinders as we can see here
they're short cylinders they have a nine
plus a zero pattern for micro to do
triplets it helps give them kind of like
a collection of straws is a way to think
about it at least how they look visually
the centrioles found mostly in
eukaryotic cells involved in the process
of cell division
Sam shows may be involved with
microtubule formation disassembly during
cell division and in the organization of
cilia and flagella which I'm gonna talk
a little bit more detail you can see
again it looks almost like a circular
form of uncooked pasta for example
now these microtubule arrays of cilia
and flagella they contain specialized
arrangements of microtubules therefore
local motion they help the cell move
cilia and flagella share in common ultra
structure however cilia is only found in
eukaryotes as an important no procures
do not have cilia so if you see cilia
you immediately know you're dealing with
a eukaryote prokaryotes do not have
cilia and we see it's kind of the
picture here of a flagella now getting
to a little bit more detail here cilia
small numerous Vaghela tend to be large
and single see the flagella here on a
sperm cell and we have the silly here
kind of in a surface opaque little tiny
hairs or appendages so if Adele helped
both help move when the micro to be
double side past one another each cilium
or flagellum has a basal body at its
base kind of acts as an anchoring point
to help that cell move the flagella are
hairlike projections in the cell that
aidan movement and our found in both
prokaryotes and eukaryotes prokaryotic
flagella are small there's simple
structure of rotary movement and our
proton driven you character Gela because
both can have alpha Gela they tend to be
larger and more complex structure you
have a bending movement so kind of think
about it was one kind of like spins like
a rotary movement and when it's kind of
just a back and forth movement and
that's to see the comparison between the
procure and Eukarya jello now in new
carrots cilia are much shorter than
flagella cilia move in coordinated waves
like oars or kind of like the wheat in
the wind often used in preventing dust
accumulation from your respiratory
system so it's kind of like as a
filtering component so gentle move like
a propeller or a corkscrew kind of that
kind of like rotary movement there and
commonly used for locomotion just as
they wouldn't about they help the cells
move as well
cilia only found in eukaryotes for
movement you can see that forward stroke
in that back strip you're kind of that
back and forth kind of motion like kind
of kelp in the rising and falling tide
of
in the waves for our eukaryotes cilia
and flagella motion the flagella as they
said moves in kind of a snake-like
propelling cells kind of back and forth
motion in this silly have that direct
back and forth so when I say that motion
of flagella kind of like that propelling
cells kinda like that propeller kind of
spinning if you will these cilia have
that true back and forth at a fixed
point back and forth motion and it's
like a beating rate for about 40 or 60
strokes in a second so they're moving
very quickly I have a picture here kind
of think of like the kelp and underneath
the ocean it's very slow movement but
the same general movement there
lastly the extracellular matrix so it's
secreted by cells it's on the exterior
portion of the cell large number of
fibrous proteins collagen is one example
might be familiar with hearing that in
to good hair products it's bound by
integrant so it's helping kind of like
stick everything together helping that
cell communicate potentially with other
cells and bind together that
extracellular matrix can also be
important for communication between
cells so just another example of a
component within our cells