okay here when I take a brief overview
of the influence of population density
the example image here would see a very
densely packed population or population
of high density so we have two main ways
to influence this we have density
independent effects these are effects
they're independent of the population
size but still regulate growth
most of these are aspects of the
external environment such as weather
related events such as droughts storms
and floods are also physical disruptions
such as fire in road construction in
contrast the density independent effects
we have something called density
dependent effects these effects are
dependent on the population size and
after regulate growth these effects have
an increase in effect on the popu as the
population size increases so the more
people you have the greater influence
these effects may have only the
increased population will be a birth
rates or emigration a neutral change
would be migration within an area the
way to decrease population density
dependent factors B through death rates
and emigration so if we look at a graph
here is the picture here we see the line
a line B and line C which one of these
curves shows the effect of density
dependent factors and which one of these
curves shows density in dependent factor
keeping in mind our density independent
ones are externally such as they could
be examples of droughts storms and
floods density dependent could be birth
rates or death rates
immigration or emigration so the answers
here if you look at these graphs here
you're welcome to pause the video and
take a guess yourself answers would be
density dependent would be B here
because we are limiting our population
growth and it is the independent factors
can be like storms and floods and
droughts and floods so I could see a lot
more variability that occurs in saloons
our population density remember carrying
capacity is the maximum amount of
individuals in particular environment
can hold but we want to maximize
population productivity
harvesting organisms so this could be
for example fish in the ocean the goal
of our sea urchins for commercial
purposes is to maximize net productivity
this area here would be the maximum
sustainable yield or optimum yield lies
partially up the similar curve so if
we're looking at harvesting individuals
it's really the maximum air we want to
harvest this will allow the population
kind of bounce back and help will
regulate itself we don't want to harvest
it all the way down here we don't want
it to go all the way up to the very
maximum it's kind of in the middle here
is the maximum sustainable yield of a
population on three the area where we
can be able to harvest individuals in
this case could be example for fish
without hurting the total population
that naturally exists