here we're going to look at three
important glands of the endocrine system
the thyroid parathyroid and adrenal
glands you can see our thyroid and
parathyroid are located very close in
proximity to one another
in the throat region and then our
adrenal glands are located on top of our
both left and right kidney so starting
first with the thyroid gland where it
lies just below the Adam's apple
in front of the neck you could see it
located here and highlighted right there
it's two most important home runs are
thyroxine which is increases the
metabolic rate and promotes growth and
it contains iodine lack of iodine in the
diet can cause Gators which we're going
to take a look at so thyroxine if we
don't they're looking for the iodine it
contains iodine if there's a lack of
iodine this is gonna swell up and get
quite large and result in a goiter
calcitonin is the other hormone that's
important and that's stimulates calcium
deposition in bone puts calcium into
bones calcitonin that Gorda that I
mentioned
iron deficiency causes the thyroid to
enlarge that tries to produce the
hormone thyroxine it getting larger can
ultimately look like this and this is an
extreme case the where do we get iodine
in our diet a lot of times insult will
see what's called iodized salt and those
small amounts of trace amounts of iodine
located in there can help prevent a
goiter from forming to keep the thyroid
gland it's normal size when the hormone
is the parathyroid gland and this is
when it's located I could say too close
proximity to the thyroid gland and
there's four small glands you see here
one two three four that are attached to
the thyroid and they produce the
parathyroid hormone typically
abbreviated P th one of only two
hormones essential for survival next is
a fail-safe mechanism ensuring calcium
levels never fall to low regulating
calcium is very important I have another
video series on that and this is kind of
that failsafe hormone the hormone
preventing it from getting too low if
calcium gets too low in the body that
can easily cause death too
because calcium ions are key for muscle
contractions it's their main part and
remember that your heart is a form of a
muscle when levels are low PTH
stimulates osteoclast cells to break
down the bone matrix ensuring that that
99% of calcium you have reserved in your
bones
shirring that 1% is always present in
your circulatory system
this will cause a raise and calcium
levels in the blood the adrenal glands
see them located here but the left and
the right are two glands located just
above each kidney they're composed of
two parts the medulla which is the inner
core you see here and this is
responsible for adrenaline and
norepinephrine this releases in times of
stress too soon a rapid deployment of
body fuel and then there's the cortex
which is the outer shells we see here
and that is cortisol that's its demise
carbohydrate metabolism and reduces
inflammation all the testerone is also
important first two million kidney
uptake of sodium and other ions from the
urine when our kidneys are doing
excretion and also retention of certain
ions this is the other hormone that's
absolutely essential for survival so the
couple essential for survival hormones
and that's the other one as I mentioned
number two hopefully this is helpful to
understand some of the glands are very
important in recruiting system