this debaco university video is going to
look at the entourage effect
i think those that watch this video in
its entirety
may have may spark some interesting
conversation
in the comments below
[Music]
all right let's talk about the entourage
effects the reason we have this image
here as we
see a picture of two faces well it's
kind of like one image is made up a
bunch of
other smaller images that's kind of what
the entourage effect is
a bunch of small little things that come
together that create a
larger picture we're looking at this
from a scientific viewpoint
particularly with the entourage effect
this article does get cited quite a bit
this is a good one
to kind of take a look at and maybe kind
of research it here's the proper
citation
look at the article for yourself there
would be advised
so the android effect what's the concept
of the entourage effect just in general
the term entourage effect was coined by
israeli
israeli researcher dr raphael mukulum
to explain how a combination of cannabis
compounds
is more effective than an isolated
compound so it's the idea that
we have a bunch of these different
commons all coming together
the sum is greater than any individual
parts currently the term is used
to describe the way photocannabinoids
terpenes and other cannabis compounds
work together cooperatively
as opposed uh to one type of kinema
leading the charge while the rest follow
uh as the world entourage implies there
so not quite perfect use of the term but
the the idea that the sum of all these
parts is a greater effect than any
individual
so canvas and the entourage effect
canvas contains hundreds of molecules
that have the ability to interact with
our bodies and minds
general categories cannabinoids
flavonoids and terpenes just in general
all these canvas-derived molecules work
synergistically with one another
potentially enhancing the most desirable
effects that's why people are looking at
researching
determining what combination might be
the best or what
ratios might be the best for specific
effects
all related to this entourage effect so
cannabis and terpenes well kind of in
the image presented right uh
here terpenes may support or enhance the
therapeutic potency of cannabis such as
thc and cbd
this potential relationship between the
cannabinoids and compounds is known as
the entourage or the ins and symbol
effect terpenes
have the capacity to modulate the way
thc and cbd will bind to cb1 and cb2
receptors
in their own therapeutic effects which
are synergistic with the effects of
cannabinoids
so you have these kind of like
combinations of two creating that
entourage effect right here
so cbd and thc interactions well cbs
displayed an unusual ability to
antagonize cb1 at very low nano
molar levels that's basically very very
small concentrations
in the presence of thc despite having
little binding affinity
which is a fundamental example of the
entourage effect
this suggests that even in the presence
of small amounts of thc the binding
potential for
cbd becomes greatly increased so again
you have that kind of combination of the
two being greater than any single part
according to russo this supports cbd's
modality effect on thc
association adverse events such as
anxiety
uh tachycardia hunger sanitation and
rats in humans
however a definition a definite
correlation between cbd and the effect
of thc
has not been established so again we're
seeing this potential of this
interaction between these different
compounds
now what's the relationship between thc
and cbd well this is one example here
um we're looking at this kind of extract
the box moles probably mispronouncing
that
are cbd and thc extracts administered in
clinical settings as an
oral spry the cbd proved to be a
critical factor in the ability to treat
pain
in cancer patients who are unresponsive
to opioids
as a high thc extract devoid of cbd
failed to distinguish from placebo this
is a certain modular relationship
between thc
and cbd in most likely other cannabinoid
types and families
so what this means is basically they
needed to have both of these a
combination
to get the desired effects just applying
one or the other did not get that there
was that synergistic kind of combination
of the two
in this particular study that caused the
desired effects
so this is kind of what most people
associate and correlate with the
entourage effect
however we have to keep an open mind and
that there is this
scientific american article that's
published that basically states some of
its parts is marijuana's entourage
effect scientifically valid
so this is kind of an interesting
article you're welcome to take a look at
we'll explain it a little bit more here
it stated that industrial players swear
pots many chemicals work
in concert but most scientists here at
thc solo so this is potion
april 20th of 2017.
maybe a little weird as person 4 20 on
2017.
uh talk is cheap here so we're looking
at just in general uh the lay public has
really taken on the notion of the
entourage effect
but there's not a lot of data this is
mari a neurobiologist at columbia
university and cannabis researcher here
so i kind of give the example here of
like talk is cheap and just because you
hear it a bunch of times
is it actually true or is it actually
fact so counterpoint to the previous
article so that previous article that i
highlighted is
is right here welcome to take a look at
it but this is kind of a
counteraction to that previous article
the sense that the entourage effect
gained
some ground in 2011 and russo published
a paper in a british
journal of pharmacological review
pharmacology reviewing the potential
interactions
between thc in various cannabinoids and
terpenes and that was the first article
i highlighted
now we're looking at the counterpoint
which is the article here
published by a scientific american so
neurochemical actions
non-thc cannabinoids do have some
neurological actions
as they can affect often in different
ways cannabinoid receptors in the
central
nervous system most commonly cited
examples are cannabidiol
or cbd so we are seeing that cbd does
have some direct ways
that it alone can cause alterations with
neurotransmitters and receptors
and have an impact on the neurochemical
pathways of the body
ethan russo another researcher pictured
here
in about 40 percent of people about 10
milligrams of thc can potentially cause
toxic psychosis or thc induced psychotic
like
symptoms such as delusions so 10
milligrams about 40
of people will have that um reaction
sativex
a multiple sclerosis medication that is
not approved in the united states
has equal amounts of thc in cbd
and at amounts of 48 milligrams so 4.8
times greater than here
of thc in this in their study only four
patients out of 250 exposed about 1.6 of
people
had this toxic psychosis there so this
is a very important demonstration of
this
synergy thc alone is a poor drug and a
very poor therapeutic index
but in combination there can be some
potential
or greater benefits therapeutically with
reduction in potential for delusions so
i say you know show me the data what's
what's the data showing what are we kind
of looking at here
still there's no hard evidence that the
entourage effect is
actually real i know that statement will
come as a shock to a lot of people and
i'm sure i'm already getting comments uh
within
this video but double-blind clinical
trials are the gold standard for
research studies
in medicine and have never been
conducted to investigate the effects of
marijuana's terpenes
or its cannabinoids other than thc so
keep in mind we're talking about these
double-blind studies these clinical
trials
there's phase one phase two phase three
and phase four trials
uh we're looking at seeking fda approval
in this example
but basically we're having more people
tested for the
validity of any statement or any drug
that's being brought to market
so anecdotes are not data so holm says
that he does not like the fact that the
entourage affects supporters best
evidence lies in anecdotes
but he thinks they still tell an
important part of the story
because studies have not been carried
out but you have thousands and thousands
of people reporting the same thing it
gets hard to ignore
i'm not saying that it's not necessarily
not true for those that made it this far
in the video
but we're basing really attractive
effects mostly in this care the ink
the anecdotes than the actual clinical
trials studies are difficult because
currently being a schedule one
status of the drug putting research
licenses out of reach of many scientists
making it hard to conduct those clinical
trials at the current time
so what about edibles too another
important consideration edibles lack
terpenes since they're
volatile compounds and edibles need to
go through a heating process
they also reported to have effects with
basically no terpenes so how are they
going about
showing positive medical potential
effects for patients
uh it could be true but i always give a
question there
he says that marijuana may actually have
the entourage effect but it's still
impossible to know without more
information
such as strain comparisons so i'm not
saying it's not true
we're just saying that right now don't
really have great scientific
evidence we're kind of on the weak side
opinions anecdotes
maybe some initial lab studies can be
conducted is there some studies in some
humans
randomized controlled trials ultimate
gain to the metal analysis or systemic
review
this is very strong evidence this is
very weak evidence and sadly the
entourage effect falls closer
to that weaker than the stronger side so
we also have to consider the placebo
effect this is kind of our last little
statement
here the placebo effect is very powerful
if you believe smoking a bud will give
you
a bright cerebral experience spilling
with
creativity or that a thc pill will make
you anxious and paranoid
then that is what you are probably going
to feel
we have the example here of one person
dating a drug one person take a placebo
that's no drug and basically getting the
same result because they feel they're
taking the right
the drug so they're getting the
anticipated effects there
so again we get a little bit of
complication added here
so with our entourage effect not saying
it's not real
we just need to realize that right now
there's not some great scientific
studies really in support of it
not saying those won't come in the
future and that's great about science
and hopefully the future of research
but right now we don't have any great
scientific studies but hopefully that
will change
going forward