okay here we're investigate the hand and
some of the bones that make up the hand
and what their proper terminology is and
also where they're located so starting
with in general we have the carpals the
metacarpals and the phalanges
each hand consists of 27 bones that are
divided as wrist bones for the carpals
so we're gonna want to be thinking down
here our palm bones are actually the
metacarpals and our finger bones are the
phalanges we're gonna look at them just
a little bit more detail but you can see
that they're color-coded here and
there's more than one type of Flinders
called distal and intermediate phalanges
and also proximal so those terms of
being able to understand distal proximal
still come into play and you see that
theme reoccurring throughout the many
units of the skeletal system start with
the carpals here the eight irregularly
shaped carpals are the most proximal
bones of the hand so remember for
looking at the hand here this still
would be farthest away procs will be
closest to the midline or most proximal
so we're right here in this region this
would be the carpals there's eight
irregularly shaped bones in this region
keep in mind we have our radius in our
olla down here and just above them they
articulate with the carpals above the
carpals we have to give the metacarpals
of the end so this is the five-minute
car polls that indicate approximately
with the carpals and distally with the
proximal phalanges so they're numbered
moving a lot early to medial to start
with the thumb which is metacarpal one
I'm sorry which is admit a couple one
and then end with metacarpal five at the
little fender so we see their numbers
moving laterally starting with the thumb
region and these are also considered
areas of our palm last here we have the
phalanges now the digits named in
similar fashion to the metacarpals
moving a lot of it to the the middle and
starting with the thumb again so the
thumb again is their starting region
however we look at this image we see our
distal phalanges aren't immediate and
our proximal phalanges anyway look it's
particularly the thumb region this one
here in particular missing let's their
intermediate phalanges
so the exception is the thumb this
contains only a proximal you get in
green here and a distal phalange there
is no intermediate phalanges as part of
your thumb this relaxes intermediate
foliage the length of the flames
decreases distally so as we're getting
further away our phalanges are getting
smaller the size or length of those
bones is getting progressively smaller
keep in mind again our metacarpals our
palms located here and our Purple's are
down here articulating with the ulna in
the radius