this is a video you've all been waiting
for here in debaco university i'm going
to walk you through the real difference
between an indica and sativa plants i'm
going to show you with examples and i
hope you enjoy
[Music]
so many people ask about the difference
between a sativa
and an indica now a lot of that talk
occurs at a bud tender shop uh that's
really not the conversation needs to
occur where the camera relationship
needs to occur is here at a growing area
and in front of me here would be what's
called a sativa dominant type plant now
what makes it sativa dominant there's no
buds on here how can we tell we don't
know necessarily the chemical profile
really the sativa indica is based on the
morphology of the plant and this one
here expressing strong
sativa dominant characteristics so what
are those characteristics well it's the
tallness
look at the leaf
very thin
very wispy this is a plant that's going
to get very tall this is indication of
your true sativa morphologies and that's
really describing how the plant looks
and how the plant behaves not
necessarily the chemical profile that a
lot of people associate with is sativa
or an indica so this is sativa now let's
go take a look at an indica dominant
variety
so here in front of me we're looking at
an indica dominant variety and what does
that make it different than the sativa
we just saw again here's that sativa
leaf getting a little wilty but we can
see that very thin
kind of leaf morphology well the indica
will be very different
here is an indica
on say much fatter leaf a lunch wider
leaf a much shorter plant you'll notice
tends to be a little squattier it can
still get tall still photoperiod
dependent but the indica sativa debate
that we hear uh different effects that
the plants produce really isn't the true
case we really that really does impact
the morphology of how that plant looks
which is far a cry from what we see
discussed in bud shops we're talking
about chemical profiles and effects
sativa indica really has to do with only
the morphological differences that we
can clearly see with these two different
types
and here on the left we can clearly see
the indica dominant variety
by its wider leaf morphology
and then here on the right hand side we
can clearly see a sativa because it's
much thinner
leaf morphology so again nothing to do
with what you hear in grow shops nothing
to hear what you hear in blood tenders
it all has to do with the morphology or
the physical structure
of the plant