in this tobacco university student
series video we're going to learn the
correct way to take a soil sample in
both a field as well as an indoor
application that's using a mineral based
soil and why it's important to go
through this process
[Music]
the reason that we would do a soil test
is because we need to know what's going
on in the soil before we actually plant
our plants this is because we want the
biggest yield possible and so we need to
know how to amend the soil properly
that's why we take a soil test so i have
a soil core here i'm going to want to
pick the area that you plan on growing
your plants in and try to dig it in six
to ten inches deep
once it's in there you're going to want
to spin the corer to take your sample
the reason we want it six to ten inches
deep is because that's where the roots
are most prevalent we get the best root
profile from that
once you're done spinning you take out
your corer you see we have the soil all
in there and dump it out into your
bucket
after that you're ready to take your
next sample
now how you go about determining where
that next sample is taken can play into
a little bit about knowing your field or
knowing your location so it can really
be as fine or as broad as you want if
the field history is known this can be
very helpful however when in doubt if
you're first sampling an area favor more
sections and if the results come back
similar you can merge those the next
time things you want to be considering
is like maybe an eroded area a lightly
colored soil and a darkly colored soil
this would be kind of like a broad way
to kind of segregate things here we're
looking at a little bit more of a detail
we're taking into account slope or fence
lines or manure added or a low spot so
you really can get quite detailed with
it if you want to go through and do that
now when you're going through and taking
those six to ten samples or more it
should be random but should also still
effectively cover the area minimum six
to ten would be taken depending on the
area
that you're looking as far as
determining that but this kind of when i
talk about random you know an efficient
way to walk through the field but
sampling from that location and repeat
the same process for your other uh
subdivisions within your sample site
now that we've taken all of our samples
out from the ground we're ready to send
it out to be tested so what you're going
to need is a labeled bag so that no one
gets confused either the scientists or
you when it gets back to you of what
soil it is
then you're going to want to take
roughly
two cups which is like two handfuls of
soil and put it into your bag
once you have that ready
just seal it off
get your paperwork ready and send it off
to the lab
all right we just saw the proper
procedure for soil sampling and outdoor
mineral based soil however i want to
remind you that if plants are growing in
cellulose media then the soilless media
extract sampling procedure and
specialized test should be conducted and
there's a separate video on debaco
university on that specifically now in
this operation that we're going to see
we're going to move indoors and we're
going to use a modified traditional soil
sampling technique because mineral based
soil was used it was a combination of
soil and compost with some rice holes on
the top so the basically the regular
soil sampling procedure could be
followed from mineral based soils with a
couple few modifications into smaller
colors using the trowel using six to ten
containers to make our final sample that
will be sent to the lab growing in
containers is different than a typical
field but the principles of soil
sampling when it's mineral based is
essentially the same
so this is how you take an indoor soil
sample obviously it's a little different
from taking an outdoor soil sample
because we are inside
we're growing out of a bucket we're
already irrigating and most of the time
we have amendments made like rice holes
to prevent bug breeding within the soil
so
you're going to want to move anything
obstructing the soil like the rice holes
out of the way
so you could clearly see the soil
take your trowel
and put it in about four inches deep i'd
say that's a good size for this bucket
then you're going to want to cut out an
area kind of just circle the trout
around until you have like a one inch
diameter to take out
now clearly it's going to be a little
more difficult since we're already
rooting
but it's still possible you just take
your hand grab the sample out of this
out of the bucket
now once you have your soil sample you
can put it into this bucket
once we have our two cups worth we're
ready to start sending it out to the lab
so we're going to need to take labeled
bags to put each of our soil samples in
so neither the scientist or we get
confused when testing the soil
you're going to want to take two cups
worth which is if you don't have a cup
about two
handfuls
and put it into the bag
now once you have about two cups worth
you're going to want to take your bag
seal it get your paperwork ready to go
and send it off to the lab to be tested
and for those that want to learn more
about soil testing there's some other
debaco university videos this one
provides a detailed look into soil
sampling with other tools and methods
included such as using a pvc pipe or
just a simple shovel
when that soil goes off to the lab if
you want to kind of see what it goes
through well the path of soil through a
testing lab you ever wonder what that
soil kind of goes through this shows the
full and complete process and then
lastly just another brief overview the
process with some other suggestions
provided so you're welcome to check out
these additional videos on soil sampling
because it's very important you get a
good sample to the lab so you get
quality results back so you can make
proper amendments if you need to