here we're gonna see how the
hypothalamus and the pituitary gland are
linked together and how the nervous
system and endocrine system can work
together to help the body maintain
homeostasis so looking at how they're
linked well the hypothalamus is the
master nerve control center relate to
the nervous system and it receives
information from nerves around the body
about internal conditions it can release
some hormones and regulates the release
of hormones from the pituitary gland so
that it can it release some hormones it
can also help regulate what the
pituitary gland is releasing pituitary
glands conserve the master gland it's
part of the endocrine system it's roots
a broad range of hormones that regulate
other glands within the body we could
see exactly where they're located in the
brain here and here's our hypothalamus
and there's our pituitary gland again
looking a little bit more specifically
we see the hypothalamus which can
release some hormones but it's directly
kind of connected here to the pituitary
gland so the pituitary gland is located
in the bony recess in the brain below
the hypothalamus at this region right
here it's actually two glands a
prostitue 11 an anterior lobe and it
produces nine major hormones the
hypothalamus located up here secretes
hormones into capillaries that cause
pituitary to release or inhibit the
release of hormones so this hypothalamus
is helping regulate the pituitary gland
now the portal system that carries the
hormones from the hypothalamus to the
pituitary as we see here this kind of
connection between these two portions
located right the portion in the center
of the brain so when we're looking at
the role of the hypothalamus dáil almost
receives sensory information and relays
some to the hypothalamus so we're gonna
felassan our hypothalamus and the
hypothalamus and again there's that very
important pituitary when the
hypothalamus is responsible for
monitoring the body temperature pH and
various other conditions it will then
signals pituitary gland if conditions
need to be corrected so for example if
temperature got too warm or too cold or
if pH got too high or too low the
hypothalamus will be receiving that
and then telling the pituitary gland to
kind of help correct the situation as
needed so the role of the pituitary
gland itself it's the master gland that
signals other glands to produced at home
as a thing you need you can see a couple
examples right here the anterior lobe of
the pituitary side receives signals from
the hypothalamus and responds by sending
out appropriate hormones to other
endocrine glands the profs terior
portion of the pituitary receives
oxytocin or antidiuretic hormone ADH
from the hypothalamus and it relays them
to the body as necessary so you could
see in green the green arrows here these
are anterior pituitary hormones and then
pross teratomas are the two in purple
here both important and for the body to
help maintain homeostasis now the
control hypothesis pituitary is actually
called a negative feedback inhibition
it's regulated by hormones whose
secretions they stimulate so was this
means we have cold exposure with the
hypothalamus releasing hormones to the
anterior pituitary releasing a hormone
that then itself once released and found
in higher concentrations can itself
impact or reduce or stop the anterior
pituitary gland from producing so this
negative feedback loop I'll another
lecture on feedback loops it's just a
brief overview of the negative feedback
loop where this particular hormone can
negatively impact or reduce in this case
more Homer and being produced the whole
reason is once this is produced in high
amounts and completes the job that it
needs to wants to stop the body from
producing it wasting energy and to
prevent other body from having to re
regular those conditions in this case
this negative feedback is a efficient
way for the body to once it reaches
proper appropriate levels to maintain
homeostasis