so here are we looking at the eye and
not just the human eye but vision in
general so on that topic
what decision well vision begins with
the capture of light energy by
photoreceptors many invertebrates have
simple visual systems in the sense that
they're photoreceptors are clustered in
eye spot they perceive lights direction
but not necessarily a visual image like
us and it's if you hear nice very simple
come very basic to very complex
development of the eye
now there's four phylum the abbe evolved
well-developed image-forming eyes
annelids mollis arthropods and
vertebrates this is our flat worm that
has just the eye spots and all they may
look like very distinctive eyes they're
simply only able to tell light from dark
eyes are strengthened ly similar in
structure but believed to have different
evolutionary paths amongst all of these
violet eyes if animals as we see here we
have our insect I very basic very large
area of reception there the human eye of
the vertebra compared to the octopus and
initially especially if you look at both
of these it look very similar however
what's distinctly different is the
number four region before it's the blind
spot in our eyes we have an area within
each eye very small but it's a blind
spot and what happens here is there's
lack of photoreceptors however in the
octopus eye there is no blind spot the
retina continuously in tearaway and
three is the optic nerve and that's
what's sending all this image all of
this information of the image to the
brain for processing continuing on the
structure of the vertebrate eye eye
works like a lens of focused camera via
the cornea located here and that's a
transparent covering that focuses light
we then have the lens which completes
the focusing and ciliary muscles that
change the shape of the lens now located
here and they can help pull or kind of
condense down that lens so that the
image could be properly focused on the
back of the eye where their retina is
located the iris is a shutter that
controls the amount of light allowed in
see that evident here the pupil is a
transparent
okay directly in the center the redness
at the back surface of the eye and the
retina contains two types of
photoreceptors both rods and cones the
center of the retina the four Ferrara is
what produces the sharpest image the
Fabra is the area that's producing that
sharpest image you want that focused on
the back of the eye is that's what's
going to allow the image to be perceived
in its clearest form now rods are very
sensitive to dim light as we see here
are they connected Singlish colors nor
can they detect the edges of images they
produce a poorly defined image in
contrast so that cones can take color
and they're able to detect edges well
may help produce very sharp images rods
and cones both of these are located at
the rear of the retina not the front
because this is where our image will be
focused if it was in the front as her
own lenses that image then gets
projected in the back now color vision
there's three kinds of cones that exist
each absorb different wavelengths of
light we have our blue our green and our
red so despite only having three cones
were able to perceive many different
colors so these many different colors
were able to perceive as a combination
or a blending of what these cones are
receiving we said evident here with our
red in our green when they mix together
they form yellow now if you mix red
green and blue we get that white light
event in here and a combination of these
it shows kind of the distinctive colors
here or how I able to get these general
wavelengths of light and this is how
were able to perceive all of these
variations of colors now if you didn't
see any colors there you might be color
blind which is a condition where a
person cannot see all three colors it's
caused by a lack of one or more types of
cones it's inherited as a six-link trait
is more likely to affect males because
it's an x-linked recessive inheritance
rate one in 12 men will be affected an
average and one in 200 women be affected
by color blindness if you see here if
you see just a bunch of dots you might
be color blind
sheis 74 here so the 74 I was a number
for this colorblind test now continuing
on at the eye were focusing for distant
vision we're looking in the distance for
things light from a distance needs very
little adjusting for proper focusing
Farpoint vision the distance beyond
which the lens does not need to change
shape to focus is about 20 feet closer
than 20 feet we call that close vision
in the closer source as the light is
bent more sharply by the relaxed lens to
strike the retina so we see both of
these striking two distinctive back of
the retina here for distant vision our
lens is very flat for close vision our
muscles have adjusted to cause that lens
to be fatter bending that light so that
it directly hits the back of our retina
for clear image I'll focus in for closed
vision we have a combination which is
the change in the lens shaped by ciliary
muscles to decrease this factory power
we see that here see that fattening of
the lens causing again that focus point
to be directly on the retina
constriction is the patellar reflex
constricts the pupils to prevent
divergent light rays from entering the
eye if you've ever had your eyes dilated
after going to the eye doctor if this is
what it all looks like pupils will
dilate and this isn't I here that did
not have people dilation convergence is
the medial rotation the eyeballs towards
the object being viewed this is kind of
a distinctive case here what this person
is able to independently move one eye
compared to the other but to focus on a
closed object both eyeballs are going to
converge to that midpoint their problems
with refraction so if you wear glasses
this is important to you if you have
normal vision that's with the light
focus properly nearsighted myopic is the
focal point is in front of the retina so
we see here is evident of
nearsightedness that focal point is is
in front of the retina that means that
when the image does hit the retina it's
blurry
how does that look well you see here is
a clear image and here's kind of the
mirror objects being a little bit better
in focus and those just slightly further
away here
not having quite as distinctive kind of
sharpness to that image farsightedness
the focal point is beyond the retina and
corrective lenses with a different type
of lens we see here
so as a focal points behind the retina
we see that here in the king the image
here is still blurry
these are corrected farsightedness with
a convex lens see here in
nearsightedness there's a concave lens
and that's adjusting so that in both
cases now the focal point is directly on
the retina Epsilon's is found in glasses
there's a bunch of different types more
than just for near and farsightedness
depending on your vision you may have
multiple lenses in your glasses to help
with both near and far focus bifocals as
the name implies there's two different
types of lenses we have one for far
typically locators the top of the lens
in near for the bottom portion trifocals
this name implies there's three there's
a far or middle in an ear there's also
progressive lenses they've changed
magnifying power near to the middle to
far vision and gradually they don't have
these distinctive lines as a trifocal or
a bifocal would have in general their
purpose is the same to help the
individuals see clearer this is the
image of Seattle being refracted through
myopic glasses their binocular vision
primates and most predators have eyes in
front of the head the two fields of
vision overlap allowing the perception
of 3d images in depth prey animals
generally have eyes located on the sides
of their head this prevents binocular
vision but enlarges the perceptive field
of view you see that here with our
pigeon these pigeons have a very large
field of view because they're often
preyed on owls are predators and they
have not quite as larger field of view
more overlap more of a blind spot will
say these are more focused in these two
fields that overlap the line perception
of 3d images in depth you ever want to
try this you take both of your hands and
put them out in front of you and go
through and touch the tips of your
fingers but then if you close just one
eye and try to do it you'll often miss
because you lack that 3d depth
perception
lastly some animals chameleons in
particular
here can move each eye independently
this can allow for a greater field of
view they can focus both eyes and select
prey before striking so this is another
kind of unique adaptation that some
animals have four independent eye
movement hopefully this is helpful in
giving you that brief overview about the
eye