so here we're gonna look at the absolute
evolutionary path to apes so I've had
some students that look like this kind
of when I'm given lectures and then when
they realize all the slides where I say
there's a test tomorrow typically
students may kind of switch and it looks
like this we're going to talk about
these two particular types of monkeys
and what makes him each unique so
starting with the evolutionary path so
storage humans of evolution begins
around 65 million years ago with the are
canta it's a small group of a burl
animals that were primarily insectivores
fed on insects they underwent an
explosive radiation that gave them rise
to different types of mammals including
bats and primates now I say radiation
we're not talking about like nuclear
waste radiation talk about radiation in
the sense of how they're organized in a
cloud ram so this radiation there's a
lot of branching that's occurring a lot
of diversification is a way to think
about it so the earliest primates have
two distinctive features that allow them
to succeed in this a burl insect eating
environment grasping fingers and toes in
overlapping binocular vision so you can
see here evidence of our grasping
fingers and toes to climb limbs hang
from branches and use tools the overlap
in binocular vision using two eyes let's
the brain judge the distance precisely
so our binocular vision when our eyes
overlap we're able to determine how far
an object may be close or away from us
so if you know anyone who has damaged to
one of their eyes they may be restricted
from playing certain sports because of
their lack of depth of perception about
40 million years ago and why a stands
for a million years ago the earliest
primates split into two groups and we
have this kind of before monkeys group
that we kind of allocate here and it's a
smaller group
they're probably nocturnal and
herbivores only a few survived today so
they're very ancient and as a result the
monkeys that now have kind of developed
in hominids have F replaced or reduced
the amount of
these particular monkeys that are around
so higher primates include monkeys apes
and humans these are diurnal and
herbivores so remember die Arnold's
referring to organisms that are awake
during the day compared to our nocturnal
are organisms that mainly function at
night they also involved bigger brains
improved senses and adapted for daytime
foraging live in groups with complex
social interactions and tend to care for
the young for prolonged periods of time
these are all examples of this
particular type of monkey the diurnal
versus the predecessors which was mostly
nocturnal early anthropods are now
extinct anthropoids sorry but now
extinct and they evolved in Africa their
direct descendants our old world can
also new world monkeys so I've heard of
old world monkeys these are ones that
kind of stayed in Africa but they have
two lineages the old world in the
hominids and mainly ground dwellers
don't have a prehensile tail the new
world monkeys ourselves you see here in
South America and Central America they
it's where they migrated to they
developed in isolation and are at a burl
they also have that prehensile tails
this is an example what Anu I'm sorry an
old old monkey would look like this is
just an example of a new world monkey
now when comparing our Apes to hominids
Ayanna's evolved from these and apes in
hominids and humans are the direct
descendants or in the direct ancestors
so directly descended from these
hominids children's these are the
closest living human relatives because
they share about 98.4% of their nuclear
DNA gorillas and humans to share about
97.7% but that in perspective what
percentage of your genes do you share
with other organisms well it's about 98%
with the chimpanzees 92% of the mouse
leaving up 44% with the fruit fly 26%
with yeast and 18% with the plant so you
can see there is still a fair amount of
overlap
even though
it might be very different compared to
organisms that might even be in
different kingdoms comparing Apes to
hominids you see our similar structures
in the same colors here there's also
some distinct big differences
so the femur in this case is angled out
here our fumer signal in our pelvis is
for us is bull shaped for the chimpanzee
it's long and narrow and you can see
again some of the comparisons that are
derived here the common ancestor for
both beeps and hominids sought to have
been in a burl climber comments became
bipedal which means walking upright by
meaning to pedal mean walking walking
upright with two legs hips evolved
knuckle walking and that's what you kind
of see here they're kind of hunched over
appearance there's an technical
differences between the two are related
to a by local motion so when you're
walking upright certain things are going
to kind of shift in shape to make it
more efficient and if you're what's
called a knuckle Walker kind of hunched
over a lot
so the concept of bipedalism seems to
evolved as our ancestors left dense
forests progressives and open woodlands
so if you're in the most of trees
there's a lot of overgrowth this kind of
knuckle walking hunched over way of
getting around might be advantageous
however when you go to the open field
here how bright and bipedalism is
definitely favored questions did pie
bipedalism proceed or succeed brain
enlargement you know which came first
fossils on earth in Africa demonstrate
that bipedalism
exceeded extended back four million
years ago substantial brain expansion on
the other hand did not appear until two
million years ago so this evidence
suggests that bipedalism occurred before
brain expansion as I mentioned
bipedalism if you've seen videos online
maybe of dogs walking with purses here
upright this is not an example of true
bipedalism this is simply an animal
that's kind of learned to kind of walk
upright the true bipedalism here we see
the change in structural features
causing it to be more efficient for that
particular organism to walk in this
upright fashion