this in the a brief overview of the
Integra Atari system and even though you
may not know initially what that means
by looking at the picture here and
probably guess we're going to be dealing
something to do with our own skin so
starting with the basics Integra might
actually mean skin and skin and it's
appended make up the Integra teri system
that's why it's a system so we're at is
talking about skin so with the
appendages such as nails and hair and
they'll be future videos on that skin is
a contain Asst membrane that and is our
largest organ our skin alone accounts
for about seven percent of our body
weight so kind of important to keep this
in mind that this is covering our entire
body
it makes up 7% of our body weight so for
every hundred pounds you have about
seven pounds of just skin weight when we
talk about the dermis and the epidermis
and this cutaneous membrane is a
combination of both of those in this
system I'm talking about remember we're
also involving nails and also hair so
regions of the skin so just to go over a
couple two distinct regions we have the
epidermis epi meaning top and then the
dermis being the low lower level but the
lowest level here is the subcutaneous
level or the hypodermis this is a fatty
layer and it lies deep within the layers
of the skin so it's important to keep in
mind at first two distinctive regions
are the epidermis and that's the layer
that you can physically see and any of
the dermis below that and then the
subcutaneous or the hypodermis and
they're kind of used entertain ibly
lying beneath that and it tends to be
fatty meaning it contains adipose tissue
so some of the functions of the skin
there's a couple of major ones
protection cushions insulates and acts
as well waterproofing protects the skin
from chemicals heat cold bacteria in
screens UV light ultraviolet light can
think of it like a spacesuit as offering
protection from us from the harsh
outside environment synthesizes vitamin
D with UV light so it puts together
vitamin Davies just sunlight to help us
sum all that necessary vitamin regulates
body heat it helps with the adipose
tissue prevents unnecessary water loss
and contains sensory receptor or nerve
endings involved in the integumentary
system there's a couple major
functions here of the skin moving out as
a nice picture of the internment system
its components you're going to see this
image quite a bit while initially right
now some of these terms may sound a
little bit unfamiliar hopefully by the
end of this lecture series a lot of
these will make sense and you'll be able
to identify where they're located and
also their important function for the
body so the epidermis provides is the
most top layer with stratified squamous
epithelium that's just the type of cells
is what it looks like
there's several distinct layers and
there's two different types of skin
there's what we call thick skin which is
five layers and found on the palms of
your hand and soles of your feet and
then thin skin which is four layers and
basically covers the rest of your body
thin skin also is where hair follicles
are located thick skin is five layers
and does not contain any hair follicles
to give you just a quick comparison of
thin versus thick skin we could see the
epidermis here thickness on that thin
skin and where the skin is thicker it's
yet epidermal layer being much larger
much thicker in that region so skin
contains four basic types of tissue is
epithelium connective tissue which is
part of the dermis muscle tissue and
nervous tissue so right now I'm just
gonna kind of go over those basic tissue
types
there'll be other videos that go through
and discuss the muscle system
let's go system and the nervous system
but right now I just know it's made of
these four basic types of tissue the
dermal layer so we're getting a little
deeper into the skin now this is the
second major layer strong flexible
tissue often referred to as the hide so
you can see the animal hide here it's
isn't made up of mostly the dermal layer
rich supply of nerves and the vesicles
here critical role in temperature
regulation and it has two layers its
papillae layer which involves the dermal
papilla and the rectal layer which is
deeper layer and composes about 80% of
the thickness of the actual dermis off
lecture lines are creases in the palms
so I don't write can read palms like
maybe tell me my future there but this
is looking at the dermal layer this is
what's giving the actual ridges to the
palm in
new noggin a little deeper here to the
subcutaneous layer or hypodermis these
terms are kind of used interchangeable
you can see here hypodermis is actually
greek for below skin and subcutaneous is
actually latin for below skin
so those translate to the same just
again note one wanted really preferred
over the other be able to recognize both
there's a composed of loose connective
tissue adipose is an example stabilizes
the skin position loosely attached to
the dermal and muscle tissue so again
we're down here on the lower region this
is kind of tying this in this upper
epidermis and dermal layers and also
containing our veins and arteries and
some of our nerve endings in this
beautys layer hypodermis contains fat
cells different patterns of accumulation
based on male or female for those fat
deposits provides thermal insulation of
adipose tissues really great about and
cushions underlying organs another
important function remember the
hypodermis reserves hypodermic needles
and getting the other injection it's
being injected down into this hypodermic
layer again we've seen this picture
before hopefully now we're starting to
put together a couple pieces in other
videos you'll notice where some of these
other terms are also mentioned so this
entire image does not make sense to you
now hopefully we're starting to put
pieces and bits together as far as kind
of key items you should know at least
from this lecture looking at what's be
able to identify the epidermis dermis
hypodermis and some of the other regions
will become in the future there