continuing with our skeletal system or
if arrived at the pelvis and we're going
to learn about the bones that are fused
together that make up this structure
that you may have heard of called
the hip bone so these hip bones it's
important that they're very strong and
maintain their integrity because the
total weight of the upper body rests on
this region this region also protects
several organs such as the reproductive
organs the urinary bladder and portions
of the large intestine also the area
where that femur articulates with so the
pelvis is composed of three fused bones
these are not independently mobile they
are fused together with the ilium
located here the ischium located here in
purple and then the pubic bone so and
that's okay too right here the sacrum
which is in green here and here anterior
and posterior view is part of the
vertebra so it's important that we make
that distinction of separation is
technically not part of the pelvis
region here that hippo you could see
here again our three bones composed
together fuse together make that hip
bone up
remember that sacrum is part of the
vertebral column it is not part of the
total hip bone gender differences of the
pelvis so if you want to identify a
skeleton as being male or female you
typically look at the hip bone here now
rather than memorize degrees and numbers
for women it's 80 to 85 a little bit
wider angle what's up with the birthing
process and men 50 to 60 degrees there's
kind of little tricked here so if you
take your hand and the angle formed the
pubic arch is approximately the angle
between the thumb and index finger that
would be indicated that would be a woman
the skeleton however if the angle
between the index finger and the middle
finger if it matches this then we're
looking at it's probably a male so this
can help you identify quickly a male or
female skeleton by simply looking at the
pelvis in the degree that we find here
at the pubic arch