this is going to be a very brief
introduction to the appendicular
skeleton because I'm breaking apart into
all individual pieces this one's only
going to focus on this shoulder girdle
here so the bones of the pectoral girdle
or the shoulder grill here are called
the scapula just the shoulder blade
that's okay
here and the clavicle you took you may
know as the collarbone these bones allow
the upper limb to have exceptionally
free movement so that's how they
participate in the skeletal system now a
and B we should be familiar with our
views of the body and be able to
identify those so our scapula right
prosti review and i'm not going to make
you memorize all the different parts for
at least in my class but the bones of
the scapula it should be able to orient
or highlight where this would be located
if we're looking at the right prosti
rear view of the scapula in contrast to
that this is the right anterior view so
remember Oscar is going to be in the
back that's looking at it kind of in
this way and then the anterior view is
can be looking at this way and see it's
much smoother on this region so it's
that quick overview of the scapula and
the clavicle the initial start to the
lesson on the appendicular skeleton