okay here we look at the inflammatory
response process now I like the image
included here of our foot showing
different degrees of inflammation with
this toe having the greatest degree of
redness we're going to learn about a
little bit more it's occurring at the
cellular level when we see this external
appearance on our skin so starting with
in general the inflammatory response
well it all starts with an injury and
ultimately it leads to the healing
process we may think of when we hear the
term inflammatory such as some of the
negative factors the redness the
swelling the heat in the pain but
essentially that is part of the healing
process and ultimately this is what has
to go through the body in order to try
to eliminate sources of infection so
that proper healing can occur
now inflammatory response here is our
skin and we have an injury a cup for
example in that skin we notice it's red
and the presence of bacteria here our
leukocytes or white blood cells are
leaving the circulatory system to invade
this area to try to prevent infection
now in general this inflammatory
response is triggered whenever the body
tissues are injured again in this case
we're looking at skin tissue the whole
goal is whole purpose of this is to
limit the spread of damaging agents such
as the bacteria also the body needs to
dispose of debris pathogens and this
sets the stage by out cleaning up this
area of potential sources of infection
this is the stage for a proper healing
or repair process looking at this image
we notice that three main stages are
occurring first we have injured tissue
there's up here and we're noticing our
leukocytes are entering that area here
this this leukocyte particular this mass
cell is really seen Piston chemicals are
causing the blood vessels to expand and
become more permeable and that's causing
a redness and swelling so this image
doesn't do a great job of showing the
redness and the swelling but what is
causing that redness in that swelling is
the red blood cells or the red blood
vesicles here becoming more permeable so
causing the redness and the swelling we
have this influx of red blood cells this
influx of white blood cells also to the
area neutrophils and then monocytes and
macrophages migrate to the site of
infection or injury so they're working
their way through these we'll sell them
at the dermal cells and they're working
their way to that initial cut and here
we're noticing some bacteria are being
taken in and destroyed eliminating the
chance they could get into the
circulatory system
now acute inflammation kind of we've
seen this picture simulator before but
shows the histamine being released and
here we see the white blood cells or
leukocytes exiting out the vesicle here
and entering the area where the
pathogens are present so mast cells
detect injury and nearby cells release
histamine initiating the inflammatory
response
histamine increases the blood flow to
the wound site we see an increased
amount of redness and increased vascular
permeability allowing fluid proteins
phagocytes and other immune cells to
enter in connective tissue these events
result in the swelling the redness of
the injury site due to the increase in
blood flow they can also feel warm if we
ever have that injury that occurs
inflammations also state of pain do the
events of stealing nerve pain receptors
that could be because of the initial cut
site or could be also because of the
cascading of events that's occurred now
signs of inflammation there's five main
ones we're looking redness clearly
evident here the feeling of heat and
swelling Evans pain and potential loss
of function in the inflammation area so
these are five cardinal signs of acute
inflammation as occurring histamine such
I mentioned before they help our body
get rid of irritants such as allergens
they can make you sneeze too you're up
pitch to help remove that irritant so a
lot of times we associate these with
being negative associations here's our
LR histamines typically our bass cells
are the ones that's inducing those
histamines and causes inflammation and
our increased mucus production so if
this is in relation to an allergen
this look that is very negative but it
can be advantageous in an inflammation
sense to help increase the blood flow
there and increase the white blood cells
now in relation to an allergy we have
things called anti histamines they're
chemicals or drugs taken in order to
reduce symptoms of allergic reactions
they block histamine which we see here
they're blocking some of those receptors
released from the mast cells they
decrease the incidence of symptoms
caused by histamine response so because
history is not able to bind all these
receptors the response is dulled and
this is what some of benadryl Allegra's
are tagged claritin some of these anti
histamines function in this very similar
format where they're able to block some
of the receptors clog up some of those
pores reducing the effectiveness of the
histamine reducing the allergic response
that we have you do some of the redness
and the swelling and the tearing and all
the negative associations that we have
with allergies