as the title suggests we're going to be
investigating the stomach in a little
bit more detail in this video lecture so
the stomach and its gastric glands we're
going to focus on the stomach is a
sac-like portion of the track and it's
kind of lipid surface enabling expansion
you can get larger and smaller and
adjust to the contents that it may have
it needs an extra layer of smooth muscle
for mixing food its gastric juices it
doesn't just hold it and sat they can
kind of move in mix as two kinds of
cells parietal cells which are the cells
that are secreting hydrochloric acid
into cells which are secreting
pepsinogen so we see that examples here
are parental cells in our chief cells
those secreting the respective
substances this is very important for
our digestive process see a zoomed in
portion here notice that the stomach as
we look at it the interior layer here so
these deep pits areas well this is where
these secretions are occurring and
they're ultimately coming out here and
this is why it's important during the
mixing process not only to get the
hydrochloric acid pepsinogen out but to
allow that food to have some form of
mechanical the digestion as well as this
chemical digestion thalassemic stomach
produces about two liters of
hydrochloric acid and other gastric
secretions every single day so it's kind
of a staggering amount when you think
about it the gastric juice has a pH of
approximately two so it's very acidic
this pH kills most bacteria in jessup of
the food and also denatures food
proteins this is a good thing as we want
to start to break them down the mixture
of partially digested food and gastric
juice is called chyme if you remember in
our mouths when we start adding saliva
that we called a bolus and now when
we're mixing these gastric juices it now
becomes time time leaves the stomach
than the small intestine
through the pyloric sphincter remember
sphincters can open and close and that's
what's allowing a portion of this food
hopefully after it's been at least
partially digested to start entering
this small intestine
keep in mind it goes from esophagus to
stomach to small intestine not the large
intestine or gastric anatomy in general
it's during ingested food mechanical
breakdown
with ingested food disruption of
chemical bonds these very harsh acidic
environment and also the enzyme that
produces production of intrinsic factor
and this glycoproteins required for
absorption of vitamin b12 in the small
intestine so not only is it performance
from breakdowns it's also setting up the
ingested food items for the next step
the stomach reforms primary digestion of
proteins by pets in so some digestion of
carbohydrates but cell they're amylase
and lipids by the lingual lipase is
occurring what's important about the
stomach is that it becomes more fluid
and around about two years of day I was
just hydrochloric acid it's a low pH
around to pepsin activity increases so
we may think of enzymes always working
at a neutral pH and that's not the case
IFS antigens actually has improved
activity at a more acidic range protein
disassembly is starting to begin here
and although the digestion occurs in the
stomach nutrients are not absorbing
that's a very important point to make
here this is purely digestion both
chemical in mechanical but we have not
absorbed anything yet both acid and head
for hydrochloric and pepsin the form of
the enzymes in the gastric juices and
our muscular contractions also occurring
in the stomach
we've put important for the digestion
process digestion is different than
absorption so ulcers too much acid or
bacterias is kind of interesting the
hormone gastrin regulates the synthesis
of hydrochloric acid increases our
enzyme production overproduction of
gastric acid can occasionally eat a hole
through the stomach wall scalded gastric
ulcers these are actually quite rare
actually what's been shown is there's
actually this bacteria that will infect
the cell walls and that can cause ulcers
to occur over 90% of the
gastrointestinal ulcers are duodenal
ulcers and that's our small intestine
there it's caused by too much time in
the small intestine too much of that
acid escaping out of the stomach and
going in to the small intestine however
here this bacteria here is entering and
breaking down the mucous cell wall I'm
getting ultimately to those layers of
the epithelial tissue and
that break in that kind of barrier here
he's leading to that ulcers that burning
that occurs
so actually ulcers in the stomach while
originally thought to be solely caused
by high acid production hydrochloric
acid in particular it's actually been
related in many cases to the presence of
this particular bacteria that's causing
this h pylori is causing this kind of
eating away of that protective layer
causing ulcers in form so in this case
it would be better to take an antibiotic
than an antacid to help reduce the
presence of these ulcers lastly
heartburn or acid reflux what's
occurring here this strong acid this
burning feeling in the chest caused by
the stomach on the acid coming up the
esophagus this is typically due to a
faulty esophageal sphincter you see here
that acid is able to sneak its way up
causing that burning sensation this
occurs especially when you're lying down
and when you lie on your right side
because when it's more important on the
right side if that's kind of the way the
stomach's oriented it's easier for those
gastric hydrochloric acid and acids in
the stomach to kind of leak out that
esophageal sphincter if it is in fact
salt