and this debaco University video I'm
going to go over the many uses of hybrid
peroxide in the garden which include
going over how it can help improve your
seed germination how it can utilize it
to sterilize your tools as well as
control potential foliar as well as soil
based diseases so come along and learn
about how this very simple product can
have multiple uses for your benefit in
your garden
[Music]
thank you
now first off we should start with
basically what is hydrogen peroxide so
it's a simple molecule H2O2 light can
break it down and basically cause the
original molecule to form into water and
oxygen in the gaseous formed there so
kind of a pretty benign end products
here water and oxygen gas this is part
what makes the end result so safe you
know we want to be careful with the
original product
so the general mode of action how does
something so simple work it's
essentially the decomposition process
releases an oxygen and produces a
hydroxyl free radical that damages
proteins in DNA and that's where it can
kind of help reduce the presence of
certain diseases certain bacteria
certain funguses and potentially even
viruses it's basically how it works
however from a user standpoint we want
to be aware and cautious of hydrogen
peroxide because it is does have a
strong oxidizing agent it's also a
mucous membrane irritant and can cause
what's called peroxide burn if you get
it on you in high concentrations it'll
literally turn your skin white if you're
applying especially higher
concentrations in closed environments
you will feel potential irritation on
your mucous membranes and if you spill
it anywhere if you I be advised that
it's an oxidizing agent can also be
corrosive
what are some of the advantages of using
this though uh then as I hinted to it
before it can kill both fungi and
bacteria as well as algae copper also
fits into this category but has many
other issues such as interactions with
other products can have photos toxicity
you can have long residuals can also be
an environmental contaminant if you're
adding a lot of copper fungicide
hydrogen peroxide really does not have
any of those negative effects so and
also there's no residue left behind so
other products you may have applied you
may go back after it dries on the leaves
and get kind of this white residue that
will not happen with hydrogen peroxide
however no product is perfect so here
are some disadvantages it does have a
very short residual time meaning it
doesn't last for very long I'm not very
you know light as I said breaks it down
so it doesn't last very long this can
require frequent applications and can
only kill what it comes in contact with
so that means if you're not getting good
spray coverage or good even spray
coverage you're not going to really see
the benefits as much as you would if
you're getting uniform consistent spray
coverage there and really a fine
coverage as well will help increase the
effectiveness of this product
now it's important to note at this point
that I'm not sponsored by any particular
company all products were purchased at
retail cost there's no sponsorship of
any kind and the products mentioned here
so keep that in mind uh that this is my
honest opinion based on what I've gone
out and purchased just like you can
now there are some common hydrogen
peroxide that is typically found to be
around three percent it does come
typically in a light block container you
want to avoid high heat as well as
shaking and it does have a shelf life
that will be listed on there the reason
why you don't want to shake it is by the
shaking motion of it it will cause the
degradation of that product which want
to be mindful of the shelf life and not
that it necessarily goes bad and will
cause any harm just the percentage
listed that three percent will start to
degrade and break down from there you
can also store it in a cool environment
that'll help prolong the life of the
product as well
there's also General concentrated
hydroponic hydrogen peroxide products as
I said were mentioned here in the garden
so these concentrated products shown
here even though they might be food
grade around the 10 to 35 percent and
they are typically found off label Pool
Products sterilizers or something like
that it is recommended that you purchase
a product for your intended purpose and
follow the printed label so while these
might be the same product if they're not
recommended for agricultural purposes
they're not going to be the focus here
even though they say food grade that's
for food consumption grade that's not
necessarily assumes that they can be
applied to food based on the label
so agricultural focused products are
going to be the ones again focused here
biosafe systems as product lines what
I'm going to focus on they have items
that you may be familiar with such as
xero tall oxidate sanidate and
terraclean
now the four main uses that I'm going to
dive into detail here are going to be
how hydrogen peroxide can help improve
seed germination how it can be used to
sterilize tools how it can be applied
for foliar diseases as well as soil
treatments for soil-borne diseases so
we're going to focus on these four in
great detail and hopefully give you some
specifics
so first off the improved seed
germination so soaking in plain water is
effective and for known difficult seeds
adding gibberellic acid or gas is
suggested however gas have a shelf life
can be hard to get and acquire a
specific PPM or parts per million
concentrations to really be effective
this is why some growth will suggest
adding kelp to the water of seeds and
you know are going to be soaked but this
is typically a random dilution with
inherent variability of the hormone
concentration so even if it does help
it's not really a repeatable method in
contrast to this using hydrogen peroxide
has been proven to increase germination
rates it's needed low concentrations
it's easy to get and can be used for
other purposes both in and out of the
growing area
so this is a research article here that
I'm going to pull some data from but I
always like to provide the original
protocols so you can take a look here if
you wanted to know any of the
information this is the research data
original article I'm going to give you a
brief summary here
so the research findings again this is
kind of an idea of what they were
looking at to get to the result they
looked at seed sterilization germination
and ceiling development were carried out
in hydrogen peroxide solution at
different concentrations and in short
they found that one percent hydrogen
peroxide solution showed the fastest and
most efficient germination High
germination efficiency for very old
seeds with lower viability was also
demonstrated in their study this
protocol demonstrates that Superior
germination compared to water control
and reduces the risk of contamination
making it suitable for tissue culture
and other sensitive applications as well
as any applications you might be going
into such as rock wool or soil or
soilless media any of that this water
control compared to the one percent and
even went higher than one percent but
one percent was shown to be the most
effective
that seed soaking solution here and
again I'm just showing you regular
generic store purchased hydrogen
peroxide is really what I recommend here
the goal is to generate that one percent
solution uh because this is a three
percent solution so it's one part hydro
peroxide and two parts water I give you
some examples here in both ounces as
well as milliliters so you can
effectively or easily get to that one
percent concentration ultimate
concentration from that three percent
solution for those that want to know the
math behind it it's C1 V1 equals c2v2
where you've got concentration of the
original material and volume of the
original material equaling the
concentration and the volume of the
resulting material there so you can go
through and do your calculations as you
see fit
now I mentioned something else that
hydrogen peroxide can also be used to
sterilize tools frequent cleaning of
tools can help prevent the grower from
being a vector for disease just in
spreading from one plant to another
instead of you pruning one plant going
to another Or Another We're spreading
that disease putting your tools or
soaking your tools in this can help
reduce that chance having a small
container of what's called sanity
solution can make it easy for Growers to
do quick submersion of the tools they
are using to Simply Clean it note though
if viruses are the main concern milk
would be advised for the specific
purpose as the protein coat the virus
particles in the proteins from the milk
I should say coat the virus particles to
reduce the chance of the virus binding
to plant cells and this was common
practice for Planters of tobacco dipping
their hands in milk to again prevent
them from being vectors or spreading
tobacco mosaic virus
now tool sterilization solution note
this is not a cleaner so if the tools
are being used are very dirty be sure to
remove the other means the bulk of the
organic matter on that then we could see
that these are quote dirty tools here
with a lot of the soil or sand or just
generally organic material essentially
the tool should be pre-cleaned for this
to have maximum Effectiveness meaning
the hydrogen peroxide will be much
reduced in Effectiveness if you have
these dirt particles here already you
want to kind of clean them maybe with
soapy water and then follow up with a
peroxide treatment and you'll get the
most Effectiveness from that treatment
now the solution here um should make it
fresh daily once diluted the solution
should be used for that day or even
potentially less if you're doing a high
volume
if exposed to direct sunlight this will
speed up the degradation process as well
so keep that in mind essentially the
active ingredient will start to break
down and become less effective if it's
stored for a long period of time so just
as we see here we have a clear container
clearly some tinge to that container
probably these tools put in there a
little dirty it's going to much less
effect in this and if it was a light
block container and the tools were
pre-cleaned before and then dipped in
the sanity solution if you're using it
frequently for example tomato pruning
you may want to make a new mix of
solution midday to help ensure the
maximum and consistent sterilizing power
of the original solution
now two sterilizers with that
concentration what should we be looking
at to keep our tools not only visually
clean but also clean of potential
diseases so when cleaning tools the
higher end of the range can be used with
little threat of damage to the tool
plant or user so you can can favor a
little bit on the higher end of the
scale it will always look like a clear
water solution so be sure to put it in a
special labeled container so you and
others know that that is a hydrogen
peroxide solution at the end of the day
a final submersion in the solution
followed by a rinse can help reduce the
chance of corrosion of the equipment so
we don't want to just like leave it
soaking on there because it could it
could damage your equipment if you're
doing it daily and for long soaks you
want to just give it a quick rinse
afterwards hopefully keep your tools
nice and clean and also giving them a
long life
now what I recommend specifically for
this would be the sanitate 5.0 product
typically 1.6 to 5.4 fluid ounces of
this product with 5 gallons of potable
water typically a conversion of that
would be 47 160 milliliters to 19 liters
of potable water the ideal solution for
controlling plant and human health
pathogens on a variety of hard
non-porous surfaces such as floors
tables benches tools equipment restrooms
and more are listed and try to provide
you with the label here an example of
the product but by all means take a look
at this maybe in more detail and look at
the full extensive specimen label before
purchasing anything
now the third item that I mentioned was
foiler applications this is one of the
few bacteria sites that exist in general
but it also does work on fungus as well
now here's kind of a list of everything
that it can that's on the label for leaf
and soil based pathogens and this is for
zero tall 2.0 and I just kind of
highlighted two here Alton area a very
common one this is what it looks like on
the leaves and powdery mildew also what
it looks like on the leaves now again as
stated on the label tobacco mosaic virus
is listed but again if viruses are your
main control I think there's products
that are more effective but you can see
it's not just alternator powdery mildew
fuserium which we'll talk about at the
end anthracnose botrytis Downing mildew
potentially as well pythium rusts and
scabs so we can see a wide variety
listed at least on the label
so advantage to the foiler application
is that there simply is no residue this
reduces the chance of burning the plant
causing phyotoxicity be sure to follow
the recommended concentrations as with
high concentrations there can be
peroxide burn of the plant material if
you're mixing it too strong so there is
still a chance of that burning but the
ideal is no residues so by keeping those
concentrations falling there's not just
adding a little bit more that's what's
going to cause the peroxide or the
chance of a peroxide burn be mindful of
that essentially the product does break
down into water and oxygen gas but if
it's too concentrated there is that
always run that risk of that just like
on your hands that peroxide burn but
regardless this will be no residue
leaving your leaves nice clean and shiny
with no white spots or chance of
interactions with products applied after
or even before
now the complete coverage is really
important so with this and really any
other contact product good plant
coverage is very important as this has a
direct impact on the effectiveness of
the product so we could see here find a
medium course Very coarse or extra
coarse kind of sprays in the gallons per
acre suggested applied could also take a
card and kind of get an idea of your you
know what kind of coverage you're
getting investing in a good applicator
or applicating equipment is advised as
well as the applicator themselves taking
the time to do it properly
a Mr or fogger uh where aloud offers the
greatest coverage in a short period of
time that is also a very reliable and
repeatable process
hand pump mechanical spares can be used
but time should be used to help ensure
complete plant coverage which can be
time consuming to do properly so again
just keep that in mind
now getting into the Fuller application
solution so the recommended product
xeritol or oxidate they're both Omri
listed would be in this category note
that both of these have the same active
ingredients in concentrations and also
the same EPA registration numbers as we
can see right here and right here note
that sometimes one is approved to be
applied while the other may not be so
check your local regulations and I would
recommend you check them yearly because
sometimes things can change
uh for example oxidate in at least one
state as a restriction that no further
applications are allowed but xeritol
does not have this same restriction so
be aware of that getting the 5.0 is a
more concentrated version of the 2.0 and
you simply use less so even if you're
getting like for example oxidate 2.0
versus 5.0 be aware of that because your
dilution rates are going to change the
amount of product you're going to need
to add of the 5.0 is of course going to
be less than the 2.0 so again just as a
reminder for that to reduce the chance
of you doing unintentional plant damage
now other last one mentioned here was a
soil treatment I'm going to give you a
little bit of a background on this as
well and as well as an in-field example
so this is where hydrogen peroxide is
showing greater interest and some
initial results are the reason for its
continued use some areas have strict
regulations on products for controlling
soil-based diseases and this is really
for good reason as these can have long
residuals and negative impacts on
non-target environments so certain
fumigation products well initially
showed some promise the kind of risk
reward benefit the risk the environment
it's a little bit higher than should be
really allowed in some cases and the
benefits were shown to be in some cases
variable at best
so the soil treatment hydrogen peroxide
can control a wide range of soil-based
diseases with low residual so it will
not have long-term negative impacts on
the environment it is much easier and
cost effective compared to steam
sterilization and while steam
sterilation may be the better option
it's not easy to do it is costly in both
labor and equipment so this offers
another alternative that might be a
better utilized by more people to get
some Effectiveness rather than doing
nothing if they cannot perform true
steam sterilization
so looking at the site prep here so
there are still some site prep to that
should be implemented to help improve
the effectiveness of hydrogen peroxide
if you're going to be using utilizing it
as a soil drench so first off you want
to clear the crop residue
some can be on the surface and or
partially incorporated into the soil but
a lot of plant residue will simply
reduce the soil penetration so we want
to have it like this would be okay this
would be considered to be okay we don't
want to have like a large amount of
residue simply going to reduce the
amount of percolation you're going to
get
um so just keep that in mind the soil
surface should be quick or kind of rough
till to allow for greater percolation
into the soil profile you don't want to
have like a style solid locked up layer
there you want to kind of have it start
to be kind of broken up to allow that
water to penetrate to allow that
peroxide also to penetrate quickly into
that soil profile ideally after
application you should not till the soil
as this will just dilute the soil
clearing cleaning that you performed
because if you basically kill the and
clean up the first inch and then you go
to mix it up well now you've just kind
of reduced the amount of effectiveness
of that product however you can do a
post application until if you think the
main concentration of pathogen is just
in that very top surface I mean you can
incorporate there if that's where your
target is
soil should have some moisture to it
more water will be added as you drench
but this if the soil is dry this reduces
the water movement to the soil profile
if that soil is already moist the
capillary action will take that water
deeper and offer better cleaning of that
soil and removal of those pathogens
now what solution to recommend for this
well terraclean 5.0 this is recommended
as intended for outdoor soil based
applications prior to planting the rate
at three gallons of terraclean in 275
gallons of water over a thousand square
feet this produces a 300 part per
million solution which is the rate being
suggested by other growers in what seems
to be generally accepted so giving you
that kind of at least a good starting
point
now looking at some specifics to
remember when we're looking at a soil
based treatment when using terraclean
5.0 it's important to have everything
ready to go as the last step is the
mixing and the applying an evening
application is preferred to reduce the
UV light which will break down the
hydrogen peroxide as this will simply
degrade it so if you're applying it in
times of low light that just increases
the odd that it will last even just that
little bit longer
once you once the concentrate is mixed
is added and mix it well and apply it do
not let it sit for expand periods of
time because it will start to break down
and that's a good thing you want it to
break down because you want that's the
breakdown process and what's going to
allow that Effectiveness but if you kind
of mix it all and kind of wait and hang
around and have a bright sunny day
that's just simply going to reduce that
total concentration I always like to
think of it's kind of like you know
setting up for a pit stop you know you
come in everything's prep to go you get
everything ready to go and you kind of
turn it around pretty quickly because
that breakdown is again what you want
but this makes it effective but it
should also be occurring in the soil and
you don't want to be occurring in the
tank or where you don't have that
pathogen present
now how do you go about delivering this
well this can be applied via a diluted
in a large tank or injected the chemical
rejector uh the end result is
essentially the same so you can use a
diluted water tank or a chemical
injector it really doesn't matter the
same end concentration is really the
goal I do caution you if you are using
the injector system to make sure you run
plain water through the system when
you're done to reduce the chance of
corrosion on internal components of the
injector or any fittings you may have
the same would be advised for a tank
system to extrude your pump it doesn't
have that speeding up of any corrosion
so post soil treatment you can add back
beneficial microbes the manufacturer and
says these can be added only two hours
after the peroxide application this is
when the you may see some foaming of the
soil surface during the application when
that is basically dissipated you ideally
can add back your soil microbes however
giving the area an unofficial smell test
the microbes for in my case I did add
them 48 Hours post application as this
is when the distinctive hydrogen
peroxide smell could no longer be
detected and that's what I deemed it to
be safe to add the microbes back without
the chance of them being killed by the
peroxide there the manufacturer says and
it's definitely evident in the first two
hours there's definitely a lot of
reaction but I could just smell it a
little bit later I wasn't super rushed
so I did wait two days not the two hours
now moving on to the soil treatment in
the micro replenishment of the Terra
grow so following the manufacturer
recommendations Terra Grill was added to
the same area that was treated with the
Terra clean product 48 hours prior this
does contain allow classes and
beneficial microbes and was applied over
the same area with less water since the
soil was still saturated from the
original application keep in mind that
cold and cloudy conditions particularly
that of the early spring can induce
reduce evaporation now what the product
kind of looks like it's kind of a
powdered product you add it to water it
dilutes very well and very rapidly not
sure how important this step may be but
it was still followed based on the
recommendations from the manufacturer
and this is an Omri certified product
now there is soil treatment limitations
so this will not solve all of your
potential pathogen issues it does not
seem at least it does seem at least to
delay the onset of soil-borne diseases
this hydrogen peroxide treatment while
steam sterilization of the soil would be
the most effective the time cost and
labor to accomplish this is drastically
more than the hydrogen peroxide
treatment so again if you can still do
this steam sterilization that would be
advised but this may be prohibited for a
lot of Growers so this is offered as
another alternative
now how do we how does the soil
treatment of hydro peroxide compare to a
mustard cover crop well the advantage of
hydrogen peroxide treatment is that it
can be accomplished within 48 Hours of
removing the plant or even less if you
follow the two hours just by the
manufacturer could potentially all be
done in one single day this can help
allow the grower to select a soil
stabilizing cover crop instead of trying
to get a mustard crop up to flour
Incorporated sealed before getting to
the winter cover crop seeded seeded and
germinated in time for the end of the
season particularly for those growing
long long duration outdoor crops the
peroxide treatment followed immediately
with was followed I should say was
followed immediately with a grass seed
cover crop seems to be easy and
effective and ensures minimal soil
erosion and helps ensure a little bit of
a rotation there with a monocrop if
you're growing a dicot or other crop
there
now my personal experience here just to
give you a little bit of a background
here what I'm relating this to is that
while growing site was treated with this
hydrogen peroxide it did end up getting
lab confirmed root based view cerium
however I want to add a little caveat to
this the vine that was infected was
about the fifth from the end when the
plant was being removed all the older
growth and that's the growth that was
like original was clean on the internal
internal Vine portion as well as the
roots the pumpkin did develop a rot spot
leading to an unofficial weight but a in
a DQ at the way off we can see what it
looked like in Wade two days after
weighing the pumpkin was cut up we can
see the evidence right here and
expecting a rotten mess of soup on the
inside actually exactly the opposite was
observed the pumpkin was perfect on the
inside so no signs of raw so the seeds
were actually harvested and everything
was all great where the rat spot was was
an external rot not an internal rot so
even though there was lab diagnostic
serum in the portion of the plant it did
not get to the internals of the pumpkin
so this is a kind of sign that this
hydrogen peroxide treatment May
certainly have had some benefit we can
see how the leaves look during the
season which definitely kept them
healthier longer which is again another
positive experience
the looking back at the treatments we
could see here how they looked and they
degraded and this was the vine here that
was removed and because it was being set
to the lab where the kind of infection
originally started the Oddity of the
serum showing up on the newer growth and
while causing some plant issues not
getting into the pumpkin or really
traveling down the vine indicates low
levels of inoculum so why was there
fusarium and that's kind of the obvious
question that's fair to ask due to the
late season onset in the odd location
this is likely due to Simply missing an
area when performing the drench starting
area was small and basically caught
early and then isolated so be sure to
get the entire growing area when
performing this treatment because any
areas you miss could create a pocket of
a disease particularly soil-borne
disease that could spread to other
portions of the plant
now soil treatment going forward looking
at this you know what are my conclusions
based on what I've observed the plan is
to continue with this soil treatment to
reduce disease pressure while it may not
be 100 effective the delayed onset and
Mitigation Of most pressure sure makes
it more effective than many of the
harsher chemical options that exist and
I point you to this image here where the
newer growth versus the older growth the
older group of course had to be serum
first and then newer growth was still
healthy so again in case I found it
early but this again was later in this
season so you know to be able to support
over 1100 pound pumpkin definitely shows
that there were still some actively
growing plant material but I wanted to
remove that and take some plant out for
part of the study so it was interesting
to see where the isolation of the
disease actually was
so soil treatment other factors again
just trying to keep in mind is that this
is only a supplement for disease
mitigation plan cover crops are still an
important component so I want you to
think this is a replacement for cover
crops should be used in addition to
cover crops for many soil-based diseases
you want to reduce the chance of over
watering and excessive nitrogen
applications
so adding a lot of nitrogen fertilizing
over watering are going to encourage
Disease by you being aware of that and
knowing what you have that will help
naturally create an environment that
will allow diseases to naturally be able
to spread quite aggressively so keep
this in mind that there is a disease
trying to lead the host environment
pathogen this can be one thing to kind
of help reduce the amount of pathogen if
you keep up the other two and cover crop
and be mindful of your environmental
growing conditions this could be a
effective way to reduce the onset and
reduce the severity of a disease that
you're seeing in your crops