don't let the name fully is small
intestine this is a very important part
of the digestive system keep in mind
this also occurs this is where our food
items are directly entering after they
leave the stomach even from the stomach
to the small intestine and then to the
large intestine so stomach to small
intestine look at the small intestine a
little bit more detail it's the bodies
it's called true digestive that and what
does that mean well that is just that
kind of area of that mixing pot there of
where all of this food items is kind of
mixing occurring digested and also very
importantly absorbing that breakdown of
large molecules into smaller ones which
are then absorbed into directly into the
bloodstream the total length of the
small intestine is about nineteen and a
half feet there were about six meters so
it's quite the long tube that we have as
part of the digestive tract now within
that small intestine we have our villi
we also have our micro villi highly
increasing that surface area we see our
blood capillaries our venules are
allowing for this kind of increase in
surface area to help the body more
efficiently absorb nutrients because
that's a very important component of the
small intestine now what does that look
like
histology I have that kind of cutaway
here of our villi and our muscle layers
are absorbs sort of surface our lacteals
our capillaries or arteries or goblet
cells there's a lot going on in this
small intestine we can see that when all
the images here we can see the folds
that are occurring we can see the villi
and all that time graph here the micro
villi does they are really small here
these are the dots and all of this again
it's helping increase the surface area
to help the body be able to absorb which
is a very important function of the
small intestine nutrients more
efficiently so the starting with the
small intestine we just left the stomach
we're going to the duodenum this is the
first 10 inches approximately four
percent of the small intestine
Isis closest to the stomach is the
mixing bowl four pieces
be kind off in the stomach and digestive
secretions from the pancreas and also
the liver on close proximity near the
duodenum is the actual site of digestion
the pancreas secretes important
digestive enzymes there's many of them
the liver secretes bile salts into it
that make it easier for fats to be
digested it's also a separate video
lecture on liver there or even there's a
little bit more about what that secretes
and also the pancreas functions of the
dividing them it receives the time again
from the stomach first portion of the
small intestine it also is very
important that it neutralizes the acids
before they damaged if you have highly
absorbent of surfaces of the small
intestine to increase that pH from that
pH of 2 we need to bring it up a little
bit to that more closer to neutral and
even slightly basic moving on the
jejunum is the middle part of the small
intestine that's about 8.2 feet long in
this location there is chemical
digestion and also a very important
nutrient absorption that's occurring we
could see here the transverse section
how high that surface area to volume
ratio is and as this allowing food
passing through to very easily be
absorbed into the body very small villi
lots of these little kind of finger like
projections allowing the food passes
through for that to be absorbed in the
capillaries continuing on there the
ileum this is the final segment of the
small intestine this is also important
for absorption it's about eleven and a
half feet long well there's sphincters
that control the flow of material in the
ileum into the large intestine the
presence of goblet cells you see one
right here in a little zoom in here
these secrete mucus like seven's is
called mutants in the wall of a phillium
villi so again we also have this
important for secretion they help keep
everything lubricated as we're working
our way through the digestive process
lastly in our small intestine we have
intestinal secretions or watery soup you
know 1.8 liters per day enter this
intestinal lumen it moistens the kind
buffers acids we don't want to burn are
very important absorb ative surfaces
keeps digestive enzymes impressive
in solution it is the movements that
kind of arrives in the duodenum right
out of the stomach week Paris taluk
action here moving it towards the
jejunum this is not under central
nervous system control right instead of
that smooth muscle helping mix and move
our food after we leave the small
intestine we're then going to enter the
large intestine