okay here well the basic overview of
thermodynamics this picture gives you a
real quick summary or having a system
and its surroundings which are separated
by a boundary little more specifically
here the definition is the study of the
flow and transformation of energy in the
universe
thermodynamics directly translates to
heat changes it's only concerned with
large-scale observations let's look at
an example so the first law of
thermodynamics it's the law of
conservation of energy say set energy
can be converted but not created nor
destroyed an example that be here we
have our food energy here right energy
stored in the food and our chemical
energy that we eat is converted or
transformed into mechanical energy when
we run since energy cannot be created or
destroyed it can only be converted the
total energy before in the food items is
equal to the total energy after even
though a transformation occurred this is
the first law of thermodynamics the
second law of thermodynamics says that
energy cannot be converted without the
loss of usable energy energy lost I put
that in quotes here is converted to
thermal energy so we see our energy
before and this kind of box here and our
usable energy after is a smaller portion
even though if we add up the usable
energy after in the unusable energy
after we get the same amount it was this
unusable energy well this unusable
Energy's can be that thermal energy so
if we take a ball we balance it in the
same area again and again again it'll
actually be warmed the area where it
keeps bouncing will be warm there's a
transfer of thermal energy that energy
is what we call lost in the sense that
were not able ourselves to use it
however we still account for that energy
and it's still accounted for so the
total energy before is the same as the
energy after however we have to account
for some
that other energy that is considered
unusable and that typically is lost in
the form of heat even though we add up
that heat energy plus our usable energy
we will get the same amount whose again
we cannot create or destroy energy
hopefully it's a good quick overview of
thermodynamics