okay here I provide a brief overview of
the thoracic cage see some of the main
components here are costal cartilage you
kitted in red the sternum is that Center
bone here and then the ribs located on
the end here so starting with that kind
of bony thorax or rib cage
notice that the ribs are labeled 1
through 12 starting at the top here and
working your way down we have that
sternum at the end of the sternum skull
design fight process as the little kind
of portions to hang out down here see an
eye inversion here this is the superior
and inferior orientation this should
help you if you understand these terms
the orientation of the bone in the body
you could see the sternum or body of
that sternum here located right here
focus a little bit more on the ribs and
the cartilage and how these kind of
interrelate and how we can identify
different types of ribs so there's three
main classifications of ribs there's
true and also called fixed ribs these
are indicated in a red here these are
just rip tears that are directly or
indirectly attached to the sternum as we
can see there's a direct attachment and
here's kind of indirectly this white
region here is actually cartilage but
you see each is individually connected
to this sternum false ribs
our ribs eat through 12 - see down here
and they connect the sternum indirectly
via costal cartilages of the ribs above
that connect to the sternum directly any
what that basically means is here's our
two false ribs connecting here and this
cartilage then is joined together in
that connects directly to the sternum
here we're seeing a rib directly
connecting directly connecting directly
connecting to certain these false ribs
are all joined together and we'll see
that in another image this cartilage
that then joins to the sternum lesson
the floating ribs and is there in blue
and this one probably should also be in
blue right here refers to the lowermost
11 and 12 so actually this one should
have a little cartilage here there's so
called because they attached only to the
vertebra in the back here they do not
have a direct
to the sternum or cartilage of the
sternum these ribs are relatively small
and delicate and they include kind of
Cardinal cartilage at the very tip of
them can give you a little bit Orion
different orientation here the costal
cartilage are segments of the carlo's
that connects the sternum to the ribs
and helps extend the ribs into the
forward motion this College also
confirms to the elasticity within the
walls of the thorax allowing the chest
to expand in compressed during
respiration we see here our floating
ribs in the back and our false ribs here
and these are joining and attaching this
cartilage then attaches to the sternum
our true ribs are the ones right here
and they're directly attaching to the
sternum in the classroom we also have
skeleton you're welcome to take a look
at that and see how the different ribs
look how they're oriented and can you
identify what it's a false rib what's a
floating rib and what's a true or fixed
room