so this tobacco university video is
going to take into account the threat of
humans
to cannabis plants and this is the
threat of humans outside of the grower
your neighbors and people around you
what threats they can pose
to cannabis plants
[Music]
all right let's get into the threat of
humans to cannabis plants so first off
people
and the cannabis crops well after all
the challenges of growing people can be
another issue that's worth
mentioning two main methods of negative
impacts uh can be complaints as well as
physical damage
points some girls will set this signs up
stop you're on camera about the plants
that they're growing
uh they don't want us to want to see
they don't want to see anybody
they want anyone to steal anything and
rightfully so so
keep this in mind that humans are
another kind of quote unquote pest
need to be mindful of so when we're
looking at the complaint
end of things before you start growing
an operation it's wise to inform your
neighbors
for indoor growing this may mean the
need to add additional carbon filters or
other means to reduce odor of the plants
because some people simply just do not
like or can't stand the odor
outdoor growing it's a good practice to
let others know and show them paperwork
if you have it regarding your license to
ensure that they don't
necessarily get surprised all these
canvas plants going in
they know you're doing it in a legit
manner
then know your local regulations so no
matter the size of your operations know
your local and current laws regarding
regarding
cannabis cultivation some are very loose
regulations
others are much more stringent be aware
of the total plant number
number that you have in veg and flower
with those approved varieties and so on
you want to make sure you know your laws
your rules your regulations
and that you are also in compliance with
all of those now for outdoor growers
we're looking at the are suggested that
they may want to post signs that state
no trespassing at property boundaries
and also maybe inform people if they're
growing industrial hemp with no thc
to encourage people not to be removing
plants be also on the lookout for
trespassers as this can involve the use
of cameras in monitoring systems as we
see
right here i'll file a trespass action
request form if this applies to your
area if you do catch someone
this can offer a formal documentation of
that
secure your property use of fences can
make it clear boundary lines
patrol your properties this can help you
catch a potential issue early
utilize your local neighborhood watch
have others in your area contact you if
they see something suspicious
part of that local network all this is
advised
to try to limit the negative impact
other humans
can have on your cannabis crop