this is something a lot of growers may
not want to admit to
but the threat of burning their plants
with over application of nutrients
this debaco university video is going to
cover just that
[Music]
all right let's get in the threat of
nutrient burn to cannabis plants
so most growers tend to over fertilize
their plants nutrient burn is typically
a grower induced error
when they do not properly calculate the
nutrients needed by the plants
or think they need a little bit more
also growers typically think more
fertilizer can fix a wide range of
problems when it actually may cause more
than it would solve in this kind of leaf
structure here this kind of burning here
is evidence that maybe they over added
the nutrients to this small growing
plant
and caused it kind of to get this kind
of crinkled or stunted
look to it now you want to avoid
nutrient toxicity so follow
manufacturer's recommendations
know the ph values and concentrations of
your nutrient solution
favor on the low side and work to higher
concentrations after you see how the
plants react
if you go through an over add it can be
just the same negative effect as if you
were to under add
it is a whole lot easier to add a little
bit more than to try to take a little
away
now i want to be mindful to recognize
deficiencies and there's many of these
charts that exist
know what certain deficiencies look like
will help you ensure you can correct
problem
problems early on giving you the
confidence that you can identify
something early
so that you don't get into that chance
of reaching those toxic
or excessive levels in a plant tobacco
university also has more
cannabis specific videos on recognizing
nutrient deficiencies
you also want to know your fertilizers
so many fertilizers have a blend of
nitrogen phosphorus and potassium and pk
so do not make application for one
nutrient without considering the other
nutrients
meaning if you calculate the amount of
fertilizer to add for 120 parts per
milliliter of nitrogen
which if you're learning how to do that
search tobacco university for that
do not forget about the phosphorus and
potassium as this could lead to an
over-application of these nutrients
if you're only focusing in calculating
for nitrogen
also you want to be sure you have
specialty fertilizers on hand it may be
a good idea to have some fertilizers
that are nutrient specific
to ensure as a grower you can dial in a
fertilizer program if there's a
deficiency notice
this is recommended for at least
nitrogen and calcium magnesium should
have some specialty fertilizers on there
because this is typically something very
quick you need to add
and something cannabis plants require
you also want to know fertilizers
compatibility so we have some just some
example charts here
some fertilizers can be mixed while
others have reduced solubility and
others simply are incompatible
test your mix before adding it to your
plants and consult one of these charts
ahead of time
so you know you don't waste your time
making an incompatible uh
mix this just gives you some of the
various common fertilizers that might be
added
what's what's compatible what has
reduced solubility
and what is simply incompatible there so
be mindful of this
before you go through mixing fertilizers
so you don't do more harm
than good to the plant because if you
mix these two together and just go
through and apply it
you could cause nutrient burn if you
over apply it could cause nutrient burn
so just ensure that you're giving the
plants what they need not anymore
keep them at optimum level and they'll
be at the peak of efficiency