on this debaco university video we're
going to look at the threat of some
grower errors to cannabis plants since
we've all made mistakes when growing
here's going to be some helpful tips to
help you try to avoid some of those
common
grower errors
[Music]
now as we can see here these plants
definitely look a little stressed
could be excessive nutrients could be
improper ph but we're going to go over
the threat of grower errors to canvas
plants
so hopefully you don't make some of
these same errors
so first off realize that when you're
growing plants errors will be made as
growers errors will be made but
identifying them and limiting the
negative impacts they have
are important know your own errors
own your own errors if you will and
realize them own up to them
and then make adjustments from there
documentation is important to be able to
recognize an
error that may have been made a while
back that takes a little time to show up
in certain plants some are not immediate
some take time
and it's important to have that
documentation
you also want to be writing down your
dilution rates so as growers
typically use a lot of different
products that's nothing wrong with that
but have an area where dilution rates
are written down as a reference so you
can ensure you do not work from memory
also be sure to actually measure and
estimate the amount that's being added
and you can write it right on the bottle
have a set chart have a set paper you
always go to so you're not just going
off of memory
also check the ph in concentration of
anything that you're adding
to ensure any unnecessary plant stress
is added
be sure to check your solution to avoid
something being applied that is outside
of the expected range these blue
guardian
monitors if you temperatures the ph
values the concentrations
also just a quick little pen here to go
through and check
can be a great way to ensure that you're
not going to give the plants any sort of
stresses
this is particularly important at the
very early stage or propagation stage
as plants are very susceptible to very
high doses of fertilizer can cause burn
or crinkling of leaves so be extra
mindful during that phase
to ensure you're not giving them
something that's way out the range of
the accepted ph
or concentration range to reduce the
chance of you inducing
any errors and negative impacts on your
tender cannabis plants