in this debaco university video we're
going to look at the threat of spray
damage to your cannabis plants
and how you can kind of factor should be
aware of and it can avoid this potential
issue
[Music]
all right let's look at the threat of
spray damage to cannabis plants
first off sometimes good intentions can
lead to damage
so when applying anything to plants be
sure it's worthwhile
if there is always risk of damage make
applications at times of low light and
reduce plant stress
to reduce the chance of damaging the
plants do not make applications because
you think the plant needs something
be product specific and spray with a
purpose meaning spray with something you
know the plants need
uh for a given reason if you're just
kind of like i think they need this
that risk to reward factor is definitely
in the chance
a greater risk than reward so what are
some sources
of plant damage so while many products
can be mixed sometimes
interactions can occur and this can
result in two products that are not
damaging on their own
can have phytotoxicity when they are
mixed
sometimes this can be seen upon
immediate mixture if you look at the
container before you go and apply it
other times it's only when it's applied
so be mindful of that
be cautious with any new mixes and
materials be sure to read the label of
both manufacturers product
for any possible interactions and
warnings also
be mindful of the method of application
whether it's a low pressure mister here
or a high pressure
gas-powered mister this is a great for
fogging an area but if the plants are
too close this could also cause some
physical damage to the plants
you using a spreader sticker to your
applications spreader stickers are great
additions to help coat the leaf surface
and increase the effectiveness of
products however a little goes a long
way with these items so do not over add
them
also with the increase in product
to the plant surface interaction this
can improve efficiency of products
so when in doubt go with the lower range
of concentrations if one is provided by
the manufacturer
i mean if the manufacturer gives you a
range i'll apply this from this rate to
this rate
and you're using utilizing a spreader
sticker you might be able to favor that
kind of
lower end of the range to not only use
less product
use less potential for contamination but
still get the same effectiveness because
you'll get a better coverage
here we can see an area where really
spreader sticker really isn't used
because all the water is in distinct
droplets
spreader sticker will cause it to kind
of form a sheet of water over the entire
leaf surface
improving the interaction now that
method of application i hinted to
earlier
when applying products to your plants a
forest spray application can increase
the likelihood of damage
mist blowers as i showed you earlier are
great for large operations
but be sure the true force of the air
blast is not applied directly to the
plants
stand back several feet a mist of
material
is all that's needed so position the
application to minimize potential
plant damage by physically forcing that
application
onto the leaves now you want to watch
out for young plant parts just in
general
when making an application you may want
to avoid the newest growing portions of
a plant
as these are not fully expanded it will
likely be the most sensitive to spray
products
and will likely become damaged damaging
new plant growth has also long-term
negative impacts on plant performance
because you could be damaging your
apical growing meristem or your side
branches
reducing the amount of plate material
you're going to get as you would expect
so lastly spraying during flowering the
flowering phase we can see right here
while you should be careful at any time
you're making applications to your
plants
during the flowering phase warrants
extra caution
late season spraying can increase the
likelihood of plants failing inspection
for pesticides
also you don't want to negatively impact
your final product
so while not advised it can be done just
with even more caution
than during other stages of plant
development so again be mindful what
you're spraying spray with a purpose
be careful of your application make sure
in the end you're doing more benefits to
the plant
than potential risk or harm to the plant