okay here we look at three kinds of
natural selection while in general on
the natural selection process is all the
same it's actually three ways you can
classify how a population is shifting so
the first one is stabilizing selection
and humans infants with intermediate
birth weight the highest rate of
survival as we see here we can see our
birth weight and our infant mortality
rate from type decreases dramatically
but then actually heavier babies can
also be at odds for infant mortality in
chicken eggs of intermediate weight of
the highest hatching success with this
stabilizing selection is is the before
it's just a normal kind of curve here
and the after has a little bit steeper
incline and that kind of that more of
that peak so just comparing here percent
mortality odds are if you find out what
you weighed when you were born
Zyra probably right around seven ish
pounds a little bit more a little bit
less doesn't mean every individual below
2 pounds dies it just means that the
likelihood of mortality is increased
another type of natural selection is
called disruptive selection where before
we had this mean and this could be kind
of like the gray rabbit here and then
all of a sudden we get this selection
for two ends of the spectrum with bird
beaks the intermediate bird beat it
could be a disadvantage
it could be unable to open a large seeds
and too clumsy to open small seeds
sometimes that middle ground is not the
advantage so in this case you either
want to be a black rabbit or a white
rabbit the great ones for ever reason
not advantageous so this just shows this
disruptive selection we're taking our
meal and selecting for basically both
extremes then there's directional
selection this is where we're taking our
mean and we're shifting it towards the
in this case the right flies that flew
towards the light world they made from
the population therefore the remaining
flies made it and the experiment
repeated for twenty generations and
we're selecting four in this case flies
that were unattractive to light this is
shifting the mean entirely so what once
was a very low
percentage of the population now becomes
the mean or the average this is
directional selection so those are the
three types this is another graphical
representation again showing that
disruptive selection are before
population and then we're selecting for
both extremes as indicated here where
for whatever reason this 10 is not the
best color you want to be a darker or
lighter color our stabilizing selection
where we're noticing that that middle is
the best or favored upon and we're
selecting against the extremes an in
directional selection or once our
population might have been short now
we're shifting towards eight taller
population