see thrips are another major problem for
growers in general this is kind of some
of the damage they can leave behind this
kind of stippling to the leaves here
it's like someone took a little rough
sandpaper and you're gonna scratch the
leaf surface is common thrip damage and
it's a pretty severe case pictured here
now I want to identifying thrips their
tiny slender insects and they tend to
jump since they're poor fliers and see
how a couple here very small very thin
kind of this tannish kind of yellowish
coloration almost see-through to some
extent and they don't travel very far
because they can't really fly that well
but they can kind of jump around if
disturbed they typically like to be
found in places that are low light now
we're to look for them when I check the
undersides of the leaves because they do
like that low light or within the
protection of flowers plants within the
stations we evident by the presence of
tiny black specks which are the feces of
the actual threats we're going through
inspecting them you do want to get close
and look this person kind of shooting
from the Sun this is an onion field but
looking deep down in an area where the
light is kind of minimal that stippling
we can see a zoomed in version of it
here and this is kind of how it looks a
little bit on the more macro scale now
how to prevent them and this is kind of
a zoomed in version and this is again
how small they look in relation to the
leaf when it inspect incoming plants or
cuttings when isolate throat infected
plants if they are identified because
they can easily kind of be cross
contaminating other plants you may have
nearby well we keep weed free barrier of
at least 10 feet around the greenhouse
we help discourage drips entry having
that 10 foot buffer kind of reduces the
chance that you're going to have a high
population very close to the greenhouse
would be very easy for them to come in
and infect your plants they also wanna
dispose of plant debris in tightly
sealed containers if you do identify
them I'd want to be just throwing them
away in open containers because they
could breed in there and get picked up
by fence or other carriers to get into
the facility how to control them will
due to resistance of many insecticides
more growers using biological controls
earth reps
there's commercially available natural
and
including predatory mites beetles and
insect killing nematodes and fungi that
can be used so a wide variety of
biological biological controls are
available for threats the beneficial
insect killing nematodes that are used
against the fondant snap larvae may also
be effective against their pupae in
growing media so it kind of gives you
that dual action control could link to
YouTube is if YouTube it video you want
to see it in action there and also a
document here for more information this
again shows you the trip getting
infected here with biological controls
perturb using at greater rates now that
there's a buildup to resistance to
common insecticides