in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over some of the timing of
cannabis compounds and how they're
accumulated
within the cannabis plant
all right let's get into timing of
cannabis compounds here looking at from
a scientific standpoint
so first off some data here if you want
to look at the original data always try
to include that
and that is here at the cornell hemp
association
they have a great little um information
that they've posted
online the link is right here i'll be
pulling some of the highlights of that
data here it's from a 2019
cbd cultivar trial so they were
comparing total potential cbdt
over time and they have their kind of
data presented right here
so total cbd and total thc accumulation
curves
for the 30 cultivars that they tested
and here's the color and here are the
cultivars they chose to use
most cultivars accumulate high levels of
cannabinoids by week two or three
and the top 10 centimeters of shoot tips
were sampled
and cannabinoids were qualified using an
hplc
high pressure liquid chromatography
across
most cult of our studies these cbd and
thc trends
seem to be similar but there are a few
standouts so when we look at the data in
general we're kind of seeing this
general trend or this increase here
overall
of our kind of cannabinoids here and
this is looking at cbd and this is
looking at
thc however there are a few standouts
and i tried to highlight those here on
our next
slide right here so two cultivars listed
here
peak their cbd levels before thc reaches
the maximum levels
however what i want you to realize is
that both of these produce tg levels
above
the federal limit of 0.3 threshold
so if we're looking at thc this dotted
line represents the federal threshold of
0.3 percent
and we could see this about all these go
well in excess of that
however the two that i'm highlighting
here try to put in yellow and we can see
that our cbd versus thc
towards the end here you know looking at
weeks you know say
seven and eight or so six seven and
eight you can see there's definitely a
dramatic
increase in the thc levels while the cbd
levels remain the same
if not trend slightly downward overall
so it's just important to remember
that if we're playing very close to that
line of 0.3
waiting to the very end in some
cultivars might cause the crop to go
what's called hot or go
above that theoretical threshold now
these examples they were above it
even before that point so it doesn't
really apply to this situation but just
again
something else to consider when you're
looking at choosing a cultivar and
knowing what it might be producing
trying to maximize your cbd production
but may go above that thc
threshold now most as i said we'll
exceed that 0.3 percent total thc
however this is notable in some
cultivars it is possible for thc levels
to increase
in the later weeks into flower so again
this is where choosing that cultivar
knowing your cultivar is very important
not in this case but in other cultivars
this may be close to the 0.3
threshold and this could be a notable
observation and that's kind of where
you're taking the canvas plant and
saying are you in the hemp plant
category
or in the marijuana plant category now
another research article here
welcome to take a look at looks at the
accumulation of bioactive metabolites
in cultivated medical cannabis again
summer provided here
so what are cannabinoids accumulation
where are they exactly accumulated
well cannabinoids are synthesized and
accumulate in unfertilized
female inflorescence which is basically
the flowers specifically within those
flowers the trichomes that are found on
the surface of the
flower and also the leaves the trichomes
are these
small white structures that we see right
here and we can see
definitely excessively produced right
here these other white structures here
are called the stigmas
we're looking at the trichomes being
these small white kind of structures
here
that look like they have like a little
like mushroom type head on the top
so what's the kind of schema for
developing the cannabinoids now the
cannabis we're talking about here
could be a delta 9 thc could be cbd
or cbc now we're saying there's a lot of
complicated kind of
biosynthesis pathways a lot of enzymes
involved in genes in the pathways
have been kind of isolated to kind of
get an idea of where these are derived
from
when we're looking at the very early on
this uh transferase
we're kind of looking at the kind of the
starting
molecule here would be cbga that's kind
of where we're starting all this the
plant kind of produces that
to synthesize the production from that
particular compound
so once we have the cbga the plant then
can produce the thc
synthase cbda synthase or cb
cbca synthase we're getting that next
kind of step there
we're producing the thca cbda and
cbca now we then have the heat
or decar carboxylation step to generate
those final
end products with also carbon dioxide
given off
so based on the inheritances the
chemical phenotypes the genes for tca
synthase
uh cbda synthase are considered to be
co-dominant alleles
what does that mean that goes back to
our biology basic biology
codominant alleles well alleles you've
got one chromosome from the
male and one chromosome from the female
co-dominance mean they can both
be expressed one's not going to be
dominant and recessive
they're going to be both expressed
that's kind of an important note when
we're looking at developing
varieties or kind of looking at this
pathway in more detail
the gene for cb ca synthase is
in is an independent locus so it's in a
different location
within the entire genome however based
on dna sequencing
and analysis one of the transcription
expressed in marijuana in hemp samples
multiple linked loci for the t h c a s
and t h sorry and the c b d a
s genes are proposed so here we're
having
that even though these might be
distinctly separate in our pathways
there could be linked as far as
genetically and that's important for
looking at developing new varieties
there are published genomes for cannabis
and the genetic diversity of the
biosynthetic pathways of cannabinoids in
both marijuana
and hemp strains is under investigation
we're trying to better understand
these particular pathways because some
growers some breeders might be looking
at producing more cbd
how can we go about that versus thc and
staying below that
federal limit potentially so if they all
originate from the same molecule
how do we try to get the plant to select
for this particular pathway
because that's deemed to be advantageous
and then lastly we have the kind of
bioactive
forms of the cannabinoids so the
bioactive forms of cannabinoids are
produced following
a light or heat induced decarboxylation
reaction
to generate the cbg the delta nine thc
the cbd or ultimately the cbc
so all of these kind of are kind of
getting into the specific pathways of
the plant
might be a little bit more kind of
in-depth and complicated there
but i think it is kind of interesting
just to kind of have an idea an
appreciation
that we have an original molecule and
then from there the plant is going
through with enzymes
activating different pathways to produce
these different compounds
so this kind of is great for looking at
research going into the future
we're trying to select one of these
particular cannabinoids
over the other