interested in learning about tinctures
in nanotinctures derived from cannabis
well this tobacco university video will
help answer just that
let's get into tinctures and nano
tinctures made from cannabis
so first off we're going to be
highlighting some products made by ct
pharma
why because they go through and publicly
make their analytical reports publicly
available in labels of the products they
produce
the descriptions and opinions and uses
in this video are intended to provide an
understanding of some end products of
the cannabis plant
and those important analytical reports
will be provided at the end
and they're often a missed component
that should accompany any product
someone is interested in purchasing so
first off let's start with the
description
of tinctures just in general tinctures
are a precisely formulated alcohol-based
marijuana extract
made from steeping cannabis material in
ethanol and it's a liquid that is
consumed orally for long lasting effects
nano tinctures are an alcohol-free
formulation
that can be added to a beverage with no
added taste they're designed to suspend
within a solution instead of adhering to
the container
so that's kind of that nano scale that
nano technology a lot of
new research being done that area it was
just really small particles so it's able
to stay in suspension
much easier what are some options when
we come to tinctures well
ct pharma offers tinctures that have thc
cbd and a one-to-one ratio of both
potency and dosage vary based on strains
it's important to make sure you're
matching up
whatever style of tincture that will
match
your intended needs now use of tinctures
well they can be consumed orally
lingually in the mouth or infused into a
drink for easy discrete consumption
they're popular among non-smoking
patients as there is no combustion or
inhalation
necessary so just another kind of option
here
that's derived from the cannabis plant
now examples of those certificates of
analysis as we can see here
we have the lot numbers we have the
testing for microbiology microtoxins
heavy metal and pesticides
as well as the terpenes and cannabinoids
that we
most often associate with and lastly
there is the label
as well so keep in mind that the labeled
example here
provides kind of a summary of all of
those numbers but it's your right as a
consumer
to be asking for those actual analytical
reports as well
now how do we get these numbers uh how
do we kind of go through this process
well kind of typically they are analyzed
on a high performance liquid
chromatography or hplc analyzing
this quantifies the cannabinoids is a in
gas chromatographs
hplc and gcms which is gas
mass spec and then the hplc is the high
performance liquid chromatography as
well for terpenes
so this shows you some of the equipment
that's used to generate
those testing samples it's always good
to get this done at a third party lab
and you confirm that
when you're looking at the actual
analysis here
so again just be that part of that
informed consumer have an idea
of where those numbers are coming from
and this is a great way to educate
yourself
and others about end products produced
from cannabis