so here we're going to look at tire
impressions and the examination process
for those tires being able to understand
the different types of tread
and what to look for so it's all going
to be covered here
in this video lecture so starting with
crime scene evidence versus
the known so the tire trade examinations
compare tire impressions recovered from
the scene with tires
taken from a known vehicle those two
categories of tires are the suspect the
vehicle
is suspected to have or be at the crime
scene and then we have
vehicles we need to also eliminate these
are vehicles it could be the police
ambulance or other sources for known
purposes all tires should be seized from
the suspect's vehicle
to allow an adequate comparison and
picture should be taken here as we see
also with the indication of that what's
red on the sidewall as well
these are class characteristics so keep
in mind class characteristics can be
used to eliminate suspects tire
or suggest a tire could have made the
track
these characters include the size the
tread design and wear marks
these aren't individual characteristics
they're just saying the same clasp with
the same
general type of tire could have made
those
particular tracks again we're looking at
some of the details here and this is why
images and photographs from the scene
can be so
important i mean this can lead to a
visual comparison these tire impressions
that result of transfer from
um tread detail entire against a
substrate in this case it could be
kind of this sand could be the actual
asphalt could be snow
it could be mud impressions can be made
here
it can be two or three dimensional
forensic examinations
can begin with visual comparisons to
eliminate tires which do not match the
impressions it's a great way to kind of
quickly eliminate or quickly classify
certain prints
just by using the visual cues known
tires collected should be inked
and have 3d impressions made for
comparison purposes
keep in mind you want to look at the
entire tread you don't look at small
section
forensics examination continues with a
full circumference test of the
impressions this is where kind of like
ink the tire
you want to ink the entire circumference
of the tire
not just a small section impressions are
superimposed on known
impressions over cast or the original
tire
the goal is to try to find consistencies
or a unique abnormality
which such as a point of damage or
something caught in the tread
to try to match up that particular tire
with being present
at that part of the crime scene general
tire
evaluation other factors that should be
investigated include the
tread design we want to be looking at
the
tread dimensions and noise treatments
potential wear features
and random individual characteristics as
you mentioned it could be a damage point
in the tire or potentially even a small
stone
caught in that tire because that can
lead us to the individual
characteristics that can help us
kind of use to identify an exact tire
remember individual characteristics can
change
over time that's why it's important try
to get the match to be as close as
possible
you could have the refilling point a
plug point be a nail in the tire
be the different wear marks different
cracks in the tire
or something kind of unique that's that
is wedged in that
end rubber there so again these are
individual characteristics and this can
really help solidify an argument
that that tire was present at the
particular scene that was documented
obtain an inked of the known standards
this is where it's important to kind of
get that instead of said that entire
circumference of the tire you can use an
ink surface that's longer than the total
circumference of the tire to ensure you
get everything
also have the surface to receive the ink
of equal or greater length so here's the
ink area you want to make sure you ink
the entire tire
you want to have an area where you can
transfer that tread over the entire
surface
because the goal is to obtain a full
circumference in compression
for that tire then we have something
called tread
blocks and these are tread designs are
comprised of tread blocks which vary in
size to help reduce
noise the arrangement never repeats and
is different on each side
which is why a full circumference
impression is so important
because you'll have the manufacturers
have different dimensions for those
tread blocks
to help reduce overall noise of the tire
while it's being driven you want to
offer comparison of the ink to the cast
so it's advised to pass the ink
compression directly over the cast to
try to identify
corresponding tread blocks and take that
and kind of kind of shift it to see if
you can get
different areas to match up the match is
found this can
the specific tire segment can be
compared to the actual tire
directly which can really strengthen an
argument
actual um to cast tire comparison the
blue tape is used to show the matching
segment
that the cast corresponds with because
the caster mirror is only going to be a
small portion of that tire
so here we're trying to determine well
where is it within that tire
so do you notice something unique either
in the cast would be a little harder to
see
or the actual tire well when you're
looking at
very close and look at looking at the
visual the photograph overlaid on top of
the cast shows
on this correlation where this stone
placement is an exact match so just go
back for one second here you can see
that there's these stones caught in the
tire and if you look very carefully
might get an indication of that stone
also showing up on the cast when you
kind of overlay those two
over one another it's very probable that
this tire made the cast impression at
the crime scene so here it's very
possible that with this visual match
that you have these individual
characteristics
that this kind of stone here matches up
with the cast
and the original tire indicating that
it's very likely or very probable
that this tire made the cast impression
found at the crime scene