so if you've ever looked at the sidewall
of a tire you may have seen a
whole bunch of letters and numbers and
thought they were just random
however they're not here we're going to
go over entire sidewall decoding and
we're going to develop
an understanding for what those numbers
and letters actually mean
so first off here's a quick breakdown of
just kind of an example of a sidewall
it can tell you department of
transportation can manufacture and plant
code
the tire size manufacturer identity
number
week in year the tire was made all good
valuable information
so first off that decoding process what
does it actually look like was it
involved
well the department transportation
number known as the d.o.t number
consists of
and this is just an example the dot
impression the plant code manufacturer
date of manufacture and keep in mind
that tires made after january 1st in the
year 2000
have four numbers in the last group
while prior to that there are only
three numbers so that can again help
determine just on a large
scale where that tire may have been
originally made they all follow this
same general pattern i'm going to go
through and break this down a little bit
further
so retrade tires do dot number decoding
is slightly different than a just
regular tire
so keep in mind that the retread tires
are slightly different numbers
they have something called dotr
department of transportation retread
or r indicates that it's a retread tire
so be careful
of that if you see that r it's going to
be indicating that this is a retread
ypy is manufacturer retread goodyear v
tread
in canada this was where this was
manufactured so again
it can tell you with that code or at
least identifying that code
it can then go to a conversion to tell
you exactly
where that was particularly made and we
have the date and year of manufacture
so if we're looking at something that is
a one two zero
one that would indicate it was made in
the twelfth
week of the year two thousand and
one so an example here of zero eight
zero
two this tire was manufactured from the
eighth week of the year
2002.
so come entire designations that we see
here again the same kind of
indication occurs we have this example
here
p stands for passenger tire this 185 or
in this example here 195 is the
approximate width of the tire
measured in millimeters 65 is the aspect
ratio
rs stands for a radial tire and 15 is
the
rim diameter in inches so you get a
little confusing that measures one thing
in millimeters nothing in inches
but these are just what these numbers
correlate with
so if we take this tire and kind of
break it down into a little bit more
specifics
we'll take a look and see and decode
this sidewall here
so first off we see the p well p stands
for passenger tire
so these tires are often called p
metrics note that the lt stands for
light truck st would stand for special
on trailer
and t would stand for temporary so in
the case we see a p this is a passenger
tire the absence of a letter at the
beginning of the size description
indicates that it's a euro
metric tire the 225 so we see here the
225 represents the approximate
section width or with the tire from
sidewall to sidewall again measured in
millimeters
the larger the number simply put the
wider the tire
is the 60 60 refers to the aspect ratio
which is the nominal sidewall height
reflected as a percentage
section width so the sidewall height
this tire is 60
of 225 or approximately 135 millimeters
um r here r stands for radial
construction which is the industry
standard for passenger
cars and light truck tires a b or x
and placement of r would indicate the
tire has
a bias or ply construction
the 16 is the rim or bead
diameter 16 represents in inches keep in
mind the diameter
of the beads which means that this tire
is designed to fit on a rim with a 16
inch diameter the 97v is a service
description
and this final component the size
designates called a service description
indicates the
load index and the speed symbol of the
tire
so load index of 97 in this example is a
two or three digit code that represents
the maximum load the tire can be carried
at speed indicated by the speed symbol
so this again getting into a little bit
more of the specifics and this is why
when you're choosing a tire for your
vehicle
uh depending what tire it is there's a
lot of
options uh provided they're not just all
tires so 16 inch tires anything will do
there's a lot of specialty descriptions
to keep in mind to maximize the
performance
and match the performance of your
particular vehicle
and lastly here's the full sidewall
information so this kind of gives you
just that general
summary there everything that i've
described here how it looks on a tire so
i invite you to go out
look at the sidewall of any tire if you
and if you have one in the parking lot
you go to a parking lot just take a look
and hopefully you can with this video
describe a little bit or develop an
understanding
of what those numbers and letters
actually tell you about the specifics
for the tire you're looking at