so here we're going to have some entire
track evidence and kind of what's
included
in collection of this particular form of
evidence
so first off we want to be looking at
when we're documenting
uh tire tracks we're going to be looking
also at the
width of that tire track we also want to
be considering the wheelbase
dimensions and that gets into the
specifics of the vehicle
if there was a turn involved could we
get the turning diameter
and also the relative position of the
turning tracks because this will all
kind of play
into determining potentially what size
or what proportion vehicle
made those tracks so this vehicle tire
width so the width is the stance
that we're looking at the track width
it's a measurement made from
the one center of one wheel to the
opposite center of the
other wheel and again this is considered
the track width
the front wheels turning produce
unreliable measurements so rear wheels
accurately record turns because they're
going to remain always
consistent so it's again looking at that
track width for the rear tires
would be the measurement we want to try
to determine or take
we have something called a wheelbase so
the wheelbase
is the measurement of the center of hubs
from the front wheels
to the center of hubs from the rear
wheels normally these measurements are
not present at a crime scene but they
can kind of
help indicate if we have a suspect's
vehicle is important to take that into
consideration
now if it's just a regular car they may
not vary that much
but for example here in the extreme case
we have a limo uh we
will have which will have a much longer
wheelbase
we could have something really short
like this little kart it's gonna have a
very short
wheelbase and that's again center of
front tire to the center of the
rear tire you have something called
turning
diameter so when we're looking at
turning diameter it's a diameter of
circle the vehicle makes when
steering wheels are fully turned
pertains to front wheels
only turn diameter is measured by b
squared
over a plus a where b is the distance
between two points
on the turning circle and a is a
distance between outer
margin and midpoint between x and x
not there so this is just a way to try
to determine that turning diameter
which can be involved if there are skid
marks or indications if a
car was able to leave very quickly we're
skidding
area and these tire tracks were made
this turning diameter could play into
determining whether or not the suspect's
car
could have made those prints
we have the position of tire in a turn
so again if you can find turns those are
great indicators
because when a vehicle moves in a
straight path only the rear tire tracks
are
available to us as researchers and
investigators
however when the vehicle turns the rear
and front tire tracks
rack separately so you can get an
indication of both
it's important to understand and
document these at a crime scene
now we see the obvious year of made in
sand are made in snow
but if they're looking at over a mud or
a gravel area potentially or a soft
substance in any way looking at those
tire positions and related to a turn
can be a very important piece of
information
now lastly if we're going to recover
this particular evidence
as i said typically mean the soft
substance which makes it really easy or
really easy to see but can be a little
fragile to be able to collect that
evidence
so first off we want to take photographs
from all angles
with and without measurement tools and
ruler if possible want to take a cast
over about
three foot impression and that requires
about 15 to 25 pounds of dental stone if
you're really looking at capturing some
of the details
of that we do want to measure the width
length and depth
and the direction of travel noted
impressions could be made
if possible but pictures of the source
tire
must be included for comparison so yes
it's important to document those
impressions but we also
need to try to match it up to the source
tire to be able to determine whether or
not it was possible
for the suspect's tires to have made the
impressions found at the crime scene