some girls were often wonder should I be
flowering plants or should I be waiting
what should I be doing you know when
should I kind of signal that plant to go
into flower that's we're look at just a
couple things that might help you
clarify this and determine when to make
that change now keep in mind that photo
period dictates vegetative or the
flowering phase for plants so plants can
be switched to flower or even reverted
back to vegetative stage for cloning if
desired by the grower based on the photo
period that they're exposed to so keep
in mind that for most varieties the
grower has control so it's up to the
grower to decide when it's the most
advantageous to make that transition
now that flower timing remember auto
flowering cultivars will flower based on
days old
not on the photo period all others
indicas and sativas will be dependent on
the photo period so if you are playing
those auto flowering varieties you don't
have to worry about making the switch to
flower or not you can almost mark on a
calendar or get an approximate idea of
when they should be flowering just to
give you an idea otherwise if you're
growing in the kids RCT is you can kind
of pick or choose the date you want
change the photo period and induced file
flowering on your plants so sometimes
when a flower depends on simply the room
height how tall can your plants and get
you do not want your plants to outgrow
their vertical space so that can
indicate or telegrapher when they should
be inducing flowering I know how far the
plant should be from the lights and if
you are ceiling limited it will dictate
when you flip the photo period on them
so keep in mind especially for some
areas might be in a grow tent or
facility with low ceilings this can help
make this the decision for you if you're
an area here we have a large area you
have more options but sometimes your
lights might be fixed and a certain area
so that can help limit your decisions
and allow you to time out the proper
period to switch the vegetative state to
the flower on state you also should know
your cultivar or the general habits of
your plant
indicas can grow about twenty-five to
fifty percent more in vertical height
while they earn flower
sativas can potentially double their
height during the flowering stage
keep mine sativas have that kind of
longer taller appearance in indicas are
more that kind of squatty er appearance
there so again knowing the cultivar that
you're using can also help make an
informed decision your starting material
should also be a consideration did the
original plant material come from seed
or from a clone clones can grow in
height quickly but make sure if you are
going from a clone that they do have a
sufficient root system here's two clones
pulled from an aeroponic cloner it see
this one has intruded yet this is just
starting but you wanna let Susan pry go
for a little bit longer to allow it to
have a sufficient root system to be able
to support itself through the rest of
the vegetative phase and so that you
have a healthy plant going into
flowering