if you're considering topping your
cannabis plants and wondered a little
bit more about that method
this tobacco university video is for you
all right let's get into top topping as
a pruning method for cannabis production
so first off what is topping sometimes
it's called tipping sometimes it's also
called pinching the plant
this kind of shows a great little image
that of that what that looks like
there are all forms of pruning each has
their own preference to
where a grower will physically choose to
top or to cut the plant off
topping is removing the growing tip from
the main stem
that will give you basically two stems
this can be performed multiple times to
get more stems and branches
as we see here and typically this is
done when the plant is
at four to five nodes or so up so it's
not done at the very beginning that done
really late
typically four to five nodes but again
growers choice
and it can be depending on the growing
situation as well as the variety they
might be growing
so how much to top what would you go
through and how much you go through and
topping we can see that evident right
here see that pinch point we see those
two additional kind of growing points
where there was one now there'll be two
some growers would simply pinch the tip
of an active and growing portion of the
plant
others like to take three plus nodes off
to get the bonus material as a clone
if you take a little bit more you can
take that off you get the pinch point
here you're gonna grow into two well
that cutting you just took off you can
now go through and clone
however an additional bonus is the plant
will be larger and slightly more
developed so it can push out of the
stress a little bit easier than recovery
time
typically if you do it when its plants
is very small if you're removing the
water it's going to produce new leaves
that can cause a little bit of a lag
time so that's why some growers prefer
prefer to wait a little bit longer but
again up to the growers or growers
choice
so topping an autoflower would that be
advised it's strain dependent as there
can be various levels of success
typically it's best to top an auto early
in life cycle
this is suggested to be before day 21
with day 14 kind of being the target
the fourth node can also provide a good
marker for growers
genetics need to be an aggressive grower
to maximize yield particularly if you're
doing this
pruning method with an autoflower now
what's happening in the plants
well we're having this kind of hormone
shift removing the actively growing tip
removes the concentration of oxen in the
plant taking that tip
off this will auxin reduces lateral
blood formation
so when you remove the tip you're
removing the highest concentration of
auxin here
as we see right here and what that does
is that basically now causes the plant
to grow
lateral branches more aggressively this
is also done a lot with poinsettias
so this removing of the apical meristem
removing that auxin
will now induce lateral buds to grow
which is a great thing
now we're going to take a quick look at
an example of this kind of method of
pruning an
outdoor grown plant a little bit later
in the season
but just to show you kind of what the
plants may look like if you wait a
little bit later
to go through this plant topping method
hope you enjoy
so many times growers want to know kind
of how does a pruning style affect the
plant particularly getting to the end of
harvest well this is a prime example
here
if you look at this plant the apricot
mirror stem was removed
meaning the central stalk was cut was
topped essentially somebody call it
topping their plants
and what we're noticing when we take out
that apical meristem unlike the plant
over here where we're maintaining the
apical meristem we get one large bud
and the others kind of suffer here we're
cutting it right here getting side
branching to occur
so you're moving the ox and it's a plant
hormone and that will kind of induce
side branches to form so what's the
advantage of growing a lot of side
branches well as you can see
here without that apical meristem now
we're getting a little bit more of a
consistent harvest on some of the
side branches now you're noticing all
the buds still are pointing upwards so
even though this is kind of growing out
in that kind of v y pattern all the buds
will still
point up the intention is and this is
maybe just a little bit of late here in
the season
but what the intention is to get more
even uh buds
throughout the top here instead of
having just that one central
main bud now we're getting more buds
that are
larger in size so again just a different
pruning style
but this kind of shows that topping that
may have occurred sometimes it occurs
by the grower actually cutting it
sometimes in the outdoor environment in
particular the wind may kind of select
that
but this just kind of shows the end
result that you can get
from topping a plane