in this tobacco university video we're
going to look at the
difference between total thc and delta
9 thc and there's a lot of confusion
about
what's total what's delta nine hopefully
here we'll get
to some clarification between these and
how
delta 9 is calculated which is very
important for legal aspects
so understanding thc potency reporting
and a lot of this has to do with the
reporting
so first understand that the thc
molecule is
naturally produced in plants in its
inactive form known as
thca only a small fraction of the
active delta 9 thc typically written is
here delta 9
form is generated in the plant however
heating the inactive thca
results in its conversion to the active
delta 9
thc however only a maximum of 87.7
of the inactive thca can be converted to
the active
delta nine th sa so here we have the
thca the inactive form
and here we have the delta 9 thc the
psychoactive form
of thc so they are structurally
different
usually it takes heating to be able to
get to the delta 9 form of thc
so once it comes to reporting was this
kind of why is this important
well in addition to reporting thc a
values labs must now calculate the
amount of delta 9 that
can form from thc a and that can
form is through the resulting of heating
this is where calculations come into
play
so why is this important well thca is
converted to delta 9 upon heating
however thca loses 12.3 percent of its
weight
when converted to delta 9 thc how does
this factor into the calculations and
reporting
well first you need to determine the thc
values
and independently determine the values
for thc
a and delta 9 thc then you want to
subtract 12.3 percent from the thc a
value
this is due the difference in thca and
delta 9 thc molecules
and then 3 you add the delta 9 thc and
the new thc
a values together to get the total
thc value so that's that difference
between the total and the delta nine
thc values and i get these sources here
are listed
in the description if you want to check
them out for yourself here i'm providing
kind of a nice little description here
to walk you through the process now
let's go through an example here of this
reporting
uh and again gonna put some numbers here
so feel free to pause the video or
look down in the description as well you
can find some of the slides and go
through this yourself
the data shown here at the top right
indicates the thca content
of 24.34 in the thc
or the delta 9 thc content of 0.74 in
this particular
example sample provided to determine the
maximum delta
9 thc that can form from this thc a
value
the thc value must be multiplied by
0.887
so here's our 24.34 thca
times that .877 we get 21.34 which is
the maximum
delta 9 thc that can form from there
to get the final total thc remember
talking about the difference between
delta 9 and total
thc value this is the maximum delta
9 thc derived from the thcs and
is added to the value of delta 9 thc
that was present
in the sample so again going back here
this would be the 21.34 percent that we
calculated here
as the maximum delta 9 thc that can be
derived from
the original thc a value and then we
want to add
that 0.74 delta 9
thc which naturally occurs in the plant
to get a total thc value
of 22.08 percent we would see that
listed
right here so it gives you kind of an
example here of reporting in total thc
calculations here
now the delta nine thc testing for hemp
under
connecticut's public act 19-3 which is
established in august 27 2019
in this example the lab may dry the
sample prior to extraction
both to convert thc a to delta 9 thc
and provide a driving basis for analysis
the analysis must be done using
either of the following methods could
use gas
chromatography the gc and or it could
use high performance liquid
chromatography hplc
and with gc this also converts the thca
to thc during analysis
in our analysis procedure is one test
and will result in the
total delta 9 thc compared to
hplcs and they calculate delta 9 and thc
separately from
thta using the formula listed below
within
their document now looking at the labs
processing
wet samples labs processing wet samples
will need to calculate a dry weight
separately and apply that to
measurements to test
results to convert to dry weight basis
so remember it's always factored on the
dry weight basis so if you get a wet
sample
to take that into consideration lab
processing wet samples must use a
technique
capable of measuring both thca and delta
thc and use the formula present on the
next slide to convert those thc a values
to delta 9
thc while other metabolites of thc exist
the they only include thca in the
calculations
so for example delta 8 thc is not part
of the calculations
only delta 9. so it's important to make
that distinction
the formula to use is mentioned
previously
total theoretical tetrocabidiol or thc
content is the maximum of possible delta
nine thc in a hemp crop
if total conversion were to occur and
would be determined by the following
calculation
so the sum of the concentration of the
delta nine thc
in its precursor thca multiplied by
again at 0.877
on a dry weight basis and reported to
two significant figures and here's the
calculation
that total theoretical thc equals
the concentration of delta 9 thc plus
the concentration
of thc a times
that .877 and add those two together get
your total
theoretical thc value so there's a lot
of math here and conversions
kind of walk your way through it look at
the example i provide and that will help
you hopefully give you that
idea of how that delta nine tt compares
to the total
thc values here now the method of
testing
now labs must indicate the method of
testing used on their certificate of
analysis or coa
the same must also include a statement
whether or not the sample has delta 8.
i'm sorry delta 9 thc concentration
greater than that
0.3 on a dry weight basis
and this will determine whether they
pass or fail as being hemp
or fail being above this level would
then be classified federally as
marijuana
the resulting reporting limit is defined
as at 0.3 delta
9 thc this includes measurements of
uncertainty determined by the laboratory
as an example if the measurement of
uncertainty is 30 the reporting limit
will be 0.39
thc and all samples below 0.39 will be
reported as
less than 0.3 which is very important
from the federal standpoint set by the
2018 farm bill
the results below the reporting limit
report is that 0.3 percent
will pass and above that will be
quarantined reported as a status of
failure so from a hemp grower standpoint
to make sure that the crop they are
growing is
hemp is important to have this test done
to make sure that there's that
certificate of analysis that stamp of
approval that is truly hemp that you're
growing
and it passes this test here looking at
the
thc levels within that particular plant
so hopefully this was helpful always
welcome to go back and review look at
the
description for sources and again thank
you for tuning in to this
other dubaco university video