as the title implies I'm going to be
going over transplanting which is a
critical step especially when we're
growing container grown crops so how and
when to transplant well once the clone
is filled its containing want to remove
it and plant it into a larger container
and that can vary depending on the size
container it originated in here's one it
originated in a very small plug well
what are the clone flip the container
upside out and place it into a premade
hole into the larger container be sure
to water everything in and keep it under
constant conditions to reduce plant
shock plants that are transported late
will become pot bound so it's got a
little bit of it timing then I don't
want to wait too long or go too early
this would be one of one of them want to
go much longer than that just looking at
the amount of roots in this plug
suggestion container size so typically 3
gallon pots and $10 hot or what's
commonly used 3 gallon pots we typically
recommend for plants up to about 3 feet
tall and revise your plans that are two
to three months old 7 gallon containers
can hold a plant for its full term
awesome it will prefer 10 gallon
containers and hold a plant for over a
year to some extent when you get into
like 7 or 10 gallon pots it comes down
to personal preference some growers
really like the 10 some other like the 7
so we're transitioning from one to
another or trying different sizes so
there's no quotes at 1 gallon pot size
that will work in all instances when
selecting our container size it's
debated but larger containers use more
media and are often more forgiving and
can reduce clinic stresses so that's one
advantage sometimes specific variety
have it can dictate what size containers
use at the image here there's always
kind of pros and cons you kinda gotta
weigh each side
bigger containers are more forgiving
with these more media so again whatever
fits your condition people grown great
plants in a variety of sizes of
containers the container material that
was interesting in general there's solid
wall there's breathable materials solid
walls reduce water loss of it can cause
roots to kind of circle breathable
materials such as grow bags or in this
case we have the slats cut in here can
cause root pruning which helps create a
dense root ball without the plant
getting root bound is called kind of air
pruning that occurs so again both of
these in this case the same size or
gallons
but very different methods and we have
to consider both options and figure out
what works best when transplanting
during transplant process good tempt
inoculate roots if you choose to do so
since it's typically a good amount of
root surface area to come in contact
with applied products yet not a
requirement but can allow for a very
efficient transfer of that plants can
also be watered in with low dose
fertilizers at this time we don't really
want to go with high dose because of
those freshly exposed roots you have the
chance of burning them grown juice
reprinting wool I cut the roots well can
help restart plant has become pop down
it's something that's really did sink
that pop and go through and cut some of
these roots help rejuvenate the plant
kind of get it back going this may
encourage to start growing again even
it's kept in the same size container to
take the plant out cut some of the roots
and put it right back in the same sized
container because the root mass has been
reduced causing that kind of tricking
the plant that kind of rejuvenate itself
proper media fill height so girls often
want to fill the pot to the very top
because kinda like the ice cream cone
effect this is not advised and kind of
see this in this instance where the
potting main is right up to the size of
the container what about this 2 to 3
inch gap to the lip to the soil line
this allows you to combine hand water
very easily and church all of medium
remains in the container if you fill the
medium high it's gonna only produce the
cleanest of conditions but can lead to
irrigation issues with increased size of
runoff coral tration and mediating on
the floor causing a great habitat for
potential unwanted organisms to view
living when a fill and not pack the
media is a lot of times people go
through and pack in the media and make
it really dense I want to keep some
porosity to it I don't really want to
press it all down and squeeze out all
the air not sure where Brewers think all
the media is gonna escape to but packing
media will reduce air infiltration and
make it harder for their roots to
breathe keep in mind the roots light
gauzy to exchange oxygen remember to
perspire just like you do so suffocating
them is not advised that they need
oxygen dance lobby but to squeeze out
all that moisture and all that kind of
air pockets also place the cut again you
can pack it in very lightly but keep in
mind the whole point if they have some
sort of air in that container in that
media too
allow the roots to breathe