okay the topic of this video is
transport proteins looking here at our
phospholipid bilayer see several
proteins embedded now much remember
going looking back diffusion can occur
without any proteins however here we're
looking at transport proteins so in
these examples were looking at
substances that may need a protein to be
able to move them across the
phospholipid bilayer now this can be
because of their size because they're
charged for many different reasons but
simply they need a protein now needing a
protein does not automatically mean it
means energy passive transport can occur
with channel proteins and carrier meat
mediated proteins however not all
carrier proteins are part of the passive
transport some do require energy and we
call those active transport let's look
at some of those on more detail so
starting first with active transport
this requires energy from ATP remember
adenosine triphosphate to move
substances against the concentration
gradient what this an example this is up
the concentration gradient so what this
looks like here is if we look at our
membrane and we have a high ion
concentration here and a low ion
concentration up here typically the
process of regular diffusion just
passive transfer of materials occurred
these materials would diffuse across the
membrane
however because we're looking at active
transport this is where we're using
energy ATP to pull these ions even
though there's a low concentration of
them pull them across the membrane to
force them over here even though they
don't want to be so it's kind of like
you not wanting to go to class and being
out in the hall after passing time and
someone has to come grab you and bring
you into class just all your fellow
students so that's an example of active
transport moving against a concentration
gradient or there's a low amount of
concentration and being pulled across to
this area of higher concentration this
can be advantageous to the cell if they
need this particular ion again after
transport requires use of carrier
proteins there's two types there's can
be a membrane pump or a couple
spork so membrane pumping can see the
word pump think of a normal pump could
be a water pump requiring electricity
requiring energy to be petroleum
products the key part here is requiring
energy and couple transport when I talk
about our code transport systems here so
again our active transport requiring
energy ion pumps they could move these
are sodium ions potassium ions calcium
ions magnesium ions potassium and sodium
exchange pump is a very common pump
these proton pumps are moving hydrogen
ions as we see here uses photosynthesis
or food energy to create a photon
concentration I'm sorry a proton
concentration gradient that then is used
to manufacture ATP this is higher
hydrogen ion concentration is higher
proton concentration is what's being
generated here in force through ATP
synthase here to generate ATP so in
order to generate ATP we need our
protons don't want to have a higher
concentration in this external
environment in this internal memory
moving them across and forcing them over
in this case is allowing them us to
harvest the energy in this case we see
this example here and we see a lot of
folds remember our surface area to
volume ratio a lot of folds here
indicate this could be what a
mitochondria does the mitochondria is
forcing concentration of gradients and
then harnessing that energy through its
particular protein passing only through
one way and as a result taking ADP and a
free phosphorus deterrent ATP so proton
pump moving hydrogen ions and
photosynthesis want to go over that
we'll see that in more detail or food
energy create this proton concentration
gradient that then is used to
manufacture ATP because there's a lot of
protons here they want to diffuse across
we the cell and that lets them go
through in one area and as ATP is
generated looking a little bit more of
the membrane pumps carrier proteins
whose energy from 80
P to move substances across the membrane
up its concentration period same thing
here we see a high amount of potassium
ions here we see only one on this side
the pump is pumping them in this case
across requiring energy to move them
across moving that concentration
gradient here we see again here's our
potassium coming in and here's our
sodium leaving you see ATP bring broken
down indicating energy is being required
sodium potassium pump is one active
transport system it's very common in
cells and again it's moving the sodium
which is the NA plus here and the
potassium which is the Chi and there's
binding and again this is just
representing a protein requiring energy
for this to occur after transports
carrier mediated one ATP so one energy
molecule okay right here is moving three
sodium's out and two potassium in so
it's not always an equal number transfer
so here our binding sites here we have
three green molecules in this case these
represent the sodium's and two orange
representing potassium and this ATP is
causing this movement across it's called
a trans membrane potential because it's
creating electrical charge across the
membrane so across the membrane is trans
membrane and this potential is an
electrical potential it's because these
are both ions and they're moving not in
equal amounts causing a shift in the
amount of charges that occur on one side
or the other side of the cell here's our
proton pump okay minor control membranes
in cellular respiration the proton pump
uses energy to transport protons from
the matrix mitochondria to inter
membrane space what does that mean we're
simply taking our hydrogen ions and
we're concentrating them on one side
they want to diffuse across that can't
get through this phospholipid bilayer
but they can get through this ATP
synthase that's this big black molecule
here and because they're moving through
as they're moving through the cell in
this case the ATP synthase is harnessing
that energy and it's using that flow of
protons to take adp plus the phosphorus
to Train ATP this is an active pump that
generates proton proton concentration
across the mitochondrial membrane
because there are more protons outside
the matrix and inside and it's the
environment here forcing them through
this is part of reason why my tenders
have so many folds in them because
they're I having a lot of these ATP
synthesis in the membranes allowing a
lot of energy to be generated the co
transport mechanism here capable of
moving substances either with or against
their concentration gradients key to key
to terms here are simpler zin anti
Porter's so you reporter one partner
just moving one thing in one direction
that's what's going on here binding here
it's being released and pushed to the
other side our co transports are a
little different we classify them in two
ways so example here we have our
symporter 2/7 is move across memory in
this same direction same thing same same
code transport and be on this side of
the cell membrane Turvey move to the
other side here our anti port system
just as name implies to services with
cross-burning in opposite directions and
ante directions and is this also called
a counter transport system so if you see
here the triangles moving this way and
the green squares moving to the other
side in this case here we see them both
binding to our protein and they're both
being released on the other side
hopefully this helps explain some
transmembrane proteins