okay this video lecture is going to
focus on the process of transpiration
just basically water movement through a
plant in the roots
through the stem and out the leaves it's
important uh for many aspects of the
plant one
in particular cooling as well as moving
nutrients
so we're looking at the transpiration
process
we have water movement in the plant we
have the vascular plants have conducting
systems for transporting fluids and
nutrients to the plant
water and minerals enter through the
roots and are transported
through in the xylem we see the xylem
look pictured here on the left
carbohydrates are synthesized by the
photosynthetic process
and are transported through the plant in
the phloem we see that on the right here
these little red circles represent the
sucrose or
sugars you'll notice that the water or
xylem
goes from the bottom of the plant
towards the top
phloem in this instance is kind of
moving downwards but it can move
anywhere
so phloem is able to go up or down the
plant xylem is going
mainly from the roots to the shoots as
we call it from the bottom
all the way up and through the plant in
that one direction
now the flow of minerals in and out and
within the plant we see here
water is passively transported into the
roots that enters the xylem and we can
see that here at picture number one
as we look here in the stem region the
forces of cohesion and adhesion cause
water molecules to form
in a column of xylem these are little
water molecules and this is looking at
the xylem it's in the plant and number
three here the water moves from the
xylem to the mesophyll cells
evaporates from their surfaces and
leaves to the plant by diffusion
through the stomata that's how it's
going to lead is water
vapor and this whole process escapes
repeating this is why you have to
constantly water
on your house plants for example because
they're constantly going through this
transpiration
process now root pressure several
factors
are at work to move water up the height
of the plant you can see water entering
here at the root hairs
those are the very fine areas and that's
where water is going to be coming in
the initial movement of water into roots
involves osmosis
and water moves into the cells at the
root because the fluid in the xylem
contains more solutes than its
surroundings
these solutes in the cell here are more
densely packed with
for example sugars and nutrients and
ions
that water through osmosis is naturally
going to want to move into those root
hairs
ultimately entering the xylem and moving
up through the plant this asthmatic
force is called root pressure
but by itself it's not sufficient to
push the water up the plant stem
and we kind of see another example here
of the water surrounding the soil
particles entering the root hairs
ultimately working its way into the
xylem there's more to it than just this
to create a sufficient root pressure
there's also the solute potential and
this is represented
by the symbol here the solute potential
is caused the osmotic potential
water moves in response the difference
in water potential between the two
systems the left and right side of the
tube so in a perfectly balanced system
we see the water at the same height on
the left and the right of the tube
because there is a difference in water
potential water will move from the soil
to the plant's roots
root cells via the process of osmosis we
see
here we have some solutes water is
naturally going to move
towards those sides we want to try to
dilute those solutes through this
semi-permeable
membrane this is why solute potential is
sometimes called
called osmotic potential now there's
other ways we could add positive
pressure if we add pressure we could
force water to kind of move
and increase this side of the tube if we
create a suction effect or a negative
pressure we could draw water
going this way so again pure water is
going to be even
but here's just a kind of a passive
example by adding solutes to a
semi-purple membrane the osmotic flow of
that water is going to shift to one side
this is occurring also in the help of
capillary action so in addition to root
pressure capillary action
adds to the pull put that in quotes
there to the moon of water up the stems
it's kind of not you know physical like
pull as you think like a pull of a
magnet
but what capillary action is doing is
it's the result
from tiny electrical attractions of
polar water molecules
to the surface that carry an electrical
charge this attraction is called
adhesion so we're looking at capillary
action
here we see a red liquid and we see
different diameter
tubes as the diameter of the tube is
getting smaller we're noticing that the
ability for that
red liquid to travel up the tube is
increasing
and we see that here we have our gradual
increases that gets smaller and finer
it's able to fight the force of gravity
and overcome that force to a greater
extent
this capital reaction is not strong
enough to help pull water up the stem
but this is a
again all these factors are coming
together helping the process
capital reaction depends a lot on the
radius of the tube and you can see again
those smaller radius
having the greatest degree of ability to
resist
the force of gravity a denser fluid and
the same two rises to a smaller height
than other
if other factors being equal so here
we're seeing a more dense material and a
less dense of equal diameter
and how that affects the degree of
capillary action
this adhesion and cohesion that i
mentioned keep in mind that cohesion
is like molecules sticking together we
see the two water molecules
sticking together two water molecules
sticking together because of the
hydrogen bonds it's cohesive
in adhesion dissimilar molecules are
sticking together
so water will interact in is charged
with polar molecules so here we have
the polarity of the water adhering or
sticking to the outside surface here
so it could be the water to the surface
of a leaf it could be water to the
interior parts of the xylem
it's that kind of water attaching or
adhering think of like a piece of tape
tape adhering to the wall adhering to
dust sticking to something other than
itself
now this transpiration how does this
kind of relate to this final
transpiration process
the final pulls the process of moving
water up the plant chute is this
transpiration
water evaporating from the tops of the
leaves is the tube that pulls the column
of water to through the bottom roots
the column of water does not collapse
because water molecules are attracted to
each other
this is the process again called
cohesion the narrower the diameter of
the tube the
more tensile strength that will occur or
resistance to separation of the water
column that'll help again move that
water up
through the plant that transpiration by
which the plant is
leaving the the plant leaf in this case
so more than 90 of the water taken in by
the plant is lost to the atmosphere
mostly through the leaves and
specifically through the stomata the
leaves the pores
water first passes into the pockets of
air in the spongy mesophyll
and then evaporates out the stomata high
humidity and low temperatures decrease
the rates of transpiration
so because we're talking the biological
system there are factors that do impact
this
the transpiration process in general
looking at kind of a nice uh
image here that a tree and this would be
true for even house plants
the cohesion intension theory of sap
ascent is shown
where we again having that water coming
through the root hairs those really fine
areas and then entering the xylem and
then working its way
with cohesive and adhesive properties
drawing water up through the xylem
ultimately reaching to the leaves uh
ultimately into the mesophyll cells
and then ultimately leaving out the
stomata
so evaporation from the mesophyll cells
produces a negative water potential
gradient that causes water to move
upward through the roots
and ultimately through the xylem you can
see that while the root cells are a
negative
pressure there is a greater negativity
of the atmosphere and the leaf tip so
this
in relation here because this is more
negative
water is being pulled in that direction
the atmosphere is very negative and
ultimately that's why it's going out the
stomata and that's why the stomata are
regulated to help reduce the amount of
water loss
now impacts on the transpiration rate
temperature as you see as we increase
temperature the rate of transpiration
will increase and then plateau to a
certain point
our wind velocity as the wind velocity
keeps increasing so does the rate of
transpiration
and kind of an opposite effect is
humidity
as you increase the humidity as you
increase the moisture that's in the air
the rate of transpiration will actually
inverse or decrease
so if there's more water in the air it's
harder for that water to evaporate and
therefore the rate of transpiration will
decrease for that plant
now this stomata as you mentioned are
regulated when guard cells
are plump and swollen they're said to be
turgid and they're going to be
having that stomata be open as we can
see here
when those kind of lose their water
they'll kind of collapse and collapse
and close on themselves
this is allowing the plant to reduce the
amount of water loss
you can see again here where's certain
environmental stresses
that can relate to that there can be
hormones that can affect that
but when those cells are nice and
swollen they're open allowing for water
exchange
and then when that water is lost they
will close
balance between water and air so when a
plant has opened their stomata they can
breathe and exchange carbon dioxide and
oxygen which is what they need to do
however when the stomata are open the
plant is also losing water and runs the
risk of dehydrating
so this is why plants want to be
regulating this process because they
want to maintain
a high degree of tertiary pressure but
if they leave their stomach open for too
long though you can wilt and die
so that's why they're constantly
regulating this to a certain point that
if you don't water the plant that's in
the container
it's ultimately going to wither away and
sadly
perish so if you do provide plants with
the right amount of water they can
regulate fine and grow
if they're not they're going to go
through a wilting process if you don't
want them for an extended period of time
and they do need the water
they ultimately will burn and die due to
dehydration
so what are your plants