in this debaco university video we go
over transitioning your cannabis plants
from the vegetative stage
to the flowering stage while this may
depend
on the strain you're growing or indoor
or outdoor try to give you helpful hints
in all of those situations
[Music]
all right let's go over transitioning
cannabis from vegetative to the
flowering stage
sometimes called flipping the plants so
first off making the change what can
depend on the starting material
and what type of plant type you're
growing for example you're growing seeds
or do you start from clones or do you
have a photoperiod dependent
or do you have an autoflower that's
going to kind of influence significantly
when you make that change or if the
plants make that change on their own
you're dealing with autoflowers so
starting with these seeds compared to
clones comparison when timing the
transition be aware of the stage of root
development
clones tend to have an aggressive top or
vegetative growth
and they grow that a little bit faster
than seeds in the early stages
so be sure also to inspect the roots if
you're going through any plant
it's good to kind of take take it out of
the container if you can
inspect the roots make sure the root
structure one is looking healthy
and well developed before you're going
to put it under the strain
of going through the flipping from the
vegetative to the
flowering phase now if you're looking at
photoperiod dependent
so strains they change from the
vegetative to the flowering cycles
based purely on the duration of light or
photoperiod that they're exposed to
for autoflower strains remember the
transitions based only on plant age
so knowing when you started them will
influence when they're naturally
going to go through that flip
automatically for those growing
photoperiod strains you have a little
bit more options particularly indoors
you're looking at when do you decide to
make that flip
of the photo period from the vegetative
stage to the flowering stage
so this can also depend as i said indoor
you have that control
outdoors not so much these transitions
will occur for both indoor and outdoor
locations
for indoor locations offer more grower
control of timing keep in mind for the
indoor
growers that might be growing grow tents
or ceiling height limited areas
plants are still continuing going to
grow vertically
after you change their vegetative to
flowering stage
so you don't want to run them all over
the top and then flip them things
they're going to stunt and stop
they're still going to continue to
stretch for outdoor growers
this will require growers to make
decisions based on the conditions
that are out of growers controls meaning
the photo period is going to change
naturally in the outdoor environment
what the outdoor grower has control over
is when they start those plants
when those plants go on the ground that
can influence and time it well with the
natural photo period to match up when
they'll naturally change a change over
and flip
to match so that you'll have a
well-developed plant
now the great debate of leaves versus
buzz vegetative or flowering
there is a need for a plant to produce
quality leaves and good morphology to be
able to support flowers or buds
while growers tend to focus on the buds
it is important to consider the general
plant shape
and productivity if you don't have
enough leaves to capture the sun
they won't have enough energy to push
quality buds or flowers
without a quality plant structure the
buds will suffer so timing is important
for growers to maximize
this total production so it is a little
bit of a balance documentation both in
written and picture form
to know when you flipped your plants is
important to try to determine
did you leave them the vegetative stage
too long did you not in the vegetative
stage long enough are you getting the
quality production
and are you getting it in the maximum
efficiency so hopefully this gives you a
little insight in making that transition
from the vegetative to the flowering
stage depending on your specific
conditions