okay here we're gonna look at the
transport and exchange of carbon dioxide
and oxygen this occurs through the
bicarbonate buffer system so when we're
talking about carbon dioxide being
carried and red blood cells in exchange
for oxygen that is what's occurring in
the broad sense but here we're gonna
look a little bit more at the molecular
level to understand in greater detail
what's actually occurring here now to
start off the transport exchange of
oxygen hemoglobin binds with oxygen
within red blood cells we see this
example here here's our hemoglobin it
also gets moving it and is it's changing
shape in one case we have it
deoxygenated one case oxygen so indeed
actually and there's our oxygenated so
it does change shape when bound with
oxygen when this hemoglobin is binding
then the red blood cells with the oxygen
this will cause more to diffuse in to
the blood plasma from the blood plasma
in lungs most hemoglobin molecules carry
a full load of oxygen and that can be
called our our state as soon as our
relaxed State this is when the
hemoglobin is fully oxygenated and again
because it's occurring through the
process of diffusion after binding our
oxygen to hemoglobin more can diffuse in
from the blood plasma pH also influences
that a decrease in pH causes greater
release of oxygen from hemoglobin why is
that important well as cells metabolize
glucose carbon oxide is released into
the blood this causes two main things to
happen an increase in the carbon dioxide
pressure of carbon dioxide and hydrogen
ion concentration in capillary blood
keep in mind pH stands for the measure
of hydrogen ions if we're increasing our
hydrogen ion concentration what we're
essentially doing is decreasing our pH
causing acidosis this decreasing pH this
acidic environment can weaken the
hemoglobin two oxygen bonds but it's
important that we don't let our blood
get too low or too acidic because that
can completely break apart our ability
to bind oxygen continuing on carbon
dioxide is transported in blood in three
main forms one is dissolved in the
plasma and this only accounts for about
seven to ten percent it can be
chemically bound to hemoglobin since
about 20 percent is carried in red blood
cells so this is for heat complex
molecule here as
they know you know hemoglobin the vast
majority are 70% is transported as a
bicarbonate ion what does that look like
hco3 the minus sign it's a bicarbonate
ion so you could see here someone's
period in the red blood cell here's our
procurement ion dissolved in the plasma
as carbonic acid so as the name kind of
implies acidic environment last we have
some carbon oxide dissolved within the
plasma
so this carbonic acid in this acid in
general something we want to keep track
of so transport exchange of carbon
dioxide well looking at this kind of
equation here if you're not familiar
with chemistry chemical equations this
arrow means the reaction is continuing
this way in a reverse arrow meaning the
opposite is happening so carbon dioxide
diffuses in red blood cells and combines
with water to form carbonic acid so
here's our carbon dioxide combines with
water to form our carbonic acid so
that's going this way which will quickly
dissociate or break apart and do
hydrogen ions in bicarbonate ions and
it's going this way however in red blood
cells carbonic anhydrase we see here
it's an enzyme and it can reversibly
catalyze the conversion of carbon
dioxide and water into carbonic acid so
there's a lot going on here the key part
is Kerman oxide in water will break down
foreign form carbon carbonic acid this
carbonic acid can break apart or as we
call dissociate into carbonic and
hydrogen ions and this hydrogen ion
concentration it gets too high this will
cause a decrease in our blood pH create
a more acidic environment which can be
very dangerous to our blood respiratory
and circulatory system so looking at
here a little more of a pictorial level
at the tissue level by Kerman it quickly
diffuses from red blood cells into the
plasma the chloride shift to
counterbalance the out rush of negative
bicarbonate ions from red blood cells
chloride ions cl- move from the plasma
into the ever throw sites so what's
going on here we have this exchange of
our negative charges we have our oxygen
moving this is occurring at the tissue
level that are aspiring so the respiring
for the requiring oxygen that's going
into the cells and as we see carbon
it is leaving now it's leaving and going
into different forms here it's funny
with the hemoglobin here it's combining
with the water to form our carbonate
ions and here's simply dissolving into
the blood plasma so this scan shows you
pictorially the three different steps
that we talked about in this slide here
so it is all chemically bound in
bicarbonate ion we see them all pictured
here oxygen is simply diffusing into the
cells at the lungs these processes are
simply reversed here we see our carbon
dioxide leaving in our oxygen entering
so by kearney ions moving to the red
blood cells and bind to form with
hydrogen ions to form carbonic acid the
carbonic acid is then split by carbonic
anhydrase permits an enzyme to release
carbon dioxide in water it's right here
this is the enzyme creme nessa can also
diffuse from blood to the alveoli
so this is occurring again the ally
within the actual lungs high surface
area allowing for this exchange to occur
influence of carbon acid on blood pH
this is the important part the carbonic
acid and by chronic buffer system
resistant blood pH changes this is a
good thing this is that buffer system we
have the acid in the bicarbonate kind of
playing off one another if hydrogen ion
concentration is Noble I begin to rise
which is excessive hydrogen ions being
added to the system they can be removed
by combining with this car Bernie if
hydrogen ion concentrations begin to
drop carbonic acid can dissociate
releasing the heavier ions so because we
have a way to post take in excessive
hundred ions and also release hydrogen
ions this is how we develop this buffer
system here we're able to buffer the
system right over to if something gets
too high we can bring it down and then
it gets down we can dart bringing it up
this is maintaining our blood pH and
approximately that 7.35 to 7.45 level
very tight control lastly or a
respiratory rate can change can also
alter our blood pH it's important
provides fast-acting system to adjust pH
when it's disturbed by metabolic factors
we're going for a quick run in the burst
of energy that can potentially shift our
pH we need a way to quickly be able to
correct that and prevent it from getting
outside
normal range as it does we could have
our protein cap function properly we
could have reduced oxygen levels to
certain parts of the body and all
negative things could basically happen
if this buffer system was to fail you
keep in mind we have this bicarbonate
buffer system and this carbon acid and
oxygen exchange that's occurring and
hopefully now you can appreciate what's
occurring a little bit more at the
molecular level