here we're gonna look at the process of
translation now here will may be
translating one language into another
language back into the original language
yeah we're gonna look at translation in
this lecture series is going to be
converting our mRNA sequence into an
actual protein so let's get into it
so if we're talk about translation if
transcription and this refers back to
the central dogma of biology we're
looking at DNA being replicated and
transcribed and translated transcribe or
just like we see here someone typing on
an old typewriter is the process of
taking DNA and transcribing it into RNA
this is a process through RNA polymerase
it binds to one DNA strand at the site
called a promoter region so the promoter
region is kind of the initial like
region it moves along the DNA pairing
complementary nucleotides and then
disintegrates at the stop signal so we
see here here's our DNA or
double-stranded DNA
looking at the sense strand and here's
our mRNA and our RNA polymerase in this
region or taking a double stranded
region taking one particular sequence
here and we are now producing an mRNA
sequence that will then be used in the
next process so this process of
transcription the promoter regions where
it's starting and we're transcribing our
DNA into our mRNA and again keep in mind
D RNA DNA contains thymine and RNA will
contain uracil so you need to actual
translation what is this it's converting
the order of nucleotides of a gene into
the order of amino acids in the protein
Emma RNAs are the blueprint or copies of
the nuclear genes mRNAs are read by the
ribosomes in three nucleotide units
called codons each 3 nucleotide sequence
codes for an amino acid or a stop signal
so let's look at this again here here's
our DNA we're transcribing our DNA to
our RNA and we're translating our RNA to
our actual amino acid sequence that will
simply generate our proteins keep in
mind these codons are these three coding
regions and we don't read necessary each
individual nucleotide one at a time they
actually look at them in groups of three
in these codons are what's referred to
as generating the particular amino acid
so you can see here our episomes
these are the protein making factories
of the cell these have a large and a
small subunit these mRNA to direct
assembly of a protein and a ribosome is
made up of two subunits each composed of
our RNA so if you want to go back and
refer to the types of RNA lecture you're
more and welcome to is a lot of that
comes back and is involved here you
could see our T RNA sequences our mRNA
and this ribosome is made mostly by wait
at least of our RNA which is ribosomal
RNA now the basic process of making a
protein the mRNA binds to a smaller
episomes subunit the large subunit joins
the complex forming a complete ribosome
no doubt large and that small subunit
joined together and that little gap in
between there the mRNA is the mRNA
threads through the ribosome producing
the Polytech peptide remember
polypeptide polypeptide mini peptide
bonds peptide bonds will hold or link
the amino acids together and a
collection of amino acids will form
hopefully a functional protein so
transfer RNA these bring amino acids to
the ribosome they are anticodon region
binding to the mRNA these three base
pairs and at the three prime end here
where the hydroxyl group is where the is
where the amino acid would be attached
they have the anticodon region again
bind to the mRNA and the three prime Oh
H is where the amino acid will be
attached and it does look like a basic T
type structure that forgets the name
transfer RNA
so as a transferring but it also has a T
like shape the normal process here's our
DNA transcription transcribed to our RNA
translated to a protein these large
letters capital letters represent
different amino acids now the genetic
code converting a codon to an amino acid
so important to know how to read and
produce the proper amino acids giving
the
so remember these are current threes so
you want to take the first letter and
use this column here so we'll just say
for example the first letter was an a
that's gonna put you into this row here
now when the second letter let's say it
was are you so we're in this row you
will put us in this column with the
intersects or in this box right here and
the third letter if it was a G we're
gonna be in this row and this column and
in this specific box here so it would be
Aug would be this C start codon here we
notice if our codon was UGA we would go
you would find G we'd find a and we see
that corresponds that they stop codon
located here now it could also be you a
a you hey hey that also be a stop codon
and you AG wouldn't need another stop
codon so there are some redundancies it
see here's a bunch that also represent
on the same amino acid and on certain
cases in technically rare cases we have
some that encode for only one amino acid
or only a couple and code for the same
amino acid not as many redundancies
there this is a typical square or box
type this also is a very similar type
it's the same a different icon it's in a
circular format here you'd start with
the first letter in the middle and you'd
work your way out so if you remember
back here some of our stop codons you AG
you to a to G and this black circle
means it's a stop codon our start codon
was Aug so we want to find our a for our
first letter here's our you and here's
our g there's our start comeback
so you can see it reads basically the
same way just presented in this a
different form the basic process of our
transcription remember our DNA we're
transcribing it to form our mRNA mRNA
gets translated into a basically amino
acid sequence using the protein same
basic process
so necessary components for our
translation
remember that's mrna to a protein we
need a ribosomes with your tRNA we need
our mRNA remember here's our anticodon
region here would be our you know acid
which would be very specific to that
particular codon and this would be our
ribosome here or basically the
protective structures allowing this
process to occur
now ribosome somebody's attached and
start the translation process we could
see here MMA team it is our start codon
tRNA carrying the first amino acid is
paired with the start codon of the mRNA
there's an a site AP site in an e site
the e site holds the tRNA carrying to
the next amino acid sequence so a is
kind of the start p site holds at ni
carrying the grinning amino acid chain
it's middle and east site is where the
tearing exits so a good thing is the
first letter in the alphabet where it
starts P site is kind of the middle one
each site is where it's exiting so
here's our a or P and this would be our
East site here exiting out the tRNA keep
in mind that TNA is exiting it no longer
has an amino acid attached to it because
it added it to the polypeptide chain it
has to go out and find another amino
acid in line to it
oonh acids are joined by a peptide bond
those proteins are polypeptides made of
many peptide bonds they're linked
together with this bond and in the first
trna is released it is now missing the
amino acid and has to go back and find
that you know acid were combined and
come back again we see the same basic
picture presented slightly differently
so you can hopefully see the
similarities and see the differences or
being develop a better understanding of
this process process continues to
ribosome contingent on the mRNA until
the second tier anaise and the P site
and this allows the process to continue
we have this communal binding this
linking is kicking out coming back
repeat repeat repeat down the whole
messenger RNA sequence through growing
peptide chain if you notice the ribosome
moves along the mRNA and amino acids are
continually added to the ever growing
polypeptide chain the stop codon
detaches the polypeptide sequence in the
last two nights release resulting in the
dissociation of the ribosome subunits
what that means we see is the same ball
here but if we look back and remember at
some of our previous images there's
actually two subunits from our large and
subunit and that basically stop region
is causing these to fall apart and when
they fall apart they release the linear
chain of amino acids it's a peptide
chain where can hopefully go folds to
perform a functional protein kind of
translation process summary again it's
the same thing we have our initiation
step we have elongation step basically
bring it that chain over here with our
termination step our release factor your
Aug set stop codon and then the parts
are recycled so just because these
immunity these amino acids are growing
here and just because all of a sudden
our two are RNAs or two ribosomal
subunits dissociate doesn't mean they're
completely wasted they are allowed to
reform and go through the process again
these amino acids are given up by the
tRNAs are used for the protein as a
result this tRNA it's released has to go
and find another amino acid and bind to
it and it's tried to process again
so beefing with this translation process
and basically this is how proteins are
made how this may look DNA transcription
to translation we saw this in the DNA of
replication so you can kind of see a
very similar pattern here except we're
only forming a single chain here we're
noticing the presence of yourself
indicating we're making RNA from our DNA
strand so we see our single strand kind
of forming here going right down and
right along our DNA here's our mRNA it's
the person in nucleus we're exiting out
the nucleus now we're in the cytoplasm
of the cell here's our two subunits
here's our tRNA here's our bonds being
formed our peptide bonds being formed
and we're looking putting together our
amino acids ultimately were forming a
protein we notice that all of these are
different amino acids they're all coding
and reading these three codon sequences
however at the very end scissors stop
codon you see I represent
associate this moves on to another
ribosome here's our peptide chain
hopefully for
into a functional protein remember
structure determines function
translation process summary again same
basic process as we saw there we have
our two subunits binding to the mRNA
TNA's are coming in linking a bunch of
amino acids together ultimately release
factor stop codon causes a new protein
to basically be formed another great
link here if you want to look from DNA
to protein a 3d model the process
continues until the stop codon enters
the a site and ribosome complex falls
apart in the protein is released another
way to show the translation process
keep in mind certain portions of it that
transcription portion occurs actually in
the nucleus but the ribosomes are
located in the cytoplasm are outside the
nucleus so this RNA sequence this mRNA
must exit out to the nuclear pores and
if you want to hear different videos
from different presenters I put a couple
links here you're more than welcome to
check those out