now growers of cannabis can be indoors
or outdoors
and everyone thinks the other one's
easier however here i'm going to go over
how you take your small
cannabis plant how you transition it to
an indoor or an outdoor site what are
the advantages and disadvantages of each
here on debaco university
[Music]
all right assuming you have a nice
little cannabis plant let's go over
if you put it in an indoor or an outdoor
location where are some of the things
pros and cons with each so first off
indoor outdoor production
where will your ceiling or clone be
spinning the rest of its cycle you want
to think about is going to be in the
indoor or is it going to be in the
harsher outdoor environment we have a
little less controls
but also a little less upfront costs so
first off for indoor
applications what's the advantages well
grower has control over the environment
it can produce higher quality flowers
and it can allow for specific
experimentation so it's great to kind of
have this as
an option if you're looking at creating
experiments looking at strains
indoor environment that control offers a
lot of advantages offers a lot of kind
of
ways to see differences a little bit
better
now the disadvantages of being in an
indoor production
is simply the cost of all the equipment
that you need as you can see here in
these
examples these you need to supply the
lighting you need to supply the water it
needs to apply the air circulation
there's also challenges in producing
high total biomass
simply because of the expense associated
with the area
you also have a lack of natural outdoor
conditions
which again could be advantage can be
disadvantaged but in this case a lack of
natural outdoor conditions you have to
make sure
you're regulating and simulating that
outdoor
conditions to maximize the growth of
your plants
now for those outdoor productions again
are indoors productions pros and cons
outdoor same thing
what are some of the advantages of
growing outdoors overall you have
reduced
cost of production compared to indoor
production as you just mentioned because
you get natural sunlight exposure
there is no need to go back to the
previous slide no you need to have
lights
here with different wavelengths and
changing out bulbs and you know
supplying electricity and cooling that
will get natural sunlight exposure and
that's kind of
free it's also easy to grow large
quantities because you don't have to
worry about or under the constrains
of that kind of lighting application
there however all is not glorious there
are also some
disadvantages to growing outdoors
there's simply a lack of control over
environmental conditions it could be too
much water too little rain
too much sun different soil types so
these are all things to take into
consideration
it's also increased pest pressure from
natural as well as insects as well as
larger potentially deer
can also impact the area certain soil or
field conditions are not supportive for
plant growth
so you want to be mindful of taking a
soil test so you're not putting your
plants in an
area that they may look good initially
but then will not come to term at the
full
end of the harvest cycle so again each
has their advantages and disadvantages
you've got to pick one and you've got to
deal with some of the conditions you may
have control or not control
over and hopefully will produce a
quality product
regardless of indoor or outdoor
conditions as long as you go about
planning