here we'll look at the plant hormone
trike antinol and while this may be sold
in powders for our growers to use
because of its many listed benefits and
research be careful where you purchased
those powders and exactly the
concentrations you're using because it
can have a very fast effects on plants
and very variable effects that can also
cause plant harm if you use too much of
it as with any hormone so in general
where is it found well it's found in the
cuticle waxes in in beeswax actually
it's a growth stimulant for many plants
so it works across many different plant
species research has reported that it
can improve growth in yield and
photosynthesis and protein synthesis
uptake of water and nutrients nitrogen
fixation and enzyme activities all these
are great things that growers are always
seeking for a ways to improve this is
why this hormone trike antinol vvt-i
a has gotten so much attention now it
can increase free amino acids and we do
sugars inside wall proteins in rice and
maize within five minutes so it's very
fast-acting also being applied at nano
molar concentrations at some very small
concentrations there's been reports
within one minute of the roots and
plants and shoots noticing in effect so
this hormone in particular can work
extremely fast one to five minutes of
application there can already be a plant
response so that's important if you're
looking at adding this to be very
careful because you can change the
potential physiology of the plant very
quickly some of the benefits though are
that can increase in dry matter
production could lead to an increase in
secondary products all great things
there's also strong evidence that
application of tri Cantona applied to
either the root medium or the leaves
enhance the growth and yields of
vegetables and other crops including
agronomic and horticultural crops as
well as medicinal and aromatic crops
under normal in adverse conditions so
this is great potential research showing
that this can help improve the yield of
crops with very small quantities it can
act very quickly in those crops this is
why continues to
look out further research because while
we may be noticing these benefits
particularly for vegetables if it's
something we're consuming we want to
make sure that's tested and vetted for a
proper process so that's safe for human
consumption