okay here I'm going to explain the
triangulation method how it relates
typically to crime scenes and
particularly to sketches and
documentation of where things might be
located
some of the information I got was from
Ashland up Pierson that the web site
found here at SlideShare so starting
with triangulation method let's look at
what is this about well first off and
want to Train Lee anything we need to
have fixed points we have areas of
reference or to measure off of there's
no set saying of what has to be a fixed
point typically we're using the larger
objects these fixed points act as
accurate measurements that must be
recorded so that the scale of the
finalized sketch can be prepared for
presentation so we have these fixed
points and that's what's allowing us to
establish this area and act as points
that we can then measure off of in from
so looking at the triangulation method
of locating evidence well here an item a
is 10 feet in southeast corner of the
room and 815 the southwest corner of the
room SUNY North is this way these
measurements will always intersect at
Point A's location so now what we're
looking at and going through
triangulation with Ella fixed items so
now how we triangulate for Part A here
so evidence must be translated with two
fixed points how would object a be
triangulated not from using the corners
of the rooms we have our desk here we're
looking at transition without that fixed
point so the desk is not fixed since is
that touching the walls located and has
not been determined
so a desk needs to be fixed in space we
have to measure that to start here it is
one inch from the on this wall I'm three
feet from this wall providing the
measurements the desk is not fixed in
space now object a can be fixed to the
two fixed points of the desk now we've
established where that desk is now we
can measure from there
so I'm decay can now be fixed from the
two fixed points from the desk as
depicted and the above the sketch five
feet from here and six feet from here
now we've established where that desk is
located now progressing to object flush
to the wall I would after they be
trained over the desk that's flush to
the wall well because it's flush to the
wall we don't have to measure about
find it you can measure its distance
from this wall and we can now take our
two fixed points from the corner one
motion is required to place the desk
along the wall plus it's flush with the
wall making it fixed and then the object
is translated as usual how it was flush
to both walls if it stuffed in the
corner how do we do that well we don't
dis tablished a desk at all we can just
measure from those corners of that desk
to get the triangulation where point a
is located
once evidence of training that it can be
a fixed point to train the other items
from so if evidence a was here to
evidence B we can work also from that
fixed point to this circuit point in
this case object B so the rectangular
coordinate method we see here nice kind
of coordinating things were object a and
B might be located it's another great
way right angles to again from the wall
and distance from the wall center of
mass so what does this refer to well
I've had to do with blood splatter or
some other forms of liquids how are we
dealing with that or how are we going to
measure those who can measure each three
of those in this case when I get a
couple more well we're gonna measure to
what's called the center of mass so
since blood droplets are no particular
defined shape they are trained from the
center of mass what does that mean well
this is our blood spatter were kind of
estimating the center to be right there
and that's what we're trained leading
from not any one particular droplet or
from the center of that massive there
unless we have a projection sketch so we
see all the data that's included all the
details or the translation that's
included the legend of what the letters
correlate and where north is located now
it's not the scale or you could say that
quarter inch equals a foot whatever fits
the conditions here we can see the level
of detail that's seen in the sketch and
many times training missions are trained
the triangle relation method is used to
do know for example where the bolt hole
is in relation to the walls to get an
idea where that's located to be used and
shown in courtroom settings