on this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at trimming tool
options for cannabis both on a manual
standpoint and also a mechanical
standpoint
and some of the pros and cons associated
with each
[Music]
all right let's get into trimming tools
for cannabis well first off trimming in
general
unlike many other plants cannabis does
require some method of kind of
singling out unpollinated buds for the
rest of the plant material
the process of removing the leaves near
the buds can require some detailed
trimming
if you're going for high quality dry
flour as your chosen
end product however there can be a lot
of plant volume
to get through so utilizing some
mechanical method
may be advised at least to remove some
of the bulk material
allowing for less plant material that
needs to be manually removed
which will improve your overall
efficiency so some will use a
combination of manual
methods as well as mechanized methods
now some will choose to use one or the
other
so if you're using hand trimming methods
your manual methods
the advantage of this is that allows
each bud to be handled in a very unique
way there's someone physically there
going through and taking out
this leaf and not that leaf or removing
that or trimming it in this angle
so that's the great part of it the
disadvantages is with that option is
that it is very labor
intensive you have to go through and be
mindful and take one section and not
another section
and be careful not to remove very vital
portions
remove those excess areas so that's why
some growers will go with a
kind of a machine trimming kind of
option as we see here a trauma version
it's very efficient method particularly
for high volume material
simply feed in the system here and it
goes through and kind of
manicured buds kind of come out the
other end the disadvantage
is that this can damage buds because it
is a mechanical kind of tumbling process
and there are other methods but
regardless machines do have more of that
physical contact with the buds and could
damage them
they also may remove too much plant
material because they're not
able to go through and be very precise
and unique with each individual bud
now some growers are utilizing both
methods where they
have a lot of plant material to process
so as a result they use a trommel or
some other form of mechanized system
might be a good first step to initially
trim the buds and then
this will remove some of the larger
leaves bulk material which will then
allow for
the grower to spend time doing the
detailed work with each unique dry
flower
so it gets the individual attention it
needs to look its best
now this is only possible kind of
because of the larger volumes to take
off some of those plant materials
so that the amount of individual
attention or the time that's spent with
that individual
tension is definitely reduced then
starting with freshly harvested plant
material or dried plant material
and starting basically to remove all the
leaves
and then go through and manicure them
sometimes utilization of that mechanical
machine
can be advantageous to take out some of
the grunt work and then allow the kind
of
trimmer to go through to the detailed
work so you're producing the highest
quality
end product possible