okay what we're looking at impressions
here if we're looking at
footwear there can be two and three
dimensions of these impressions taken
it could be kind of an inked image which
would be a two dimension or kind of a
poured cast to take advantage of the
three dimensions
so i'm going to cover that here so
looking at the footwear analysis
well areas of footwear which are
examined by analysis include the design
of the shoe the physical size and shape
the wear marks
and also individual identifying
characteristics such as
cuts and or tears or or the gum that
might be present or a nail
or anything else that would be kind of
very specific
to that one particular shoe now two and
three dimensional are impressions well
how do they differ we're looking at
our two dimensional impressions those
are impressions made they could be on
tile
wood flooring similar highly available
surfaces linoleum
it can be also latent prints three
dimensional impressions
are remaining after a shoe permanently
deforms the surface found in sand mud
or snow so that is an example of the two
to three dimensional impressions and
both
can be very important now the visible
prints as we see
here these prints are visible with no
additional processes
needed so the ones you can just kind of
look down and quote find
if you know where to look this could be
examples include soil or the materials
picked up by the shoe or deposit onto a
flat hard contrasting surface
there's a variety of surfaces and
materials deposited makes recovery
from those prints very complex so again
whether it's
something that's in a very hard surface
a very soft surface
a heavier individual a lighter
individual all this is going to impact
the visibility of those particular
prints
and we have something called latent
prints so these prints require some
process to make them visible or
very difficult to visualize these latent
prince examples could be very
barely visible dust if it's kind of in a
kind of attic for example it hasn't been
disturbed a lot
impressions and polishes or wax or waxes
those might need some additional kind of
processes done
to be able to make them visible either
to be photographed or just be visible by
the investigator
those are latent prints so here we're
looking at two-dimensional impressions
so once an impression has been
photographed the print may be able to be
lifted
off the particular surface electrostatic
lifting can help transfer it
and fingerprint powder can be used in
combination with what's called pvs
which is polyvinyl
which is a casting material that can be
used for impressions where electrostatic
lifting
may not work so this is kind of this
kind of
example of how we can potentially lift
that print off the area to be examined
in the lab
we have also three dimensional
impressions so this
example here is where we can use dental
stone its primary method of
casting footwear impressions on wet
surfaces
spray wax maybe we have to be used to
first seal the impression off
then a mix of dental stone on site with
water in a sealable bag for about
three minutes and the stone hardens in
about 20 minutes
in about 24 to 40 hours but a day to two
days hours it will
be fully hardened and can be used and
stored
it's important to kind of create this
little setup but this is pretty easy to
do on site it doesn't really require
a lot of materials because it's all kind
of self-contained
now those 3d prints are shoe prints made
into soft material such as dirt or snow
the composition of the material will
determine the detail
of the impression made this often
requires making up a cast of the print
as we can see here and there's other
types as i said this
dental stone for example we can have a
little cardboard side here to help
sit in place this can be a great way to
help preserve those prints
to be able to be investigated looked at
and compared and entered as evidence at
a later date