now here we're going to be looking at
different types of growing containers
and we can see in this image the wide
variety of containers being grown here
we'll get some things that are a little
bit more commonly used so first off the
common types of containers are plastic
or solid side pots AER pots fabric pots
grow bags biodegradable pots by a couple
different names here and also discuss
where square pots vs. round pots may be
most advantageous to use so starting off
with the obvious we have our plastic
solid side pots and see a wide variety
here they're very common to consider to
be the standard there's many options in
size and shape and color and thickness
they often have the option of being
reused this is what makes them the kind
of standard they're kind of lightweight
they're easy to get they can get in
large quantities oh and the options are
being reused is the main reason why
these are considered the standards
however there's other options available
to growers such as air pots the goal is
to maximize aeration they induce air
pruning of roots to reduce roots
circling basically they allow air to
come in and because the root tips then
to kind of dry out and cause those roots
tips to dry out but then causing
increased branching now they've been
used a lot in tree production as we can
see here to make for easier transplant
process again well there's a zoom in one
of here they can be used also on a large
scale they've gone through some
different revisions but again in tree
production is kind of where they're most
commonly being used now these are
looking at being transplanted outgrown
propagated and then transplanted fabric
pots are smart pots is a name-brand
familiar with that they clean the same
benefits as air pots but they have the
added benefit of easy delivery storage
and shipping this is because they
completely fold down and they keep most
vacuum sealed many pots to be shipped in
a very small area they're available in
very small sizes too as you can see here
very large sizes so don't think that
these fabric pots are just limited to
small little grow bags they can be grown
full-sized plants in an outdoor
situation that we see here these pallets
are approximately 4 feet by 4 feet just
to give you an idea there's a
traditional plastic pot in comparison
grow
Baggs something a little different
there's potential confusion between
fabric pots and bags depending on the
material grow bags are typically made
from plastic creating a solid sides so
unlike the fabric pots we saw there is a
lot of breathing that may occur these
are typically solid sides how are these
plat this plastic is considered as
closer resemblance of a heavy trash bag
than a rigid side of a traditional
plastic pot they offer again the ease of
storage reduced shipping cost and light
weight and benefits associated similar
to the fabric pots the drawbacks include
that reduced usage life is typically one
to three years at one of these grow bags
that will not last forever and depending
what conditions they are used in then we
have biodegradable pots the goal is be
able to plant the entire pot to reduce
waste and time common types include the
peat pot or Jiffy Pop there's Cal pots
dot pots and croire pots these are some
common names 50 being by the most widely
known Cal pots being made out of
literally cow manure and I say
biodegradable while we have all the
different pot types the vat it really
does vary we can see here's a field
trial Iran with tomatoes you could see a
choir pot here rates that he did not
degrade at all even though roots were
able to penetrate the cow pot almost
completely broke down the jiffy pot did
break down but still has some of its
large components still visible in the
field after a growing season air for
tomato then we get to the bay of round
versus square and keep in mind that the
plants now prefer one over the other
however to maximize space to grow me one
a favor one versus the other
brilliant plant development square pots
are preferred since this allows
efficient packing plants and minimizes
empty space that we see here can align
all these pots up together reason why I
like the square pots early on is packing
all these together efficient use of
space and also kind of keeping that
moisture level a little bit higher
there's no reduces air flow in total
they're keeping all those that moisture
they're in close proximity and also
allows these to be tapped under lights
efficiently later in development though
is when transplanting and shape is less
of a concern simply because plants are
not growing in a pot to pot kind of
situation
round pots are preferred simply because
there'll be less media used for the same
basic footprint because those plants are
going
be bigger and spread out those pots are
going to be touching typically anyway
sober can switch over to the round so
even though the plants don't really care
which one versus the other the grower
may depending on the situation depending
on the growth stage of the plant