okay here we're gonna go over different
types of RNA up to this point you might
have thought there's only one type of
RNA when in fact there's actually four
main different types of RNA we have them
labeled here mRNA tRNA our RNA and RNA I
we're going to go through each of these
in detail and try to give an explanation
and how they relate to seller and
biological processes so starting with
the main components for protein
production now there's three key
components that we have RNA that are
required to make proteins mRNA and that
stands for messenger RNA you see it
labeled here and it's single-stranded
it's producing a message or a single
strand of nucleic acids tRNAs transfer
RNA we see that located over here so
transfer RNA is transferring or reading
certain regions on the mRNA and
transferring an amino acid so it's
responsible for grab my new acid bring
it to the mRNA sequence and transferring
that from some point in the cell to
developing a polypeptide sequence our
RNAs ribosomal RNA that's the one
pictured over here so this ribosomal RNA
down here is what is involved with
protein production so what we have a
large and a small subunit and over here
the mRNA is basically going and being
read right across and going to the RNA
so here in the our RNA we're noticing
that the mRNA is being protected
now the trna located right here is
what's coming into the ribosome and
that's it's transferring the amino acids
just as a reminder we're talking all
about RNA here and that's ribonucleic
acid deoxyribonucleic acids DNA Nance
without that oxygen on that backbone
sugar chain so just keep those in mind
these are all RNA okay so looking at
mRNA in more detail remember mRNAs and
from messenger RNA it's a short section
of genetic material encoded from a DNA
molecule so
organized into three base pairs called
codons so we can see up here or saying
that there's the three base pairs those
are the codons and we could see them
kind of each little individual unit here
working its way down all the way to the
end here
each of these three base pairs is a
codon now up here we're noticing at the
very end it says a stop codon so this
stop codon is important because each
codon encodes for specific amino acid
sequence only the stop codon does not
encode for an amino acid sequence it
actually terminates protein synthesis
it's a way of saying stop or end so to
speak and it is still a three base pair
it's so look at all of these a's G's C's
and use are the same nucleotides that we
learned with DNA keeping in mind that
because we see you your so we were
definitely looking at a DNA molecule to
continue on with messenger RNA there's
actually two different subtypes of
messenger RNA so we have what we call
pre mRNA going to mature mRNA now don't
confuse mature RNA as this M being
mature this mRNA is here in here still
stands for messenger RNA so there's pre
messenger RNA to mature messenger RNA
pre RNA contains in trying to turn
non-coding sequences and we see those up
here there are regions of the pre
earning that don't encode for anything
these introns are spliced out or removed
resulting in a continuous strain of
exons which is what the mature mRNA is
composed of so why would there be
non-coding agents why does this make
sense well in the event that there's a
chance that there's always going to be a
mutation that could occur an error in
the nucleotide sequence
well while there is checks and balances
to try to prevent that by having these
introns the hope is or the odds are if
one does occur it may occur in one of
these regions and be spliced out and
removed and basically having no impact
on the final mRNA contrast to that if
there was only this mature mRNA produced
every single base pair would
be absolutely necessary if there's just
one error somewhere it could really
offset the sequence or type of amino
acids which could make the protein
non-functional by having these introns
there's a chance if there is a mistake
it could have occur here and would not
affect the final mRNA sequence located
here okay so here the tRNA remember that
stands for transfer RNA it is
responsible transferring or bringing
amino acids to the ribosome hydrogen
bonds give them all a distinctive T
shape it actually does look like a T and
they have two attachment sites down here
we have the codon so the anticodon
region which is going to bind to the
mRNA so down here is going to where the
mRNA is going to be that anticodon is
gonna have three pairs
that's what's gonna bind to the
complimentary mRNA coming up top here
and in this region here we're gonna have
the three prime region which is where
the amino acids are attached and that
amino acids going to be attached there
and it's gonna correspond with down
below the particular codon sequence so
every tRNA does not necessarily have the
same amino acid the codon or anticodon
down here signals and allows only a
specific type of amino acid to bind
there so every tRNA has a specific
binding site at the mRNA region and it
will correspond with a very specific
amino acid sigma trna provides a link
between the mRNA and the amino acid
sequence of proteins by carrying the
amino acid we're down here is our codon
that are anticodon here's our tRNA and
our amino acid be linked up here
each tRNA has specific amino acid that
corresponds to a particular codon
however there are some different codons
that have the same amino acids to help
reduce the chance of change amino acid
sequence
there's redundancies built in our RNA
continuing with ribosomal RNA 60% the
ribosome by weight is our RNA the other
40% is some proteins
that sounds a little weird that there
takes proteins to make proteins but in
this case it's true there's slight
differences between prokaryotic remember
our bacterial and eukaryotic are
clearance in our animal cells in size
but they perform the same function this
large s in small a stands for a large
subunit and a small subunit in ProCare X
what's called 50s in small to 30s and
eukaryotic a large 80s and a small B 40s
the actual numbers aren't important here
the key part is it to understand that we
have a larger unit smaller unit binding
together there's a small gap located
right here and that's where the mRNA
sequence single-stranded will work its
way through as we're going through the
process of protein synthesis putting it
all together here we have our ribosome
our large subunit here our small subunit
here this is the little gap I was
talking about we will see mRNAs fits
right in there encased inside these both
large and small subunits we have our T
RNA tRNA has an amino acid and as these
come through we're building an amino
acid chain so you can see how these
three main types of RNA all come
together to produce a chain of amino
acids that will ultimately hopefully
produce a functional protein but I did
mention one more and that one was I
called RNA I and it stands for RNA
interference and it inhibits gene
expression by sound some targeted mRNA
sequences refer to a gene knocked down
or a silencer and this is a type of gene
regulation without a small single
stranded RNA so the SI stands for single
stranded and induces a double stranded
RNA d/s RNA so RNA needs to be
single-stranded here to be efficient the
copied but when we have our RNA i its
interfere with this process it's coming
through and it's binding with this mRNA
causing it to be double-stranded not
really allowing for it to be easily
replicated in the ribosome and that can
stop the production of a particular
protein this could be because the cell
may not need that protein do enough that
protein can be made already and it's a
way to stop that protein production
cells do not want to continue to keep
investing energy to produce proteins
that they don't
need RNA AI is increasing the number of
published scientific articles back in
1978 very minimal number of articles
then we see an exponential increase to
2005 so it's not even super current data
and it's continued to just produce a lot
of published work it's important because
of its contributions or its the benefits
that some of this can offer declaring
medicine so the advantages is that it
could be used to target diseases with
minimal side effects due to the high
degree of specificity meaning we're
looking to target a particular disease
we don't want to kill every cell we
don't only want to kill the disease
cells well by having an RNA I the
potential is at least theoretically if
we found a very unique mrna sequence we
could develop these small single
stranded RNAs and they would bind to
that mRNA causing it to be chopped up
and basically stopping the production of
proteins for a given disease and this
could be very helpful now while this is
talks about the theoretical sense there
is some real-world applications there's
a timeline made to medicine so in 1986
first demonstrated potential and animals
in 2010 first in human Phase one
clinical trials begin now this phase 1
clinical trial may not mean much but I'm
gonna go over what these refer to phase
1 basically first to very early stages
both phase one and phase two clinical
trials show therapeutic applications in
2015 only five years for this occur is
pretty quick and in 2017 currently first
in humans Phase three trials begin and
that's a lot more advanced clinical
trial that's showing its passing these
certain phases so these clinical trials
what do these mean this gives you an
idea so if a zero is just very basic
effect on the body
phase one we're getting into is it safe
in humans that study can be designed to
terminus X the drug device in humans
usually involves a small number of
volunteers phase threes randomized
trials there's a control groups compared
to a placebo group and it's kind of
tested against that we're now into Phase
three trials which actually is quite
exciting because it's testing the
large-scale safety of its
to miss these studies involve randomized
blind testing once phase 3 is complete
this is the key part a company can
request FDA approval for marketing of
the drug and that's when we come
available to the mass public once that
occurs and pays for trials can occur
so we're it's very exciting to know that
our nai is being involved as phase 3
trials where it could be soon released
to the general public to be able to help
prevent or cure or suppress certain
diseases
hopefully with very little side effects