this tobacco university lecture is going
to focus on different types
of explosives so first off we have the
low explosives and these have escaping
gases of about 3000 feet per second
and they're kind of a crucial element is
a physical mixture of
oxygen and fuel examples are black and
smokeless powders
these are a mixer mixture typically of
potassium nitrate charcoal and
sulfur smokeless powder is a nitrocellus
and perhaps a
nitroglycerin a kind of compound there
getting into high explosives well these
have a much quicker
velocity the escaping gases approach
10 000 feet per second and it's usually
oxygen
contained in a fuel molecule two types
we have the initiating which is
sensitive and will
detonate rapidly when subject to heat or
shock and it's used to
um you know other explosives from an
explosive
train we also have non-initiating which
is relatively insensitive requires heat
or shock to kind of cause that chain
reaction to occur
and this includes for example the ever
famous tnt
we have also chemical explosives as well
and these are ammonium nitrate fuel oil
anfo typically referred to as a black
powder
and dynamite would be classified under
that commercial explosive
category then we have military
explosives
so um c4 which is
also known as r dx
when we have a whole bunch of others
that can be mixed with tnt
to make grenades and other forms of
explosives
used in military settings lastly keeping
with the
military sadly something that the
military has to deal with a lot of
are called ieds and these stand for
improvised explosive devices
and these are typically low explosives
but they're placed in confined
containers which is what makes them so
dangerous an ied is a bomb constructed
and deployed in ways other than the
conventional military action
sadly typically put along roadsides so
that when uh
opposing military vehicles come by then
they are detonated at that point
they may be constructed of conventional
military explosives such as artillery
rounds attached to a detonating
mechanism nineties are commonly used as
roadside bombs
typically what you see here so this is
just a general
overview of the different
classifications of explosives