so you may wonder why is it important to
understand different types of tire wear
well it can apply to your own tires if
you go out and look at your own tires to
see how the
pattern of wear might be occurring can
get an indication
of something that you may not have
optimized with your tires
or if you find a suspect's car and match
up the
evidence at the crime scene with certain
wear patterns of the tire and they match
up
it can help strengthen a case against
someone
so first off we want to take care when
we're looking at tire alignment
with a car and how that's going to
impact the wear patterns of the tire
so something called camber toe and
caster
so camber is referring to the inward and
outward tilt of the tires
as viewed from the front you have
something called toe and this is from
the side
to side difference of the tire this is
the front and the back is it toe in or
toe out
there's something called caster which is
the slope of the steering axis and
that's kind of like you think of a
caster
on a shopping cart you can notice that
there's
negative cast if it's forward or
positive caster there
so tire alignment can also play into the
wear
as well looking specifically about the
camber
this is the inward and outward tilt of
the tire so it viewed from the front
this is that inward and outward tilt
uh inward tilt is considered negative
and outward is considered positive so we
look kind of at the car right here
we can see it has negative camber and it
has a lot of
negative camber this is used to
distribute the load across
the entire tread not so much in this
case improper camera can make the tire
aware on one edge
as probably indicated here and cause the
vehicle to pull
to the side that has the most positive
on camera
there's something called toe this is
referring to toe in and toe out
this is the side to side difference in
distance between the front
and rear of the front tires so if the
distance is closer at the front it's
called toe in
so we see indicated here on this race
car we tow in
and then the difference is closer the
rear this would be called toe out and
again this can also impact the wear
last we have caster here as far as
orientation of the tire
the caster is the fourth is the four or
f slope of the steering axis that's
referring to whether it's a negative
caster
or a positive caster a neutral caster
would be
it straight up and down the an example
here would be the
shock assembly positive casters when the
bottom of the steering axis
is in front of the tires contact path
negative is of course the opposite
so factory alignment specs for basically
all vehicles call for a certain degree
of positive caster
because this will help ensure good
stability and help maintain straight
head direction
with the promotion of steering wheel
self-centering
so this helps that wheel kind of
naturally want to track
in a straight line which is very helpful
for handling purposes
so when we're looking at our tires and
we're trying to estimate the
tread and where it may have worn or how
much it is worn
we can use a penny or a quarter using
currency to estimate the tread
simply using this penny in our quarter
the depth of the tread can
be closely examined and kind of looks at
the difference between
when you put the penny down how does it
match up to the
head of the in the person printed on the
currency there so for example looking at
the
difference between when push it down and
two
30 seconds tread is legally worn in this
case so we're looking here it's just
basically touching the head of abraham
lincoln
we flip that same penny around here and
look at six 30 seconds tread
well that's going to match pretty much
the base stairs there of
the lincoln monument
proper tire inflation so when we're
looking at properly inflated we're going
to have maximum amount of contact
under inflated only the edges are going
to be coming in contact and over
inflated you're just going to have that
middle crazy that little kind of like
that little bit of a balloon
effect so you want to refer the
vehicle's ornamental to owner's
manual to make sure that you have the
correct amount of tire inflation
that's located on the door frame this
can also be checked on a suspect's car
if you take the tire pressure and
compare it to the door frame you can
have an indication of whether it was
properly
overly or under inflated old amount of
cars prior to 2003 might be inside the
glove
box fuel filter flap trunk lid there's
different locations it could be
most are typically found on the door
jamb
area do not use the pressure indicated
or molded into the tire sidewall
this indicates the pressure needed to
meet the tire's fully rated load
capacity
not necessary specifically what was
matched for
the vehicle itself so under an
overinflated if you get this little
weird kind of
symbol that shows up on the dashboard
that's an indication of
typically low tire inflation and
underinflated tires
have a higher rolling resistance which
reduces fuel economy
and they wear more rapidly so that under
inflate is going to have this kind of
wear pattern here there's going to be a
lot more wear on the outside side walls
than in the center however if you over
inflate a tire the opposite occurs over
inflation would have more wear in the
middle because you kind of get that
little
balloon like effect there so this is why
it's important to have proper
inflation because you don't want to have
these uneven wear patterns however in a
crime scene they can help you identify
or match up a potential tire
to a suspect's vehicle this just again
shows some more comparisons
of all the different types of under and
inflation
methods and over-inflation methods and
different patchwares and cup wears
just to give you some kind of model
examples in comparisons because
initially they may look very similar
if you look at them closely you'll be
able to determine the differences
and hopefully identify these individual
and unique wear patterns