here we're on touch on the types of
proteins as a general quick short
summary there are many different types
of proteins keep in mind that the types
of proteins can be defined by their
shape because that will help determine
potentially their function so just
general types of proteins well they all
have different functions but share the
same building blocks and those building
blocks are amino acids some examples or
classifications of proteins we used as
an enzymes degrees for transport some
proteins are structural such as collagen
or keratin somebody's for defense
some are contractile so looking again at
our specific types of proteins well the
ribosomes are important for protein
assembly and it can be they can be
free-floating in the cytosol and also be
attached to the endoplasmic reticulum
for bisko's a type of protein that's
involved in the photosynthetic process
pepsin is an enzyme found in your
stomach to help break down food actin
filaments are structural components of
your hair giving it its strength despite
its very small diameter and insulin is
important for regulation of your blood
glucose levels all specific types and
related to proteins so there's two main
classifications we're looking at protein
structure
there's the structural ones which are
long tables that provide shape and
strength so for example they just gave
your hair as these long kind of cable
like structures and then there's your
globular here these are grooves and
depressions either kind of foam this
more three-dimensional globe like shape
and these are typically enzymes and also
human globin has this type of
classification protein functions there's
three examples of protein functions here
we have transport so some proteins
transport various substances such as
oxygen ions and so on this example
provided here's hemoglobin so human limb
is a very specific shape that it takes
on these are the heme units the iron
units and this is important in your red
blood cells for carrying oxygen now I
said structure bleeds to function so
shape has a direct impact on function
normal red blood cells this nice
cross section we call this biconcave
disk they look like this and then we
have this abnormal condition called
sickle cell they have this weird sickle
kinda Halfmoon shape to them and it
greatly impacts the function of red
blood cells so here we have a normal red
blood cell and then here we have the
sickle shaped the normal red blood cells
are smooth they're round and they're
called
I time cave discs they move very easily
through our capillaries and through our
vessels arteries and veins in our
circulatory system they transport oxygen
very efficiently sickle cell shaped is
you have sickle cell anemia don't move
easily through the blood they're stiff
and sticky they tend to form these
clumps and get stuck in blood vessels
there's not a good thing this can block
blood flow blood blood vessels to limbs
to organs and it's good cause serious
infection or organ damage this is not a
good condition to have also they could
just look at the shape not as efficient
at carrying oxygen another function of
proteins can be information transfer
look at the example here of certain
protein hormones or peptide hormones I
insulin is an example because it helps
control the amount of sugar in the blood
your body needs to maintain homeostasis
it needs to maintain a very controlled
amount of blood glucose levels insulin
will help keep that in check also
important for defense in the form of
antibodies
it marks foreign bodies for illumination
here we have our antigens are antibodies
these are very important shape you could
see here is all distinctive shape this
again relates to proteins here lastly
our protein functions they can form a
catalyst so almost all the chemical
reactions that are in a living cell are
catalyzed by enzymes in general when
enzyme does is it reduces the amount of
energy needed to reach an end product so
here to combine a with B without the
enzyme would take this much energy
before produced the complex a B
with enzymes here taking a lot less
energy to produce the same end result in
this example we'll notice that the time
it takes to produce with or without the
enzyme is the same however what is
reduced is the amount of energy without
enzymes we would not be able to survive