so this video lecture is going to go
over some basic classifications or types
of tires
there's a lot of information contained
on all of the slides so be sure to pause
if you want to learn more specifically
about each tire
i'm going to just going to give you a
brief overview here in the video lecture
for the different types of tires so
first off the kind of
probably the most obvious we have your
passenger or all season
tires these have those longer tread wear
good ride reasonable traction
kind of your kind of common one that
you're most likely to see because they
can be used
year-round or all season
moving on from a passenger all season
tire we can have winter tires
particularly in areas that tend to get a
lot of snow
or winter weather this is designed for
maximum traction and snow kind of slushy
ice you can see the different tread
pattern
over here located here on what's defined
as a winter tire
now they're typically not used all
season because they tend to be a little
bit more aggressive
and better able to handle the winter
type weather
but maybe not necessarily as good in
other kind of conditions
found during the summer and spring and
fall months
they have all-terrain or mud tires now
what you're noticing
here is they're really focused on kind
of off-road traction
and they have really large kind of deep
treads
large knobs on the tires so they're
great for being off-road in mud where
you need a lot of that kind of grip
and traction but they really don't
perform great
on road and their wear life on asphalt
is probably not the greatest
either so again these are a little bit
more specialized
for being off-road in this example here
and they're also typically oversized as
well then we have
drag racing uh radial tires or dot
legal tires these are tires that their
goal is to maximize acceleration
and to be able to allow a lot of contact
with the road
surface they've designed kind of for
drag racing a lot of traction you'll
notice the tread compared to our mud
tires
much reduced a lot more surface contact
on the road
now again these probably would not be
the best to be using in any sort of
wet or kind of wintry conditions but
they are considered d.o.t
legal meaning they do have the depth
required to technically be used on
dot roads now in comparison to those
we have racing slicks which their goal
is really to maximize
the surface contact that they have with
the
road surface however racing slicks or
true racing slicks are
never intended to be driven on the
street or exposed in near freezing
temperatures they have very minimal
area here where any water could be
sheeted off they have absolutely maximum
amount of contact
therefore used in a lot of racetracks
and autocross only special use
tires they have something called trailer
tires which on a quick look may look
very similar to an all-terrain tire
but they're specifically built for
stability durability and payloads are
not for
powered vehicles they're simply for it
to be put towed behind on a trailer
um so if you're looking at investing in
crime scene that has you know multiple
tire tracks and there was potentially a
trailer involved in some way
towing something these are going to have
a slightly different tread pattern so
they're going to be something to
investigate
and to be able to section out from the
towing vehicle
they have a temporary spare tires so
this is one that's
there can be full-size spares there can
be half spares or part spares
again differs by manufacturer but these
are simply light duty
special purpose temporary use tires so
not something you're typically going to
see
unless a vehicle involved in the crime
scene did have a flat and you'd have to
change it
and did have to put on a spare tire so
again just another
different way or different tread pattern
different tread tire type
to consider