many growers when they're looking at
determining the peak harvest of their
cannabis plants
we'll look at the trichomes a lot of
growers when they're looking at the
trichomes notice there's more than just
one type of trichome
well this video here will explain the
different types of trichomes that you
might be
visually seeing
[Music]
all right let's get into types of
trichomes explained here we can see them
visually represented
we're going to go into them in a little
bit more detail
so first off what is a trichome well
trichomes are small
hair or other outgrowth of the epidermis
of the plant typically unicellular
and can be glandular these structures
are the site of cannabinoid terpene and
flavinoid production
and this is why growers look at them and
think that they're so important because
really
that's where all of the chemicals that
they're looking for are being produced
these are found in more than just
cannabis plants so keep that in mind as
terpenes function as a natural plant
defense
mechanism in other plants as well here
we're seeing some of the kind of
visual representation of them some you
might be more familiar with
some maybe just think these little
background structures but they're all
kind of a protrusion
of that epidermis now we have the
glandular
trichomes here and there's again there's
going to be a whole bunch of different
types i'm going to try to present some
good
visual images as well as some
descriptions here
so glandular trichomes are going to be
kind of in this category and they
produce and store
large amounts of cannabis resin which
are found in high quantities
in female flowers but are also found in
leaves and also on the stems
of particularly younger plants so that
is only found there
they can be found in other portions of
the plant as well glandular trichomes
can occur
as small bulbous trichomes with one cell
cell stocks
cecil glands which are attached directly
at the base
without a stock or multi-cellular
stocked granular trichomes with
long multicellular stalks into the
brachials surrounding the pistol flowers
what does that mean if you look with a
strong magnifying loop
kind of towards the area of the flower
or in fluorescence that's unfertilized
you might be finding these different
structures here there are three common
glandular trichomes here as we can see
listed and we'll go through each of
those and show you kind of a good
picture
of each so you can identify those
different glandular trichomes are all in
that same
category so starting with the first one
the bulbous
trichomes here and these bubbles
trichomes are found throughout the plant
but do not produce or contain
cannabinoid or terpenes
they're very small 15 and 30 microns in
size
so they are that kind of that little bit
of that kind of like bulb
like look to them and found throughout
the plants not just in one
area but do not really contain any
cannabinoids or
terpenes so not really a main focus to
determining
the peak of harvest or how well your
harvest may go
then we have the capitae sizzle
trichomes
so in this example here these have
globular shaped head here and are the
most common as are found on the stems
leaves and also the bracts so they're
found in multiple locations in the plant
while these trichomes do produce
cannabinoids the levels produce are much
lower than the capitis stocked trichomes
which are discussed
on the next slide these are mid-sized
measuring from 15 to 100 microns across
so they're a little bit bigger than the
first ones
but really produce cannabinoids but not
really to any great degree
so these are the kind of the highlight
ones i think the ones that most growers
are kind of seeking out and looking for
these are the capitated stocked
trichomes and they are the primary
source
of the cannabinoids terpenes other plant
oils
found in cannabis plants that develop
only after flower formation
so these are the kind of the key ones
that we're looking for humans that we're
going to be looking at as far as
determining peak harvest
going from that clear to that cloudy to
go a little bit beyond maybe the amber
state
if you look at the bracks of the flower
there are small
tiny mushrooms that measure about 150 to
500 microns tall
so in relative comparison much taller
than the other ones
so it makes it great for kind of that
visualness to kind of like zooming in on
now we also have some non-glandular
trichomes which are the ones that be
located
uh here as far as structures go there
are hair-like extensions resembling leaf
hairs
with slender kind of pointed apex they
protect the plant from its environment
mainly through physical means
restricting access to animals and
insects preventing water loss or
light degradation and fungal infection
so they do have
important plant functions it's
characteristic on cannabis to find
non-glandular trichomes on both the top
and also the bottom of the leaves and
there's two main
non-glandular trichomes found on
cannabis plants
so first off here so here we have the
systolith trichomes that have
characterized bear claw shape
and have calcium systolic resembling
knobs
visual at their base kind of see them
located right
here they're looking really in detail
they're found on the upper surface of
the leaves and range from 150 to 220
microns in height frequently these
trichomes are broken at the
knob feet so they can be broken right
right there at that kind of
area we see three represented or
highlighted
in this labeled diagram right here
and we have the non the systolic
trichomes as well
and these are found most often on the
lower side
of the leaves bracks and brachials and
tend to be fine
and slender shaped there so here's
basically there's no like bulb at the
bottom
they're just kind of that looks like a
little clear hair protrusion
from the leaf surface there remember
these are all epidermal kind of
protrusions there that are occurring
so hopefully this was a nice kind of
breakdown of looking at the different
trichomes
so if you're looking at the leaf surface
looking at the flowers you can have a
better understanding for the diversity
of trichomes
that are present on a cannabis plant