so while we all may think chromatography
is all the same there's actually
different types of chromatography
describe some of those key ones here
what we see here in the image is
probably what we're most familiar with
it's a form of paper chromatography and
it's separating out plant
pigments so as i mentioned those
different types well what are they
chromatic in general can be classified
based on the type of mobile phase
stationary phase and supporting
material it could be liquid
chromatography gas chromatography or
supercritical chromatography
if you're using a supercritical fluid as
an example
so that liquid chromatography is an
analytical
chromatography technique used for
separating ions or molecules that are
dissolved in a solvent
it's commonly used for liquid solvents
such as a mobile phase and a column
composed of solid
beads which would be the stationary
phase and there's some
varying types with even within liquid or
lc chromatography you can see just one
example
here we have something called gas
chromatography and this is our gc
chromatography this is a technique
used to analyze the quantification of
volatile compounds this separates
volatilized samples
with a carrier a gas system mobile phase
and a column composed of a liquid or
solid beads
as the stationary phase so we're looking
at identifying certain volatile
compounds
paints uh gasoline for example gas
chromatography is something that can be
used for that in forensic science
paper chromatography is something you
might be familiar with something we may
have even done
this is an analytical method that's used
to separate out colored
chemicals and substances separates out
the dried liquid samples with a liquid
solvent the mobile phase
and paper strip is the stationary phase
you can see an example of that here
the beakers and then some even just
regular markers
and water for example thin layer
chromatography we're getting a little
bit more specific here
this is often called tlc chromatography
and this
is a technique to separate non-volatile
mixtures it can separate dried liquid
samples within a liquid solvent or
mobile phase
and a glass plate is covered with a thin
layer of silicone gel
as the stationary phase so getting a
little bit more specific
than our paper chromatography but again
still looking at
non-volatile mixtures those
classifications are based on the mobile
phase used we have the gas
chromatography we have the liquid
chromatography you can automate some of
these
or the type of mobile phase whether it's
a gas or liquid we have machines also
that can
allow for a very high degree of
precision and repeatability
classification based on that stationary
phase used well
name of the gc the gastroenterology
methods could be gas solid
chromatography gas liquid chromatography
bond phase
types of stationary phase that could be
used solid
liquid coated there's different types
that can be used and they'll be specific
for the materials you're trying to study