okay so here might investigate three
major types of growing media as often I
get asked well you know which one's the
best and there's no direct answer to
which one's the best but so a lot of
people that use kind of three main types
or you may have your own but it's kind
of the three main staples that I see
very commonly I used our one is Pro mix
this could be considered a standard mix
for many growers and certain grow shops
they'll have bales of this all stacked
on one another it's a versatile mix that
serves not only as a good standalone
product but it can provide a quality
base to tweak for individual needs it
does contain it does have peat moss as
its higher percentage which is typically
65 to 75 percent of the total product
here you can see here this is pro mix BX
with mycorrhizae and general purpose
they make a lot of different sub recipes
there this is kind of one of the
standards just to consider is it even
the base material it's also metro mix or
Sun grow there's many different blends
for this some consider it to be
confusing because of all the options so
it's important if you do find once you
like to get the tag and to know exactly
what you get so that you're able to go
through and repeat that send girl
horticultural Kevin now owns many other
brands so this is something else that's
happening in the marketplace where one
brand is going through and buying up
other names that you might be familiar
with so so for example if I've heard
sunshine advanced black gold and Metro
mix are now all owned under Sun Grill
horticulture of Canada the last one here
is happy frog growers like this company
for not only the current media substrate
but also the nutrient charge' is
typically added I can also be
pre-inoculated with beneficial soil
microbes as we see listed here in proper
gills program for the mycorrhizae and
the fungus and then for bacteria b c and
c fu colony forming units per gram
listed here this can make a ready to use
product directly out of the bag and this
is why some growers prefer this to use
as part of their graph so those are just
three examples there experiment find
something you like and work with it is
there a perfect growing mix no find ones
you can work with and one that you can
modify
and maybe use a base material and they
all have their own little quirks and
keep in mind watch the labels to make
sure that the manufacturer doesn't
change what's inside the bag even if
they call by the same name