now you may not realize it but there's
actually different types of lab water so
we might just think water is all the
same h2o well that's not necessarily the
case just like some people aren't
familiar there's different types or
grades of maple syrup so when would we
use these different types of lab or what
are they I'm going to try to explain
here so these different types of lab
water are referring to different levels
of purity higher levels of purity are
needed for very sensitive techniques
where containments could negatively
impact the results so these higher
levels of purity we want to be using on
experiments and protocols will call for
these when you're using equipment that
has high degree of sensitivity why not
just use the highest purity all the time
well simply put it's because of cost
this cost a lot more also it's not
needed in the majority of cases would be
a waste so you want to be sure that
you're using the purity for the
sensitivity of the equipment that you
have go to the high sensitive equipment
you can use a lower grade it's a lot
less expensive you're going to get the
same end result so type 1 is ultra pure
water this is the purest grade of lab
water there is use for highly critical
applications mass spec is one that
really requires this ultra pure water if
you're doing trace element analysis that
can be another one because if there's
trace elements in that water those are
going to negatively influence the
results there's biotechnology we're
using RNAs aren't and DNA's free water
we're looking at is pure water it
doesn't have any way that comes going to
break down or mess with DNA studies that
you may be doing won't break down any of
those so again these are ultra pure
water type one the highest grade of
water very expensive as well pure water
tech to recommended source for ultra
pure systems to please from buffers
marker biology media prep it's very
clean water it's not quite type one used
in areas where microbiology we don't
want to grow other microbiology
organisms or looking at using something
that is a source of water and it's less
expensive in the tank one and often used
in these particular cases
type 3 is instrument fed fued water
should say
we're looking at its produced using RL
water reverse osmosis or the the
distillation process most commonly used
water grades it type threes the most
common are most cases is typically fine
glassware washers can use this humidity
chambers autoclaves all these can
typically require distilled water or
reverse osmosis water sills can use that
such a high degree that in some labs
will be distilled water on tap sort of
speak it would be a large tank or a kind
of a plumbing system that allows a
separate faucet to be used to get that
water so because this is a clean water
source and used in many experiments
lastly tap water as its name implies it
comes directly from the faucet tap often
contains minerals easiest to get and
least expensive if the procedure only
states water this is the type that's
assumed simply because the small amounts
of kind of other minerals or particulate
that might be in there aren't considered
to be levels that will impact the
results of the study and if it says add
water you can probably get away with
just tap water otherwise it will specify
the type of water that's required
hopefully it didn't complicate things
too much and developed a better
understanding of the fact that there are
different grades of lab water and where
they need to use