okay here I'm gonna go over different
types of cannabis cannabis indica sativa
root Alice and also hemp cannabis now
while these different types are kind of
ingrained in the industry we don't learn
here that the differences may not be as
great as you may initially think so
indicas sativa is rude Alice and hemp
cannabis may have different looks or
different morphologies but the actual
difference between these plants may not
be as great as you may think so but this
disclaimer here because there's
different morphologies that allow us to
classify this canvas and that's
typically what's used to denote them in
two different categories
however the phenotype does not always
match the genotype some backgrounds with
plants are also not well known due to
the blending of genetics while general
characteristics are presented please
realize that plant behavior may not
match the cannabinoids it can produce so
this naming inconsistency there's a
disconnect between research in the
general public
much of this traces back to the
underground market now hitting legal
challenges that have opened up the
market for more varieties to plants by
the same name may not be the same
genetic so we're getting into something
that may look initially the same but we
kind of go into the microscope and look
at the scientific end of it we're seeing
some great differences that do occur
so why contains be unpredictable
well breeders have been making crosses
and documenting so we would think they'd
be the accurate but without genetic
markers there's being a being trapped
there is a high odds of mix-ups
occurring just from grower error also
the possibility of misinformation being
spread for the purpose to protect
breeders varieties cannot be ruled out
so there are two kind of factors at play
that probably contribute the fact that
these names aren't necessarily directly
matching it up so how our name is
defined will often the structure of
morphology the plant defines the variety
this is not taken to consideration the
chemical profile of the plant it creates
an inaccurate correlation so we're kind
of basing a morphology and as you see
here with the plug if you know if it
fits it's got to be this variety if it
looks like this it's got to be this and
that's sadly not the case here so
genotype versus name it's possible for
the same variety from two different
suppliers to have vastly different
chemical profile
suppliers will often say if you find a
good strained stick with that supplier
but this is not a good long-term
solution this variability prevents
presents a huge challenge especially for
the medical market and as a result many
have chosen to go with extractions
rather than actual plant material so
that they can know exactly what they're
getting each and every time so what does
this mean it means you're not trust the
name matches a clearly defined set of
effects see here with the mouse and the
cat now should not always be trusting
the cat here peer extractions will
ensure consistent chemical profile
regardless of the starting material the
extractions can be found in purified
products which reduces very variability
compared to use of the flower genetics
versus observations there are databases
being constructed so future
understanding of cannabis genetics we
can clear however general
characteristics of the three main types
of camps will be presented here along
with some concerns of those
classifications but we are certain to
pool a greater dataset saying what we
see and also genetic markers for the
cannabis plant so canvas indica well the
origin has come the countries Pakistan
and Afghanistan we're colder climates
with shorter seasons that's kind of
where the indica can be traced back to
the morphology I called the George
Costanza of plants it's short and stocky
these leaves kind of had this morphology
as we see here sure in Saki leaves the
general behavior is conducive to indoor
growing where space is often limited due
to its morphology these dense plants
with broad leaves lead to heavy
production with the possibility of four
to six crops per calendar year it's
often marketed as offering relaxation
decreased nausea and pain and good for
nighttime use
sativa its origin is found more towards
the equator or the climate tends to be
warmer and longer also the average day
length is stable over the course of the
year so sativas thought to originate
near the at the equator okay and here
looking at the sativas morphology these
are considered to be like the giraffe of
cannabis plants they're tall and their
thin leaves are long and thin which is
kind of the opposite of indicas they're
physically the biggest of the three
varieties they tend to have more
continuous growth have it leaned a more
Ariat appearance then grow up
fifteen feet tall to produce higher
yields but sometimes it takes a little
bit longer for them to get to this stage
so it comes at the cost of sometimes
longer at flowering times in market is
as increased creativity for people
looking to get things done in daytime
use and this is what they're marketed as
but this doesn't necessarily mean all
sativas will have this so the indica or
sativa abate despite clear distinction
there is widely presented in the
marketplace actually there's very
limited scientific evidence to support
the separation between the indicas and
the sativas are there morphological
differences well yes
however the strain classification does
not match the chemical profile
sativas and indicas can have similar
chemical profiles despite very different
morphologies so indica or sativa the
specific classification does not
correlate with the particular affect or
compounds produced and this is a big
point to kind of remember here while
plants look differently different this
is the only distinction between the tail
so the chemical profiles can videos can
be the same even though they may look
very different and this is despite what
typically is marketed as one producing
one effects in another they can actually
produce very similar effects would alice
is an auto flowering cultivar of
cannabis its origin is kind of in cold
regions of countries like Russia and
China and this could be a distant
relative sativa potentially because it's
autoflowering its heavens own
classification it's a new kid on the
block the morphology is I call it the
hummingbird of plants it's small and
fast it's recognizable by its small
leaves and minimal side branches as this
kind of refresh on your plant structure
with thicker stems now it's an auto
climb strain which eliminates the need
to be precise with photo period as it
will flower after three to four weeks of
growth no matter the time of year three
harvests seventy two hundred and ten
days recedes this is an advantage of
having this auto flowering kind of comes
a robot kind of becomes like automated
as often uses crosses with other strains
to increase yield and have the auto
flowering characteristic carry over so
that growers don't have to worry about
the photo period adjustments naturally
low and T&amp;T is how it h sees how its
marketed short lifecycle annotation
being incorporated into other hybrids
to give the best of both worlds kind of
is that quick cheetah like turnaround
time can can kind of create this mixture
of two different varieties with good
potency and auto flowering plant which
is what growers typically find
advantageous the general morphological
summary here indica sativa ruderalis you
can kind of see now the comparison
between the three and how they look very
differently but again keep in mind the
chemical profiles that they produce
could be very similar