so here on this tobacco university video
we're going to be investigating
different types of evidence
and how we may go about classifying them
so when we're looking at two main
categories for
evidence it's important to know what
category the evidence you're collecting
falls into
for example whether it's a direct or
testimonial with circumstantial such as
a physical piece of evidence
this main broad classification of
evidence that may be collected now
direct or testimonial evidence includes
first-hand observations
such as testimonies from eyewitness
accounts written statements confessions
or
video cameras testimonies may sound
convincing but need to be cross-examined
so even if we get those shortly after
a crime has been committed keep in mind
because it is classified as this direct
evidence or testimonial evidence
we need to back that up with other
supporting data
now circumstantial or physical evidence
this is indirect evidence that can be
used to imply
a fact but does not directly prove it it
refers to any evidence that would be
present at the crime scene but also
includes items found in the suspect's
possession
so just because it wasn't found directly
at the crime scene
it may be necessary to investigate and
use that because it may show or tie a
better story
to be able to determine the full
idea of what had happened at the crime
scene
we also have different types of evidence
so with these different types we're
looking at what are some examples of
circumstantial or physical evidence
that could be collected at a crime scene
so be thinking about these different
types of physical evidence
again something as simple as a trash can
here all sorts of dna fingerprints hair
all sorts of things can be collected
here's some evidence examples so here we
have blood here fiber soil glass tire
marks paint chips explosive tool marks
firearms ballistics
shell casings pollen dna these are just
some evidence
examples that can all be very important
to a crime scene
now if we look here how could you how
could these types of evidence be
classified
further so if we have all these
different types these fingerprints tool
marks blood
uh soil class tire marks how could we go
about classifying these
so again be thinking about these are
things that could be collected at a
crime scene how do we potentially
classify them
well looking at here's just some
examples of some broad
forms of classification we get that
circumstantial physical evidence and
detailed classifications while we have
biological evidence
that include body fluids hair natural
fibers plant parts and dna
there were some physical components that
could be like bullets or
casings or artificial fibers or tool
marks and then we get into trace
evidence
this refers to physical evidence that's
found in small
but measurable quantities it helps the
investigator to not only
identify what to look for but to also
find them and collect them in a way
that preserves them so they can be used
and entered as evidence for a crime
scene