okay here we're gonna be looking at
types of population pyramids this kind
of gives you a just a general overview
here rapidly expanding population
pyramid in expanding stationary in a
contracting one this is also how they
look here a little bit more detail in
this is the general shape and this is
how they look when we break them out per
age group here we look at some of these
examples but this is a good kind of
reference slide to be to understand the
different types of population pyramids
that to exist so starting with the
basics well population pyramid is the
total population divided into about five
year age groups the percentage of people
in each of those age groups is presented
and the percentage of males and females
in each age group is shown in a very
clean and distinctive manner the shape
of the pyramids is controlled by the
rate of first rate of deaths or
migration again this kind of shows just
those examples again of expanding
stationary and contracting populations
evidence of expanding or high birth rate
rapid fall in each upward age group due
to high death rates here with a very
short life expectancy we're look at some
of these in more detail with some
countries as specific examples so first
off let's look at the general shapes
that we're going to deal with well in
expanding shape is going to have this
kind of triangular appearance here
stationary is going to be kind of block
shape and negative contraction is going
to be a triangle with a point in the
downward direction I'll be contracting
this would be expanding in contrast to
that so what is this population pyramid
what this kind of look like well let's
take a look at this one here so just a
mock example we see the male's here on
the Left females here on the right we
see the age groups here down the middle
then we have our populations broken out
in the millions just be 13 million 26 39
52 and 65 million and that be for males
and females there are three little
subsets here this age group of 60 and
older is considered elderly dependents
then we have our working population
which is about age 15 to 8 59
and then we have our young dependents
here so these are the young ones that
are too young to start working the main
core working population in the elds
elderly dependents that are depending on
that working cat population there for
the most part now populations age
structure and sex ratio can be used to
assess its demographic trends as we see
here was Christmas Island and over here
we see a large portion of males compared
to females in particular a very large
population in the male's of the age 25
to 29 so this gives us an idea of the
demographics of this particular island
we see that very evident here of this
with this population pyramid now
triangle shaped pyramid the expanding
pyramid is Kenya here expand it's a very
large base and we see a very small kind
of up towards the top here growth fates
are slow life and with a very short life
expectancy sadly in this country this
expanding pyramid shape is broad-based
with high birth rates narrow tops there
is a small elderly population which
means there's a high death rate sadly a
portion there's a large portion of you
young people and it's a high young
dependency or ratio the sex ratio this
bounce pyramid there's a balanced sex
ratio from males to females it's not
favoring any one particular gender then
expanding pyramid in contrast to that
see expanding pyramid is expansive this
population pyramids have the classic
triangular shape looks and how this
one's a little bit different than the
previous one that we saw it has a wide
base like we saw it the other one which
indicates a high birthrate and a narrow
topic negates a high death rate but we
see there's deeper into the population
here with a greater population generally
speaking an expanding population is
characteristics of low standards of
living high birthrate do the poor access
to birth control lack of education and
so on
in a high death rate due to poor medical
care or potentially nutrition see that
here was Syria and Haiti so we see a
large populations kind of that 29 and
under but then it decreases rapidly as
that population of individuals within
that population age a negative growth
pyramid well this is a shrinking
population there's a long life
expectancy for Italy here we see this
negative growth meaning there's not as
many young people as they are that
working-class as ever best older so
Greece we see that same negative growth
pyramid and that's evident by the narrow
base that occurs which shows a low birth
rate which is a decrease in population
of a portion a large portion of the
working population at 15 to 59 year old
see that's the majority of that
population there and the sex ratio again
is a balanced pyramid so there's an
equal balance between females and males
in this case between a negative growth
pyramid will be evident of Italy or in
this case Greece this negative growth
population is a population period have
narrower base than the reproductive age
population this indicates a decreasing
population trend and the low birthrate
is indicative of a well developed
country so just we saw with Italy in
Greece we see the same thing going on
here with Germany now male to female
ratio is also pretty equal but this is a
negative growth population pyramid now
is stable pyramid has low infant
mortality is low population growth and a
long life expectancy we say it's stable
it's pretty much consistent throughout
as I have been consistent the whole way
we have to keep in mind is just based on
you know normal human activity people
are not going to live to be 100 plus the
same portion of population and it's
going to be the age 50 to 54 so there's
gonna be a natural progression downward
we see pretty much from age 65 to 69
here all the way down at Basin being
born pretty stable
population overall and this is a
rectangular shape or zero population
growth it's a narrow base so there's low
birth rates the life expecting is high
in these stable populations this is
about 80 plus years is the expected life
expectancy low death rates and this is a
stable population bars of equal length
and there's a balanced proportion here
the sex ratio is also balanced now we
may see that in this case in Denmark age
30 the 34 is a little bit less but
overall we're kind of looking at general
trends here that is stable population
pyramids have a vase similar to the
width of the population of the
reproductive ages which indicates a
stable population generally speaking
these stable populations in this example
here Aruba are characteristics of a
high-standard living this high standard
of living is due to low birthrate
I do two good family planning that
access to birth control financial
planning and education overall the
country it's a low death rate due to
good medical care nutrition in education
they said before we can't have it a
complete box but life expectancy of
about 80 years old orient in this case
over seventy is just indicative of good
stable population again we see the
bounce or sex ratio between males and
females very equal and Aruba here 2015
is showing a prime example of a stable
population pyramid