on this tobacco university video i'm
going to go over understanding watts
volts and amps for cannabis production
in relation to utilizing grow lights
so you think it's as easy as plugging
the light in let's go over and
understanding
some of the watts volts and amps you
might have in your grow lights
so you can be efficient with your
production so first off
amps looking at the generalness here of
the amps refers to the flow
of the current think of it as the flow
of water in a pipe the flow rate of amps
will determine the available amount of
electricity to the electrical system
the number of available amps determines
the amount of lights that can be
operated at one time
very important if you're in a larger
grow area to know how many amps can you
supply how many grow lights can you
support
for your area growers need to know what
amp service they have available and also
what electrical appliances
they have in addition to the grow room
lights to know how many lights can be
safely supported if or if a
system upgrade is needed so while we
think about our lights and that is an
important consideration
do we have any water pumps also to
consider do we have any
other things that are consuming
electricity that we need to be aware
of to don't just think about the lights
we have humidifier dehumidifier
you know water pumps all sorts of other
things that may require
electricity we also have extra amps are
a good thing
so keep in mind that if whatever your
system is you don't want to push your
electrical
system to the max for example while 1000
watt
light operating at 120 volts requires
8.3
amps growers should allow and calculate
as if it was consuming
10 amps as this will reduce the chance
of system overload
and increase the reliability of the
electrical system so you might be
familiar with your panels here
knowing how many amps knowing where the
circuits are
what's kind of the rule of thumb when
you go through and calculating this well
the general
in general when calculating for a
thousand watt grow light 120 volt
circuit uses 10 amps 240 uses about 5
amps to be about
half the total of amps as the volts
there double
also operating any circuit at 80 percent
of capacity is a good idea
in the sense that it will reduce the
chance of burning anything out
it'll allow some wiggle room in case
there's increased amount of
energy consumption at initial startup so
again it's just
always good to play it on the safe side
don't push it to the absolute
theoretical max
so mention volts there let's talk about
them a little bit more volts does
relate to amps so the higher the voltage
the less amps that are needed to operate
the device but it does not mean they
will cost
less to operate common misconception
when the operating voltage is increased
the number of amps or the current will
also decrease
but the amount of power or watts what
required will remain
the same so again this is often kind of
this misnomer there
of should i go run on 140 volts or 200
240 volts run it in 240 i'm consuming
less amps as we can see
you know right right here if i'm running
120 volts 10 amps
240 only five but keep in mind the
wattage
still a thousand watt light in this
example would still be the same and
that's what you're charged with
so again running one versus another is
not going to reduce any sort of
cost when we're looking at energy
consumption
so mentioning those watts here watts
does refer to the power
needed or used most growers would
calculate their growing space and then
determine the number of watts
needed to sufficiently light that area
to provide
50 watts per square feet foot over a 10
by 10 area
the grower would need to supply about a
thousand watts of lighting
just to give you one little math kind of
quick comparison there
now we're comparing watts efficiency so
this is kind of where it comes into you
know a lot of the new lights a lot of
lights are stating
their efficiency which is a great thing
for growers to be able to compare
so watts can also be used to determine
the growth space overall efficiency as
many growers will talk in grams per watt
produced
to compare different lighting options
the lighting efficiency in terms of par
which is again
photosynthetically active radiation per
watt is often used since this
offers an effective way to compare the
efficiency of different lighting options
not only looking at the lighting but
looking at the bulbs used
looking at the type or style of lighting
looking at the reflector being used
what type of grow area do their walls
are their grow tent wells or mylar walls
or the lenses being used
and what the power supply is all these
can have an impact there on the total
watts use efficiency
now what's the both scenarios if grower
has a thousand watt grow light
in situation one grower has 120 volt
system
they will need 8.3 amps to support this
light
if the grower has a 240 volt system they
only need half of that or 4.16 amps to
support that light
so again it's important to keep that in
mind that the
volts can impact the amount of amps that
are needed but essentially in the end
you're looking at a very similar
watt consumption and that's usually what
you're charged with so that's not going
to reduce your overall cost
and make sure you buy the right you
purchase the right light
for your electrical service
now 120 or 240 volts this gets again a
lot of attention here of which one's
better which one should i
choose i don't know this one's reduces
my amps
so when operating grow room on 240 volts
you can operate twice as many lights on
the same
amperage than if you're operating on 120
volts so typically larger operations
will stick with the 240 volts
with either voltage the lighting system
will still require that 1000 watts or
power
so essentially both voltages will cost
the same to run
with the 240 usually allows growers to
run a few more lights there
now keep in mind you just can't buy one
and decide you're going to flip the
other
there are different outlets so the
manufacturers have come to a consensus
to make it
easier to prevent people from plugging
the wrong light into the wrong socket
you'll notice that there's different
shapes to the outlets to prevent you
from making that mistake
now watt hours so companies bills based
on the watts so
different voltages do not save money
directly so just keep that in mind that
just because you're using less amperage
does not mean it's going to cost you
less
to run so the appliance wattage versus
the operating time in hours versus the
watts used
so little calculations here that you can
apply to your own specific lights that
you might be using
so when comparing watts lights and volts
there are these mathematical equations
just provided you with a couple
kind of the triangle here is very common
this kind of provides you with the same
information here
watts divided by volts is amps watts
divided by amps is volts
watts equals volts times amps so again
just a little comparison there
if you wanted to go ahead and do some
independent calculations
for your own specific growing conditions
this is the information you would go to