okay here I'm gonna give you a brief
overview of understanding the disease
triangle how that we see indicated here
we have three different components
coming together to triangulate and form
the occurrence of disease now the host
or susceptible host is the plant in this
case and the pathogen is another word
for the disease the environment are the
conditions that's occurring so no
disease when there's no interception we
have the host in the proper environment
but there's no pathogen present at the
same time you don't get disease same
thing if you have the host and a
pathogen without favorable environmental
conditions
you still will not get a disease what
happens to when all three of these come
into intersection with one another when
all three of these are present at the
same time you get this scenario that
develops and this is where disease will
occur when all these intersect that's
are you getting a triangulation in that
disease that forms there needs to be all
three components interacting for the
occurrence of a disease if only one is
missing then the triangle will simply
fall apart so in order despite getting
disease cursing is very easy it's
actually a combination of factors that
are all coming together at the same time
for that disease to occur and what those
environmental conditions may be what
that pathogen is will be dependent on
the form or type of disease that's
present but still with the host the
environment in the pathogen all coming
together at the same time that's where
you get disease and upsetting this
triangle can be a great way to offer
control and not allow disease to occur
at a particular plant host here