so if you want to learn more about dry
flour cannabis
this tobacco university video is for you
[Music]
all right let's go over understanding
dry cannabis flowers
and first off i want to thank ct pharma
here
uh special thanks for making their
information analytical reports product
labels and information publicly
available online
the descriptions provided here will give
you some insight into dry flour cannabis
and also kind of what an analytical
report an example of one is
so you can be an informed consumer so
looking at just the general description
of dry flour products well dry flower
cannabis is looking at large clusters of
dense plant material
filled with numerous medical benefits
mainly green but dependent on the
cultivar can be filled with
color hues of purple and orange as well
so don't think that it always has to be
green there can be a lot of anthocyanins
will be associated with a purple
coloration that you may see
there's many different cultivars all
with individual names different
cannabinoid percentages
and unique terpene profiles so
just don't get locked in there's only
one particular image that you need to
find
to show good dry flour so what's a
description of
dry flour just in general is basically
the flowers harvested from the
best i put that in quotes part of the
plant and is
hand-picked based on quality this should
come with a certificate of analysis and
a label on the product
if it does not come with one you should
be sure to definitely request one and
you'll see an example of one in this
lecture series an example will be
provided here
later you can go through and research at
least this one was provided at the
current point in time
so keep in mind there is dry flower
variety there's hundreds of different
cultivars
all with different terpene profiles with
different effects main groups are your
sativas your indicas your hybrids but
there's also technically your auto
auto flowers or wood wireless prices can
range
so again don't get locked in any one
thing
there are a lot of options and that's a
good thing the canada concentrations
range from 10 percent up towards the 35
thc
thc and cbd mixes are also available
this just shows you down here some of
the morphology of the leaves of the
plants
so what's the uses for dry flour well
it's one of the most popular choices at
dispensaries
as it's easy to use can be smoked
vaporized for access to
medical effects very quickly and easily
effects could be felt within seconds to
minutes after consumption
and it also offers easy storage since it
can be kept
at room temperature and is a fairly
stable product
here's an example of a certificate of
analysis
so again this is just showing you uh
looking at the testing
so here looking at the certificate of
analysis we can see there's microbial
parameters testing
heavy metal testing mycotoxin testing
pesticide testing
and we can see a pass on all these it
also gives the results
uh recommended limits so this is all
good information
should be getting with any flower you're
looking at purchasing
in addition you're looking at terpenes
and cannabinoids
also expressed here but keep in mind
while most people will go to this
we also have to be mindful with that dry
flower
we need to be mindful of microbial
analysis heavy metals mycotoxins and
pesticides as well
as the terpenes and cannabinoids we
might be interested in what does the
label look like was just one example
here
again give you some of that summary
there of some of the components
keep in mind that they do give the
general quick summary of the past all
the micro toxins heavy metals micro
uh micro biological and chemical residue
testing there
but even beyond the label you have the
right as a consumer to go back and ask
for a certificate of analysis here to
confirm that
and make sure the lot numbers match up
so this provides you just a little bit
more information
about dry flour so you can be an
informed consumer