so on this debaco university video we're
going over a foundational lecture here
understanding par ppfd and pfd
to maximize cannabis yield and if you're
not familiar with these terms
this is a great lecture to pay attention
to
[Music]
all right let's go over some of these
foundational terms regarding lighting
so you can better understand them and
apply them to different situations
so first off light intensities
importance what's the importance of
light intensity
well the levels of light intensity can
have significant effects on post
synthetic rates which directly relate to
a plant's ability to grow
measuring the light intensity involves a
few different options
so it's important to know the background
of each we're going to cover some of the
key ones here in this video lecture
when measuring keep the distance between
the meter and the light source
consistent
because the light intensity is follows
the inverse
inversely proportional to the square of
the distance
this is the inverse square law so what's
important to utilize or to remember
is that as you move that meter away from
light sources
it tells the inverse square law meaning
the distance is going to have a major
impact on the intensity that you're
going to measure
so you want to make sure you're keeping
that consistent because even a small
distance is going to cause a massive
change potentially
in the actual intensity of light because
it's a squared
distance is squared in that equation the
light energy at twice the distance
away is spread over four times the area
and that's why it's so important
to keep that distance consistent meaning
when you double the distance of light
it will decrease by 25 so we want to be
very mindful
to keep things consistent particularly
for measuring light or looking at
developing any sort of
comparisons to keep that distance
consistent
now when we're measuring light a lot of
times you'll see manufacturers
mention lumens and lumen is a standard
derived unit for luminous flux which is
weighted according to the model of a
human's eye sensitivity to various
wavelengths
essentially contains wavelengths humans
can easily see
there's no connection to the
photosynthetic process of plants
unlike a par reading which i'll talk
about here so the term that gets tossed
around is
lumens are for humans because this
it takes into account that the lumen is
a measurement of what we can see well
but if we're looking at artificial
lighting we want to know what the plant
can utilize that refers to par
so lumen readings really are not worth
all that much
we're talking about that par that i had
mentioned what is parts
stands for this photosynthetically
active radiation
now par um light so that's the light
when we're talking now moving away from
lumens now we're looking at kind of this
idea of
the importance of plants so this power
wave light is the wavelength of light
within the visible range of 400
to 700 nanometers which drive a
photosynthesis with photosynthetic
process and we see that kind of listed
right or shown
visually right here here's the par
reading and this is kind of capturing or
measuring
those wavelengths that fall in that
range note that chlorophyll
absorption is higher in the blue and red
portions of the light spectrum
so two light sources can have the same
par output but depending on the
wavelengths produced
can have different plant performances so
we're just measuring and this kind of
bowl here shows kind of the photons that
are captured
it could have a lot of red and very
little blue or it could have a lot of
blue and very little red and you might
get the same
par reading so just keep that in mind
that power readings
are taking no greater emphasis on one
wavelength or another it's just the kind
of the collection
of all the photons present within that
light source that was shown here is also
it's not measured as below 400 and
above 700 when we're measuring in par
now ppf which is the photosynthetic
photon flux provides the number of
photons in the 400 to 700 nanometer
wavelength range again
that drive photosynthesis which are
emitted by a light source
this is the same range as par the unit
for ppf
is the micro moles per second and this
is the quantity of
light particles emitted per second
simply put the ppf exam
is amount per time so we're looking here
however ppf does not consider the
direction in which the light is emitted
which means it does not
indicate the light that actually reaches
the leaves as we see in the example here
we see our light source
we see all the light being given off by
that light source
well if the plant is down below that
light source these kind of
areas here where the light is being kind
of reflected in upward direction
it is being produced but not necessarily
captured by the plant
so this leads us to the ppfd which is
the photosynthetic photon flux
density this provides the number of
photons again and that's 400 to 700
nanometer wavelength range that drive
the photosynthetic process
which are emitted by a light source in
the same range as the previous two
talked about this unit again is micro
moles
per meter squared per second so
this unit tells you how many photons
which drive
synthesis impact the area per second
simply pfd is the amount
per area also per time so this is kind
of giving you the idea of now we have
this little collection vesicle at the
bottom here
how many are actually being accumulated
per that area
over a set number of interval of time
so now we're using a reflector we're
trying to eliminate the loss we're
trying to capture
as many of those light wavelengths as
possible one of those photons as
possible
of different wavelengths now when we
compare par
to ppf and ppfd par is the
is a generic term still used in common
speech referred to as the energy flux or
photon flux
typically it's a unit is watts per meter
squared ppf is used
for the amount per time usually micro
moles per second
and ppfd is used for the amount per area
per time
micro moles per second per meter square
times second
ppfd helps define the intensity of light
over a given area so again instead of
just measuring those photons
produced by the light well now we're
looking at how many we're collecting
ideally hitting
the leaf surface however there's
limitations to these
in the sense that all of these are bound
by that same 400 to 700 nanometer
wavelengths of light
however in particular with cannabis
research where uv
and far red wavelengths are of interest
these above terms do not take into
account these wavelengths since they are
outside of that 400 700 nanometer
range so to take into account the
greater wavelengths there's pfd that's
taking now going beyond that limitations
before
of just 400 to 700 nanometers so
pfd or photon flux density
is a measure of the number of photons in
the 300
to 800 nanometer wavelengths passing
through
particular area per second so now we've
expanded that range
from all the way down to 300 all the way
up to 800 nanometers
the unit is micro moles per meter
squared per second
it's the amount per area per time
measuring that 300 to 800 nanometers so
this is not
limited to the 400 to 700 talked about
previously
those photosynthetic wavelengths
they take into account far red and also
ultraviolet radiation so this can be
very important particularly
when we're talking about cannabis
production which is why this pfd
is considered kind of the unit to start
to take a look at
now as i mentioned units are important
so always check the units used
in any work you're reading micro moles
per meter
squared per second is key and what ppfd
is measured in and you see here
different units have different um
can we can have numbers associated with
that so i only weigh 58 well in what
units
standard chicken masses you know if
you're making up units or not following
certain units
it will allow you to do better
comparisons
or at least make a potential for
comparison if you keep track of the
units
that a particular manufacturer might be
posting or what a particular scientific
study might be showing
so when we're looking at how do we get
those numbers well light sensors are the
primary instrument
used to quantify the light intensities
of horticultural lighting systems
these sensors work by using an optical
filter to create a uniform
sensitivity to par light growers will
use this style
for a point in time measurement but some
options to connect these to data loggers
can allow for an accumulation of
readings
for different day-to-day comparisons
which can be quite useful
it's just an example here of one of the
meters you can kind of use them to get
an idea of the density of light
just as a point in time but also link it
here and get an overtime
so when we're measuring that ppfd now
apogee the mq620 extended range pfd
sensor
allows for uv and far red photons to be
measured
research has shown the value of adding
uv in far red in particular with canvas
production
while this meter now can start to
measure some of that range
the 1040 nanometer top cutoff also means
that the sensor will measure thermal
outputs of hps fixtures and other broad
spectrum lights
so the sensor is intended for use only
in led environments
what does that just generally mean well
when we get to these higher nanometer
kind of
wavelengths we could also be getting
into kind of the thermal output
of certain lighting which might cause
readings to be artificially high
which is why these are typically used
more in led environments where you're
not getting quite those high thermal
outputs
as you would with a hps or high pressure
sodium light
so how can this help to maximize
cannabis yield kind of putting this
together here well since canvas is a
high light
tolerant plant there are more potential
options when it comes to lighting
unlike a lettuce crop that needs lower
intensities canvas is a high
intense light plant with the
ever-changing artificial lighting market
understanding these terms can help
growers make informed decisions which is
kind of the whole point of this entire
channel
to allow you to get to gain some
information also with cannabis the
secondary compounds are also important
for branding plants with wavelengths
outside of the typical par
or ppfd spectrum may be advantageous
when it comes to maximizing yield
at least knowing what is being produced
within that wavelength range
might help make better informed
decisions when you're starting to make
adjustments
now with all of this research and all
this information a couple people here
uh to thank uh in the sense that
compiled some information some research
these are great people to kind of go
through and take a look at as far as
some other research that they may have
produced
i try to provide a little bit of a
summary here to get you to understand
these very important topics
and hopefully it was helpful and
hopefully you're able now to go through
and develop some more comparisons and
start asking
more educated questions