welcome to this debaco university video
here i'm going to go over understanding
plant hormones in a general sense
not getting into specifics but providing
with an idea of kind of the
commonalities amongst all the plant
[Music]
hormones
let's get into the understanding of
plant hormones here so first off in
general
plant hormones are regulators of almost
all aspects of plant development
and plant responses to their environment
they're active in very low
concentrations but have profound effects
on the plant
what that means basically is that it
doesn't take very much of any particular
home iron
to have a major impact on the plant that
we say
plant hormones are specifically
regulated and controlled which is very
important
simply because of the large impact they
have on the plant growth
and development this is for all stages
everything from germination
to pollination everything in between and
for all plants not necessarily just your
angiosperms
so hormones are important signal
molecule so just like in animals
same thing that hormones in plants are
also
very important and something not to be
kind of
understood well something not to be
taken for granted
plant hormones act as dedicated
signaling molecules plant hormones are
synthesized by the plant
and are transported some distances at
least one cell
diameter within the plant so this is
kind of that signaling molecule they
might be produced in one part of the
plant
but might have their effect in another
part these hormones have important and
very specific effects on the physiology
the growth and development
in vivo which is inside a living
organism of the plant
so it's because they're produced in one
area they're going to signal to other
portions of the plant
so this is very important for that those
cells to be able to signal
of to one another within the organism to
be able to get that
plant noticed effect now the plant
hormone cycle so these are just a couple
here
picked picked up kind of as a random
kind of graph here
again looking at specifics there's going
to be little differences that do occur
of course
but we're looking at basically the
hormone level and
basically four stages of the plant and
we could see that certain ones are very
active for the germination phase
and then the vegetative growth phase
they might be reduced and then they
might have peaks right before flowering
and then go down back down again for the
fruiting and ripening stages where
others might increase
so you can see that there's a lot of in
play a lot of flux
that occurs during the plant growth
cycle
on what hormones are active when and in
relation to what other hormones
ones might be active now the binding of
hormones so in a general sense
hormones act by binding to a specific
receptor remaining bound and not being
modified when acting
so we talked about earlier talked about
earlier that plate hormones
have a profound effect on the plants
however they're active in very small
amounts
how is it possible if something in small
amounts have a large effect
well what's happening is the hormone is
binding to a receptor
here's our plant here's our cell plant
cell because there's a cell wall here's
our receptor binding
and then there's a lot of relay
molecules a transduction pathway occurs
you can think of this as if we had a
pyramid of dominoes and we
knock one domino over we're having this
kind of transduction
pathway that is resulting in activation
potential of many different
pathways that's going to result in a
response an activation of cellular
responses both in this cell
as well as potentially neighboring cells
in that one hormone that one binding to
one receptor
can cause this amplified affected
response and this is why they can be
active
even though their concentrations might
be very very small
now when we're applying hormones to
plants this is something that's commonly
done for example over cloning adding
rooting hormone
spraying hormones in the plant can be
referred to as a dryness addition where
we're applying things to the outside of
the plant here we see a plant recently
potentially sprayed with water that is
being added extracellularly
the rates applied often do not match the
plant-produced levels as the goal is to
better understand plant response curves
at different levels
so just because the plant produces
hormones at a certain level or
concentration
growers may be applying them at
increased levels to help
increase the rate of that response which
may happen in some cases but remember we
over at certain hormones that can
actually have negative effects
studies can also investigate how the
same concentration of a hormone
may impact different species tissues and
development stages with the
intention of better understanding
hormone impacts the same hormone applied
at different stages of growth
could have potentially very different
effects as we saw with that graph
earlier
now there's some challenges with our
plant hormones
so most hormones can be synthesized and
degraded by many roots making them a
challenge to study it's not just
applying hormone x
and get response as you would
essentially with say a fertilizer
major problem when you apply them on the
extracellular basis uh in
androgenous levels with the levels
within the plant experiments are
difficult to establish
causative links between the hormone and
the response in
vivo and just as a reminder in vivo is
in the living organism
and in vitro is in glass so in vivo is
actually the organism
in vitro might be for example tissue
culture as we see here
just because we see it in tissue culture
doesn't necessarily mean that may
translate to kind of
out in a field application some studies
utilize inhibitors or mutants which are
called knockouts where they take that
gene and they knock it out
they prevent the plant from making it
and this aids in the study of certain
hormones impacts on plant development
what if the hormone was missing
how would that impact the plant so again
this is just kind of that general
overview of plant hormones you can see
why they're so hard to study
simply because of all the interactive
effects that might occur