many growers know to look at the
trichomes of their cannabis plant to
determine harvest
but many wonder what should they be
actually looking for
well in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over some great images
and give you that kind of step-by-step
guide on what to look for
in your trichomes to determine your peak
harvest
[Music]
all right let's get into understanding
visual cues of cannabis trichome
development to maximize harvest
so we want to monitor the color change
so by monitoring the change in color of
the gland heads
particularly the grower can evaluate the
ripeness of the flower pistol at plants
using a 30x loop or higher is advised
for some
other form of magnification of the
trichomes for close visual inspection
now it's important to say that we're
monitoring the color change so this does
not mean you just look at them once and
go from there
it's great if you look at them in the
early stages when hopefully they'll be a
clear coloration
we're going to see they're going to
progress to this cloudy coloration and
then
ultimately this amber coloration if they
go a little bit far
so we're going to see this kind of stage
in progression but that's the general
trend that those trichomes will be going
through
so first off those stages and this kind
of highlights it here as well
early to middle flowering resin heads
will be mostly clear
you can see this is a great example of a
mostly clear head right here
this would be another one as well during
the final phases of bloom cycle
the trichomes will transition from a
clear to kind of a cloudy milky white
color
and eventually turn to an amber color so
what's that cloudy milky white look like
we've got a couple here that are in
focus that are showing that kind of
cloudiness
here's kind of one as well and as you
can see there's
more but they're kind of out of focus in
the background most seasons growers say
the time to harvest is when the bulbus
heads which is the top portion here
are cloudy with a few amber ones here
and there about a seventy to thirty
percent mix
one of those amber ones look like where
they're kind of the most obvious
coloration change
uh and we can see this on this
particular image it's not like
everything changes
at once we see some that are clear some
that are also in the cloudy stage
some are also in the amber stage all in
the same structure here
this is why it's important to visually
check your plants to see those
transitions that are occurring and see
that change or that shift
in percentages so what do those kind of
clear trichomes kind of look like here
well in the early stage of development
the clear color can
indicate they're not full of
cannabinoids and terpenes you can think
of the clear
color meaning that they are quote empty
now it doesn't mean that they're
completely
empty when they're clear but just kind
of as a visual way to kind of correlate
and remember
clear you can think kind of empty
there's nothing in there so to speak
again not true from a bio uh botanical
standpoint but that kind of gives a
great visual clue of like oh it's clear
it's empty i can see right through it
not looking there's nothing there to see
uh bud should not be harvested at this
time because at this point they're
basically immature uh
before their kind of peak maturity and
they lack the desired compounds
now this doesn't mean you'll be
harvesting when there might be a couple
that are still clear
but if the vast majority are clear hold
off on the harvest process
now we get to those cloudy trichomes we
kind of see here different
degrees of cloudy when trichomes start
to go from a transparent to kind of
to a translucent transparency this is
the sign that harvest is getting closer
remember transplant is clearly is be
able to clearly see through
translucent we're getting that cloudy
milkiness and then opaque would almost
be that amber color where you're kind of
blocking light
this cloudy look uh growers can think of
the trichome becoming
full of cannabinoids again that's
botanically true
but here we can see that cloudy
appearance that what's giving it the
cloudiness
we can think of as being the
cannabinoids that are accumulating the
next step is that opaque kind of amber
color
and it's thought to give in some cases
give that energetic high
you know it may not be fully correlated
with the coloration
to the after effects so what does that
amber coloration kind of look like
well when we get to those amber um like
heads
we're progressing from that cloudiness
uh white collar of cry
of trichomes we'll change the yellow
brown amber color
waiting for some of the trichomes to go
to this coloration is a good sign that
harvest of the cannabinoids can be
maximized so it's okay if a few go to
this amber color let people think oh
it's too late
okay if a few go to that it's time to
get the vast majority in that milky
white coloration
however if nearly all the trichomes are
this color at harvest this may mean peak
harvest was kind of missed
leading to some degradation of the
internal components
uh sought to give a body high with some
people
but here we're seeing a couple amber and
that's perfectly fine it's a sign
probably getting right close to that
peak
harvest now that mixed trichomes as i
mentioned they all don't turn
necessarily in the same day at the same
flip of a switch
since all the trichomes will not change
from cloudy to amber at the same time
can be best to aim for a mixed
coloration to determine
your exact harvest time now the exact
percentage of cloudy and amber
may be impacted by variety state of
development and your kind of ability of
timing as well
so when we have that kind of mix here we
do see some that are kind of clear some
that are cloudy some that are amber
uh we want to kind of make a judgment
call as far as when
we're going to determine that peak
harvest it's usually when the trichomes
are a mix
of the colorations uh that i described
here
now kind of that general summary if you
want kind of kind of sectioned out this
picture here
i want that general summary of clear
cloudy or amber heads you can look at
that kind of general summary image here
as well as going back through some of
the other images on the slides
to help you determine when you're
looking at your cannabis plants the
exact
peak of harvest so you're maximizing
the cannabinoids and terpenes produced
without getting into any
loss due to over ripeness or degradation
there
hopefully this tobacco university video
was helpful in determining your peak
harvest
and maximizing your harvest as well