okay here we can see a plant that's been
uh potted or transplanted several times
we can see the original plug that it
started in then the larger container it
went to and its current container so all
of these stages help kind of maximize
the space that a grower can grow plants
in minimize the amount of lights and
help the efficiency value of the plant
but the upper of the growing operation
transplanting oftentimes plants will be
translated during the vegetative phase
to encourage top growth and also to
maximize a growing space the amount of
times that this is done is transplanting
action in what size containers that are
selected are mainly grower dependent
there's no set gallon amount or size
enough that you must go to overall of
course the trend is increasing but what
size use as maximum is slightly grower
dependent most using seven or ten gallon
pots for their larger size some as small
as five and some as large as 15 one of
the mindfully near transplanting also
want to harden off your transplants if
you are transplanting changing the
lighting at the same time be sure a lot
of time for the plants to transition to
reduce the chance of damaging those
plants want to be careful and mindful of
leaf burn because this can be a sign
that you're pushing that growth on that
kind of ragged edge they're really doing
severe damage to the plants while you're
trying to help them out with the
transplant phase this can be
accomplished by sometimes taking lights
and hang them further away to reduce the
intensity which is great for growers
because it can also increase the
lighting footprint during the vegetative
stage of growth