okay here we'll be looking at the upper
limbs of
the body and to provide you some
information and some comparisons between
those uh bones
in particular so first off those upper
limb region what do they consist of well
the
they consist of about 30 bones in three
regions your arm or
shoulder to elbow your forearm your ulna
and your radius and your wrist and your
hand
the upper limbs consist of the humerus
which is that upper arm portion here
radius and all on the forearm you have
eight bones inside your carpals
five bones and your metacarpals and
fourteen bones in your
phalanges you can kind of see them
listed here in this
image as well now we have the humerus
which is a bone of the upper arm i'm
talking right in this region
here it runs from the shoulder to the
elbow approximately it articulates with
the
scapula from the shoulder joint and
distally articulates with the radius and
ulna
at the at the elbow joint again see that
here
and it's highlighted in red in this
image
now looking specifically at the forearm
contains those two bones
looking over here the ulna and the
radius
so a lot of people confuse these two so
hopefully i'll be able to provide some
clarification
now the radius all the extend parallel
from the elbow where they articulate
with the humerus
uh and the wrist the humerus and the
wrist
the radius is larger than the ulna so
that's kind of like your big
taco message of the radius being larger
than the
oma not to try to put it here in bold
and small
and you can see them listed right here
and this might be a little hard to tell
but i think here you can kind of see
radius compared to
the ulna and atomically the radius is
located laterally to the ulna
placing it near the thumb you can see
that here so the radius if you're
looking at your hand
race would be located near your thumb
and the ulna would be
on the other side and atomically the
ulna is located immediately to the
radius placing it
near the little finger again so your
radius would be closer to your thumb
and your ulna would be located closer to
your pinky
finger so now looking at pronation and
supination
so pronation and the forearm is the
rotational movement where the hand
and upper arm are turned inwards so if
we're looking here this is where you can
because if you feel
if you hold your hand here you can feel
that a bone is moving
and that is basically the radius rolling
over the ulna
supination is the forearm occurring when
the forearm and palm are rotated
outwards
that's kind of exposing the palm when
both bones are essentially
parallel to one another it's considered
to be the standard position
so if you ever see an image of anyone
their palms are usually facing out
because that keeps the bones
parallel and that's considered the
standard position