okay here we're look at urine area
system organs the organs involved tied
in directly with the urinary system here
so starting with the basic organization
of the urinary system so we have our
kidneys it is an important component of
filtering the blood we also have the
urinary bladder this provides temporary
storage reservoir for the urine we also
have paired ureters here the reason why
they're paired because they're
transporting urine from the kidneys to
the bladder unless we have the urethra
which is transferring the urine from the
bladder and having it excrete or go
outside of the body in addition we also
have our kidneys which is an important
component of the urinary system because
it produces the urine it has awesome
main structures here called the renal
cortex the renal medulla the renal
pelvis and the nephrons I have a
separate video on the nephrons and those
are the actual functional units of the
kidney this is what they look like you
may have heard of kidney beans because
they have this kidney like shape to them
this that there's a lot of blood vessels
entering and capillaries going on that's
important because this is the main site
of filtration for the blood you also
have two kidneys even though you only
need one to survive so you often hear
people donating a kidney and are still
able to survive because your body has
kind of redundancies and backups
just giving you an indication of how
important the kidney actually is if two
of them case wants to fail your body
still wants to have another they can
survive them quit facts about the
kidneys they filter 200 liters of blood
daily allowing toxins metabolic wastes
and excessive ions to leave the body in
the urine through the ones or this site
of the actual filter that's taking
things out of the blood and inserting
them into the urine so they can be
excreted from the body approximately 1/4
or about 1000 to our Millers a systemic
cardiac output flows through the kidneys
each minute so it's a pretty intense
amount that's why we have so many
capillaries here is so many sites to
allow this exchange to occur all the
blood in your body is filtered about 60
times a day which means about two and a
half times every hour through your
kidneys that's why it's important for
your body to help
eliminate those toxins that are building
up and store them in the urine so they
can be excreted from the body the urine
itself the formation of that is it for
filtering actually the plasmas of the
blood so a plasma is the majority it's
fifty five percent this is again
occurring about sixty times a day so
it's actually being filtered the
filtrate contains all plasma components
except protein and loses water nutrients
and excessive ions to become urine
during contains metabolic wastes that
are unneeded substances now based on the
color of the yarn to determine the
degree of hydration or dehydration of an
individual if we're looking at more of
that darker yellow color be more
dehydrated looking at that lighter
yellow most clear color would be a
hydrated person call the years
determined mostly by the breakdown of
products their red blood cell
destruction the heme of hemoglobin is
converted by the liver into water Seibel
forms it may excreted into bile and
indirectly into the urine and the urine
the yellow pigment of urine is your uric
row their urine contains some ammonia
which is very toxic but as we learned in
another video that they're also body
converts it to urea a less toxic form in
the body would rather excrete the urine
in the form of the nitrogen from his
urea in the urine rather than ammonia if
you have high amounts of money it will
have a strong odor to it you can see
there's also other things phosphate
chlorides magnesium potassium and so on
so for ions as part of the earth however
the vast majority of urine is water
lastly the bladder it's the earning
bladder collects urine from both ureters
and from the kidneys the bladder is
largely
retroperitoneal which means even hold up
about 500 certain millions of urine and
this electric perineal a lot a bit of
change sizes so it can go larger as its
as more urine has been accumulated me at
the urge to pee and then go through
through the sphincter muscles in the
lease to hearing and excrete that from
the body
eliminating I'll also waste products
from the body this is in how your body
is able to filter the blood
concentrate toxins
them from the body to avoid an excessive
buildup which can threaten the life of
the individual