okay he wrote me going over a brief
overview of the urinary system and how
it plays an important role in our bodies
so the first off there's five main
functions of the urinary system first
one is to regulate blood volume and
blood pressure it does this by adjusting
the volume of water lost in urine and
also by releasing renin and every throw
PO and these are two ways that our body
can help regulate our volume of blood
but also our pressure this is kind of a
little bit of that kind of complex
system here with runnin here and
angiotensin and release of hormones that
can cause different changes in our body
now looking specifically at the runnin
and angiotensin system
renin is an enzyme that's released by
the kidneys so part of the urinary
system in response to a drop in blood
pressure which increases the
reabsorption of water so that's one way
want to be able to reabsorb water in our
nephrons Brennan also catalyzes a
production of angiotensin which is a
hormone that causes arterioles to
constrict raising blood pressure so
think about it this way this is our
normal blood vessel by constricting
through vasoconstriction closing that
down we're causing an increase in our
pressure this will also cause water
retention to occur so think about both
of these systems and how they work to
help the body maintain homeostasis of
blood pressure that gets too low what's
something that the body could do if it
gets too high it's something in contrast
to what we saw before with where we can
kind of reduce our blood pressure
because we want to maintain that
homeostasis looking at the conversion of
angiotensin one angiotensin 2 if you
have a complex process here I'm just
going to cover it in the very brief
sense we have enzyme our reaction the
liver releasing the angiotensin into the
blood kidneys also releasing the enzyme
renin into the blood this will cascade
into angiotensin 1 through enzymatic
reactions it's converted with the ACA
the indention converting enzyme in the
pulmonary blood
this is causing angiotensin 2 so in the
back
reaction is causing that conversion in
your attention to this is gonna
stimulate widespread vasoconstriction
when arterial are going to constrict or
get smaller they're gonna stimulate the
adrenal cortex to secrete ll2 durst Oh
which is ultimately going to cause the
kidneys to start to retain more water so
it's delaying sodium up taking the
integral cell membrane and the distal
convoluted tubule you collecting ducts
they haven't looked at the nephron video
you're welcome to take a look at that
and ADH is causing aquaporins to move to
the collecting ducts and plasma membrane
which is increasing water reabsorption
so all this is kind of occurring uses
helping the body regulate blood volume
and also pressure where were thrown is
another one mentioned this is a second
response to low blood pressure and this
is a hormone reserve apparently travels
to the bone marrow and stimulus the
production of new blood cells so how
does this help maintain homeostasis
under the way to think about it is we're
looking at our blood system for a low in
blood volume
what's are we working to increase that
we know it's made in the bone marrow
however it was our potent will the the
actual hormone to stimulate the
production increase the number of red
blood cells another function here in a
system is to regulate plasma ion
concentrations and this does occur in
the kidneys is how much is it going to
absorb Rather's will released into the
urine so this is part of that urinary
system to maintain that balance between
our plasma ion concentrations another
function is helps stabilize blood pH
this controls the loss of hydrogen ions
and bicarbonate ions in the urine or
thought it can help get rid of more of
one or the other to keep that pH and
evam you take range if the blows rate
regulates it stays within a range of
7.35 to 7.45 approximately here we see
7.35 to 7.45 and eight now that's a
large swing we're looking at into the
hundreds place of ph measuring how it
goes about doing that we have our
equation here carbon dioxide in our
water and our carbonic acid
ion's bicarbonate ions the ratio we have
of these will determine the pH everybody
can go back and forth with this to help
regulate that to maintain the proper
homeostasis in addition the urinary
system help conserve al nutrients it can
prevent excretion of waste products if
there is a deficiency or it can increase
excretion
there's determined to be an excess of
nutrients again a way that we wanted to
say in this kind of green optimal
nutrition that homeostasis we need to
reduce things if it gets too high but
also bring them up if it does get too
low lastly we're looking at the urinary
system will assist the liver to detoxify
poisons particularly amino acid
metabolism so there's call this things
called liver detox there's detoxing
recipes people go in a very simple diet
I'd help detoxify poisons but really
it's a yearning system on a continual
basis particularly the amino acid
metabolism is what the earing system
needs to do to help out the liver the
amino acid metabolism moving our amino
acids our building blocks of our
proteins that need for villain protein
can be metabolized for energy or broken
part and covered carbon chain is used to
make fat within our amino acids we have
this variant our group our voxel group a
hydrogen in our amino group this can be
broken apart by taking the nitrogen and
that can accumulate and that can be of
toxic levels potentially within the body
looking at nitrogen in particular if
ammonia generate that's it's toxic and
highly water soluble one our body to be
able to break that down and convert it
in the liver is where this occurs
converting this toxic ammonia into urea
which is less toxic and less
water-soluble both of these believe that
fertilizers that we see applied here see
a strong nitrogen component in hydrous
ammonia is one thing that's applied in a
large part across the country in urea is
also a form of a nitrogen fertilizer so
the body wants to go through this
process when it breaks down of amino
acids it will generate ammonia wants to
go through the additional process with
the assistance of the liver to convert
that to urea and it will be then carried
in the blood and in the kidneys urea and
other water Seibel wastes are converted
- urine that can then be excreted from
the body ammonium also gives off a
strong odor your rehab being that less
water siloam less toxic ideally be
converted helping reduce the stresses on
the body and easily excreted in the
body's urine