so this debaco university video is going
to look at the
u.s surgeon general's advisory regarding
marijuana use
in the developing brain
all right let's get into u.s surgeons
general's advisory regarding marijuana
use and the developing brain
so first off marijuana is during
pregnancy and a lot of
information is going to have proper
citations that you're welcome to look at
marijuana's use during pregnancy can
affect the developing fetus
thc can enter the fetal brain from the
mother's bloodstream
it may disrupt the endocannabinoid
system which is important for a healthy
pregnancy
and fetal brain development studies have
shown that marijuana use in pregnancy is
associated with
adverse outcomes including lower birth
weight
the colorado pregnancy risk assessment
monitoring system reported that
maternal marijuana use was associated
with a 50
increase in risk of low birth weight
regardless of the maternal age
race ethnicity education and also
tobacco use
kind of important there and a little
concerning we look at marijuana during
adolescence
so the human brain continues to develop
from before birth
into the mid-20s and it's vulnerable to
the effects
of addictive substances and again this
is more than cannabis but this is also
looking at thc
and marijuana in general here we can
kind of see different regions of the
brain and how tht may affect those
so they can affect areas of our brain
that control balance and coordination
so kind of like many of the green areas
then went under the influence of the
frontal cortex
which being located in this area
decision making becomes impaired
marijuana can affect the frontal cortex
involved in the decision making process
nthc affects the cerebrum during which
to condul the feeling of pain
all things that can affect particularly
teenager adolescence brain
in addition uh frequent marijuana can
marijuana use can during adolescence is
associated with a whole bunch of other
challenges as well changes of the brain
involved in tension
memory decision making and also
motivation
deficits in attention to memory have
been detected in marijuana
using teens even after a month of
abstinence
impaired learning in adolescence chronic
use is linked to
declines in iq school performance that
jeopardizes professional
as well as social achievements and life
satisfaction
increased rates of school absence and
dropout as well as
suicide attempts all negative impacts of
chronic marijuana use during adolescence
there's also psychotic disorders as well
the risk of early onset psychotic
disorders such as
schizophrenia is possible the risk for
these disorders increases with the
frequency of use
the potency of the marijuana product in
the age at first
use decreased and as well as other
substances
used there can be compounding effects as
well so again these are just reasons for
looking at and reasons really for
concern now
lastly here we're just going to look at
teens so in 2017
teens the age 12 to 17 reported frequent
use
of marijuana showed 130 percent greater
likelihood
of misusing opioids this is based on the
information presented here
also teams mixing prescription opioids
with other substances it also sadly
works the other way
those teens who reported co-ingestion
of prescription opioids with other drugs
were eight times more likely to
abuse marijuana so it can work both ways
so this is important to realize that the
brain does continue developing to the
mid-20s
and u.s surgeon general does have some
concerns posted here
regarding cannabis and thc as well as
other
products as well so again just take this
all into consideration
for any drug you're looking at
potentially consuming