if you're looking for a professional way
to store your cannabis buds the use of
nitrogen gas can be a great way to go
about this
in here on debaco university we're going
to cover just that
all right let's get into the use of
nitrogen gas for storing cannabis buds
well first off the obvious question
should be well why use nitrogen it's
already 78
in the atmosphere it's a colors or
odorless gas and heavier than oxygen why
would you utilize that
well nitrogen has actually been used for
years in preservation of perishables
during transport and storage probably
most notable
for the meat industry it's why things
come in nice sealed containers
these containers will be sealed and
nitrogen gas will be added
to that environment to help preserve
that meat as long as possible
so the nitrogen advantage so we're
looking at nitrogen the
gas flush sealed mylar bags are
excellent packaging for long-term
storage
the process flushes the bag with
nitrogen and then seals it
purging packages of oxygen extends the
life of the buds
and prevents growth of mold and
discoloration similar to that of vacuum
sealing some testing labs offer nitrogen
bagging services
using tamper-proof packaging so that's
another advantage
so this nitrogen sealing technology are
really great for that really long-term
storage and preservation
of maintaining that high quality over an
extended period of time nitrogen is
being used so you've probably
had a bag of potato chips and actually
it's been sealed with nitrogen
potato chips are shipped in
nitrogen-filled bags that not only help
with the preservation
but limit damage during shipping and
transport if you try to
push on a potato chip bag there's a lot
of air in it well that
air is usually higher percentage
nitrogen than the normal atmospheric
conditions
that helps keep all the chips from
breaking and helps keep
long-term storage because that nitrogen
has helped with that and the same
concept can be applied to your cannabis
buds
prevent the physical damage of the buds
as well as preserving the long-term
storage
by the use of higher concentrations of
nitrogen
in this storage environment so that
nitrogen saturation advantage
well sealing up containers with nitrogen
gas can reduce the oxidation
and help preserve the cannabinoids as
well as the terpenes
so it's limiting that kind of breaking
down process now as we saw it could be
in
mylar bags could also be in kind of what
looks like a
cat food or tuna fish container here as
well
this aluminum can both can have nitrogen
saturation applied to them doesn't have
to be just
one set system there is however added
cost to this
so there is at cost with this nitrogen
gas option
but consumers may not see a great value
with this unlike the quality curing and
trimming of buds that they will notice
and may be willing to pay a little bit
more
for while this is advised the use of
nitrogen gas it should
incorporate only high quality end
product to ensure only the best material
has the longest shelf life and something
you're going to hopefully get a near top
dollar for and keep in mind that use of
nitrogen gas don't forget about the
light
storing canvas and nitrogen does have
its advantages as presented here
but light can still degrade the blood
quality even if nitrogen is used
so don't think just because you're using
this nitrogen gas saturation that
now you can keep them all out in the
light and they won't be affected they
still can be broken down by other
environmental factors but utilizing the
nitrogen gas
can help preserve the local environment
those buds are kept for the longest
storage option so you're able to
maintain that high quality
for as long as possible