all right here on debaco university i'm
going to go over using propane
to heat a cannabis grow facility and
while we see the propane burners here on
the stove
we'd have a little bit more efficient to
heat our growing area for our plants
[Music]
all right let's go over some of the
details with using propane to heat our
grow facility
well first off when we're talking
propane or in natural gas heaters just
in general
they're certified for residential
agriculture as well as industrial use
they have quiet operation from
relatively small lightweight units
their power exhaust options can be used
in small diameter vent pipe
they are optional right or left hand
piping for installation
can be installed easily due to flexible
positioning of the piping
and they're sealed permanently
lubricated motor for trouble-free
dependability
and some models come with a 10-year
warranty on the heat exchanger
so all of these are very positive
aspects for a reason why propane or
natural gas heating for a grow facility
is a very common practice and as you
said agricultural
residential even industrial use so this
applies more
than to just the agricultural aspect of
things
now propane is similar to natural gas
but typically a little more costly so
again we sometimes use them
interchangeably terms
we want to be kind of mindful of exactly
which one we're going to be using for
our facility
it's typically easier to access though
than natural gas depending on where
your geographic location may be propane
offers minimal maintenance but a storage
tank
and pre-heater are required propane is
best purchased
by the transport load which requires
about a 30 30
000 gallon tank and that's usually
buried depending on your regulations
but usually it's buried purchase can be
made during a time of the year when
prices are the lowest
that'd be the most advantageous to the
person looking at making that purchase
to be very cost effective
now natural gas is one of the most
economical fuels
that's not available to growers in all
areas so just keep that in mind that
you have to check to see of its
availability particularly in
your area or your particularly growing
area
there to see if it is possible to get
no on-site storage is required since
it's piped in from trim transmission
line so this is one of the
why reasons why is limited on its
availability
simply because is it kind of sitting at
the street is it below ground that you
can
tap into or is it something that is just
not existent in your area
natural gas burns cleanly requires
little equipment maintenance
and used for central boilers or remote
unit heaters
this should not be the only heat source
for dedicated growing spaces because
some suppliers include
a interpretable claws interruptable
claws which
allows them basically to turn off your
supply in time of extreme need
usually during cold spells when the fuel
is needed to heat homes
as a backup fuel supply and equipment to
burn it are essential under these
conditions
just because your agricultural area
heating up a growth facility you're not
necessarily high in the list
and you want to look to see if there is
that interruptible clause where
if the demand is very high and the
supply is low they can actually
with their claws turn off the natural
gas flow to your facility
for larger users it's best to buy a
direct purchase
from one of the large suppliers near a
well head
adding the transmission cost to the
pipelines will give you a total fuel
cost it's important to take into
consideration
the total fuel cost there so again
not every heat source is ideal this one
is a
great and worth consideration if it is
an option in your area
but again consider all the pros and cons
with any heat source that you plan on
using