so you're interested in learning more
about using fuel oil to heat a cannabis
grow facility
well you've come to the right place here
at tobacco university because that's
just what i'm going to explain here
[Music]
all right let's get into the details of
using fuel oil to heat a cannabis grow
facility
well first off with any oil we want to
be considered it might take into
considerations
particularly with oil we want to
consider the oil tank that's going to be
required to be on site
this is an above ground storage tank
that must have a containment in the
event
of a leak or a spill this is an outdoor
storage
pumping the oil out in cold winter
months could be a problem
could gel insulated tanks or additives
to the fuel to protect against this
hazard
need to be implemented so it's not just
kind of that always oh
like the gasoline in your car oil
storage tanks sometimes can have issues
in that cold winter months if
not pre-treated the oil can actually gel
in the tank and cause it to become
unburnable there's number two oil which
is home heating oil
which you're most familiar with if you
have oil to heat your house or facility
already
this is number two oil is nearly
identical to diesel engine
fuel it's a relatively clean fuel that
demands
slightly more burner maintenance than a
gas burner in comparison
it's cleaner due to the recent switch in
the united states to ultra low sulfur
fuel
that's just caused to become cleaner not
100 clean but at least
cleaner at least an improvement of what
it was then we have number four
and number six fuel oils these oils have
higher heating value
than the number two fuel oil but require
preheating
and a greater attention to equipment
operation
because they're more viscous which means
they're thicker than number two
oil contracting for the winter fuels
uh fuel needs to be when prices are low
which is typically in august you want to
get those contracts in and signed
usually around august or early september
because this can cause considerable
savings and money and ensure that you
have a supply for the winter
this is not something you just buy
necessarily on demand
is definitely advantageous to go through
and seek a contract out towards the end
of summer
then lastly there is waste oil so waste
oil comes from the collection centers
from cars and trucks
some of this oil is cleaned and reused
for lubrication much of it is available
as
fuel at a few cents per gallon waste oil
that has not been processed requires a
settling tank to trap water and sludge
that might be present
these have to be disposed of to me epa
regulations do their classification as a
hazardous waste
therefore waste oil has a heat
equivalent about 150 000 btus per gallon
which is very similar to number two
fuel oil so again it can be a lot
cheaper to get potentially
does require some other specialized
equipment so all of these are sub
categories
under adding fuel oil as a heat source
for a cannabis
grow facility