so many growers talk about adding amino
acids to their cannabis plants
is it a worthwhile process here at
tobacco university
we'll answer that very question
so let's get into using amino acids for
cannabis production
so first off what are our amino acids
which basically start with the basis
and there any group of organic molecules
that consist of a basic amino group
an acidic carboxyl group and in an
organic r
group or side chain its variable this is
unique to each amino acid
we can see them listed the 21 listed
right here the remaining two bonds of
the alpha carbon
atom are generally testified by hydrogen
atoms and r group so keep in mind that
kind of this amino group here
what defines the different amino acids
is kind of this side chain here
we can see some are electrically charged
side chains some the positive
charge some of the negative charge some
have uncharged
side chains some are special cases some
have um hydrophilic
phobic sorry um side chains so all these
must be taken into consideration
it just causes amino acids to make up
proteins that gives proteins their
unique
shape so here's a reference article
looking at some
applications of amino acids improved
yield and lettuce
by enhancing photosynthesis and nutrient
availability
so we're going to relate this to
cannabis so amino acids study
conclusions here looking at the lettuce
they can be inferred that the l and
that's just to form methionine
increase the chlorophyll concentration
of plants and contributes to the saving
of energy
thus boosting plant yield in lettuce
this also led to
significant increases in observed
physiological factors in lettuce leaves
and lower concentrations because of
at high concentrations it affects oxygen
uptake
which can kill plants this is again
where dosing is a very important
parameter to consider
more is not better in brief looking at
the lettuce the l
methionine at concentrations of 0.2
milligrams per liter showed the best
effect on the growth of lettuce plants
so how does this kind of relate to
cannabis or if we're looking back
through how can
relates to cannabis well applying a
general amino acid product may have
limiting benefits
as a result indicate that specific amino
acids needs to be studied
that there only may be a limited number
that could show plant benefits
just adding amino acids isn't really
going to help plants per side
might be some specific ones that may
have direct application
also the application rates are another
important consideration since higher
rates have been shown to have impacts on
plant hormone pathways
that could result in plant death or at
least negative
impacts on the plant so if you're going
to use them amino acids
do so carefully and in moderation and
observe the plant
to see if you're actually getting a
benefit or a change always good to run a
control which is one that would not have
amino acids to see if there are any
visual differences or morphological
differences
to determine whether it's not it's worth
the
extra expense of adding amino acids to
your cannabis
plant production