so here on tobacco university i'll be
describing using liquid carbon dioxide
for cannabis production
[Music]
interested in using a very dense uh
very pure form of carbon dioxide well
using liquid
might be worth a consideration
particularly if you're a larger growing
operation
so liquid carbon dioxide is similar to
compressed carbon dioxide at least
in the general methods that would be
implemented liquid bottles are
essentially a denser form
of compressed carbon dioxide however
unlike compressed carbon dioxide
liquid carbon dioxide requires
refrigeration
when being stored and typically it's
found in larger sizes
here we see a 300 pound 500 pound at 750
pound
they even come in larger sizes than that
for your liquid
carbon dioxide now as i said this does
require specialized equipment
so there is more required equipment when
using liquid carbon dioxide and this is
why it is commonly used
for larger applications where compressed
carbon dioxide tank
would simply be too large and require
two frequent fillings
so using liquid as we can see here this
is probably your regular
for size comparison 50 pound bottles and
see how large this liquid carbon
dioxide tank is so specialized
equipments but can be justified
for larger growing operations now liquid
becomes a gas so if you're using liquid
carbon dioxide it will not be delivered
to the plants
as a liquid but it will be delivered as
a gas
so it will be heated and injected via
the gaseous state
now that does not mean you can go
through and go through and add a fire
extinguisher and you know add
the gaseous state in this way now here's
using the fan help disperse it
not really recommended in that way be
much more precisely delivered to plants
and allows for very consistent results
so
same general idea but in the very
general sense but not
like this so liquid carbon dioxide set
up what was that
what would that actually look like well
here we see there's a safety relief
valve we have a pressure gauge
a darker colored ring around the top of
the cylinder indicates a siphon tube is
present
so when we're looking at the actual kind
of cylinder i'm noticing there is a
gaseous carbon dioxide
that's about five to ten percent of
carbon dioxide by weight is
unused because only gas remains and we
have the liquid carbon dioxide here at
700 to 800 pounds per square inch
if you're looking at this in general
very similar to a gas estate a
compressed bottle
but as we saw here additional equipment
is required
and tends to be used in larger sizes for
for larger operations where simple
compressed bottles
would just be too laborious and not as
efficient