here on this debaco university video
we're going to go over the distillation
of cannabis to produce an extract
[Music]
so while it may look like there's a lot
of equipment here and there is and
there's a lot of little
degrees of specialization this is a very
popular method
used for cannabis extraction so we're
going to go over using
the this distillation process for
cannabis extraction and why
despite its complexities it's utilized
at such a large scale
so first off what's the general
description of the distillation
process and again there's going to be
some differences depending exactly
the process that you may look at but
they're all going to have the same
basics the distillation method is going
to be using the solvent extraction
method in a
distillation kit extraction of the
desired plant material until you have
all the cannabinoids
terpenes and flavonoids collected in one
mixture
this material must go through
decarboxylation and also winterization
steps
you'll see a lot of these kind of
distillation areas a lot of these
receiving flasks
so there's a lot of necessarily moving
parts
a lot of components that are required as
part of this using a precise heating
element to the material is heated to the
max of 315 degrees fahrenheit
to boil off the terpenes and flavonoids
the resulting steam
is then pushed through a series of
cooling tubes where it's condensed back
into just
the desired flavonoid terpene mixture so
temperature regulation
temperature moderation all very
important because that's going to
determine
exactly how you collect everything now
they continue to raise the temperature
to boil off the cannabinoids so you're
kind of going through this distillation
you're pulling off one thing
next thing next thing so you continue to
raise the temperature to boil off the
cannabinoids
the cannabinoid steam is then cooled via
cooling
cooling tubes and condensed into highly
potent distilled
cannabis oil resulting two mixtures are
then combined to create the end product
which is typically thc the
thc to distillate now there is
a lot of simplified versions here we saw
before there's a lot of other machines a
lot of other separation methods
this is kind of a simplified version
here however
one necessary component is usually what
we see here
we see this right here is called a
rotary evaporator
and this rotary evaporator receives the
solvent that was used to extract the
cannabinoids from the flower
and heats off the solvent often ethanol
based and leaves the crude oil waiting
for the decarboxylation step
and we can see here temperature
regulations we see a lot of
computer controlled things which is very
good because we want to have everything
repeatable and consistent to get those
exact
particular terpenes or cannabinoids
we're looking for this extraction method
now that decarboxylation step the crude
oil from the rotary evaporator
is moved to an alternate container and
is ready for decarboxylation
where it's heated to about 104 degrees
celsius for 90 minutes
while spinning at 250 revolutions per
minute
so there's kind of that crude kind of
general uh extract that's
going through we have that rotation that
is occurring and spinning
and we can see temperature as well as
time very important protocols as part of
this
process of extraction now example
of a white film distillation machine so
here we see one
uh pictured right in the image here we
see these different flasks we also see
very different colorations because
remember we're extracting
distilling off different components on
the top right the decarboxylation oil
from the rotary evaporator
is ready to go through the machine and
then we have the
bottom left flask where the disc or
terpenes
is located the bottom right flask here
is the crude oil
and then we have extracting terpenes at
lower temperatures about 158 degrees
celsius and high pressure
the extracting distillate is a higher
temperature about 170 degrees
celsius and the lowest possible pressure
these pass the oil through the the
extract the terpenes then take the crude
oil from
from that pass and put it back in the
machine for a distillation extract
so sometimes things do have to pass
through multiple times
just to ensure you're pulling off those
specific fractions
of that original product now what is
that
resulting end product well the end
product of cannabis distillation is
the distillate as we can see right here
it's a pure oil-like substance with
nearly 100 cannabinoids
this distillate is used as the base
ingredient for most edibles
and most vapes it can be either thc or
cbd based
or a multitude of other cannabinoids
because of this high percentage
and this degree of specificity is why
this method
of extraction for cannabis is so popular
despite all of the required kind of
chemist background
and distal process and equipment and
monitoring and protocols
there is a kind of advantage in the end
product
after going through all those steps now
what are some advantages of this
distillation method just in general
that as i said extremely pure product
when compared to other extraction
methods you can have those
distinct separations occurring also
gives the
operator complete control over terpenes
and flavonoids and it can be easily
automated even though the initially it
may take a little time to kind of
learn all the protocols it can raise up
the option to be easily automated
however with any system it's always not
just advantages what are some of the
disadvantages
of this system is that it can be very
costly
can be a long process with multiple
steps it can take days to pass one liter
of crude oil through the machine
and the distillation process strips the
cannabis of all compounds except for the
desired compound
which may have dramatic effects on the
terpenes when adding them back into the
mixture
so that's just an important thing to
keep in mind it's great that it's very
specific
but because it's specific you're kind of
separating out those components
that maybe have a synergistic effect so
this hopefully explains a little bit
about the distillation method of
extraction
for cannabis plants