on this tobacco university video i'm
going to go over using electricity to
heat a cannabis grow facility
[Music]
all right if you're thinking about using
electrical heat to heat your grow
facility
let's go over some of the details you
should be aware of well first off the
advantages of using electric heat
there's low installation cost there's
dependability with electric heat
it's application flexible quiet
operation
low maintenance and easy to service all
these sound like great advantages
for electric heat simple to connect to a
power supply there's usually power in
the facility anyway
do have to be careful about the wattage
requirements
of your size of your heater
dependability there's really no moving
parts so it's a great thing
there can be air deflector blades
installed to help control
airflow over the facility over the area
within the grow room
quiet operations you're not dealing with
any really loud noises
low maintenance because the motors are
totally enclosed thermally protected so
that's a great thing
and the fan motor are exposed usually
for easy access
if needed to be accessed now
the electric heat for individual grow
rooms for individual rooms themselves
having nearly instant heat in a grow
space is advantageous to prevent the
temperature from dipping too
low this type of heat source can also
allow for specific temperature targets
to be varied room to room
with different thermostats based on
different sections so that could really
one allow a grower to dial
in the heat in different rooms and also
try to minimize the cost of heating
those individual rooms
you want to check to be sure though when
you are going through and considering
electric heat
to make sure that the electrical system
can handle the addition of an electric
heater
always consider the worst case scenario
and that's where all of your electrical
systems are running at the same time
even though that might not be the
intention this includes your lights your
pumps your fans
and any addition to the heater that you
may have you don't want to have what's
going on looks like here we just start
plugging everything
in and oh if that works let me try
something else oh that's still working
let me try something else
you want to be mindful of exactly how
much amps
your system is drawing and what breaker
system you have everything hooked up to
lastly is again that word of caution
because we are talking about a grow
facility
within grow rooms there's always water
of some kind around
so just be sure to take extra
precautions to make sure that
it's kept isolated and away from areas
where electrical heat
is in general heaters tend to be large
consumers electricity to make sure they
do not come in contact with water
make sure there's distinct isolation and
separation
so you're providing the sufficient heat
that the grow facility needs
with the proper safety precautions in
place for both the plants
as well as the grower