so wood is a common heat source but here
at tobacco university we're going to
look at using wood to heat a cannabis
grow facility
so if you want to use wood to heat your
grow facility let's go over some of the
details with that and considerations you
should be making
so first off wood heat just in general
wood is relatively inexpensive
as forest residue no waste chips or even
as
sawdust often the cost is driven more by
the transportation
in handling than the actual product this
could be dependent on
location as well a lot of times people
are using wood heat to eat their houses
so it is again a very common form of
heat source
wood versus oil so looking at kind of
the comparison between the two here
fuel oil requirement for about 20 000
square feet
of greenhouse space located in
connecticut would be about 20
000 gallons for the heating season if
wood is
substituted as a fuel source this would
require a hundred and approximately
110 cords of hardwood this means that
handling about 220 tons
if the furnace was fired by hand so
that's again an important consideration
when we're looking at how we're going to
be utilizing the wood
there's going to be a manual loading
type the cost of the wood is only six
thousand dollars delivered
in log length compared to the 35 000
for the estimated oil cost now keep in
mind that log length is not nice chopped
up and kind of ready to go
as the picture shows above me the
difference is enough to have reasonable
payback for the equipment
and to pay for what's called a night
fireman somebody has to constantly
feed that fire and keep it going for the
duration of the night when it is the
coldest
so again all these have to be taken into
consideration
however when we're looking at wood we
also want to be considerate of the
moisture content furnaces and boilers
that burn
cord wood or chips and sawdust are
available the heat value of the fuel
depends on the moisture content
so for example green hold tree chips
have a heat
value of about 8 million btus per ton
dried
chips have a heat value of 14 million
btus per ton
so that re reduction in moisture content
really
increases the btus or the british
thermal units
of that wood that it can provide if the
wood is burned at high temperatures more
than 1500 degrees fahrenheit
very little smoke or pollution occurs
that's another important consideration
if you get that heat high enough
you can have a very clean burning with
your wood again that wood could be
relatively low cost but there are going
to be that associated
night firemen at manual feeding that low
moisture content taken consideration
as well as the having enough supply
for your area depending on how cold
that season may be