interested in learning more about adding
humic acid for
to your cannabis plants you've come to
the right place here at tobacco
university
where here we're going to discuss this
very topic
all right let's get into using humic
acid for cannabis production
so first off what is humic acid probably
should just in generally just define
that
uh humic and folic acids are the final
breakdown components
of decaying plants and animals found in
prehistoric deposits
one source of humic acids is the
sedimentation of layers found in
liardinite it's kind of this kind of
fine
powdered black granulated form
this organic matter has not reached the
state of coal but it kind of has some
properties or at least feels some of the
coal
and differs from soft brown coal by its
high
oxidation degree as in as a result the
process of coal formation
has no value as fuel so this is not
going to like burn like coal
but if you looked at it and didn't quite
know what it was it has some
similarities to like a very finely
granulated coal product
now we're looking at the research
article here where they looked at the
impact of nitrogen phosphate potassium
and humic acid supplementation
looking at the chemical profile of
medical cannabis and again i'm just
going to provide a brief overview here's
the link you can learn more about it
so humic acid and thc levels well for
example the following uh humic acid
applications
thc levels at the top of the plant was
reduced from 11.8
to 7.4 percent and consequently
concentrations throughout the plant
height did not differ significantly so
if we're looking to just get it to thc
the
top center and bottom portions of the
plant definitely seemed like there was a
reduction
which kind of seems a little odd here's
our commercial phosphorus potassium in
our humic acids
that there's an overall this reduction
from 11.8 to 7.8 percent thc levels
so a little bit concerning here if we're
looking at trying to maximize some
cannabinoids
i'll also see here with cbd and cbg some
of the differences that occurred
that's just a clear indication of what
occurred with just
thc levels again more data here if you
want to investigate or pause the video
right now so going on to the impact of
humic
acids well the nutrition treatments were
supplemented with umic acid
enhanced phosphorus fertilization or
enhanced nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium
hemetic acid was found to reduce the
natural variability of all of the
cannabinoids
studied so it's just kind of concerning
there
the results demonstrate sensitivity of
cannabinoid metabolism to mineral
nutrition
so you want to be mindful that adding
more inputs to your plants
may not get you always more return
now there's nutrients impact on the
cannabinoids
so phosphorus enhanced treatment
did not affect thc cbd cbgn or cbg
concentrations in the flowers
from the top of the plants a sixteen
percent reduction of thc
concentration was observed in
inflorescent leaves though
it's an important note the complete npk
supplementation
increased cbg levels in the flowers by
71 percent
and lowered cvn levels in both flowers
and inflorescent leaves by 38 and 36
respectively so this is also where it
comes important as growers
to understand what cannabinoids
specifically you're looking to produce
or
maximize because that can impact what
fertilizers or what treatments
you might give to your plants rather
than just trying to
try something i hope for better results
looking at targeting specific compounds
and how they are influenced by the
inputs that the grower utilizes you can
see here
has a great impact we don't want to do
anything that's going to increase
cost and time and labor that's going to
cause a reduction in yield
so be an informed grower do your
research and make educated decisions
on anything you choose to add