in this debaco university video
the sediment filter and details
surrounding that will be covered
[Music]
let's go over using a sediment filter
for cannabis production
so first off what is a sediment filter
let's start with the basics
the sediment filter captures and removes
a particulate matter
such as soil and debris from the water
this can apply to both municipal as well
as natural water sources
flakes of rust can enter your water
supply from corroded galvanized plumbing
rainwater can carry silt clay soil and
grains of sand
into your well groundwater supply so
it's important
if you have any of these to be utilizing
a sediment filter
so you can take out that particulate so
you can be left with
clean water at least that looks clean
sediment filters keep in mind do not
remove any contaminants
only the physical sized particles so
what's the advantage of
a sediment filter well sediment filter
is the first line of defense against
dirt and debris in your irrigation
system
this prohibits all of the solid
particulate
from entering your water supply and
impeding the performance of your water
filtration systems
such as carrying of irrigation pipes
could be wearing out
pumps doing damage to any sort of
filters or o-rings
down the line send filter is a great
guard against
any of that from happening so how do
sediment filters work will sediment
filters
physically block unwanted particulate
matter based on
its size 7 filters are like a net that
catches the particulate matter traveling
in the water
so here we see an example here we have
our larger particles our smaller
particles able to pass through
seven filters going to take out those
larger clay
sand particles in comparison to
something really fine
like ions it kind of might look like
this in the end where it looks like it's
still encased with a soil
some are more of a paper component some
more of a mesh screen
all of them basically work the same way
of filtering out
those larger particulate sizes so what
do
some filters remove well the
sediment filters can remove visible
particles matter
in any particles of dirt sand dust and
debris
they can be caught by its micron rated
capacity
so cinnamon filters also remove
turbidity from the water as we can see
here
so we said what does sediment filters
remove well it depends on
what size the sediment filter you have
the smaller the size
the greater amount that will remove
however typically also the slower the
flow rate
so this is why there are different sizes
because it may affect the flow rate or
the gallons per minute you're getting
through that filter
what are the limitations of a sediment
filter because every filter again
is has some limitations and seven
filters do not remove chemicals heavy
metals bacterias or dissolved
particulate matter
they do not improve the taste or smell
of the water so just be aware
if that's you're looking to remove
sediment filter is not going to be a
good option for you
it may produce water it looks clear and
that can be a good thing
but doesn't necessarily remove the
chemicals bacteria or
heavy metals from that water however
semi-fillers are still very common seven
filters are the most effective when
serving as pre-filters for other
filtration systems they're typically
used in conjunction with other
filtration methods like reverse osmosis
or carbon filtration as well they're
typically the first line of defense to
make these filters last
longer as well to take out anything that
might be in the irrigation water
initially so what are the different
types of sediment filters as we get into
some more of the details
there's a couple listed here our pleated
filters are best suited for large
particulate are also washable and
reusable
then we have meltdown melt-blown filters
and these are best suited for fine
particulates
so it's kind of that different particle
size you want to know what's in your
water
then here right below me we have this
string wound filters
and once overloaded with sediment they
will pass them through
indicating the need for filter change
but this could cause
issues down the line so keep that in
mind that this
melt blown filter great for fine
particulate
string works great and then all of a
sudden once it fills it'll let those
particular goes by and that can cause
some severe issues
down the line then we also have
something called bag filters which
change
in micron size between 1 and 200 microns
and then we have a spun down filter
designed to remove
large size debris from the water as well
so again depending on what you're trying
to remove
will determine what type of sediment
filter might be the best option for you
to select
so let's just talk about micron size
well sediments
filters micron rating indicates what
size particles the filter will be able
to eliminate
for example a 10 micron filter we will
remove anything
10 microns and larger the micron size of
your sediment filter will vary based
upon
the respective size of the sediment you
are seeking to eliminate from your
source
for a reverse osmosis or ro system a 5
micron sediment pre-filter is typically
recommended
this just kind of shows that relative
comparison of microns compared to the
average human hair
being about 150 and working way down
here just again give you just a general
idea of
silver mesh size inches in the microns
and the typical material that might be
removing
so nominal versus absolute filter or
ratings
kind of something that often is used as
interchangeable terms when clearly it is
not
nominal mean or average 5 micron rating
means that the filter is designed to
capture approximately
everything 5 microns and above
an absolute 5 micron rating means that
the filter remove
over 95 percent of anything 5 microns in
size
so keep that in mind that the nominal
versus absolute is also probably going
to have
a significant price difference an
absolute rated micron filter can ensure
specific contaminant is removed from the
water source
as a result that's probably going to
probably gonna pay a little bit more for
that type of precision
in your filtering method then the
frequency of filter changes and once i
know well how often do i need to change
that filter
and it really depends on many factors
one
reliable method is to watch for a water
pressure drop
so a lot of times you have your water
filter and you'll have a little pressure
gauge before
and after it you want to make sure those
gauges are reading the same if one
starts reading a little bit lower
it's a sign it might be time to change
that filter simply because
a filter clogged which is filled with
sediment will cause a reduced
reduced water pressure so that can be a
great easy way to indicate
that filter pri is going to need to be
changed however the general
recommendation is to change the filter
or at least check it every 6 to 12
months depending on the flow rate and
rating and also the type of water you
have coming into that filter system
once you have an idea you can have make
note of it write it down
and you can have an idea of how
frequency will change your filter
but that pressure drop is a great way to
know exactly when
it's time to check that filter and most
likely time to change that filter so
make sure you have an extra on hand