if you're interested in using a piston
pump to fertilize your plants
this debaco university video is for you
right let's get into using a piston pump
fertilizer injector for cannabis
production
now as we can see here in this
commercial operation a lot of commercial
operations use more than just one they
use a lot of them
these are dosatrons some people just
refer them as dosatrons but it is kind
of a name brand there are some other
options of chemi injector and
many many others but dosatron is kind of
the name brand
you can see here each one hooked up to a
different fertilizer tank allowing
different valves to be controlled
really allowing for an efficient method
of fertilization
to the plants and this is why this is so
popular
used in cannabis production facilities
so first off we're looking
here we're looking at the flow inside
the pump and reciprocating pumps are
pumps
in which a piston or diaphragm displaces
a given amount of chemical with each
stroke
the change in internal volume of the
pump creates high pressure
which forces chemicals into the
discharge pipe so what we're kind of
seeing here is we have our concentrated
solution down here at the bottom
it's being brought up through a suction
force it's being mixed with the water
through a piston
and then the blended solution is going
out to the plants
these make a very distinctive clicking
sound as that pump comes up and down
up and down up and down and it will
change with the rate of the flow if you
can increase the flow rate the piston go
up faster
if you decrease the rate of flow the
piston will go up slower
and what that is doing is that's
allowing for a very consistent
amount of fertilizer to be added to this
mixing area here
now it's important you have a pressure
regulator and also have a filter
so you're not having any clogging issues
as well as a check valve to run any
backflow
but these are very precise methods of
injecting fertilizer to irrigation water
now the basic operation of the piston
pump is similar to that
of the cylinder in an automobile engine
kind of the compression stroke an
increase in decrease to power stroke
the initial stroke the chemical enters
the cylinder through the
suction check valve you see down here
and a compression stroke the chemical is
forced into the discharge line
be located over here through the
discharge check valve
and this is water flow driven which is
great because it offers
consistent dilution rates and no needed
add for any electricity
or any other inputs simply the flow of
water
will allow this pump to work just fine
so it's also offers
self-correction so most piston pumps are
driven by the flowing water through the
injector that drives the motion of the
pump as i mentioned earlier
the movement of the piston will vary
with the speed of the water flow which
is great because it self regulates
so this self corrects and ensures very
consistent
dilution rates and very consistent rates
given to the plants
the larger piston is driven by the
pressure of the irrigation system the
smaller
injects the chemical into the irrigation
line and all this simply works with
water pressure
however this is one of the downfalls as
there are some moving parts that can
wear over time
particularly with excessive use
now there's also an example here of a
grower set up and it shows the
fertilizer
injector here along with a pre-filter
so you can have your kind of pre-filter
going through and
ensuring that you're filtering out any
contaminants you're not going to wear
this out
as quickly you have a pressure valve
located before and after again help
regulate and make sure there's no
pressure loss
fertilizer concentration tank located
right down here
a water bypass if you didn't want not
want to add any
fertilizer injector had a problem wanted
to remove on the system
a little bypass valve there also hooked
up to here a timer
and a post injection filter as well to
prevent anything that may have get
pulled up in the line
before it enters your irrigation system
particularly important with drip
irrigation
but this kind of shows you a setup and
how they can be used in a small
hole in their operation as well as a
large commercial operation
it offers a lot of good consistency
which is part of the reason
why they're so popular