here on this tobacco university video
we're going to be looking at a product
you might be familiar with
called root shield and see how it
relates to cannabis production
so in this video i'm going to go over
using root shield for cannabis
production and give you some
studies that looked at investigating the
effectiveness
of this particular product so first off
here is a reference poster and here's
the long link you can also see in the
description
link to all resources but this is also
the poster
where they looked at fusarium in
particular with some other biological
controls i'll provide you with a general
summary
so first off what is root shield i
figure i should just first off describe
what it actually is
and it does have active ingredients and
this is there's root shield and there's
root shield plus
what does the plus stand for well it
contains two versions of trichoderma two
different strains of trichoderma here
and what is trichoderma it's an organic
biological
fungicide with dual active ingredients
in since we have those two strains there
to prevent a broad spectrum of root
diseases and promote
a healthy root system it's registered
fuse
in the united states except alaska rei
of four hours and post-harvest interval
of zero days this biological control
agent has been reported to be effective
against a range of root pathogens
and in this study root shield plus wpu
transfer wettable powder
was applied at a rate of 0.02 percent
so looking at biological fungicides in
general the evaluation of biobiological
agents against pathogenic fungi can be
challenging
due to the environmental variability
that naturally exists
so you have to look at these studies and
kind of see if they apply
and see what conditions that occurred so
we look looking at comparisons
focused on a single pathogen may seem
limiting for a grower's viewpoint but it
does offer some
degree of usable information and
hopefully you find that with this video
so if you see fusarium i'll give the
oxosporium in proliferation
uh polipher tatum these
pathogens have been isolated from all
stages of plant growth from vegetative
cuts to mother plants
that typically show as wilt systems so
grower may recognize i know it's a
pepper plant but we recognize these
wilting systems
if you look on it on a through a
microscope this is what the fusion would
actually kind of look like you're
associating with a root
if you were to play it on a petri dish
this is what it may look like
so treatments impact on disease looking
at the study presented here
root shield containing trichoderma
reduced infection we can see that
located right here negative control
means a control plant that was grown
without
any disease and then a positive control
is when it was inoculated with disease
and you can see how these different
products compare
and how they are definitely show
different degrees
of effectiveness so what's the
conclusion
based on the cannabis data provided
there was that root shield did produce a
notable level of disease reduction
however regalia produced a statistically
significant level of disease reduction
and just to go back to that for a second
this is where regalia was so it was
shown in that study
based on this data regalia may be a
better option but root shield would
still be
potential for offer some protection and
it may offer reduction in other diseases
so it should be considered as a
potential biopesticide when it comes to
canvas production
remember this would be root applied and
drenched as well
i found another article here looking at
the trichoderma
and kind of presented here again i'm
provided just a general overview
this was looking at growth and
development of cbd content of
hemp so the study specifics we're
looking at
the study aimed to investigate the
effect of trichoderma ethereum
inoculation
on agronomically and quality
characteristics of two
monishes hemp varieties fedora
17 felina planted in 12 liter pots
filled with soil and 8 liters of compost
look at the study for more details on
exactly the materials and methods if you
want to learn more information
however the product they used was
trichoderma hysterium and was a
commercial product
all the details provided here with the
concentration of that product as well
in a greenhouse pot experiment was
conducted in a complete
randomized design of two treatments of
the trichodermatarium
both at a low and a high dose
represented by t1 and t2
the split applications were carried out
through fertigation at
10 and 30 days after sewing so so this
is in the ground so the plants
10 days after and the next one is 30
days after and here we see the control
where no amount was added
t1 and t2 where they basically doubled
the amount of applied fungal spores
so yield characteristics related here um
to the cbd content yield characteristics
and cbd content was
affected by different trichoderma
historium treatments and hemp varieties
for the fedora 17 and also felina
so if we're looking here percent cbd we
are seeing
a change and these letters represent
statistically different
levels there and you can pause the video
and take a look at the blood dry weight
the blood length
the in the blood compact index the
percent cbd and also the cbd yield
expressed in grams per plant
so what's the conclusion of their study
if you look to go back and pause
the data but the conclusion was the
highest values of plant height
and dry weight were noticed with t2
especially in the
felina variety trigonometry serum
positively influenced characteristics of
inflorescence such as the number
fresh weight moisture and compactness in
both varieties while the dry weight
length and dry yield of influences was
not improved
finally the fertigation of trichodermal
serum and hemp
plants was beneficial at increasing
cannabidiol or cbd
content especially in the elevated
treatment levels
so again here's this comparison the
control to the treatment levels
something based on this data you may
want to consider adding to your grow
run control run a trial yourself see if
it does make a difference
but at least there's some data here to
support that it might be worth
the investment in labor to incorporate
into your growing operation