on this debaco university video we'll be
looking at
compressed carbon dioxide bottles for
carbon monoxide enrichment related to
cannabis production
so here we see a collection of bottles
and using compressed carbon dioxide
bottles for
cannabis production is very common
practice here just some examples of some
of the bottles that can be utilized
and let's go over some of the process
involved when you're looking at
implementing
this type of system so first off this is
the most common for hobby growers using
bottle system
many grow shops have bottle exchange
program which is great
typically this is only for the 20 pound
bottles as these are the most commonly
used for grow tents in small
operations realize it can be bottles as
small as five pounds or sometimes even
two and a half pounds
up to even way larger sizes than just 20
pounds
50 can be relatively common easy to
handle
they can also be 200-pound bottles it
can be very difficult
to get at that point 20 by far the most
common
and often used in its bottle exchange
program what that is is where you bring
an empty bottle you pick up a full
bottle
you empty that bottle you bring it back
you exchange that bottle for another
full bottle so you don't get the same
bottles back
but you always have a full 20 pound
bottle with this exchange program
now the bottle weight keep in mind is
only the weight of the carbon dioxide
so just a word of caution if you're
purchasing a 20 pound bottle
this is only the weight of the carbon
dioxide it does not include
the bottle weight so when purchasing 20
pounds of carbon dioxide it's likely
you're going to be lifting
or transporting closer to 40 pounds and
that depends
on the material the bottle is made from
aluminum is of course going to be
lighter than steel as far as the bottle
weight goes
but when you're purchasing bottles or
looking at oh 20 pound bottle
that is only the weight of the carbon
dioxide not including the canister
that's included in so keep that in mind
it's particularly important when you
have 50 pound bottles
so these are often more efficient way to
purchase carbon dioxide
but they can be more of a hassle
remember a 50 pound bottle of carbon
dioxide when
purchased will weigh about 170 pounds
so take care when transporting also just
a side note on the image
next to me here while it shows these
bottles and looks like they're nice
labeled with carbon dioxide
it should be capital c capital o with
two as a subscript
so this technically looks like cobalt
two uh
not carbon dioxide so that's just a
little bit of the science behind if you
wanna have
capital c capital o with 2 as a
subscript capital c
lowercase o actually means cobalt just a
side note there
so for size reference you know we talk
about these bottles you may
look at them online well how big are
these bottles aluminum carbon dioxide
cylinder information is provided here
and shows an
average height of a person to kind of
give you that idea of just how much
bigger
that 50 pound bottle is probably part of
the reason why the 20 pound is so common
20 compared to 15 even compared to 10
not all that big of a size difference
don't want to go much smaller because
you're going to be dosing your area with
that so 20 pound bottle probably the
most common for grow shops
so in general though why are bottles so
popular
you're purchasing pure carbon dioxide
and there's no byproduct or waste added
to your growing space
that's one of the reasons why compressed
carbon monoxide in bottle form
is so popular this can also reduce the
chance of plant damage
also controllers with fudges what's
called fuzzy logic can be used
which is another way to help increase
use efficiency
bottles also do not require special
storage conditions or maintenance
basically have an area that's chained
off to a fixed point and you're good to
go
there's no not a lot of other special
storage requirements that are needed
which makes them very easy to implement
into any particular growth space
however bottle danger in storage related
to safety
carbon dioxide cylinders should be
stored indoors
and should be stood upright against the
wall and secured with the chain to
ensure they cannot fall over and
potentially damage or rupture the valve
as we can see here with our valves
exposed you also want to try to get
bottles and i'll go back for a second
that have these protective coverings on
them these are the larger 50-pound
bottles
you'll also notice the smaller bottles
also have those not only does it protect
this from any sort of damage
it can also make for a great area to
lift or to carry these bottles from so
it's dual advantageous now back to our
kind of bottle danger
the area around the tank and cylinder
should be well ventilated if possible
and should be monitored with a carbon
dioxide safety alarm
carbon dioxide tanks and cylinders
should be stored in areas with a
temperature less than
125 degrees fahrenheit which is 51.7
degrees celsius
carbon oxide tanks and cylinders should
always be connected to a reducing valve
or regulator
with a pressure safety valve to prevent
any chance of
leading to an exploding bottle which is
just not
a safe environment for anyone around it
and also they can travel quite a
distance if that regulator was to break
off so it's good to have that carrying
handle slash protector
lastly if you do have a bottle or if you
look at a bottle there will be certain
markings on that model
so this kind of gives you just an idea
of what those what seems like random
numbers kind of a test to and match
and you can take a picture of your
bottle match it up here
to get an idea of what those numbers
actually mean as far as the safety
concerns for your bottle
it is you know good information to be
aware of that they're not just random
numbers
even though they may look like it they
actually can tell you quite a bit of
information
if you know how to read them and of
course here at debacle university
providing with the information for
something you may have taken
granted of earlier now you can develop
that understanding
for just what is on that bottle