on this debaco university video i'm
going to go over using a par meter to
measure light intensity and this is part
of our student series so i'm going to
turn over to students so you can hear
from them the importance of using a par
meter
[Music]
this is a par meter and we use it to
read the light intensity coming off of
our lights and onto the cannabis plants
a lot of people don't see this as an
important
instrument to use in their cannabis grow
because they simply don't understand
that especially with baby clones that
they do not require or need as much
light as the bigger ones do and
typically with lights like these you
could expect them to be a thousand volts
so using a par meter you could see
accurately how much the light will
actually be penetrating each of the
plants so you can see down here
we read at about 330 light intensity
which is a little high for little baby
plants but
regardless
up here we have over 2 000
a reading of over 2 000. now typically
you wouldn't want your reading to be at
300 for clones because they're tiny they
don't need that much light but in our
case we're using clones from outside and
outside of course the light intensity is
much stronger so in certain cases like
this it wouldn't necessarily matter that
it's higher but it is good to have a par
meter so that you can know just how much
light your plants are absorbing