interested in learning more about
actinovate this debaco university video
is for you
to see how it may apply to your given
growing situation
all right let's go over using actinovate
for cannabis production
so first off should define what
actinovate is and activates a biological
fungicide
with this streptomyces active ingredient
what is this
this is a naturally occurring soil
bacterium that was originally isolated
from the roots
of linseed plants in england and
patented worldwide
it has been shown effectiveness in both
indoors and outdoors
in a variety of growing situations we're
going to look at some studies
specifically looking at this product
so the study here i can look at it in
more detail
this is the evaluation of disease
management approaches for powdery mildew
and cannabis
plants looking at actinovate as well as
a couple other things
if you want to look at the study in more
detail so what are the specifics of
this study well paramill divine cannabis
is caused by
a particular fungus it's a fungus that
might be different so keep in mind that
there are different versions of powdery
mildew even though common name
they're all the same powdery mildew of
squash
is different than powdery mildew that
affects uh for example
like your bee bombs or your for example
powdery mildew that affects your lilacs
there's different variants within the
powdery mildew
so to investigate disease management
options biological chemical and physical
approaches were assessed
a patternability susceptible strain was
grown indoors with continuous exposure
to powdery mildew inoculum
to really test the effectiveness of this
product
so here's the data looking at the
control which is basically an unsprayed
control
xero tol is basically like a hydrogen
peroxide
natural fungicide bacteriocyte and then
activate to see how it compares
overall we can see the trends are
that while the control had the highest
levels as would be expected
xerotal had the lowest levels inactivate
fell
somewhere in between sometimes not
statistically different
sometimes statistically different so
what are other what is other research
shown
regarding this product and there's
different forms of activity ag is
considered to be the agricultural type
well previous research has shown that of
ag to be effective at reducing powdery
mildew disease severity compared to
unsprayed controls
but it was ineffective compared to water
control on grape
and compared to both water and unsprayed
treatments it was ineffective at lung
disease incidents
so again we have to take this into
consideration on squash and cantaloupe
actinib alone was not found to reduce
powdery mildew severity compared to the
water control
and the efficacy of actinovate is most
likely due to the antibiotic
and kinase production by the
streptomyces as well as
induction of plant defenses following
the application
however in this study activate did not
provide significant disease reduction
it is not currently registered as
disease control and
on cannabis within canada
so activity applied to candidates for
powdering mildew control
uh however in the study activity did not
provide significant disease reduction
and it's not currently registered as
disease control in cannabis in canada
therefore its likelihood of being used
or its
suggestion to be used is definitely
reduced based on the data
as well as the current registration
restrictions
in given areas so again it's important
to do this study
to determine if the products you're
adding are actually worthwhile are
actually able to reach significantly
reduce
disease to prove that they're worth the
investment in time
to go through and apply them so look
more at specifics of the study they did
look at some other products
they did they do have the materials and
methods listed so this is just one part
of the research to become an educated
grower