so in this debaco university video we're
going to be looking at using plastic
mulch
to suppress weeds in a cannabis field we
can see that in the image right here
where plastic mulch is being utilized
to help cut down on the weeds in between
plants planted in the same row
we'll look at this in more detail here
on this video
[Music]
all right let's get into using plastic
mulch to suppress weeds in a cannabis
field
well first off the benefits of plastic
mold why would we want to select this in
the first place
well it's a long used option worldwide
since the 1960s and it's used mainly
with
mainly with animal annual plants the
goal is to provide weed control
improve plant growth modified soil
temperature retain solid moisture
increase yields
of course this applies more than just to
cannabis it can apply to other plants as
well
sometimes just having onions grown in
plastic mulch can really help increase
their growth compared to those that
might be right next to them in a row
that is left with bare soil
plastic mulch in related to cannabis
production specifically
so when we're looking at plastic mulch
it's a good option if you're starting
with clones
due to their poor ability for cannabis
to initially compete with weed species
also the use of clones does not allow
for the use of post-emergent herbicides
so that's another advantage or reason
why you may want to consider
plastic mulch for your in-row weed
control
addition plastic mulch can increase the
soil temperature allowing for an early
plants to establish quicker
a warm set soil up gets that root zone
temperature a little bit
warmer a little faster which can be
particularly important in the early part
of the season
now the challenges with plastic mulch
because no system is 100 perfect
plastic mulch the removal and disposal
can be labor intensive
and also expensive the general cost of
the material is also potentially cost
prohibitive to some growers
the estimated cost of up to 534 dollars
per hectare
in horticultural systems with a 2.4
meter spacing between bed centers was
observed
we also have to consider the disposal of
that at the end of the season
plastic mulches has waste management
challenges associated with it
so like where do you put all the plastic
mulch after you're
done with it yes it's hard to remove but
then you remove it and the question is
now what so what about recycling our
plastic mulches
well about 90 percent of used plastic
mulch that is
used in the united states mostly ends up
in a landfill
stockpiled or sadly burned it's often
not recycled
due to the limited sites and
contamination during usage
and simply the high cost of transport we
can see some sources listed here as well
as you're always welcome to look in the
description
for a link to sources listed by each
slide
now before you install plastic mulches
growers should be committed to a drip
irrigation method with a fertilizer
injector
simply that's going to make your overall
system much more efficient
since the soil will essentially be
sealed and i put sealed in quotes here
under plastic irrigation it will very
likely be needed so
here we see the drip tape here we see
the drip setup because you're kind of
sealing that environment out and that's
a great thing it's going to be very
efficient any water that
is in there but installing that drip
system will ensure you can irrigate
your plants in addition side dressing
with nutrients is also impeded with
plastic mulch so having a fertigation
system is also advised
however the soil should still be amended
if needed based on a soil test before
the mulch
is applied to the soil don't assume it's
going to cover it with mulch to add a
fruit and gator and it'll be all set
if soil does need a mending you are
recommended to do that before
laying your plastic mulch now the
options when we're looking at plastic
mulch
we want to consider the width how wide
will your rose be
common widths of 36 and 60 inches but
others
options may exist and may better be a
better fit texture wants slick or
embossed
typically the embossed plastic has a
visible pattern on the surface
is more resistant to damage due to
punctures wind fatigue cracking
than compared to non-embossed mulches
also linear low density has a slick
surface appearance
but may have a linear pattern with the
goal to reduce the chance of tears
while in use another option you want to
be concerned of
is the thickness thickness varies from
point six mil to two mil or greater
be sure to use an adequate strength
material and typically a one mil to one
point
uh two five mil embossed plastic is a is
adequate
for most applications and is recommended
despite potential
increase in cost don't want to go too
cheap because you'll be just dealing
with a pain
and a mess to deal with it don't want to
go too
thick because you if you're only using
it for one year you don't necessarily
need to incur
that much of a cost now we also color
choices when it comes to plastic mulches
some of them get really crazy
the most common color option is the
traditional black color
but there are other coloration options
some growers
have the option for white and black
white on black which may be used with
either
side facing upwards depending on the
specific needs so keep in mind
how you utilize these mulches can also
impact potential plant growth
clear mulch is great for warming the
soil but has limited weed suppression
abilities so keep that in mind
aluminum are silver but not gray
reflective mulch reflects solar
radiation and research has shown
it can repel aphids which can spread
viruses
it can also have a cooling effect on the
soil and keep in mind it's aluminum
that's like a reflective
mulch aluminum or silver is not the same
as a gray coloration
some growers get the gray and they think
they're getting this nice aluminum type
color because it has a sort of kind of
gray appearance
but you want aluminum or silver you want
that really highly reflective
material and be sure when you're
applying this it's a cloudy day and
still
you are highly recommended to wear
sunglasses it's very very bright
other cold mulches as we see here may
affect plant growth in the positive ways
but more research needs to be done
in regards to cannabis so i can see it's
a whole wide range of colors
traditional black or silver is typically
what's recommended
lastly we're looking at the equipment to
go through with what we're looking at
committing to plastic mulches
you want to be mindful of your field
prep so you want to make sure your field
is
all set to go before you're considering
doing mulches you want to have a mulch
layer with drip irrigation wheel we can
see that right here
and then ideally at the end of the
season a mulch lifter can make the
laborious task of removing that
much much easier so again you can see
there's a lot of equipment especially on
the large scale
a lot of commitment to this mulch but
there is a lot of equipment simply
because it is pretty widely used
for the reasons mentioned here but also
keep in mind some of those drawbacks to
see if
is this the best fit for your
environment