all right welcome to this tobacco
university video you're going to be
talking about using crispr
cas9 and marker assisted technologies
for cannabis breeding this is kind of a
very precise way a
way a methodology that's being refined
to specifically target certain sequences
within a dna
to splice genes out or add genes that
growers may be deeming desirable
so first off what is this crispr cast 9
well crispr
crispr is short for clustered regularly
interspaced short palindromic repeats
this is a system that evolved as an
adaptive immune response in bacteria in
archaea to defend against invading
viruses this is something that occurs in
nature
it allows the bacteria to essentially
keep a genetic record of invading viral
dna
to allow for a speed up and response
time to render a virus
inactive so it's actually an
evolutionary genetic kind of improvement
for bacteria to be able to recognize
foreign viral dna
and counteract it at a quicker rate this
technology though can be applied to
plants breeding
by allowing for a specific gene loci to
be targeted for gene
alteration responsible for specifically
turning a sequence and adding in genes
we may again deem desirable
so what's the use for crispr well we're
looking at crispr breeding processes
that are assisted with crispr
technologies may benefit from the
reduction the time to develop a new
cultivar
it's a really great targeted method for
being able to go through the process
of gene editing and as a result this can
allow for
a quicker development of a cultivar
instead of through traditional breeding
so what are marker assisted technologies
well there's a kind of a couple here
that i'll be covering
with isotime variation rflp pcr
in microsatellites i'll be at least
providing you with a little bit of
background it's a brief overview
of each of these within this video
lecture so let's start with
kind of where do we get this information
from it's always good to cite your
sources and we see here
a reference article that you're welcome
to go through and provide you with the
reference link to copy the first page in
a direct link
welcome to go and take a look at this if
you want to learn even more information
than is presented here so starting with
the first one that i mentioned isozyme
variation so maybe something you're
probably not familiar with per se maybe
something that's not very common and
understandably so
but isozymes are basically protein
markers this technique is based on the
principle that allelic variations exist
for many different types of proteins
this uses a simple process of making a
crude protein extract from some tissue
sources
usually leaves that are separated by gel
electrophoresis
the disadvantage though is a number of
isozyme loci that can be
scored is limited it's kind of a
limiting form of technology and
different source tissues will provide
different results
so it may not necessarily be repeatable
amongst the whole plant
as a result this is rarely used today in
favor of what i'm going to talk about
next rflps which you may still see some
instances
particularly old studies where this was
utilized
so this rflps what does that stand for
that's looking at what's called
restriction
fragment length polymorphism this is a
molecular marker based on differences in
the genomic dna level these rflp markers
are defined by a specific enzyme probe
combination
that identifies one single locus at a
time and utilizes agarose gel
separation the disadvantages of using
rflps is that
genomic clones that are represented
sequences at random
are poor choices as hybrisation probes
because plant genomes consist of a large
percent of repeated sequences
and those repeated sequences can cause
issues in the sense that there's
not necessarily 100 all unique dna
amongst the whole length
this has not been widely used for hemp
compared to other crop species
simply because of this evidence that
there is a lot of repeating units
so it makes this technique a little less
effective
then we get to pcr which again stands
for polymix chain reaction
uh something we might hear about uh more
where a common technique been around for
quite a number of years
and this is the restriction digest of
genomic dnas followed by a pcr
amplification of the fragments obtained
this uses labeled primers that anneal to
the ends of the fragments the needle
something means to attach to
having a variable number of extra
nucleotides randomly chosen so to
amplify
only a subset of the total fragments is
obtained it's really looking at that
targeted kind of genetic sequence
the labeled amplification products are
run through a polycriminal gel
and then are separated so you kind of go
through you have this long piece of dna
you're looking for a certain gene
you have these certain primers that are
targeting a specific sequence of that
whole gene as we can see right here
we go through this cycle many many times
during many copies if that
targeted sequence is there and we run it
through a gel to separate
out again visually confirm its presence
or where it may
be within that dna sequence meaning if
there was a lot of products you're going
to see a very darkened bar there
indicating a lot of
dna at that particular base pair
length then lastly here we have
something called microsatellites so
what's the microsatellites referring to
well these are short sequences of two
three or more nucleotides that are
represented from a variable number of
times
in a genome in general one single locus
is identified by each pcr reaction
but the number of alleles that can be
identified is very high
as the very variability in the repeated
motif
number is high in the plant genomes so
only recently identified and used for
cannabis is kind of like the new and
emerging technology
microcellulic markers were the most
useful in describing the
hemp germoplasm so as a result from the
studies showing
or indicating that these micro
satellites show greater promise
this is what's being considered to maybe
be utilized
more going forward at least for cannabis
simply because of the many repeated
units
that tend to exist so pcr is still
involved but not just using pcr
utilizing these kind of short sequences
these micro satellites for example here
to look for these repeats there and
shows a lot of promise looking at hemp
and can be a great way to potentially
look at breeding cannabis and knowing an
understanding of cannabis with greater
detail
going forward