if you're considering adding sugar to
help your canvas plants grow
this debaco university video is for you
[Music]
all right let's look at using
supplemental sugar for cannabis
production
you might say sugar we're not talking
about candy per se but you kind of get
the idea
so as always here's a reference article
if you want to look at researching
on sugar applications to crops may not
be necessary 100 specific to cannabis
but does
allow some information we can start to
build some potential conclusions from
so first off here is their results from
their study they did a
foliar sugar treatments comparison here
and we could see that their untreated
check
grain sugar cane high fructose corn
syrup molasses blackstrap molasses green
layered cane sugar
granulated cane sugar 100 sucrose and
again blackstrap molasses looking at
different kind of application rates
and we're kind of seeing the soybean
yield in bushels
per acre kind of presented here so again
we're all looking at soybeans but we can
see there's not
necessarily a clear winner
here in comparison so we need to keep
that in mind
now we're looking at sugar where it
would be benefits to sugar well
ladybiddies
consuming sugar increased the survival
rate of the females and resulted in
increased egg production
as compared to beetles who were not
provided sugar in their diets
kind of an interesting finding there the
researchers suggested sugar
feeding is very important for lady
beetle populations and a possible way to
help maintain beneficial species in
an agro-ecosystem lady beetles stayed
about 20 to 30 percent
longer in plots where sugar water was
applied
than untreated plots in the first four
to six hours after spraying a sugar
solution
lady beetles and the sugar-treated
plants rose by a factor of 10 to 20.
so kind of an interesting thing here
we're maybe not seeing a change in the
plants
but we're trying to increase and
maintain our beneficial
on insect populations well this may have
some potential merit
so plant defense signaling related to
sugar in rice so we're looking at
rice production sugar sugar applications
to the root system resulted
in overexpression of genes in which
induced defense mechanisms within the
plant
again here we're looking at rice
spraying sugar solutions and plants via
boiler in solar drenches resulted in
half the disease pressure
that is in the control plants one week
later so kind of an interesting finding
here
looking at the changing and gene
regulation in rice plants
15 days later control plants exhibited
severe disease compared to the
sugar-treated plants suggesting
foliar applications of sugar prior to an
attack by a plant pathogen
could signal plant defense response
responses
resulting in increased plant resistance
to that particular pathogen
the researchers also went on to note
that all plants were at the
four leaf stage during research and were
curious if they induced resistance
would continue as the plants matured so
it definitely shows potential promise at
least in rice
for the early application might be
something worth considering
for cannabis production as well
particularly that early application
before you're getting into your buds and
flowers so
why not apply it to cannabis though
research has shown no statistical
difference among sugar sources when
applied to corn or soybeans with no
statistical
increase numerous research studies have
documented increase in beneficial
insects and fields and plus treated with
sugar water solution
station application of the solution as a
bio control method reducing pest
populations
so for example if you have aphids and
want to increase your lady beauty
beetle population well sugar might be a
worthy addition
particularly in those early stages of
growth well as
yet much research to be done sugar does
play an important role in inducing plant
defense responses and recent studies
have shown reduced disease levels in
rice after application of sugar
prior to pathogen infection so again
just another consideration there
is it going to be a catch-all save all
no but does that have some potential
benefits
yes if those benefits match your growing
situations then it might be worth
considering adding to your cannabis
plants