here on this debaco university video
we're going to be looking at
manual weeding methods to suppress weeds
in a cannabis field
[Music]
so something probably all done at one
time or another but we're going to look
at using manual methods to suppress
weeds in a cannabis field here
so first off manual weeding is this can
be the most effective weeding method
to be very precise however it does
require the most
time and also the most labor which can
make it prohibitive
in certain systems now increasing the
effectiveness of
manual weeding growers should have a
regular schedule when it comes to manual
weeding
depending on the weed pressure the
frequency
will be determined based on that going
more than seven day days though between
weeding events is not advised especially
early in the season
when high soil moisture and low plant
densities may make it more
weeds more aggressive to get established
and to
propagate now i'm going to watch the
weather when we're looking at
manual weeding because often rainstorm
rain rainstorms will delay
when weeding can be done so when in
doubt weed before a potential storm
even if it's before your planned day so
because it's soil being very heavy
being very wet and waterlogged can make
it a challenge to go through and weed
and it's also going to encourage
potentially more weeds to germinate and
grow
now what's the ideal time of day to weed
well well any time you can do it really
is best the
ideal time is actually the morning just
after sun up
this way any weeds removed will have
roots exposed to the hot portion of the
day
this will increase the odds of
desiccation weeding at sunset the weeds
may be able to re-root overnight
reducing your time efficiency this can
be because if you're just kind of
leaving some weeds in the field not
removing them
off site in a separate pail or a
container if you're just kind of going
through the loophole
it can be one way can be effective but
you want to do that typically more in
the morning
it's not advised that you actually till
your soil and this is not an
advised method because growers will
often run a tiller
to bury the weeds or that's what they
think however what growers may not
realize is that they are actually
bringing up or tilling up new weed seeds
and really not fixing the problem
just encouraging a repeatingness of that
problem
now if you simply go through and cut the
weeds this is called creating a sterile
seedbed
and you're removing the weeds that
germinate and slowly killing all the
available
weed seeds to reduce the pressure at
least ideally
as the season progresses now looking at
this sterilized seed bed i have a
separate video on this
and you're welcome to search the channel
for that topic so you can learn a little
bit more
about how that may fit your particular
growing system