so this tobacco university video is
going to be looking at some
physical barriers when it comes to weed
suppression
[Music]
let's get into using physical barriers
to manage weeds in a cannabis field
so often this is cost prohibitive on the
large scale
why while it does create a great look to
the field does create a very clean field
it does require a lot of material it's
best suited for smaller
and closer in-row spacing fields not
only do you need the material but you
also need kind of ways to kind of hold
it down so the wind doesn't blow and
carry
it away so these needs to be tucked in
by bearing the edges
here we're seeing a bunch of stone
weights or
cinder blocks or pellets all those need
to be established
well so that you're not damaging the
plants if the wind was to kind of shift
or
move that but it does once established
create a very clean field and really
eliminates any chance of
weeds popping up in this clean field
that i've talked about
if a physical beer is used for the
plantings of rose it's also the walking
path can be essentially
created to a clean field that will
reduce the soil splash and possibly
reduce disease as well again it needs to
be established it needs to be held in
place very well
so you're not having giant holes so
you're limiting areas where potential
for weeds can grow but this also reduces
any soil splash in your walking rows as
well
really helps keep your plants very clean
for high traffic areas if your field has
a high traffic using a physical barrier
creates a carpet-like effect to reduce
the chance of workers
carrying soil particles from one area to
another
and this can help reduce the transfer
soil based diseases
which can be of concern particularly on
larger growing applications
here we see typically garden months are
grown in this way and they're grown in
containers
so this doesn't necessarily mean when
using a physical barrier the plants have
to be physically planted in the soil
they can be used with container growing
as well also makes it really easy to
move the plants
throughout and take them and load them
up or move them from one field to
another
so again does offer some benefits but
keep in mind that
initial establishment and upfront cost
can be
drawbacks lastly the timing of the
physical barrier is
also very important at the time of
planting the physical barrier should be
applied at that time
this can be a challenge as it's when
typically growers are the most busy
this will help increase the
effectiveness and reduce the
frustrations preventing it from shifting
during the season
a lot of times growers want to just
plant all their plants then go back
later and add their physical barrier
sometimes even the best intentions don't
really get fulfilled
also if you're planting a large scale
planting and your initial plants are
growing
it can make it very difficult to go
through and kind of re-add that
barrier almost as we see here here when
the plants are small if everything's
tucked in and established
as those plants now grow and get larger
they're taking full advantage of that
use
of the physical barrier keep in mind by
looking at your physical barrier
they can last for different periods of
time some
are more porous than others so take this
into consideration as well
when you're if you're selecting a
physical barrier which one is the best
fit
for your application