as the name implies herbicides are used
to manage weeds
so utilizing them in a large field or
even a small scale
is an option we want to be mindful and
cautious
of how to best utilize them if it's an
option that we are considering
here on debaco university we're going to
provide you with some information about
using herbicides to manage weeds
in a cannabis field
with any method of weed control you
should research it fully so here if
you're considering herbicides
we're going to get into some of the
specifics here and relate it to
cannabis so first off you always want to
check with your current state laws
and your regulations make sure
what you're looking at is also current
for the growing year
because just as it was current last year
doesn't mean it's going to be current
this year so you want to be mindful of
that you're following the current
laws and regulations i provided a link
here
uh the connecticut has provided some
guidance relating to assortment of
pesticides for hemp and medical
marijuana production
so this can be used as a guide if you're
not from connecticut to kind of
get an idea of what some options may be
or what some of the rules
laws and regulations may look like now
often this is a limited
list when in regards to cannabis common
active ingredients
incur occur a few listed here
maybe some name brands that you might be
familiar with i know avenger
very commonly used for because it is
omri certified
for most weeds grasses and broad leaves
you can use 20
vinegar citric acid corn gluten there
are a lot of options
but it might be a limited list compared
to what some other chemicals
that might be implemented or utilized in
other production methods
now herbicides caution is just in
general so this is just in general
know what weed or weed species are the
main target
to say i want herbicide to kill
everything maybe you're trying to target
a particular
weed species watch for potential drift
the finer the droplets made the further
they will travel
in wind events physically a physical
spray barrier is great when row applying
especially if there's crops present
keep in mind also of any signage you may
have to be posting
as well as the wind and timing of your
application
be sure you have different nozzles if
you're looking especially at a large
scale make sure your pressure is
regulated these are all just general
things when spraying anything
but in particular with herbicides so
we're looking at herbicides
we're looking also at when is it quote
rain fast
and when we say rain fast that means
stuck to the actual leaf this is
important particularly for outdoor
production
they might have dew coming in or rain
events typically a hot and dry morning
is the best application time when the
plant will be kind of
the weeds plant will be starting to grow
a little bit more aggressively and that
may make your herbicide application more
effective
and also the rainfast time allowed to
adhere to the leaf bind to the leaf
and reduce the chance of it running off
for some common
products here you can see a whole list
in the hours until rain passed some
taking six to eight hours
some rain fast and basically one or
potentially less than one
so again just a little comparison here
if you know the particular product
you're using how many hours until it's
rained fast here not that you want to
play the line
but just good information to be aware of
so in regards to canvas production
even if you're going to consider using
herbicides and they are permitted
you want to limit spraying to early part
of plant development particularly the
veg
side of the growing cycle you want to
avoid late season applications as this
could easily cause it to enter
the plant and show up in potential
quality tests
causing your end product to potentially
fail inspection so again
if you are using herbicides even if they
are improved approved
favor applying them early in the season
to reduce the chance of your end product
failing any sort of inspection
uh last one we're looking at herbicides
where would we utilize them well they're
commonly used to prevent
weeds from growing up fences they're
also economies to prevent
a shortening of electrical fences so in
this example or this case this might be
far from your actual plants
and this is why it's important to be
considered of potential for drift
so even if you're not applying them next
to or in row
this is another very common application
where they're made
just be mindful of drift and potential
barriers or distances you need to be
particularly with growing cannabis