if you've looked at different storage
options for cannabis buds particularly
long-term storage and considered vacuum
sealing
this debaco university video is for you
because we're going to cover
vacuum sealing for storing cannabis buds
[Music]
all right as the image shows here let's
get into vacuum sealing for storing
cannabis buds
so first off this is a good long-term
storage option
of six plus months is what we're talking
when we're talking long term storage
times even a year
later with this method there can be no
noticeable
reduction in potency which is great if
you put all that work into
growing a quality product drying it
curing it you want to make sure you have
a nice good
long term storage option so vacuum
sealers are also very cost effective so
that's another advantage is that the
actual equipment needed
is not all that expensive and can be
used in both large
as well as small scale environments also
applies to more than just cannabis buds
it can be used for other food items as
well it's why they're so common
which is a great option to have however
you do want to avoid the vacuum sealing
bags themselves for cannabis because as
you can see in both of these image while
it does seal the buds very well
the environment created by the bags and
jars is essentially the same
there will be physical damage if you use
the bags basically it's crushing
the structure of those buds however this
will not impact the chemical profiles
that's a good
thing use vacuum sealing jars for
cannabis is advised to preserve the
contents
as well as the physical structure of
those contents
and this is what i'm talking about on
jars you could use either true vacuum
sealing jars or sealable jars
that then you put into a bag and seal it
that way a lot of growers prefer the
bags
they're less expensive they store easier
they may have a chosen jar but it may
not seal quite perfectly
vacuum sealing it will be a great option
because the physical structure will be
preserved because
the buds are protected in the jar but
this may also increase the total storage
area that's required so just keep that
in mind that now probably can't stack
these jars as well as you could have
when they're just their jars themselves
small containers are great to ensure
only small portions are being exposed to
the air and degradation
which will help ensure most of the
harvest will be kept in the ideal
environment
so you want to vacuum seal large giant
containers
because once you break that seal and
open it up you'll be exposing more buds
to the outside environment keep the jars
small kind of what you'll use in a short
period of time it can be a great way to
ensure that the overall total harvest is
preserved very well
mason jars jars in general great option
throw in a vacuum steel bag that way you
know
is definitely isolated from the outdoor
environment to keep your buds
for a very long term which is the goal
here to preserve that harvest
so you can enjoy it well after the
initial point of plant takedown