everyone to learn more about the
vegetative or grow nutrients you see
at grow shops at this tobacco university
video
we'll provide some information just on
that topic
we see some wonderful plants here in the
vegetative stage so vegetative or grow
nutrients for chemist production how do
we utilize those
let's get into that now so veg or grow
nutrients just
in general these are intended to be used
during the vegetative stage again as the
name implies
for plant production but they can also
really be used at any stage of plant
growth
however they tend to have higher levels
of nitrogen to support plant biomass
growth such as the leaves in the stems
and lower levels of phosphorus and
potassium that are needed in greater
amounts during the flowering and later
stages
however that does not mean once you flip
your plants into
flowering stage you'd simply stop using
these nutrients you can continue to
utilize them
because they still can be effective even
later in stages of growth
if used properly so how long should i
veg for
best yield well this may depend on the
strain you're growing and the size of
your growing area
however in general most growers are kind
of vegging for four to six weeks
typically plants will stretch at least
fifty percent after the flip which in
that chance
transition from the vegetative stage to
the flowering stage
photo period so plan accordingly for
your growth space particularly if you're
ceiling height limited
for outdoor growers plants will start
flowering in early july
if you're in the northern hemisphere for
growing if you're growing an autoflower
remember your plant will flower based on
days
old so that may influence when you
fertilize it and what you fertilize it
with
so veg nutrients can be used anytime and
this is something a lot of growers don't
think realize that
many times growers reduce the frequency
or concentration of vegetable
fertilizers
right after flower but typically these
fertilizers can serve as a great base of
feed
feeding program for the entire grow
cycle some veg grow fertilizers do
contain
levels of phosphorus and potassium
anyway so depending on the ratio the
plant needs
many times these fertilizers are a
staple in the growing operation
so don't think just because it says veg
and your plants are in flower
there's going to be some sort of
negative interaction there these
veg nutrients tend to be a more stable
blend
do offer some nitrogen you may have to
adjust the amounts and concentration and
amount of times you use them but again
they can be utilized at the early stages
of growth
as well as the flowering phase as well
and they can help you produce a very
quality
yield