here I'm gonna give the vegetable
production overview which will hold true
for just about any vegetable crops
you're looking to grow overall the goals
to produce high-quality vegetables
efficiently planning is important to
help ensure success of the farm of the
crop and of the vitality of the business
so starting with what is farming I'm
often asked this and this is a pretty
good idea of what farmers have to deal
with and something most people can
relate to it's the game of tetris and
there's always new challenges coming
down and we're trying to find a way to
fit them and make them work for our
given situation we're rewarded then let
me get a line here and we're constantly
trying to keep this as low as possible
even though it seems like problems will
keep mounting higher and higher we try
to find a way to make the puzzle pieces
fit together and keep moving on because
we know there's gonna be another
challenge coming right behind the one we
just dealt with so how do we deal with
this
well the key part is organization and
efficiency organization and agency are
very important and all walks of life but
especially with farming well this is not
my tool wall here this is an example of
highly organized one and it makes it
very efficient standardizing what you do
is in your favor and you want us to know
is what you can so this refers to so
there's certain things it's out of your
control but certain other things that
you are able to control you want to go
through and do that speed quality
increase you want to decrease the cost
here if you've got to grab a certain
size wrench you know right where to go
and get that here the rows are the same
size the same width they have the same
hoops you're not trying to figure out
what hoops go with what row and what
field makes it a lot more efficient that
standard the standard a ssin of your
work it makes it a lot easier overall
and the key part if you do get it in
this organized fashion you want to try
to return those tools into the same area
so you can maintain that efficiency you
don't want to like this one month and
the next month all these tools being on
a scrap bench over on the side so
I'm his money I don't think to say that
I've pretty evident there I always say
you can get more money from the bank but
I still have not found a way how to get
more time so you always have to factor
in your time and I know these sunup to
sundown and then some is kind of the
working hours but you've got a factory
in your time these can't be burning
yourself out certain things that you can
make more efficient and it may cost a
little money initially but it will save
you time in the long mend and planning
is one of those steps so it's very
important to plan have a plan but also
try to be prepared for expected or
common issues but still be able to
adjust the changes on the fly so you
want to be able to observe your crop and
kind of take a look at it and document
we'll talk about planning what you see
what changes that are occurring you want
to plan for issues so here we see good
weed control we see stakes we see
everything pruned right we see
everything trimmed and organized it's
expected but like a quarterback we still
want to be able to come to the line if
we see a defense we didn't expect if we
have an observation that we didn't
initially plan for we don't want to be
able to make changes preventatively and
that's a key aspect of farming and
keeping an idea a plan but being able to
have it not be completely rigid in
adjust to the condition you're seeing at
a particular year seeds in general
vegetable don't get cheap on seeds oh
this is a couple senseless systems a
dollar less per pack there might be a
reason I always feel you need to buy the
highest quality seeds you can they have
good germination rates typically and
they could have disease resistance or
sometimes multiple teeth disease
resistance which can really help you in
season so try to save a couple dollars
here and there on seeds could really
hurt you in the long run if it disease
does to come through and have a buffer
factor I always say don't just buy the
amount of seeds that you need if you
want to have a little bit extra in case
of poor germination rate in case you
have something go wrong in case you have
a flat that falls over I went up a
couple extras just in case and keep in
mind what seeds you are buying in case
you do have success so you can order
those again even though the seed
companies are pretty good about
remembering what you ordered
always good idea just to know for
yourself the exact variety that you
bought these they've changed use the
winter or general offseason to plan it's
kind of hard to plan in the heat of
summer there use that winter that
offseason time when snows on the ground
and everything's frozen up to kind of
make your plan then and in the growing
season you basically following your plan
so have a plan follow the plan and
you'll be surprised how successful you
can be most people don't have a plan and
that's why it's easy to beat most folks
so taking this off season this downtime
where there's not as much going on is
say in the heat of August or July to
develop that plan what worked what
didn't work what I want to do what do
you think I can do well think this time
to plan and your time is valuable
be sure to factor in the time that you
spend I know you may not want to track
the hours to spend per day but remember
the greatest gift you can give someone
is your time because when you give your
time you're giving a portion of your
lights that you'll never get back so I
know you have this downward spiral here
where it seems like there's just not
enough time that they you sure to factor
in your time so you don't get burnt out
in season I know it gets tiring at the
end anyway
keep in mind what you're spending your
time on and if there's a way to do it
more efficiently so you're not quote
wasting your time