okay so here are we looking at the
vegetative growth cycle of cannabis keep
in mind that vegetative state is
focusing mainly on the leaves here and
that ultimately producing any flowers
but producing a plant with good
structure and I can carry itself well
into the flowering state which follows
the vegetative state so first off
vegetative growth of cannabis excluding
root Alice if it receives 16 plus hours
of a continuous light they'll remain in
the vegetative growth phase I deleted
the more light the plant receives the
greater the growth will be and this is
again to some extent because there can
be burning that occurs for example if we
look at nature ferns grow below tall
trees and these ferns need diffused and
reduced light so they're best suited for
that the trees however they're growing
taller and stretching so that they're
able to capture more of the light their
leaves now growing leaves welcome to our
cannabis leaves here the goal is to
provide not only quality leaves but also
while the structure to the plant this is
setting the plant up for the flowering
stage it's going to come after this
vegetative state so we considered one of
the most important phases of a life
cycle because you can determine the
yield at the end so even though there's
no flowers produced if you treat plants
poorly or set them up early in a
vegetative state they will have poor
flower production because they're not
well tuned or prepared well to go under
the stresses of producing flowers this
is why this is often considered one the
most important phases even though it is
not producing any end flowers in order
to maintain these 16 plus or 18 plus
hours of light you do have a quality
timer you need to keep it in the
vegetative growth phase as long as you
see desirable this is where timers could
become important if you're looking at a
timer and you set it to 16 to 18 hours
of light and keep it at that phase you
know change it your plants will continue
to grow under the vegetative growth
phase of the life cycle as soon as you
go through and flip the timers that can
cause them to go into flower or if you
have a timer that malfunctions
that's something ability to keep in iOS
please that can also cause them to go
into flower
prematurely while flowering during the
vegetative cycles so under normal
growing conditions after about 4 to 6 or
so weeks as a vegetative growth
plants will start to exhibit something
called pre flowers it's a male plant it
will produce flowers sooner than a
female plant this is what the male
flowers look like these are the ones you
want to call sooner to prevent any
potential unlight cross-pollination with
a female is where the female pre flower
will look like right here so when we're
looking at the vegetative state yes
we're looking at plant structure yes
we're looking at leaves but there will
be that the initial form of flowers
develop in these are pre flowers these
are not mature in any way these are
showing you though or demonstrating the
gender of the plant that you're looking
at and if you either have female flowers
pre female flowers or pre males ours
as I said the male flowers typically
show up sooner because they're looking
to produce pollen to pollinate the
female vegetative to flowering switch
once pre flowers are observed changing
these plants photo periods to an evening
12 hours of light and 12 hours of dark
will induce the flowering stage if you
keep him under their whole puzzle I'll
continue to grow and expand a little bit
during the flowering stage and get the
buds that you've desire keep in mind
that flipping these plants is advised
after you start to see the pre flowers
it's kind of like your indication that
those plants can make the switch over to
the flowering room