if you're looking at some vegetative or
grow nutrients here on this tobacco
university video
i'll provide you just kind of an example
and go through some of the fertilizers
you might be considering
[Music]
all right let's get into vegetative or
grow nutrient evaluation for cannabis
production
and keep in mind that i'm not sponsored
by any of these companies but these are
just kind of a general review
botanicare very common name the tanacare
pureblend pro grow 3 2
4 fertilizer blend essential elements
are not derived from urea or ammonium
nitrates that's something to take into
consideration
the organic components of pureblend pro
enhance uptake and utilization of plant
nutrients
at least according to the company an
amplified metabolic rate and capacity
enables plants to produce
fruits and vegetables with more minerals
and vitamins
again another statement from the company
here but this is a very common
grow nutrient blend that many growers
may choose to utilize
but then there is also the general
organics so this
is a general hydroponics i should say
floral nutrients seven
four ten be aware of the high potassium
ratio in this fertilizer so if you're
fertilizing for the grow in particularly
you're gonna be looking at the nitrogen
number and that's important but keep in
mind this also has a relatively high
potassium number so take that into
consideration when you're going through
and fertilizing your plants
then we have fox farm here this is a
fox farm grow big liquid concentrate
it's a 644 blend
manufacturer recommendations are all
stated here general feeding heavy
feeding and foliar feeding as well
keep in mind if you are going to do
foliar feeding with any fertilizer not
just this one
you want to apply it to both sides of
the leaves and you don't want to apply
it to plants that are in direct sunlight
because that could
increase the chance of damage so here we
have our
general feeding of two to three
teaspoons heavy feeding of four
teaspoons
again generally follow the recommended
recommendations don't go above because
feeding your plants more
will not necessarily make them grow any
better they have
npk industries so they get their name
from the nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium listed in fertilizers
they have a raw veg a a raw edge b we
can see different ratios listed here
they have a feeding schedule here as
well all these
products are water soluble forms meaning
they're a powder that you'll add to
water
while the company recommends equal parts
realize that there
are concentration differences in these
fertilizers the advantages
you can potentially make modifications
to match
your particular growing situation and
then lastly we have advanced nutrients
which specifically targets the cannabis
industry in their marketing and kind of
all their research
there is a great focus on ph balanced
nutrient lines particularly for
hydroponic production
however keep in mind with advanced
nutrients the products often carry a
premium cost
compared to other nutrients so again
take that into consideration
that when you're looking at applying
nutrients you want to be also
considerate of the cost
that you're going to incur for the
plants that you'll be fertilizing
hopefully this gives you just a couple
companies to kind of look at or consider
or compare again not sponsored by anyone
but just here to provide you with a
little bit of some ideas
for nutrients you might want to consider
during the vegetative
cycle of your plants