okay here investigate ventilation
benefits for plants and it's very
important to keep air circulation and
air movement for your plants and here
we're gonna investigate why that is so
starting with keeping air moving it's
important to have continual air movement
around the plants in nature very still
conditions are rare there's always a
breeze of some kind you have to be on a
sailboat to realize that to the
prevalence wind turbines if you look at
any flag it simply flapping and even the
slightest of breeze so we want to create
or maintain these natural conditions
because this is a much benefit to our
plants so mixing our air high air rises
and that mixing air can lead to thermal
stratification so what that means is
higher is going to rise and that we want
to stay to tend towards the top and cold
air will sink inside it's a tends
towards the bottom so now that is only
to be exchanged between the inside and
the outside but circulation is important
to limit this stratification that could
occur and also to reduce the chance of
disease so rather than at 50 degrees
Celsius appear in 40 down here about 45
kind of mix throughout now should be too
hot for our plants but this just gives
you that idea of having everything
modernized now the carbon dioxide
depletion because plants consume carbon
dioxide and if air is left stagnant it
can become depleted in this carbon
dioxide which can result in negatively
impacting the growth because carbon
dioxide remember the carbon is used for
the sugar production disease now that
help the plant grow but also to maintain
itself and allow the roots to do the
respiration so we want to make sure
we're not depleting our co2 which if air
stagnant that can occur by mixing that
air we're ensuring that there's adequate
co2 hopefully being mixed around the
plant said just it being depleted around
the leaf at surface air circulation
exchange is important typically you have
air exit out the top points of a
structure so this is kind of a grow tent
Harrises an exhaust fan here too the
exhausting air out the top of the
structure and indeed could be coming in
at the lower points the idea is to
remove the hot air and bring in cooler
air
despite air movement ideally the
difference in temperature should be
minimal to reduce plant stress you want
to be exhausting really hot air and
bringing in really cool air because that
can make it very difficult to maintain
consistent conditions
for your plan the goal is to have about
85 I'm sorry about 75 to 80 degrees
Fahrenheit for your plants during the
day and you can cool it down to 65 to 70
or so Fahrenheit at night and that fresh
air intake but again make sure the air
is evenly dispersed in the room and the
temperature does not cause shock to the
plants you want to be extremely hot or
extremely cold and you do want to be
kind of evenly dispersed so it's gonna
change where you place intake or exhaust
valves keeping in mind you don't want to
go through that high temperature shock
so be not on a stress potentially to
your heating and cooling system but also
the plants you're trying to grow your
ducting the goal is to avoid harsh
angles when you do have ducting so here
we have a carbon filter we don't have a
lot of right angles or 180 degree loops
or bends one to have efficient air flow
so it's not always possible to run a
complete straight line but you could see
here I've maintained kind of a straight
of a line as I possibly can if you have
too many bends in it that's going to
increase the air resistance and reduce
your efficiency so this carbon filters
towards the front of the tent here it's
exhausting out the middle so it was just
a gentle Bend here as it goes out of the
ducting target growing conditions we're
looking at 75 to 85 degrees Fahrenheit
during the day night times 65 to 70 and
that 50 to 60% humidity or so is what
you're generally targeting for your grow
room and moving air on plants this is
important because it helps keep the
plants strong we kind of having them
sway in the breeze a little bit that can
help keep them rigid and stronger
instead of getting really leggy
I can also help reduce disease from
preventing moisture from building up in
certain areas minimize thermal
stratification which is great because
you'll have an even temperature at the
top and bottom of your plants it can
allow us co2 to be mixed to help prevent
starving plants of the vital carbon now
mixing of this air can be large fans if
you're in a smaller operation this
little six inch tin we're in a small
grow tent this may be enough to keep
your plants nice and happy