okay in this lecture series I'm going to
show you some identifications for
verticillium well so you can determine
if you're seeing this in your grow
operation so the identification will
sasso low-born fungus ii survive for
four to fifteen years depending on
conditions well makes this a little
concerning is that either even under
unfavorable conditions verticillium can
last for four years and under more
favorable fifteen how it will look on
the leaves to kind of get this kind of
house belief kind of turns yellow
ultimately curling and getting a little
bit of burn associated with it
another microscopes got this instinctive
cluster like look with these circles
almost like grapes at the kind of
appearance though that occurs now we're
to look for Britta silly Molly well
first off you want to inspect the roots
because this is soil borne however in
addition to that if you have a plant
that suspected of having this you can
cut the stem on the plant that's thought
to be infected is recommended the reason
why this is because this is a vascular
disease so let us enter the root goes
through the vascular system and though
it can be discoloration found as we see
here resumed can infect the xylem of the
plant as little as 24 hours ago a very
quick and aggressive fungus wilting may
only occur on part of the plant and it
can be vascular system specific what
this means is it may only enter a
portion of the xylem indicating half the
plant will kind of wilt the other half
will look just fine
this shows kind of this specificity of
this disease that can occur rather does
the whole plant going down if it only
gets into one particular bundle of xylem
only a portion of the plant they wilt
and if you cut the plant may see these
distinctive rings and that's again
indication potentially of having
verticillium well how to prevent it well
the fungus can survive and so for long
periods with or without plant material
present so that's really not good news
for growers know your chosen media
source make sure it's reliable and newly
open containers is strongly encourage
mean don't be reusing or having very old
containers hanging around Bavarian law
prevention is also the only reliable
method of control for this fungus this
kind of gives you an idea what it'll
take under the microscope
how to control it well there is limited
control once affection occurs sorry
there's no real good news there
something the sites may help but it
should not be really relied upon for a
cure for this problem again it shows you
a little bit kind of the leaf the leaf
structure we'll have a look and we'll
yellow and if you do put into that
standard typically we'll see that Brown
region because it is transported through
the xylem which is in the vascular
system of the plant so well there's no
great control prevention is the name of
the game with verticillium wilt