hey hero and talk about viruses and how
they relate to plants and while this is
a very broad category I'm gonna try to
single out couple things to focus in on
one here being kind of a mottled look to
the leaves it's an example of what one
virus tobacco mosaic looks like so what
is why it's not easy to identify is
there's many different viruses that can
cause different visual symptoms to
mention here the modeling is one but
this isn't true for necessary all
viruses also the virus itself can only
be seen with an electron microscope or
other very extremely fine viewing mic
microscopes your traditional light
microscope that you may have used to
look at cells in say a biology class
will not be able to see viruses they are
extremely extremely small this
indication here is zero point two
micrometers extremely small viewing so
you have to use very specialized
equipment to go to puzzle identify the
virus itself now we're to look typically
you'll see a model look to the leaves
even though there are some variability
but model look is one relative
consistency across many different
viruses also viruses often do not kill
the plant entirely but they can reduce
the yields and cause visual
characteristics that develop these
leaves should be nice even coloration
and we can see that model look
definitely evident here and here in
canvas we see kind of one portion being
kind of that weird kind of coloration
look to it how to prevent it well
prevention of the vectors insects and
tools is important agents are very
common virus vector or carrier in gaad's
spreading through an entire grow
facility very quickly also smoking
tobacco in a growth area is not advised
as the smoke can transmit tobacco mosaic
virus so a lot of times we'll see no
milk no smoking signs in tobacco fields
which may seem kind of counterintuitive
but it's because of the fear of tobacco
mosaic which can translate transmitted
through the smoke of the cigarette here
for control since virus there's only DNA
wrapped in a protein coat there's really
nothing to kill you can really kill a
virus codes that this is very living to
begin with so control does not have to
do with the virus particles but those
things that may transmit the particles
the things that make area so a way to
prevent
virus infection to go back would be to
prevent acids or control your Asians
which is an insect not as a virus itself
but that's vectoring that virus particle
and also yourself or tools that may come
from an infected area try to clean those
sterilizers in a way to kind of limit
that potential unwanted
cross-contamination from a virus
infected plant to another plant you
yourself should be mindful simply
dipping your hands in milk is one way
growers for tobacco fields have been
able to reduce the spread of virus so
all things to consider because once you
get it well may not kill the plant it
definitely will have a negative impact
on the plant plants performance