on this debaco University video I'm
going to go over the difference between
a virus and a viroid so you can
understand the difference in the
distinctions between these two which are
typically used as interchangeable terms
when they shouldn't
[Music]
all right let's go over virus versus
viroid and what the actual difference is
we can see visually there's a large
difference the virus here and the viroid
here of the simpler image because it is
a simpler molecule
so starting with a virus probably what
you're more familiar with or at least
have heard more of it's basically a
nucleic acid wrapped in a protein coat
that could be a DNA molecule or an RNA
molecule a virus is an infectious agent
consisting of segmented uh this nuclear
nucleic acid again I said DNA or RNA
could be single stranded or could also
be double-stranded DNA or RNA kind of a
unique feature to viruses and that
protein coat is the surrounding
protective structure for a virus viruses
cannot replicate by themselves they need
a host cell to infect to change the
Machinery to get the cell to make more
virus particles so that host cell that
could be a plant cell that could be an
animal cell components of those are
needed to assemble and produce new
viruses now viruses don't have a single
shape we can see here this uh some
examples here we could see some have a
very straight shape like tobacco mosaic
virus some very alien-like in some of
the very spherical some can look like a
bullet shaped all different morphologies
now going on to a viroid they are very
simple now when I say simple they're one
of the most simple structures uh we know
of they're 50 to 80 times smaller than
the smallest viral genomes right now
currently virus are the smallest known
infectious agents that mainly cause
these diseases in plants so not too much
of an animal Factor here they are
free-floating a piece of circular
genetic information and they're very
very small in size so small they can
only be seen here with it as an electron
microscope as these images depict
now comparison between our viruses and
our viroids is kind of put a couple key
differences here viruses are small and
simple but virus are smaller and even
more simple is a great way to think
about it viruses do have that protein
coat they have nucleic acids infections
to all organisms plants or animals and
thyroids have no protein coat they are
mainly composed of RNA as far as their
nucleic acids are concerned and they are
in effect mainly in only plants that we
know of viruses again a little brighter
broader Host range and a little bit more
complexity even though they're still
very simple compared to a cell
now also I want to keep in mind this is
a key distinction is that this is the
appropriate time to use the word strain
when referring to viruses the variants
the strains we shouldn't be referring to
cannabis as a strain that is really
reserved for the viral
um
taxonomy and way of naming things strain
really we should be using cultivar or
variety we're talking about plants
strains should be preserved to viruses