now if you're looking to determine the
peak harvest of your cannabis plants
this debaco university video is going to
give you three main plant components to
be looking at
to determining that peak harvest time
[Music]
all right let's get into visually timing
a canvas plant's peak harvest
now three things you should be looking
at within the plant would be the stigmas
the trichomes and the size and
development of the actual flower or bud
now each of these will be briefly
covered in this video however if you
want to learn about any of these
in more detail there'll be a separate
video that will go into showing you some
examples visually
as well as providing descriptions for
each of these plant parts
so those stigmas trichomes and size and
development all focus
really on that main flower and bud and
looking at some of the details
that look at the development of that
butter flower
so first off the stigmas so a female
part
of the flower is the stigma it is it is
sticky
where the pollen would land and start
the fertilization process
but our goal in cannabis is to not have
those plants be fertilized
in canvas this structure looks like kind
of fine white fuzzy structures
that kind of resemble a whisker this is
because there
this is a area that would try to go out
and try to like capture
a pollen grain that might be floating in
the air it could easily grab on and get
stuck into here
and then go through and pollinate that
said flower that's where they have those
like fine hair like appearance that's
right they're sticky so we have a random
pollen grain kind of floating through if
it was still land here
be stuck and go through that
fertilization process
another plant structure the trichomes
and this is often used as the main kind
of
sense of is the flower ready what are
trichomes where they are small
mushroom-shaped glands that are
responsible for producing cannabinoids
as well as terpenes for the plant they
coat the surface having
resin provides a frontline defense
against
fungus insects and hungry herbivores so
they are a protection
mechanism of plants in general but they
also are the site of cannabinoid terpene
production
which is advantageous for cannabis
and lastly we have just the general bud
size and development
on a plant where there will be
variability in buds in the plant the
goal is to produce
large and dense buds consistently on a
plant which can be influenced by a light
exposure to the buds this is why there's
different pruning strategies
implemented to try to maximize that bud
size development and also density
to maximize this production uh pruning
styles play a role
in this final product particularly for
indoor growers that have limited or
direct light sources so putting them so
that they're exposed more of those buds
are exposed to the higher intensity
light
will help increase the size development
and density
and ultimately the quality of the final
product that you're producing