in this debacco University video we're
going to look at visual triome
evaluation to determine Peak Harvest
Time utilizing images uh from students
in my class as we can see located right
here to try to investigate tricomes and
give a grower Viewpoint so you can best
relate it to potentially something that
you might be able to see
[Music]
yourself all right let's get into
looking different's favorite structure
the Tricom
so first off why should we even look at
the tricomes well remember tricomes
provide an indication of the plant's
ripeness and cannaboid and turpine
concentrations visual evaluations which
be provided here may not provide the
exact number but it can indicate when
the greatest concentrations of these
compounds are likely to occur in the
plant a plant sample chemically analyzed
is the best method in providing with a
certificate of analysis though this is a
time timec consuming and costly so out
of the reach for most Growers so the
visual inspection can get very close to
Peak Harvest with minimal cost helping
Growers maximize production can also
help Growers utilizing the chemical
analysis for when they should sample
their plants to be submitted for their
certificate of analysis so we got our
different tricomes well the bulbus ones
are the smallest ones you really need an
aid to be seen yes we can kind of make
them out here and a little bit here uh
but they're very difficult because of
their size to be seen they can
synthesize cannabits and derpin so just
because they're small doesn't mean
they're not contributing um they can
swell in size once they fill with oil
the cesil ones are the larger than the
bulbous ones but still hard to see with
the naked eye they develop early about
on 3 we old plants or so so they can be
seen quite early however the stocked um
glandular capitate tricomes are the ones
most Growers are focusing on they are
the large ones they can be seen with the
naked eye and they're the prize troms
that appear during flowering and but
they are also because of their stocked
nature most likely to get damaged as
well so what are we looking at what are
we actually looking at when we look at
their Tricom an individual infloresence
here with majority of the organs covered
with stocked gland or tricomes the arrow
right here indicates the cluster of
kales and and bra covered with those
tricomes B is looking at a darkfield
micrograph of stock or tricomes
protruding from the KX of the epidermis
biosynthesis of secondary metabolites
occurs in the secretory disc cells
lining the base of the globular triome
head and the metabolites are stored in
the clear portion here at the top here
um and they will turn milky white to
Brown over the course of the flower
maturity which we'll see in the images
coming up the graphic illustration here
for stock triome structure giving some
idea of kind of the uh locations of
different cells and differentiated cells
I should say within that stocked
triome so we look at the color
differences these are distinctive clear
cloudy and Amber so clear you can think
of it as being quote unquote empty and
basically not ready for Harvest if you
can see right through it quote there's
nothing in there then we get the CL CL
ones and those are increased levels of
cannaboids as well as tpin and the Amber
ones are current are the converting in
this stage uh desirable compounds into
maybe changing to less desirable
compounds basically becoming a little
bit quote overripe in some cases um
there so we're really looking for this
cloudy to Amber kind of range uh there
all right so can we use the pistols you
know I know we're going to talk focus on
the tricomes but can we look at the
pistols well pistols can provide a quick
guide but this is really the tricomes
where the cannabinoids and Turpin are
stored so this is the plant part that
should be absorbed with attention to
detail typically recommend to use the
pistols as kind of just a quick
indication quick way to kind of look at
the flowers um as you're going down a
row or looking at a plant but really
kind of drives the oh wait those look a
little more of the ambery color let me
now Look at the tricomes this will be a
little bit variety and genotype
dependent but the pistols can be used as
an indication but we really want to use
the tricomes as the final determination
of whether we should be harvesting
something or not and again pistols
located here tricomes are those clear
Wiest structures located right next to
the leaf surface so the traditional
method of course is use a loop it works
great and still recommended but it can
be hard to really share what's seen you
know it's really hard for me to kind of
have a loop look at something and then
can I give the loop to someone else and
have them look at it um so kind of you
got to develop the eye you got to get
really up close and personal with it it
takes a little getting used to um
however there is something called the
maxi camera again not sponsored by them
in any ways a student had brought one of
these in and we us utilized it in class
and you'll see some images from that
it's a compact handheld camera
microscope that can connect an
electronic device allowing you to live
to kind of see what's going on and to
capture those
images so these are actual images uh
from class I teach uh at the University
of Connecticut these were taken of the
Abacus plants uh from class in weeks 6
to 8 of flower with the help of a
student Maxi camera and Thanks goes out
to aarin for the use of that um so you
could be able to capture some of these
images you're seeing this is a
macroscopic look of what one of the buds
looked like and now we're going to take
a little bit more of that zoomed in
version there of the triome
structure so first off the pistols that
I just talked about well we don't want
to use them for indication they can
contain tricomes so there are still some
tricomes that have developed on the
pistols these are not the ones really to
focus on not all triom contain the
desirable compounds the amber brown
color of the pistol here um is an
indication that this flower is nearing
Harvest time but is the inspection of
the tricomes that really makes the final
decision and wi the
Harvest so here we see kind of mostly
clear Tricom so close but not yet the
stock capitate tricomes can be seen
however most are clear indicating that's
too early to harvest there are some
initial kind of cloudy tricomes but
overall population must be taken into
consideration and most of them are clear
in nature there so a little too early
but good to start
looking now the previously clear are
basically now turning cloudy as we can
see that right here this indicates an
increase in the amount of canabo the
plant is producing and we're nearing
that point of harvest there so this is
kind of an exciting time uh good time to
kind of prepare the plant for that final
area there that final Harvest that's
coming very soon now note I've had put
some purple Arrow highlights that some
are having these purple colorations
um to the stocks now this is mainly
genetics and um that cause this and not
environmental factors so it is possible
for the grower to enhance the color
based on various plant stressors
temperature light spectrum and light
intensity are a couple of those that can
enhance this but really has to come from
the genetics at least initially and some
are more apt to produce more purple
coloration uh than some other varieties
again this is mainly
Abacus so those purple concentrations
again you can see on the macroscopically
as well as kind of almost
microscopically here this is a sign of
anthocyanin production this is a water
cble pigment in that in a larger class
of compounds known as flavonoids that's
a major category this is a subset of
that category while anecdotal some
people have reported better symptom
relief with um in the presence of
anthocyanins so something to consider um
if you're looking uh you know different
varieties and you kind of see some that
purple coloration anthocyanins might be
something you want to look at as an a
certificate of analysis report now Peak
cloudiness as we kind of see here um
this would be the earliest recommended
Harvest but typically the goal is to see
a few ambers before harvesting this is a
sign that we're just almost quite there
um and we could see again that high
concentration those cloudy tricomes
there again that camera does a really
good job of really zooming in and
allowing you to see what I can see
through a loop but to convey it to you
here on an image and then lastly here
these are the first ambers being see
this be the Harvest point we could see
that here and here and this really
indicates that probably this would be
the best time or the optimum time um to
harvest when you just just start the
first go in Amber if you're starting
with a new variety go ahead and um
Harvest at this time can Harvest some a
little earlier a little bit later and
pretending what compounds you're looking
for that may indicate your exact time of
harvest we looking for a general
recommendation you see a first couple
start to turn Amber Harvest it um and
use that as your gauge Point uh going
forward hopefully this helped you with
some real world images to see triome
development share with you with some of
the students had grown um and hope you
appreciated those images