you're noticing your plant doesn't look
quite right hopefully this debacco
University video can provide you a great
visual guide to fol your symptoms of
nutrient deficiencies in cannabis plants
to help you identify the issue that
might be going
[Music]
on all right let's get into the visual
guide here fol your symptoms and help
provide you a diagnosis as well a
potential way to correct the issue so
first off some of these images are based
off the research article here if you
want to get into the research article in
more detail I provide the citation here
so you can do so now just some general
reminders is that nutrient mobility in
the plant for mobile nutrients they move
to New Growth areas that means
deficiency symptoms will first be seen
in older leaves in comparison to
immobile nutrients that don't move to
New Growth these deficiencies will be
first seen in the newer growth regions
of the plant we're talking about
classifying nutrients our primary
nutrients are nitrogen phosphorus and
pottassium and they contribute to plant
nutrient content uh function of plant
enzymes and biochemical processes and
integrity of plant cells your secondary
nutrients are your calcium your
magnesium and your sulfur and these are
needed in smaller amounts uh than the
primary nutrients leading us finally to
micronutrients which are necessary for
plant survival but are needed in very
small micro quantities when we look
about fertilizers um chated or kated
fertilizers are preferred since it will
enhance nutrient uptake and improve
efficiency and utilization and the goals
plant available nutrients and some of
them also are better applied Folly so
keep in mind if you can find a cated
form of a nutrient that is definitely
the way to go now nutrient
classifications just providing at this
table here we look at our nutrients
whether it's a macro or a micro the
uptake form and chemical form and ions
its mobility in the plant in the soil a
lot of people forget we're going to
focus of course on the plant Mobility
but soil Mobility can also play a factor
into your um odds you see a deficiency
or ways about going correcting it so
first off looking at this study we got
to start with the control plant where
there's no nutrient deficiencies uh
looking a here is week five week six
week seven and then week eight while in
week eight fan leaves developed
increasing levels of f chlorosis we can
see that here and here um this is
considered the control plant so we're
really looking at the infloresence of
the flowers the fan leaves yes we want
to see them good but here to the end
you're in good shape and as a last
reminder we are looking at a plant so
there will be some variables we can here
with the sunflowers there's going to be
some variability plant to plant so I'm
going to try to show you the major or
the textbook images if you will that you
should use for comparison so let's start
with a nitrogen um deficiency so looking
here a we're going at week three lower
canopy folar issue of nitrogen
deficiency plant starting to Yellow that
might be a little hard to see but we're
having a lightening of that green and
this will typically start in the lower
leaves we look at uh week four uh um
looking at week four the progression of
nitrogen deficiency symptoms of the fan
leaves from mild uh which is on the
right to the most severe which is of
course here on the left looking at C
here the whole Leaf closis developing
and fan leaves of the lower 2/3 of the
plant canopy and then for week five
almost the entire cence of fan leaves
stem Brown and yellowing and beginning
of Sugar Leaf chosis and nitrogen
deficient plants so a really advanced
form of yellowing so keep in mind it
might be a little hard to see here but
that lightening that green and different
varieties will have different deepness
to their green coloration so you want to
be aware of that now about correcting a
nitrogen deficiency and I'll do this for
all the nutrients remember it is a
primary mobile nutrient use 100 to 120
parts per million of nitrogen
fertilizers as the target concentration
I have other videos that go about how to
calculate that your nitrates versus your
nitrates remember nitrates dissolve in
water and therefore move about the soil
with uh the movement of soil water the
nitrites are not stable intermediate and
this is not able to be used by the plant
we can see that right here ammonia can
be taken up by the plant and nitrites
can be moved but nitrites cannot we're
also looking at ammonium ammonia versus
ammonium Ammon ammonia um has the
highest nitrogen content of any
commercial fertilizer about 82% nitrogen
however it is delivered as a gas it
needs to be injected about 4 to 8 in 10
to 20 cm below the surface um here it
will react with soil water to form
ammonium which can be utilized by the
plants for other Growers calcium nitrate
is Rec is recommended there's bloodmeal
there's ALB guano and there's uras that
are also um options but with uras like
nitrates Ura needs to dissolve in and
move through water soil and can be lost
through leeching if not converted to
ammonia and then ammonium this
conversion of ammonia takes about 2 to 4
days when soil moisture and temperature
are favorable for plant growth lower
temperature slow the process which will
continue down even the freezing because
they need the microbes to be able to
work that so typically in outdoor
applications Ura is recommended in those
summer or warmer months um calcium
nitrate when it's cooler out calcium
nitrate can be used throughout the
entire um season same with bloodmeal and
wano as just a last reminder with
nitrogen it happens quick so favor on
the lower side because you can always
add more it's hard to take
away now looking at phosphorus uh
deficiency here brown spots on fan and
sugar leaves looking here a week three
progression of folar phosphorus
deficiency symptoms in the fan leaves
and then we can kind see that
progression here um for week four and
then we have week five ref by um c as
well as D which is right below me uh in
E we see the whole plant phosphorous
deficiency symptoms sugar leaves
associated with the apal INF
infloresence are shown in the insert now
I will say overall I don't see a lot of
this um so really scrutinize um these
images to see if this is actually a
phosphorous deficiency you have going on
because of course there's other
pathogens or other issues uh that could
be occurring so really scrutinize these
images and see if that's really a good
match for what you're seeing in your
plant now how do you deal with the
phosphorus deficiency how you correct
that it is a primary mobile nutrient in
the plant it's generally immobile in the
soil so that's we have to keep in mind
our soil versus our plant comparisons
phosphates versus phosphites so
phosphates are essential for plant
growth phosphites are not essential
nutrients use more as a fungus site to
induce the systemic acquired resistance
or SAR in plants and not a fertilizer
not a common SE in Plants though most
grows over fertilize with phosphorus to
be honest especially when it gets to the
flowering stage and have other videos
showing you don't need as much
phosphorus as many Growers typically are
adding reasons for not over fertilizing
are to keep other nutrients in balance
and to maximize your yields to save
money and limit potential groundwater
contamination now potassium deficiency
we're seeing the progression of that we
see that in the um sugar leaves at week
four and the fan leaves at week four and
then we see the middle part of the
canopy really showing the most severe
portions now typically it is located a
little bit more on the margins of the
leaves or the edges of the leaves loated
a bit more on the ends of the leaves a
little bit more on the end portions and
then the margins within those so good
indications or areas to look if you're
suspecting a potassium deficiency now
how do you correct a pottassium
deficiency is a primary mobile nutrient
potassium sulfate would be recommended
you could use potassium chloride or
murate potassium it does have more
pottassium 60% versus is only 50 but
there are more salt associated with it
so it is used more in outdoor
applications where might be more natural
rain to flush through that we're just
looking at large trucks trying to carry
a higher concentration of pottassium
fertilizer some Growers recommend wood
ash um you can use it but be careful
because it will um raise your pH so use
it sparingly because it will bring your
pH Up dramatically on there then it
brings us to a Calcium deficiency so
progression of Calcium deficiency
starting in the lower of fan leaves here
in week three and then we see a more
severe um progression uh progress I
should say here going from a normal kind
of more advanced uh symptoms looking at
letter C week five is General leaf leaf
margin necrosis on lower fan leaves and
then we've got upper fan and sugar
leaves starting to show symptoms as well
at week five and then right next to me
over here week six the majority of fan
leaves and sugar leaves showed that
characteristic Leaf margin necrosis and
up leaves are curled uh upwards so again
key distinctive factors here so don't
just jump to one look at them all and
really see what signs you're seeing in
your leaves and what do they actually
match up with and hopefully you're
catching it in the earlier phases rather
than the later ones now how do you
correct a Calcium deficiency it's a
secondary immobile nutrient if you add
lime there is calcium in that product
but not as much of that plant available
so keep that in mind a Cal Mag from
banare I recommend that one and biom and
Cal I've used them both I have uh tissue
tests that show Cal Mag plus from
Botanicare does raise levels so follow
manufacturer recommendations um and keep
that feed going and hopefully you'll see
a Slowdown and then prevention of that
deficiency symptoms from there
progressing magnesium deficiency is
represented by interval chosis or
yellowing uh here we see a week four is
when it's first starting to appear might
be a little hard to see but it's first
starting to appear here and that's
through inter vinal chlorotic regions
the chlorosis is moving towards the
necrotic areas in between the leaflet
mid rib and the margins we kind of see
that where the veins stay really dark
green and those in between areas where
you're first seeing it here we see more
advanced week five the most of the
smaller fan leaves started to show
symptoms and then weak sick the
magnesium deficiency was widespread
across the entire plant except for some
older and larger fan leaves so it can be
a little spotty keep that in mind
corrected magnesium uh deficiency well
it's a secondary mobile nutrient calag
has some magnesium in it but Epsom salts
has a higher concentration of magnesium
if you're really targeting that 1
tblspoon per gallon um for early onset
and folar applications would be
recommended for Epsom salts a substate
drench an a folar application would be
recommended to try to ensure that that
magnesium is going to meet both ways and
reduce the duration that your plant
remains magnesium deficient 2
tablespoons per gallon or 2 tablespoons
uh per 3.7 L for a quick uh progressing
issue and something you want to kind of
really suppress as quickly as possible
this substrate is a drench rate because
if you apply that to the leaves you risk
the chance of them damaging it is a high
concentration rate um it's only
recommended in most severe cases um
there but it has been used and there's a
chance of burn uh but don't go any
higher than that would be my
recommendation now manganese is
different than magnesium it's basically
lacking a flower size so I know as soon
as I say that most Growers are going
think oh I have a manganese deficiency
um not necessarily the case we can see
the manganese deficient versus the
control for that comparison at week
seven this is the um treatment or the
manganese deficient and that's the
control so you can see it is a slight
decrease in size and only really with a
good comparison can you really tell the
difference between those two images now
how do you go about correcting a meganes
uh deficiency you could use manganese
sulfate often branded as palm tree
fertilizer as we can see right here I
also personally recommend age-old grow
again not sponsored by them but while
the label States it only has um
0.05% remember these are guaranteed
minimums and based on tissue test uh the
likely actual concentration is quite
High because I fed um age-old grow and
I've seen manganese increase in tissue
test levels and it shouldn't at 05%
these are guaranteed minimums so more
likely than not this contains a little
bit more than that and can be used to
correct meanes and also a good General
fertilizer uh just for General
feeding leading us to a sulfur
deficiency this is um yelling of the
sugar leaves and this first appears as
yelling of the younger sugar leaves and
then progresses upwards and angled
upward in canopy fan leaves we can kind
of see that here where they're starting
to kind of go from this to a little bit
more of that upward angle the following
week symptoms did not progress in the
sugar leaves rather they progressed in
the fan leaves as we can see that kind
of here as inter vinal chlorosis not to
be confused with a magnesium deficiency
the most severe and lower fan leaves um
here so keep that in mind and look at
the distinctive yellowing it's a very
bright yellow um coloration so keep that
in mind but we first seen in those upper
um sugar leaves so timing is important
in Catching these early as any grower
should be scattering their plants on a
regular basis now how do you go about
correcting a sulfur uh deficiency
remember it's an a secondary immobile
nutrient adding Elemental sulfur or
sulfuric acid or battery acid will add
sulfur but also drive your pH down
dramatically so these are not
recommended potassium sulfate if you
need potassium it also contains um um
some sulfur with it you could also add
gypsum which will not alter your pH
there's also other sources um of sulfur
so you might want to look at those some
also give you the benefits of other
nutrients um such as calcium or nitrogen
so take those into consideration and
hopefully you're identifying this
potential issue
early iron deficiency so progression to
various disate symptoms here of iron
deficiency on the upper and lower canopy
tissue throughout the trial the mild
closis on recently developed sugar
leaves um we can see here week five we
start to see modeling and chlorosis in
the central areas of those sugar leaves
located right there and see this uh
disappeared in later weeks so catching
it early and then seeing it shift was
interesting week six though the edge
necrosis of the lower fan leaves was
evident and that is key for an iron
deficiency now how do you go about
correcting an iron deficiency well it's
a micro immobile nutrient so you don't
need much of it remember it's a micro
plant available forms are important as
adding iron nails or iron fire Lings
will increase iron but not necessar
plant available forms that's where those
keade forms can be important for this
nutrient so if you can see that on the
label um that's great uh biomin iron is
another um plant available form it uses
an amino acid to help make that plant
available and you can use Ferris iron
sulfate but in this case remember this
is um highly acidified it's a pH of too
so Growers need to make corrections to
ensure that that Ferris sulfate solution
is actually plant available and not
doing more harm than good now on my last
slide here I just want to provide you
with General deficiency symptoms so you
can kind of refer to this and see sulfur
and calcium and nitrogen and magnesium
and phosphorus to best match up
potentially what you're seeing now keep
in mind those calcium and those
phosphorus can look very close I tend to
see more calcium deficiencies than
phosphorus but utilize this here to
visually diagnose your plants as well to
hopefully provide you suggestions for
fertilization to reduce the symptoms and
to prevent it in the future