here we're looking at the voluntary in
the autonomic nervous system and see how
this relates and connects to the central
and peripheral nervous systems looking
it down here our autonomic in our
somatic systems this kind of key here
the green is the structure so for our
central nervous system the main
structure is the brain and spinal cord
and of course the function of those is
to integrate and as control centers so
looking specifically our autonomic and
our somatic nervous systems well this is
relating to systems that we have
voluntary comodo control over and
involuntary control over so a voluntary
control will be an example of impulses
from the central nervous system going to
skeletal muscles for the movement we
have control over and then involuntary
there should be muscles such as smooth
muscle that do move and do contract but
are not under our direct control now
specifically the voluntary nervous
system relays commands the skeletal
muscles and can be controlled by
conscious thought however reflexes are
rapid involuntary movements there are
rapid because the sensory neuron passes
information directly to the motor neuron
she here at the kind of the knee-jerk
test where if you hang your knee over
like a chair or a table and take a
little hammer and hit the tendon just
below the kneecap that will be a prime
example of this process and your label
kick out this must involve single
connection inter neurons between sensory
and morden neurons and like I said the
prime example is here and you could try
this for yourself continuing on we also
have within the autonomic nervous system
we have two pathways we have a parasitic
synthetic pathway and a synthetic
pathway so our parasympathetic nervous
system specifically is related to
controlling normal functions it also is
related to conserving energy we see that
with a reducing heart rate steam
activity of digestive organs
constricting urinary bladder in contrast
to that are somatic nervous system this
pathway is kind of like the opposite it
can increase the heart rate it can kind
of inhibit activity of digestive organs
so here we're students saying that
stimulate activity digestive here we
kind of have an inhibition effect
neither of these can be controlled by
conscious thought for example your
pupils that constricting or dilating
don't have direct control over that
composed of elements that act in
opposition to one another and that's the
key point here there's a way to
constrict the pupils of your eye we need
a way to dilate the pupils of your eye
you want to increase your production of
saliva
we need to inhibit that so these kind of
play off one another the synthetic
pathway typically dominates in a time of
stress and it controls the flight fight
or flight reaction and also increase
blood pressure heart rate and breathing
as an example now comparing our
autonomic nurse our somatic effort
pathways well we kind of see them
evident here and both of these are kind
of a long operate along the same lines
they're essentially the same
what's different is what branches that
they're involved in what exact
connections that they make so for
example our dynamic efferent pathway
here we have this connection between the
neuron to the ganglion which then forms
a second production projection from the
gangway onto the target effector so it
essentially here there's an intermediate
that's occurring we see this kind of
connection and intermediate before we're
actually getting to the target effector
in this case smooth muscle in this
example here our somatic reflexes for
instance involved a direct connection
from the spinal cord to skill to muscle
and this is a Linus direct connection
here and here's our synapse
there's no intermediate so this would be
example here the target effector is a
smooth muscle having this intermediate
tingly on a neuron and here we have this
direct connection between our spinal
cord and our skeletal muscle which would
be under voluntary control