so here we're going to get water
regulation in the human body I have a
separate video with osmoregulation
relating to fish here we're gonna look
at the human body this is an extreme
case of water dehydration in the case of
the mummy here looking a little bit more
of a realistic situation here
antidiuretic hormone ADH is apartment
negative feedback system that regulates
water in the mammalian body pH increases
the permeability of distal tubules
allowing for greater water recovery so
for example a person is given a dose of
ADH then more water will be retained by
the kidneys so how does this look at an
actual situation so if we're outside a
heat will cause water loss through
dehydration through the process of
sweating receptors in the hypothalamus
soak it in the brain detect the
increased blood as molarity and signaled
the pituitary gland
it's the pituitary gland located right
here that will release ADH into the
bloodstream when that ADH is released
into the bloodstream
that will cause an increase in the
permeability of the distal tubule and
then nephron and clean the collecting
duct this allows more water to be
reabsorbed into the blood to get our
nephron structure and water will be
retained in the body and concentrated
urine is produced so that urine is
concentrated because the buyers
retaining more water meaning that is
excreting less water concentrating the
air and giving it more of a yellow to
dark yellow appearance now caffeine and
alcohol and in diuretics alcohol
inhibits ADH release while caffeine
interferes with its activity part of the
synonyms of a hangover are actually due
to dehydration so what causes
dehydration in this case and why is a
cup of coffee
not a good cure for a hangover so look
at some of the items here we have our
Brut coffee I think in this comparison
the highest amount of caffeine per cup
instant coffee
redbull black tea Kenneth's Cola a shot
of expresso green tea is decreasing it
decaffeinated coffee then we'll have
less caffeine because it is
decaffeinated but it still does not
contain zero contains less but not
completely owned in it entirely
direct directs and weight loss so many
over-the-counter herbal diet aids
claim to detoxify the body or flesh fat
out of the body well many of these
contain dandelion leaves or parsley or
other herbs known to be diuretics which
increase the amount of water and salt
expelled from the body as you urine so
if that's the case we want to consider
if a person tries one of these products
it appears to lose pounds were they
actually losing they actually losing fat
they are losing weight but is it
actually in the form of fat so consider
what's going on you particular with the
kidneys also if they can see disease for
an extended period of time could be
health problems associated these
products that are clinging to flush site
and detoxify the body if they're
diuretics an increasing amount of water
and salt expelled from the body's urine
so consider that also in a last case the
king of rap now this long tale
okay regret is adapted for the desert
life and being able to survive with very
little water I want you to consider some
ways in which it's kidneys it might be
different from the human kidney to let
to conserve as much water as possible it
lives in a very arid environment you may
say looking at the pictures here well I
can just get water from the plant it
just eats the plants well there's not a
lot of plants available in the desert
environment so it has kidneys adapted to
help it survive with very little water
so I want you to consider how the
kidneys of the Karoo wrap may differ
from a human kidney what might be going
on there to help it live in an
environment where water is very scarce