okay here we're gonna look at water and
carbon dioxide during the vegetative
growth phase of cannabis so first off
irrigation keep in mind that plants will
be growing drastically during this phase
so irrigation may need to be changed to
meet demands this can mean changing the
frequency the amount of times that you
water those plants in a day and/or the
duration the
length of time that you give those
plants water keep in mind this is gonna
change as the plants grow as they get
bigger there's gonna be a greater demand
for water so whether you meet that with
increased frequency or duration may
depend on your particular operations
constraints or setup now that's it's a
water delivery there's hand watering
which is not advised a long-term
solution but it's very labor intensive
can great when they're small can be used
other kind of spot add some plants maybe
on the edge our plant near fan is
getting a little bit more breeze on it
which shouldn't be implemented for the
entire grow facility flood and drain is
possible if you can implement a large
tray system this is a four by two tray
here there's a drip emitter system we
see here on a large scale this is not
the only way it needs to look these can
be very versatile and can be changing
conditions as the plants grow or as they
switch to different rooms co2 is impact
on the veg phase if co2 diffusing co2
it's recommended basically from
emergence through the end of flowering
phase so Basin through the entire growth
phase of the plant however it can be
most beneficial during the vegetative
phase to help increase biomass of the
plant to try to get a bigger plant a
quicker plant to fill an area adding co2
if you have not added co2 before and
have set plan for your plants in the
sense of kind of I know I see them on
this day I transfer them here I flip
them then you will most likely need to
make adjustments to that original plan
that you may have odds are the plants
are going to grow quicker in larger so
this may offset initial plans that you
have if you're looking at historical
data depending on the size of your gross
base may require either more space
because your plants become bigger so you
may need to accommodate for the space or
reduce time to flower which can be
advantageous if you're on a limited
space and want to maintain the same
plant numbers so plants will fill the
areas faster resulting in shorter
duration to flowers again that
advantageous for some growers as well
communicate specifics aiming for levels
of seven hundred to a thousand is
advised I suggest using 1200 parts per
million ask them maximum simply because
going beyond this level will not likely
result in any improvement in yields we
could see this chart here going from
zero to a thousand we kind of see it
certainly taper off here even my natural
levels are right around 400 so you can
see going up to about a thousand here we
start to level off we are getting a
increase in the photosynthetic process
but going again much little above 1200
not really going to give you that much
greater yield and a lot more cost