so here we're gonna be looking at water
absorption in plants and now when we
water plants we just assume they absorb
the water we may think it's kind of like
a sponge here absorbing the water it's a
little bit more complicated than that so
I just want to go over a couple key
aspects how plants absorb water so the
first one here the main site of water
absorption is the fine root here so it's
a key component there the fine root here
is because this is where there's a lot
of surface area to volume a lot of
contact on these not only the roots but
the fine root hairs is where the major
site of water absorption occurs now once
it gets through these very fine hairlike
structures it can enter either an apple
plastic or symplastic group what that
means is the apple plastic group is
through the cell wall we can see that
here and we see that down here there's
also the symplastic root which is
through this cytoplasm ultimately
regardless of the way that the water
initially enters it's all going to be
kind of funneled to and translated to
these vascular bundles we see kind of a
microscopic view so these vascular
bundles are ultimately going to
transport the water to the rest of the
plant in this getting these vascular
bundles in a little bit more detail we
see there's two main types there's what
we call the xylem and what we call flow
now the xylem is transporting mainly
water and some ions up the plan so xylem
goes from the roots upward to the shoots
so from the roots to like the stems or
the leaves in that kind of one direction
phloem though most carbohydrates the
byproduct of photosynthesis of sugars
and it moves us corrodes up and down the
plant from source cells to sink cells so
what that means is source cells are like
the leaves that are first making those
sugar molecules and you're being
transported to sink cells those sink
cells could be actually developing roots
it could be the flower buds it could be
a growing part of the plant that needs a
lot of energy and that's what the phloem
is doing up and down from the site of
production to wherever it needs to be
transport it to look at this now I don't
have to go look in great detail but the
vascular bundles D is the xylem and
they're a little bit larger they're
almost good to them almost like
in E is the phloem fibers so we could
see the e because there's moving up and
down there's transporting source to sink
we see a lot of smaller cells here
because they're involved a lot more than
active transport the xylem just moving
kind of that bulk water I can think of
it like pipes moving through the plant
and that's moving the bulk of the water
from the roots to the shoots hopefully
that helps kind of a illustrate a little
bit the examples here water absorption
plants