here on debaco university i'm going to
go over water purification options for
cannabis production
[Music]
when growing cannabis due to tight
standards and often regulations
want to make sure everything is clean
and consistent as possible
so water purification is an important
part of this process
so what are some of the options when it
comes to purifying your water
so purification filtration this
purification process is removing
undesirable chemicals biological
contaminants suspended solids
and gases from water there is a variety
of methods that can be used which is per
dependent on the initial water
conditions and what the target substance
is
to be removed so choosing your options
first determines what do you potentially
want to look at targeting when you're
looking at removing
so water volume versus water quality
when we're looking at the two here
growers need to have a water
purification system
that will supply enough volume of water
for the amount of plants they intend on
growing
however depending on the type of water
is initially incoming into the facility
this can impact the type of water
purification system used
sometimes to get the proper quality of
water takes time and can reduce
volume be produced you see here with
kind of a distillation system they put
water in they trap
capture with the dome that's great if
you only need to water with this much
however in many other cases you need a
lot more volume
so how can you ensure you have a good
quality while still maintaining the
right volume
if it's under what's required by the
plants is there's going to be issues
you're going to have
stress issues with simply lack of water
also growers need to factor in the
volume of their plants will consume on a
hot day
at full maturity you might be able to
get by it's you know propagation stage
but at maturity hot day can you supply
enough water with your chosen
purification system some growers have to
deal with hard water or
soft water so what's the difference
between these two well for hard water
this has high content of dissolved
minerals
which is hard which make it primarily
high in calcium
in magnesium content it's measured in
milligrams
of calcium salts per liter of water
typically and as we can see here
200 to 400 is in the range of hard water
while 400 to 450 is considered to be
very hard water typical tap water is in
that 170 to 190 milligrams per liter and
while this is not
dangerous to humans consuming this type
of water can potentially
be harmful to cannabis and especially
for mixing it with other
nutrients self water contains little
minerals to none at all
under 150 is considered very soft to 150
to 200
is just simply soft water rain water
purified ionized and distilled water are
examples of
soft water with rain water once it
collects soil particles and minerals the
hardness scale
can go up so be mindful of where you're
collecting potentially that rain water
you want a general comparison between
hard and soft water little definition
formation ions and effects are presented
here
if you want more details now getting
into some specifics
so there is reverse osmosis and this is
essentially produces
pure water with an electroconnectivity
of zero
in zero parts per million it is a very
pure system however the disadvantage of
this system while you think what could
be wrong with it producing
zero vc or zero parts per million it's a
very slow process
it also generates a wastewater that's
not harmful it's just not used it needs
to be
disposed of or have a drain associated
with that
also in the system the membranes need to
be replaced to prevent micro
contamination of the water over time
tap water tap water as easily
comes directly out of the tap typically
also called
city water the disadvantage of tap water
is it can have potential contaminants
in it can be may restrict what nutrients
growers can add so talk about
contaminants we're not talking about
necessarily anything that's harmful
just potential for like chlorine or
other
minerals that may make it more limiting
on the amount of nutrients a grower can
add to that water
then we have a carbon filtration system
the advantage is that is remove chlorine
volatile organic compounds called vocs
taste and odor can also remove sediment
but this will reduce the filters
useful life expectancy so to speak the
disadvantages is it does not remove
minerals salts or dissolved organic
substances so again that comes back to
what are you trying to remove from your
water is this a good fit
for what you have in it has a
contaminant in your water
and lastly we have a sediment filter so
this removes physical particles from the
water
it's often used as a pre-filter before
other filtration methods to simply
increase the longevity
of the other filters the downfall of the
sediment filters
only removes particles and not chemicals
or contaminants
the finer the screen that the sediment
filter has
typically the slower rate of flow so
that might be important when you're
doing calculations to make sure
you can supply your plants with enough
flow while also delivering the right
quality
of water if you need any more
information on these types of filtration
search tobacco university here to learn
more about each