welcome to this debaco university video
well i'll be presenting the advantages
and disadvantages of some water sources
if you're looking at growing outdoors
all right let's get into water sources
for outdoor canvas production providing
with some examples and some advantages
and disadvantages of each
so first off water sources when it comes
to campus plants they do need water
when it comes to supplying them with
water from sources other than natural
rain
growers need to know how to maximize
their plants performance
with the water they have available and
many times growers may have
different water source options so which
one is quote the best or which one
should they choose
going to provide you with some advantage
and disadvantages of each
so first off pond water so if we're
looking at we have an irrigation pond
the advantages of irrigating from pond
water is that it's typically available
in large quantities
because we have to remember we're going
to need the water to irrigate the plants
the most
during times of drought however the
disadvantages are that it does
typically need a multi-filter system you
can't just throw a pump in here and pump
out of it
in most cases you typically need some
sort of multi-filter system to either
take particulate out
or to ensure you're not going to be
spreading any of the algae potentially
that may be growing in that
water as well then we get to city water
so the advantages of
city water is that or tap water may be
called also is that it's easy to get and
it typically requires
minimum modifications you can literally
just hook a hose up
go irrigate shouldn't be a problem there
however what of the disadvantages of
using city or tap water is that it can
be costly
compared to other sources mentioned here
and limited areas have this
as an option particularly if you're in
distant areas
or they may not be able to supply enough
water or at least justify the cost
for the volume of water that you may
need to water your plants
then there is also well water so well
water
is supply plants in very remote
locations
a lot of times you can potentially have
a well
dug or basically bored down and
irrigate water that might irrigate with
water at a location that might be very
distant
it's also a free water source and put
free in quotes there simply because
there is some costs associated with the
well itself
digging the well maybe running power to
the well getting that set up but as far
as the cost of the water itself
this case is basically free the
disadvantage of using well water is you
have to be
careful in dry years depending on how
deep that well is what its replenish
rate may be
also keep in mind that the water that
you're getting pumping up from the well
is often a cold temperature and this
might
slow down growth of plants because they
typically like warmer water
i want to check also the quality for
water but with well water in particular
you want to check the
temperature to make sure it's not too
cold especially in the early part of
germination and propagation
so you don't stunt the plants hopefully
this was a nice little review
of looking at the different options that
you might have for outdoor irrigation