okay here we're briefly cover some of
the water pumps and explain a little bit
about them submersible in-line in some
pumps now we're going to avoid the hand
pump here so if you're using one of
these odds are probably not able to take
advantage of some of the common
irrigation systems all of these here run
on some form of power rather than just
manual power here so first off we gotta
start with some terms two key ones that
you may see pumps displayed in many
different types of pumps out there the
standard classifications are they will
tell you how many gallons per minute GPM
or gallons per hour it'll give you that
quote so you have an idea of the flow
rate also you might see something called
head height that's the maximum pumping
height or called the zero flow point
that means is how high or how many feet
can that pump pump that water before
it's unable to actually cause a flow
rate now to be the head height there
this could be important if you're
mounting a pump very low and you're
putting the in the bottom of a big
irrigation tank you got to pump it out
of the tank and up to another area if
you're going uphill for a larger
operation so just keep that in mind of
what head height is now an inline pump
typically placed outside the water
reservoir they're more powerful than
these submersible pumps I'll talk about
in a second they do tend to require air
cooling and they're commonly found in
large-scale operations when oversize
these pumps due to restrictions in the
system so I've used these it can be
quite powerful it can be a little noisy
at times they are air-cooled and
sometimes they do need priming to keep
that in mind there so they're a little
bit better for larger operations are
moving a little higher volume of water
in most cases then there's some merciful
pumps these sit directly in the water
reserves that you have the advantages
these pumps are water-cooled if you keep
them that water at a good temperature it
can help cool the pump so you don't burn
it out if you are running it for an
extended period of time that will be
circulating that water in particular you
can heat the water up with this type of
pump so keep that also in mind of the
pros and cons the advantage is one of
those plumbing is mixing the nutrient
solution typically you some smaller
operations do the overall lack of power
found in this classification of pumps
despite stated values you want to figure
out what you need and then purchase a
pump that's about
double the volume that you need simply
because of the lack of efficiencies
tends to be with them so their stated
values tend to be a little bit
overstating I feel those values you want
to watch the head height so you want to
don't want to have these pump a great
distance up because they can be a little
bit weaker most of time in that regards
but just keep note of it or look for
that on the pump you looking at
purchasing I use this one here and a
flood in train operation the last one
the sub pump these are commonly used to
transfer and mixing also pump out a
basement that tends to flood so that's
really may be familiar with these they
can be classified as kind of this
special classification of submersible
pumps it can they come a little bit
larger sizes they can be measured in
horsepower but commonly is for transfer
or mixing a little bit on the larger end
of things they can have this kind of
automatic shutoff so this is just kind
of a specialized version of this we
talked about previously our submersible
pumps they need to be submersed in that
water to help pump it so if you're
looking the bigger operation this could
be some things you consider well that
gives you just that brief overview of
pumps to consider for your irrigation
options