in this debaco university video i'm
going to go over some more details
to explain dry trimming of cannabis
plant material
all right let's get into wet trimming
cannabis plant material and
learn a little bit more about this
process so wet trimming
well when we're wet trimming yields a
higher flower to trim ratio but requires
more equipment and has less room for
error
a wet trimming method involves cutting
the plant down followed immediately by
the removal of the fan leaves
and detailed trimming of the bud after
this is completed
then the drying process can begin this
process is common for very large growing
operations since there is typically not
enough drying space
so performing an initial wet trim is
needed to reduce the overall biomass
before the drying process can actually
start
so you're kind of going through
harvesting the plant and trimming it
right away
kind of immediately after harvesting
now the benefits to this method is that
wet trimming is recommended by growers
because of the greater trichome
preservation
and quicker harvesting time all with
less space needed for the actual drying
process because you're kind of removing
all the plant material
that you really don't need anyway buds
can kind of puff
out appealing larger and more
aesthetically pleasing in some cases
commercial growers typically see the
puff out as a huge reason
to wet trim to kind of create that
visual effect
this also makes the drying process
faster by removing much of the moisture
in the plant
and can help reduce the stress on your
drying equipment if you're trying to
maintain
which hopefully you are certain humidity
levels in the drying space
now the problems with wet trimming
because it's not a perfect method is
that
it's not as clean as a process as dry
trimming
so with wet trimming there'll be
noticeable residue build up on the
shears which will need
cleaning also the takedown of the plants
followed immediately by trimming
also compresses some of the required
work that needs to be accomplished and
this can make it a very difficult
process to be able to complete all in
one fellow swoop
looking at commercial harvesting
locations with commercial harvesting
often speed and efficiency is important
which is part of the reason why wet
trimming can be selected
wet trimming is also faster compared to
the detail orientedness of dry trimming
process however there will likely be
some trichome loss since the drying
process
there will not be any sugar leaves to
provide protection
the goal of volume and reduced time to
sail can hurt individual bud quality
as wet string material may not reach top
quality that can be achieved with a dry
trim
that's kind of a very important thing to
note there is that while it might be an
easier quicker
process it might hurt or reduce your
overall bud quality
if you're comparing it to a dry trim and
that reason and that reason alone
is why many growers will only go through
the dry trim process
and will not do anything with a wet trim
process
you can see that there are kind of some
advantages to wet trim and that's why
some girls do elect
to utilize the wet trim option of their
cannabis plants