in this tobacco university video i'm
going to answer the question what are
terpenoids and how do they relate to
cannabinoids
[Music]
all right so let's get to answering the
question what are terpenoids and how do
they relate to cannabinoids
so first off terpenes versus trypanoids
here what's kind of the general
comparison and this is a great kind of
difference between for definition
structure types and uses however these
are often used as interchangeable terms
but they do have different definitions
and we can see different classifications
and categories terpenes
are the naturally occurring combination
of carbon and hydrogen
terpenoids are terpenes that have been
modified through a drying
and curing process basically that's a
chemical modification
and what that does is that alters the
oxygen content
of the compound so we're talking about
on the molecular level there
terpeneites are a subset of terpenes
that contain additional functional
groups
and these functional groups could have
been added uh to produce a desired
effect
or it could be a nash occurring in the
drying process
so here we have the structure again
terpenes simple hydrocarbon compound
terpenoids hydrocarbon compound with
oxygen containing
functional groups kind of an important
structural uh difference
there as well as the other differences
you see listed right here
so what are terpenes then what are kind
of let's look at just the the general
sense what are
um terpenes because we've heard probably
that term referred to quite a bit
in terpenes are organic hydrocarbons
found in essential oils
of plants and chemist terpenes are
produced in the trichomes of the plant
it's what provides the unique scent
the terpene smell allows us to make
inferences about the strain and possible
physiological effects that it may have
we see the five most common listed here
and kind of a
standardized approach we see a lot of
wheels being used with terpenes
to help again create a good comparison
in an organized format and more of these
terpenes will be described in details
on other videos here on debaco
university
so what can impact terpenes just in
general
well the reason plants develop terpenes
in the first place is to attract
pollinators or
reject predators research suggests that
these compounds can have
medical properties so they might be
important for human use
now what can impact them while the
growing environment the growing
substrate and the time that you go
through and harvest them
now here we're seeing kind of a
comparison again provided by a company
so
take it for what it's worth looking at
our standard kind of
lighting and then adding uva and uvb
light
and the alterations in terpene
concentrations
and they kind of give all of the values
here and we can see the total terpene
concentrations
are particularly higher for mycin and
limonene increased by 40 to 50 percent
with the addition of uva and uvb light
just one example here on just that
growing environment
can change the amount of terpenes
produced not to mention the substrate or
the time that you select a harvest
so identified terpenes again this is
hopefully not too confusing it's meant
to be
a really kind of interesting way to kind
of provide an organization
as there are over a hundred different
identified terpenes
in the cannabis plant and while the
differences can be subtle
there are classification systems put in
place to reduce confusion
general smell classifications we see
like the spicy and the kind of the sour
collection we see also the earthy smells
the
sweet smells again it's commonly shown
on a terpene wheel to try to try to
develop that organization presented
now i consider this to be a little bit
more of an improved wheel by terpene
type and not smell classify them and to
give you more information about each of
them
to give you the boiling points of them
the aromas the effects they're what
they're also found in in the key medical
benefits
as well as some strains that may have
favor that particular type of terpene
these derping categories are an
improvement
method of organization over the aroma
given off it's kind of a little bit of
non-scientific way
this presentation also includes
additional properties for each for
improved comparisons
to be easily made what are the boiling
points are they different what are the
general aromas also included but not the
main way of organization
so how terpenes relate to cannabinoids
to get to that central question there
technically speaking phytocannabinoids
are a form of a terpenoid
they are metro terpenoids meaning they
have
a partial terpenoid structure much of
the commercial
commercial and therapeutic value of
cannabis comes from the aromatic
mono terpenes which have synergistic
effect when consumed
furthermore the aromatic therapeutic
effects of monoterpenes
have been clinically shown effective
this kind of shows you the
quote marijuana which is you're above
0.3 thc in your hemp
from a federal standpoint what they can
both produce they both can produce
cannabinoids and terpenes different
percentages different
combinations so again knowing your
cannabis plant and doing what it could
produce
that's how terpenes can relate to
cannabinoids they are both produced by
the cannabis plant
and this brings us to the entourage
effect which is some more is another
video on this channel goes into this in
more detail
but in general the entourage effect
describes a mechanism where cannabis
substances work together to optimize the
overall psychoactive benefits of the
plant
the idea is that you want to find the
best terpenes to cannabinoid ratio
possible
for your desired effect because as we
see here all these dotted lines all
these connections
there is a web here of of interactions
not just one thing that's kind of
systematically leading to another thing
there's a bunch of interactions that can
occur and understanding those
interactions
can create a more beneficial medicinal
purpose
so this all comes back to the very end
here the importance of
testing so not every plant in the given
strain will have the same levels of
terpenes to the expression of individual
plants phenotypes as well as the growing
environment
the only way to be sure is through a
terpene analysis
from a cannabis testing laboratory so be
sure
anything you're looking at purchasing
make sure you're getting these
certificate of analysis
they look slightly different yes it's
important to look at the terpene profile
it's important look at the cannabinoids
but also make sure that it's passing
tests for
heavy metals pesticides
microbiology things like that to ensure
you're getting a clean product
as well as a product that also has a
particular profile
that you deem desirable