okay in this video I tend to at least
address the question what is biology a
lot of students do as the study of life
but then to go much beyond that that's
really a lot of them get tripped up so
starting with a biology study of life
study of living things is a way also to
look at it and living things can be
classified into six kingdoms you're
probably most familiar with animals
plants maybe even fungi and bacteria but
there's also protists in archaea as part
of the total of the six kingdoms so the
question is well what is life like the
game of life like cereal there's a
humerus here with you had the egg and
the chicken crawling out of it but how
do we actually define what actually is
wife
well I've concluded to links to some
videos here it kind of give you an
appreciation for what life is and one is
duck egg hatching under time-lapse
another one is a monarch butterfly
metamorphosis that does occur so what is
life getting back to this central
question since biology is the study of
life we need to think about well what is
this what does life mean what does it
mean to be alive well look at a cell
here we have the individual components
cilia the microtubules Golgi apparatus
so on and so far these are the
individual components then we have this
these individual components are
organized to result in a behavior so
alone the Golgi apparatus the lysosomes
cytoplasm the cell membrane are his
components but all of these combined
together result in a behavior and
components are organized into this
specific structure so living organisms
in many nonliving things share three
properties they're complex they
typically provide movement and they
response to stimulation so that's that
getting into that behavior component
there so we see our properties of life
there's five main ones all of them
organs for these five basic properties
the first one is cellular organization
all organisms are composed in at least
one cell so it can be you just one cell
you can see here cells who pose if atoms
molecules macromolecules
cells cells combined from tissues
tissues can form organs so on and so
forth but the one of the key are the
five basic properties is cellular
organization in the fact that all living
organisms are composed of at least one
cell another is that these living
organisms that have metabolism what's
Mattel ISM we'll all living organisms
use energy you see here we're taking in
in this case chemical energy in the form
of carbohydrates fats proteins we're
going to be producing chemical wastes at
carbon dioxide producing heat forming
ATP that's resulting in our metabolism
the ability to use and break down energy
all of us are able to maintain
homeostasis these are stable internal
conditions despite wanting to change
such as blood sugar here being increased
or decreased body's trying to maintain a
relatively stable environment despite a
changing external environment this could
be walking from a room that is
air-conditioned where it's very cold
walking outside to where it's very hot
your body's trying to maintain the same
temperature despite the changing
external environment for is all living
organisms can grow and reproduce this is
we see that here whether it's human
whether it's insect able to grow and
reproduce even though the life cycles of
each individual will may be different
there is that cycle that does occur and
lastly all living organisms possess
genetic material that is based on DNA
the DNA stands for deoxyribonucleic acid
this is how we're able to inherit
certain genes from our mom or our dad
it's through the passed down of the DNA
we're able to track that and it makes us
essentially who we are so putting this
all together if you didn't get them all
there at once this is the last kind of
summary slide that all living organisms
have cellular organization metabolism
homeostasis growth in reproduction and
lastly all organisms have some form of
heredity hopefully this is helpful in
describing the properties of life