in this debaco university video i'm
going to answer the simple question
what are cannabinoids now we're going to
go investigate this in a little detail
so hopefully you come along
and are able to learn just what are
cannabinoids
related to cannabis plants
[Music]
all right let's get to the main event
why you probably came here to answer the
question
what are cannabinoids well first off we
need to understand there's something
called
photocannabinoids um as well so
photocannabis are a secondary metabolite
produced by many plants and
liverworts as well however they are
producing the greatest concentrations
and
variations in cannabis sativa
photocannabinoids are bioactive
terpenoids which were thought to be
exclusive to cannabis sativa but now
have also been discovered in
rhododendron species as well as some
legumes
liverworts genus as well as some fungi
as well so it's not just cannabis even
though here we are relating them to
cannabis
simply because they've been found to
produce in the greatest concentrations
now some of those photocannabinoids here
might be familiar with
cbd thc probably the two most famous
ones but there's also
cbc thca cbg as well as
others and they're involved in kind of
the neurological pathways and receptors
of the human body so we get into
cannabinoids or photocannabinoids what's
the correct term to use
well photocannabinoids are any
cannabinoid that's produced in the
trichomes of the cannabis plant
photocannabinoids are fatty acids
synthesized in the trichomes of cannabis
sativa
and also in the trichomes of multiple
other species
photocannabinoids interact with our
body's receptors to produce numerous
therapeutic effects and cannabinoids are
a class of lithophilic
molecules that interact with the body's
endocannabinoid system
typically abbreviated ecs often use
however these are often used as
interchangeable terms endocannabinoids
are what are produced
in animals so we have the endoca
cannabinoids and that's made
by the body because endo means within
and then we have the photocontaminants
because photo means made by
photo made by plants the photosynthetic
process
now we have the endocannabinoids which
are brain derived the photocannabinoids
and then we also can't forget about
synthetic cannabinoids and there's our
pharmaceutical lab created they all
interact with the
endocannabinoid receptors of the body
they kind of like oversimplify that we
have cb1 and cb2 receptors
different shapes because shape
determines function that's how we bind
and that's how we're looking at the
importance of the shape of these
molecules
to interrupt for their interaction with
the body's neurological system
so properties our photocadabinoids are
mostly
insoluble in water but are soluble in
alcohol
and fat and other non-polar organic
solvents so fats being a lipid those are
nonpolar in alkaline conditions
they can form water soluble petal salts
which are essentially phenols
and the phenol groups are represented
either by this or look like this
and just to take you back to little
biology polar versus nonpolar solvents
polar solvents are like water there is a
kind of positive negative
n nonpolar silence are kind of like the
they don't really have
a charge there and separation there's no
charge separation
where polar as a partial positive
negative charge is observed
so just kind of look at some of the
physical properties
of these cannabinoids now just an
overview
of the cannabis as i mentioned probably
familiar with thc cbn cbg cbd things
like that
overview of the cannabinoids here
derived in different kind of backbone
areas here the black structures here and
the black outlines have been isolated
from natural sources
blue structures located right over here
have not been found
in plants and those are kind of your
alcohol
derivatives there so again the reason
why i show this is this
shape determines function and that's
really important understand the shape
if you want to know the shape it can not
really provide a lot of information here
but just to kind of give you that
information so you have access to it
we also have side chain cannabinoids
which are sc canaanites typically
abbreviated
and in general side change canals of
cannabis sativa can be divided into ten
general groups
and these are some ones we might be more
familiar with where the delta nine
delta eight thc uh as i said
cbd cbc cbg these are all also could be
classified as what's called side chain
cannabinoids
now why are cannabinoids produce just
the great kind of step away picture well
plants produce cannabinoids as a form of
defense against insect feeding
and or a stressful environmental
conditions which can include
uv light as well as water stress in the
form of
desiccation in the human body produces
candidates also for survival through
activation of homeostasis which is that
balancing there so
here we have our cannabinoid receptors
we have our photocannabinoids we kind of
need to have this like check and balance
system to maintain the all-important
homeostasis
within any living system lastly
connecting cannabinoids to humans
cannabinoids are
the bio are bioactive in human beings in
the sense that they bind to the
endogenous cannabinoid system or ecs
which results in the plethora of
physiological responses the effect of
these drugs can treat many different
diseases ranging from inflammation
to anxiety and many others we'll cover
some more of these uh in other videos
but just kind of give you that basic
understanding here
of just what cannabinoids are beyond
just recognizing thc
and cbd hopefully this provides some
more detailed information for you