okay here and welcome to what is biology
where we're going to seek to answer that
question
here and provide a little background for
[Music]
you
well the obvious question when we're
looking at biology well by all means
life and ology means the subject of
study
so therefore biology is the study of
life
but that brings in the question what is
life so when we're looking at what life
is
life is basically individual components
that
will result in a behavior you see that
here with this newly hatched
sea turtle when we're looking at these
individual components we want to take
something
and break it down into those individual
components take maybe an organism and
break it down
into some of the tissues some of the
potential organs
or the cells so here we're seeing
someone chucking a
corn this kind of gives us the idea of
the layers that can be involved
in some of the smaller structures it can
be located within for example the cells
these little corn kernels here you can
think about them as kind of like
the cells that represent the individual
in cellular organization
all living things are composed of at
least one cell so that's a good
way to go about targeting that we also
have metabolism so all living organisms
use energy consume and use energy
in addition the all-important
homeostasis
so here we see some guy in a tightrope
balancing out all living
organisms must maintain stable internal
conditions despite the changing
external conditions that they may be
facing so they can stay on
that type of life in addition
we have this kind of blooming and
growing flower here
and this is important for growth and
reproduction all
living organisms must grow and reproduce
and see the flowers not growing but the
reproductive structures of the plant
now what those organisms are going to be
passing on is
the process of heredity so all living
organisms possess genetic material
that's based
on dna that's what's passed on to the
next generation
moving along to the organization of life
so if we have life we need to have it
organized and how do we go about
organizing that
when we're looking at life here we have
a small little ladybug we can look at
the atomic level the molecule level
and we can zoom out to the earth here
and even beyond
and this goes pretty far into kind of
the galaxy based
but you get the idea of how we can start
with something very small
the rest are very large when you walk in
the woods well what do you see when you
walk in the west you see kind of all
these things kind of coming together see
how
the water and the trees in the animals
all interact
here we have a single neuron that cannot
perform the tasks of the brain we have
something called an emergent property
where a higher level organization that
contains novel properties not found in
the simpler level
here we see neurons working together as
the functional brain that no
single neuron can perform on its own
applying the same concept to these
geese in the field here well we know
what emergent property is
what important property property can
these geese provide
addition they tend to work together for
looking for food
that's one thing but really if you see
them in the particularly the spring and
the fall
flying efficiency when they form that
nice v
now in addition we have five themes that
unify biology here
and these first one would be evolution
the gene frequencies change in a species
over time this is uh over a long period
of time
in addition another theme that kind of
ties in biology is the flow of energy
here we see plants capturing the sun's
energy capturing that light energy and
forming carbohydrates
now we see that flow of energy so those
plants are being fed on by insects ever
seen insect chewing on a leaf
gaining that energy that was once
captured uh by the plant
and then here we see the poor insect
being fed on by another insect so it's
kind of that
circle of life that we kind of go
through now in addition
we also have an interaction that will
occur this is interaction between
organisms here the plant and the insect
and we also have structure determines
function so with the knife and the fork
the structure needs to be well suited to
fit the function
the knife and the fork are a great
example of that and lastly of course we
have
homeostasis living organisms act to
maintain a relatively stable internal
environment despite the changes that
occur around them
so that again they can stay on that
tightrope of life