I think this title presents a question
that a lot of people have and that is
well what is cannabis so we're gonna
look at noon investigate look at the
background for what cannabis actually is
so first off what is the naming
bluejeans canvas is probably indigenous
to the wet habits of the Asiatic
continent here this is probably likely
where it was originated or grown I do
have a couple links here for some
sources if you want to go ahead and take
a look some of the information that I
have here try to put in a summary of
this so where'd Kim's cannabis originate
okay this has a long coexisted with
mankind which led to early domestication
of the plant it's shown up in a lot of
old records so it's been around human
interactions for a very long period of
time because price.when reason why it's
been around is its diverse amount of
uses so it could be used as textiles for
fibers such as hemp clothing or in this
case a handbag also a narcotic or
psychoactive compounds so it kind of
serves potentially two different
purposes now what's the difference
between cannabis hemp and marijuana so
this is a very kind of key and important
distinction here chemists the plant is
tall with a stiff upright stem divided
into serrated leaves and these
collateral hairs it's used to produce
hemp fiber and also a psychotropic drug
that specifically hemp so Tammis is kind
of a broad category that includes both
hemp and marijuana hemp specifically the
cameras plant grown for fiber or other
non psychoactive components typically as
a high medical value due to the CBD the
cannabinoid produced it needs to have
less than 0.3 percent THC to be
confederate classified as hemp now a
plant called marijuana will may look
very similar to hemp and almost
indistinguishable what defines it as
marijuana is a cannabis plant that is
high in THC and it's currently federally
legal so THC is that psychoactive
cannabinoid that gets you the
what's associated with cannabis or
marijuana is the high hemp is at less
than three point zero point three
percent THC and typically grown for its
fiber or its medicinal CBD value so hemp
and marijuana are both classified on
cannabis hemp is going to be by far our
focus here now current or modern
cannabis is represented by many
cultivars cultivated varieties that are
often unstable taxonomic foundations
they'll hear these names that for
example isn't called green crack all
this crazy names very unstable taxonomic
foundations the names are very variable
so it gets into how do we name cannabis
well an application of the taxon systems
in the genus cannabis together with
sativa and indica a distinction should
be avoided the sativa indica not really
a great correlation to the plant may
indicate the morphology of the plant but
doesn't go much beyond that the whole
goal here is kind of to use the
international code for a nomenclature
for cultivated plants or even aid the IC
and CP and is not man Terry uses beats
to sit epithets so sativa or indica or a
combination of the genus name and
cultivar epithet in any language and
downed by single quotation marks so an
example would be cannabis and then in
single quotation marks would be the
cultivar that be used so this defines
the name of that cannabis cultivar
there's been literally hundreds of
cannabis cultivated varieties developed
and named by medical patients and also
recreational users the downfall to
utilizing or adopting this system is
that few of these have been treated as
the real cannabis cultivars and having
been regularly named and registered
according to the proper channels so the
name such as CR super Lemon bud that
green crack Skywalker or all kind of
just names used by recreational users
and really don't have any core meaning
as far as the proper way to name a plant
with a lack of a standard this is
causing a major issue but dick
with marijuana strains that lack an
adequate description for this reason
their names cannot be accepted as
cultivar the epithets so any strain that
has not been formally described as a
cultivar for example the so called Sour
Diesel should be named is file as
follows the cannabis strain Sour Diesel
with their popularized name without
single quotation marks having in mind
that their names have no Texan avakov
elyda t so just because Sour Diesel is
very common high THC form of cannabis on
the East Coast
really that names is kind of tossed
around and doesn't have that true
taxonomical background because there's
lack of a standard so see here a blood
of Sour Diesel here's above Argo
blackberry really these names are just
kind of out there and used but aren't
really scientifically backed