so here i'm gonna try to answer the
question what is evolution
if you want kind of a fun music video to
kind of watch
well it may not be 100 scientifically
accurate uh right here right now
by uh fat boy slim is something you can
take a look at they kind of show
in there in that particular music video
process of evolution
so starting with what is evolution well
it's a change over time building on past
and current features so products evolve
knowledge evolves
and beliefs can evolve as well so don't
think it's just any one thing
is the example here clearly of the
phones and how they have evolved
uh within the mobile phone industry also
the changing that
that has occurred so within our uh
evolution
it's the mark of an educated mind to be
able to entertain the thought without
accepting it i know this can be a highly
debated or contested
topic so just keep that in mind as well
evolutionary patterns in biology have
been noted as far back as aristotle as
one of
his quotes there in the the bc era
darwin initially used the phrase to send
with modification
to explain the concept of evolution
now what is evolution looking at these
patterns of evolution
evolution have been observed in three
major areas
fossil records anatomical features and
molecular
distances so are fossil records finding
them in different layers how things may
have
changed again over time the different
layers of rock
anatomical features what similarities we
may see
that exist that may show a progression
and molecular
distances looking at our dna and what
similarities may be exist
there as well so looking at the fossil
records a little bit more detail
the evolution of a horse here provides
the most direct evidence for
macroevolution fossils are preserved
remain tracks and traces and once living
organisms
they are formed when organisms become
buried in sediment and calcium
in hard surfaces and are mineralized
array of fossils according to age have
often been provided
as excessive evolutionary change here
we're seeing the development
of what was once kind of many many toes
here to kind of
that one central hoof of a modern horse
array of fossils according to age
provides evidence of successive
evolutionary change
we can kind of see that over a long
period of time here you can also see
consistency so here we see different
rock layers and we're seeing
consistencies
uh over a period of time as well so
we're seeing things progress we're
seeing things found in the same layer
different regions
indicating they existed over multiple
areas all during the same
time this kind of shows also the kind of
formation of where things may have
existed and went extinct at certain
points
as well within our fossil records and
get very detailed
fossils have been found linking all
major groups the forms of linking
mammals to reptiles is particularly well
known you can see the high degree of
specificity that occurs here and how we
can trace things back
to common ancestors in group things as
similar species or similar related
species as well
so all things to consider here it can
get very very complex
looking at kind of one brief example
here looking at the kind of the the
whale
and kind of going back and where that
may have come from well when we're kind
of looking at this whale evolution
looking at it may once have derived from
organisms that once had
legs may have been land based as well
looking at the cow and the hippo here
kind of having distant relationships
and some of the progression in how
things don't necessarily always get
necessarily more complex
with evolution there's a better fitting
to their
environment now the anatomical records
looking specifically
it has a little cartoon representation
here but all for it rates share a
set of developmental instructions these
kind of
this fish this reptile this bird and
this human all kind of look the same if
i didn't put the
kind of titles here indicating that
there may be some
similarities that may have occurred
because they all look the same starting
very early on
now if you look at the kind of the
actual images uh you can see kind of the
same
pattern reptile the bird and the human
here very hard to distinguish the two
from a very early on indicating they may
have some sort of connection
uh early on to some sort of similar
species
we talk about homology and homologous
structures these are similar anatomical
anatomically but have different
functions they have different structure
and function but are all derived from
the same part of a common ancestor
chemistry produces this one two five
structures example provided here
adaptations to different environments
with modified its structure in several
ways
we see that here where we're having the
same anatomy the same
bones but very different functions the
human the cat the whale and the bat
well they have the same bones but the
humans using it for grabbing the cat's
using it for walking the whale for
swimming and the bat for flying
analogous structures in comparison have
similar features and functions
they resemble each other a result of a
parallel evolutionary adaptation
so here we have a fish we have a bird we
have a mammal
and they have these very similar or
analogous kind of structures
all used for swimming but if you notice
that the bone structures are different
but they've kind of reached the same
end structure to be able to best meet
the challenges of their environment
that quick comparison of analogous and
homologous structures
again it kind of puts those two parts
together same
bones different functions different
bones same
function this also groups them as well
we see
here analogous structures all used for
swimming they have a different structure
but similar function
here we have similar structure but
different function as well just another
way to present the same
information so we're looking at
convergent evolution there's many paths
to one goal
so we have convergent and divergent so
divergent may be easier to initially
understand where we have a
vertebrae and we're separating out into
two distinctive paths
for example this branch on the left is
going to produce gills
and this branch on the right is going to
produce lungs
now when we have convergent evolutions
while we have this separation
now we have the shark and the dolphin
they're both living in an aquatic
environment while one may have gills
one may have lungs uh they are starting
to develop that streamlined appearance
uh they're trying to develop those fins
having that convergent evolution they're
kind of coming back and having very
similar
features despite being separated out one
having lungs again and one having gills
analogous structures are result of
convergent evolution different animals
often adapt in similar fashion when
challenges
by similar opportunities exist and we
can see that with
different animals living in different
parts of the world developing very
similar structures
to meet the challenges of very similar
environments