okay so here we look at what a soil test
tells you so you get to be adults back
it's a bunch of numbers what's the point
of taking it if you listen really
closely though well some people may have
to listen and think it's only whispering
to you others can look at a soil test
and hear on megaphone so keep in mind
that so that's gonna be a lot of good
information and then go through some of
that here so first off we're looking at
what's it screamed for well this is
looking at a general soil test you
looking at
typical nutrients calcium magnesium
phosphorus potassium else is immune to
iron manganese copper zinc aluminum
boron and so pH is also a great item to
get and can screen screen for typically
total lead which is more addressing the
potential for soil contaminants also
some for some I'll appropriate from
mineral soils so we're looking at me in
the field based soils here there's some
very common standard nutrient tests that
most labs will test for the report tells
you is an estimation of plant available
nutrients and this is an important
concept it is not the total amount of
the element in the soil
it's estimating the plant available
nutrients they did is the Nucci numbers
provide an idea what the roots have
access to and this comes back to this
chart here we can see how pH can vastly
impact the availability of nutrients now
so Tess attempts to estimate within a
close degree of tolerance of what that
plant can pull out of the soil so just
for example looking at potassium and we
get a very acidic pH pH below 5 we can
see the availability is much reduced
again it could mean that there's a lot
of potassium in the soil but it's not
very plant available so it will test low
on your nutrient analysis for your soil
report on other tests screen for example
organic matter this can be added to a
lot of standard nutrient tests and
determine what's called by a loss
ignition test this means this sample is
tried in the lab will weigh it they'll
literally burn it in an every way the
concept here is that the organic matter
is burned off leading only mineral ash
left the amount that's lost is the
organic content and that's expressed as
a percentage so just gives a little
background on how organic matter is
typically
the procedure is typically done for that
number you see in the soil test most
growers will want high organic matter it
really depends on what your need is or
starting level is in men in their soil
six to nine percent is a typical range
but I've seen twenty percent or greater
this tends to leave the excessive
nutrients increased disease pressure
high water holding capacity on this can
cause an issue so more is not always
better for I get it better if you're at
the six to nine range and modified that
that's probably plenty good right there
if I haven't even seen lower organic
matter percentages performing at a high
level overall in the country the soil
organic matter the higher ranges are the
darker colors it's the overall soils
tend to be a little bit higher organic
matter in this region and a little bit
lower organic matter in the southwest
region so just kind of gives you that
kind of perspective but just in general
in the country where higher native or
natural soil organic matter is present
what this shows is a percent change of
percent acres of organic matter so a
30-year percent change in soil organic
carbon in particular so carbon is kind
of one key measures of organic matters
so 30-year change compared to soil
organic carbon one year typically what
we see in the reds is where we're seeing
a loss then the greens is we're seeing a
game in that everywhere has data
cropland reported you can see there are
hairs that are depleting organic matter
at what can be consumed times considered
a alarming rate especially we're looking
at depending more and more on smaller
land parcels for agricultural produce
crops something else a soil report may
give you or may have the option to
include is something called soluble
salts this fat is typically only in
comes back oh they did have salts have
been added to the area and salts can be
include chemical fertilizer compost or
even areas where snowmelt may be applied
in winter months it's a good idea to
test at the beginning with proper
management future testing this test may
not be necessary you mean you don't
always have you to include this with
every test but when you're starting with
an area it's a good one to include on
the testing list thank you James a
little bit of a weird one
these values are only as good as your
sample meaning it's a volatile
nutrient it's constantly changing in
order to get results that are filled
representives certain steps should be
taken during the sampling process to
ensure accuracy which is analysis by the
lab typically this is performed in the
month of June especially for corn
growers it's called a June nitrate test
because this tangent is always changing
if you test early in the season when
soils are cold they'll get an
artificially low value so this psmt or
precise beta nitrate test to come in
tune I want to take a full one foot core
and here's corn for example and going
right through and sampling here and here
right along the row and kind of a zigzag
form and taking those six to nine
samples or so they want to be attentive
when taking soil samples and this is
true for any type of sample we can kind
of see in this image here this is a
large corn field and kind of shows what
I'm trying to point try to get across we
could see the coloration in the
foreground here nice and green and the
coloration here by the homestead also
green but if you look at it in this area
in the middle this see it's a little bit
lighter yellow here so this might be an
area you want a sample differently or
separately this could be caused
potentially visible of nutrients could
because it could be a water or a
drainage issue here could be so profile
issue could be it all all the above so
we want to sample this indifferently so
we can see if the problem is in the
nutrients of this particular section of
this field lastly there's something
called particle size this is an
expensive test is often not caustic
justifiable for most growing conditions
it's basically the assessment of the
particle size of your soil this test is
a greater importance for golf courses
especially putting greens looking to
maintain those nice eating conditions so
for most growers I can't really
recommend the edit cost we really can't
modify for that just to give you some
background that it is possible to get
the particle size evaluation of your
soil