welcome to this debacco University video
with yet another collaboration with
Shane from migro here we're going to be
looking at what the best par intensity
for plants is as the image shows here
plant par intensity versus growth rate
will be compared in addition we'll get
into carbon dioxide enrichment and how
that impacts plants as well as DLI The
Daily Light integral and providing you
with an easy equation to do some
calculations to determine what you are
giving your plants
[Music]
well welcome Shane again we've uh got
Shane from micr grow here today we're
going to be discussing Optimum par
intensity in DLI now par intensity and
Par we have another video released I'm
going into a little bit more in depth on
what that is basically is looking at the
intensity um of light of range of
spectrums
here we're going to be looking at how it
relates to plants in a little bit more
of a specific way starting with plants
photosynthesize uh so with this par
intensity is this basically the same
needed no matter what plant I'm growing
Shane or is there differences with that
there are definitely differences um
plants have developed in nature um to
succeed in different environmental
conditions so for example there are
plants which are optimized to grow with
relatively L fire intensity plants that
would grow for example on a forest floor
where there would be a lot of
shade and for cannabis
cannabis is able to use high power
intensity so it has been shown that
there is continuous increase in
photosynthesis all the way up to about,
1500 micromoles of par intensity um
which is a a high level um after which
you get a reducing rate of
return now that intensity is important
because you know we're trying to
maximize all of our plants and
production if we're growing a plant that
needs a little less we can cut back on
that gr a plant needs a little bit more
well now we can justify that more
intense light now with lighting we're
typically growing in indoor environments
um and that gives some Growers the
option of adding CO2 and you hear a lot
about this you know it's part of the
photosynthetic equation um how may that
change things when related to par light
intensity and plant
production yeah so plants are absorbing
the photons from light and they're using
that energy to photosynthesize and
photosynthesis uses CO2 um as part of
that chemical reaction having enriched
CO2 so higher than would be available in
in the normal atmosphere which is about
400 parts per million to increase that
CO2 level so you have a closed system
and you're supplementing that CO2 with
either you know CO2 gas or a burner or
whatever system you're using you can
enrich that level of CO2 and it has been
demonstrated that enriching that up to
about 12 or 1300 parts per million can
increase the relative growth rate by up
to
30% that's the for the same in light
intensity and uh environmental
conditions and um plant genetics you can
have a relative increase of growth with
um with higher with concentrated CO2 of
up to 30% which is quite extor read yeah
that CO2 can uh definitely with the
light intensity definitely help increase
plant production keep in mind as Growers
you have to keep your water and
nutrients and everything else
supplemented as well but lighting and
CO2 is a big part of that photosynthetic
equation now when we're talking about
this intensity of light we're not just
giving them like a burst or a flash of
light something that's brought up is
called DL which is looking more about
the intensity of light or the summation
of light that it experien expences the
plant has over the over a day or the
lighting period can you go a little bit
more about this DLI maybe how it's
calculated and how Growers can better
understand how they can apply this to
the plants they growing yes when we
measure par we're measuring par at a
moment in time so that par intensity is
measuring the
photons um the intensity of the quantity
of photons over a meter squared per
second d I is actually measuring the
amount of power that will accumulate
over the light cycle so say for example
you're running at a 12-hour light cycle
you're multiplying the 12-h hour light
cycle by the number of minutes in that
hour by the number of seconds um in
those minutes by the instantaneous power
intensity and to give an example if
you're running at about 800 micro moles
of power over a 12h hour day that
generally would equate to around 40 DLI
um which is considered on the upper end
of what a plant can absorb over over one
light cycle um I would be used you know
for example in in in tomato growing if
you're supplementing um but also can be
um related to cannabis growth as
well and that's important to keep in
note if uh you know if you're growing a
photo period dependent plant you're
switching it from an 18-hour light Day
to a 12-h hour light day that will imp
your DLI as Growers so that's where
people will use more intense lights and
flowering to try to make up for that
loss of time be aware it can only go so
high the plants can only utilize so much
and I would add to that as well Matthew
that um with um with regard to we've got
typically cannabis Growers would be
growing either photo period plants which
would be flowering on a 12h hour cycle
but they may also be growing Autoflower
plants which Growers would often have a
20h hour life cycle generally I could I
would recommend a a lower average par
intensity for um Autoflower plants
because they're they're growing over a
longer day cycle and therefore they're
going to be absorbing more over that um
that longer cycle hence the lower light
intensity
recommendation excellent great point and
I know some people have explained it to
me and try to do the same think about
like a rain gauge you know you're how
much water are you accumulating over a
day versus how much is falling right now
and what's falling right now would be
the par DLI would be that accumulation
over a day when the lights go out empty
the empty the can out and then you can
go through and remeasure the next day so
just giving them more in a burst like
rainwater doesn't do much good for the
plants just like en lighten you have
have the chance of burning them so Shane
thank you for the uh detailed
information there little good background
there to hopefully allow our Growers to
better understand some of these
complexities to help improve the
efficiency of their growing
operation