this debaco university video will tell
you what to look for when diagnosing
brusset mites however we're going to
toss it over to my student connor and
we're going to let him kind of guide you
through what he looks for on canvas
plans when it comes to identifying
russet mites there's other videos on
this on the channel i'll put those in a
link in the description but for right
now let me turn over to connor us to go
over what to look for for russet mites
[Music]
so on canvas plants what i personally
look for
on on the new shoots of the the plant
itself on the new growth
um i'll use like a low
magnification
dissecting scope to
really get in there usually like one to
two times
um and what i'm looking for is little
tiny grub like larvae
almost like like a maggot that is
covering the the new growth ball that is
um
forming on the plant
and
what you'll actually see is not only
just larvae but you'll see
a few adult
live
larger
mites
almost look like spiders running around
kind of tending to the larvae and laying
new larvae
um well normally on like the small
like new buds that are forming on the
actual leaves you'll see them too
especially in the internodes of the
leaves
where the leaf actually connects to the
the stem of the the plant itself
right there that little green spot is
where
i find to be the the highest traffic
area
[Music]
so on the actual plant itself
these insects and their larvae are not
that visible to the eye but what you can
see with your eyes is the damage that
they cause to the actual plant um i'll
usually notice it on the lower leaves
first
um it'll be
as you can see here this weird kind of
color
green almost like a tannish burnt brown
orange color
on the new nodes of bud growth plant
for example on this branch right here
you can see this weird almost folding of
the outer rim
of the plant leaves
um
on multiple occasions here and even on
the new growth if you look it's already
coming in pre-folded
i call this tacoing
and this is a true identity identicator
of
russet mites on him
and what you also notice when you have
russets is a weird odd discoloration of
the
initial new growth spots almost like a
tannish even on this one too you can see
a tannish almost burnt orangey tinge on
the plants
compared to say
some nice green growth like over here
it's a lot more lighter green almost a
yellow blood growth
and you'll also notice on the leaves
itself
some stippling and some damage and
that's caused by the larvae feeding on
the actual
plant structure itself
over here is another good example
you can see that how almost orange and
burnt it is compared to
a new healthy growth right here well as
you can see here on this healthy plant
on my in my left hand you have nice
straight internodes
nice healthy white
almost white green growth
then you look over on the russet
infected plant
and
the growth is not straight it's curly
almost burnt
you see slight orange here on the
internodes
and overall just looks like there's
something off about the plant
and on the new growth up here
on the on the healthy plant
look at how straight those leaves are
very nice and healthy and
has a lot of pressure in them but over
here almost getting wilt and curled
leaves and the new growth
and that's caused by once again the
feeding of the larvae on the plant
structure itself
hindering our yield in the long run