so here in this debaco university video
we're going to go over what a cannabis
clone is and also
what it is not
[Music]
let's go through and answer the question
what a cannabis clone is and what it is
not
so first off what is a clone it's kind
of we hear them a lot
and they get this like mythical kind of
like connotation with them
a clone is simply a cutting from a stock
or mother plant
it's an asexual vegetative propagated
plant material so that's why they're so
called clones
instead of that long kind of terminology
there but that's actually botanically
what a clone is a clone is also
genetically the same as the original
plants that's why it's advantageous
we have unique individuals to go through
this cloning process
however what is a clone knot you know
when we're looking at a clone well a
clone is not a seedling
seedling here starts from the seed
develops cotyledons and it's kind of
that new emergence
your clone is that cutting asexual
vegetative propagation from an original
plant clones also will technically lack
that defined central tap root
that you see with seedlings they still
can produce an aggressive set of roots
but they will lack that central tap root
so it's important to realize that if
you're growing clones versus seedlings
you are not going to have that central
taproot with clones as you would if you
were starting with a young
seedling so why do growers like clones
they like them because it's guaranteed
or at least consistent genetics
and known gender of the plant so those
are two great aspects that are very
advantageous for growers to know
so they're not wasting their time with
potentially a seedling that might be a
male when they want a female
may not be a cross it might be new and
they wouldn't know what they're getting
so this is why growers really like
clones however for growers that like
clones
there's also what reasons why growers
don't like clones
so it's a reason why grower wouldn't
like a clone well it's a
challenge to plant you're not starting
with that small seedling you're dealing
with a
literally a plant there's also typically
increased cost per plant
versus seeds so that can cause an
increase in upfront cost for growers
but a lot of growers feel that the
advantage that i mentioned
outweigh these potential downfalls but
this is why there are those
options to plant clones or start with
seedlings
the option is up to you to choose what
fits best for your situation