okay here we're looking at the simple
question what is light keep in mind when
we're relating it to plants we want to
keep in mind whether we're talking about
a actual sunlight or for looking at
artificial light and how that may differ
between the two and what spectrums they
may give so first off we're looking at
the electromagnetic spectrum which is
the range of all types of
electromagnetic radiation the radiation
is energy that travels and spreads out
as it travels examples of though are
radio waves visible light which is only
a small portion of the full
electromagnetic spectrum UV light in
x-rays and gamma-rays
also so again keep in mind of this
entire range only a very small portion
of that is actually visible light the
light spectrum it's many different
wavelengths of energy produced by a
light source now light is measured and
it's called nanometers and you can think
of that as really small meters each
nanometer represents a wavelength of
light or band of energy but this image
prism tries to show here we have white
light coming in and we have the
different colors being separated out
however if we look closely and also we
see that here there's different
wavelengths so you can see the red is a
much longer wavelength than say the
Indigo or the violet down here much
shorter wavelength we see that also down
over here also keep in mind this light
spectrum is visible light is only a very
small portion of the entire
electromagnetic spectrum so it brings a
question of well what's sun light
suddenly something gives off infrared
visible and ultraviolet light so it's
filtered through the Earth's atmosphere
and is a combination of that ultraviolet
or UV light visible light and also
infrared radiation between Terp as heat
so sometimes a wide variety of things
more than just what we visibly can see
so what's that visible light well that
visible spectrum is the portion of the
electromagnetic spectrum that's visible
to the human eye in typical human I
respond to wavelengths from 380 to 740
nanometers again a very small range of
the entire electromagnetic spectrum one
thing I do want to point out as we saw
in the previous images radio eights are
still the long waves but in this case
they're on the right-hand side and some
of the other images they're on the left
- inside so just keep in mind you have
to be looking at the units we see any
sort of spectrum or chart here red is
kind of that larger wave length and
those violets and blues are those
shorter wavelengths that'll always
remain a constant keep in mind doesn't
mean they're always going to be on the
left or the right side now color
temperature this is measured in degrees
Kelvin is more for us humans than the
plants were trying to grow so a lot of
emphasis is put on the Kelvin
temperature chart when looking at
interior lighting for lighting up a
particular room because our eyes have a
harder time distinguishing changes at
the ends are the blue and red colors of
the visible light our eyes are actually
Mohsen to green or 555 nanometers here
at the highest perceived brightness
these other warm whites neutrals or
daylight's again apply more to interior
design than it does plants even though
some grow lights will quote the color
temperature it's of little importance to
plants