this is a term that gets tossed down a
lot that's pH you know live check your
pH what's the pH speech went up went
down where I look here exactly what is
pH well the definition is it's the
measure of molar concentrations of
hydrogen ions in a solution it can
towards whether it's an acid or a base
what is this measure kind of mean while
we're measuring hydrogen ions
what's a hydrogen ion well it's a
hydrogen atom that has a charge in this
case a hydrogen ion has a positive
charge here
a cation typically hydrogen contains a
proton and electron when it loses that
electron becomes just a proton and here
we have our hydrogen ion and that
hydrogen ion h+ cations also usually
just refer to or sometimes as just a
proton now the scale of pH it's measured
from 0 to 14 if you're us under 7 that
range of pH is is considered acidic 7 is
considered neutral and above 7 is the
basic range or alkaline now pH directly
means potential of hydrogen the scale is
a logarithmic we'll talk about that a
little bit do you determine the city a
basis of a water based aqueous which is
increasing from water based solution
there's also something called Poh and
that's potential of hydroxide and while
we typically focus on pH hydroxides kind
of like the opposite so we take P h2 and
the Poh of that would be 12 if we add
them together we get 14 which is our
scale here so again we're focusing on
the hydrogen ions here are the 0 14
scale there's also a Poh it works on the
same 0 to 14 CL it's kind of just the
opposite you can kind of see related
here but again our focus here is pH now
acids and bases so an acid is a
substance that increases the hydrogen
ion concentration of a solution so this
kind of lever shows here as the hydrogen
ions increase the pH will decrease so
examples of tomato juice grapefruit
juice and lemon juice
they have investing amounts of hydrogen
ions therefore the pH becomes lower
bases are any substance that reduces the
hydrogen ion concentration in a solution
that's defined as a base simply those
bases reduced hydrogen ions directly by
accepting them again examples of
solutions that are bases
be like baking soda ammonia and bleaches
and drain cleaners those are much more
in the base side or that pH below 7 pH
neutral is set is 7 so this is a
solution that's not acidic or alkaline
such as pure water pure h2o there's a pH
of 7 you can see these universal
indicators you know colors that they may
turn typically around that green range
would be representative of a solution
within neutral pH the pH scale of the
aqueous solution it's the measure of the
hydrogen and hydroxide ions measure of
the zero to 14 degree in most biological
fluids are in the page range of 6 to 8
each pH unit represents a tenfold a
difference that scales logarithm we see
it here this means a small change in pH
actually indicates a substantial change
in hydrogen and hydroxide ion
concentrations as you can kind of see an
example here 2 tenfold increase we're
moving that decimal place every pH so
you can see a large difference and we
may hear terms something called like
strong acids or bases so what does this
mean well strong acids and bases are
ones that completely disassociate in
water so here we see hydrochloric acid
HCL that breaks apart into a hydrogen
ion and chloride ion completely the
strong base here sodium hydroxide sodium
and hydroxide completely breaking apart
in water weak acids and bases they only
partially break apart either they only
partially break apart they can kind of
flip back and forth that's what these
arrows refer to so sometimes we see
strong acids strong bases weak acids
weak bases and this is just kind of
giving you the background of the kind of
a chemistry that's going on behind these
now we had a acid and a base for example
a strong acid and the strong base mix
them together in equal proportions we
should get pure water and salt what does
that look like here well if you have
hydrochloric acid and sodium hydroxide
which I mentioned are both strong acids
and strong bases they'll break apart
into h2o and sodium chloride that's
basically water flipping back and forth
so where does the h2o come from we have
the H here in H here that's the two H's
in the oxygen form in water and in the
sodium and the chloride forming here so
you kind of get salt water in an ideal
situation mixing a strong acid in base
here the pH scale is a concentration of
hydrogen
and given substance in the equation
behind that speech equals minus the log
and these brackets mean concentration of
hydrogen ions what does this kind of
look like kind of in a graphical
representation here
well pH neutral seven has equal amounts
of hydrogen ions in equal amounts of
hydroxide ions as we become increasing
acidity we are working our way this way
we can see the percentage of our hydrant
ions increases as we become more basic
the hydrogen ions decrease remember as I
mentioned the pH we're talking about it
from the standpoint Poh would look at
the opposite and that's the hydroxide
ion so you can see how that changes as
we shift our pH from 7 now here's just
an example why being precise with pH is
important how much greater is the
hydrogen ion concentration in the
solution with pH 2 than a pH with
solutions 6 so we're looking at this is
only a difference of 4 but we apply this
to this equation here pH minus the log
of the hydrogen ion concentration
comparing these two pH is that only
differ by 4 well it's not just off
difference of 4 points it's actually a
difference of 10,000 times greater our
four decimal places greater that's
because again this is a logarithmic
scale so that's why it's very important
to maintain pH in a very tight range
because if you don't really bad things
can happen in biological systems so so
allow these organisms to buffer
themselves on these PHS what is a buffer
mean well it resists a change in pH may
help order in particular the body and
also in plants with peaches within a
narrow range there are combinations of
hydrogen ion acceptors and donors to
help kind of reduce the change that
occurs so let's take distilled water for
an extreme example here is our volume of
sodium hydroxide this is a strong base
added so we started at neutral pH and we
add the ever slightest drop of sodium
hydroxide and we see the peach spiked up
immediately then we have different
levels of buffer or different
concentrations above her you can see
even adding a very small amount of
buffer will reduce that the quickly
changing pH the higher amount of buffer
here we can see we maintain
this ph prayed well consistent
throughout all the different volume of
sodium hydroxide found added here so
again this helps organisms maintain life
or homeostasis you're maintaining a very
tight buffer system for your blood so
this is very important that your blood
stays in a very tight range of 7.34 to
7.38 that's normal pH of 7 to 7 point
it's gonna cause some issues and if you
reach as low as a pH of 6 or as high pH
of 9 it's gonna result in death luckily
your body has ways of maintaining this
through buffers and other means and we
can see just the importance of
maintaining pH knowing what it is and
keeping it within a tight range to allow
organs to grow and develop