here we're gonna look at the common
plant pest called white flies now it's
advantageous when the name kind of
matches what they look like and they do
look like small white flies since
they've like in the close-up version and
here's a elevated population on the
underside of this leaf here so the
identification they're about one
millimeter long and a white moth like
look to them but I look like little
flies yellow sticky traps can be used
for monitoring so it's good if you're
implementing those and close to your
plants to be able to capture these for
monitoring purposes these white flies
damage plants by sucking the SAP and
vectoring the plant viruses as well so
not only is it the physical damage they
can do but some of the viruses that they
can infect her can also be a way to kind
of reduce plants yield and cause disease
to spread from plant to plant now where
to look for them they're typically found
on the underside of the leaves and see a
high population here a damage can be
mistaken for eight hit damage initially
so it's important to kind of do that
inspection not to say oh that's small
insects kind of look a little bit closer
and do you see the small white flies if
you bump the plants you might notice if
the fly is going to show themselves they
kind of fly out and around and kind of
retreat back to the plant glaze up to
the leaves with sticky honeydew is a
signature sign that white flies are
nearby because of the piercing sucking
that they are able to do to that leaf
they can kind of get that kind of glaze
kind of sticky nice honeydew look as the
sap from the plant the sugars are kind
of being released because of the feeding
that's occurring how to prevent them
well if you're an outdoor growing avoid
Berg eggplant the sweet potato tobacco
or tomatoes as these can be very common
host for white flies particularly
Tomatoes I've seen completely covered in
white flies so it can be kind of a
breeding ground for that you want a bag
and remove heavily infected plants Oster
you're limiting any kind of
cross-contamination if you're in indoor
girl you don't wanna pull one plant out
and drag it down the hallway because
that can be picked up in the ventilation
and other plants can become infected
that way how to control them well it's
very difficult but there's biological
control such as parasitic wasps but it
can be used in cursive Formosa is very
common it can offer effective
control but keep in mind these have a
tendency to be attracted to HID lights
those high intensity lights and sadly
they can kind of fly to their death as a
result if you're going to be using this
kind of parasitic wasps typically want
to find it or put it deep into the
canopy where it's more shaded from the
plant leaves someday or another option
since these can affect white flies
through their skin and in small
operations it's possible to live vacuum
them up white flies by shaking the plant
shaking the plant have gone through and
literally evacuating them up to reduce
their numbers this shows it tomato leaf
with white flight nymphs that are the
white and parasitized ones that are
black so you can see here this is a good
sign that the biological control is
doing his job it takes a little time for
it to get established and spread through
the area but if established properly it
can be a method of effective control for
white flies