on this debaco university video why
flower id is important for cannabis
production will be covered
there also is another video on this
channel which will go over exactly
how to identify both male and female
flowers on cannabis plants
[Music]
so we see pictured here a nice female
flower we're going to go over in this
video lecture
wi-fi flower identification is important
for cannabis production so first off we
have those
male versus female flowers that we need
to be mindful
and well-versed in identifying because
cannabis plants produce distinctive male
and female plants
they are a diocese plant you have a male
plant or you're going to have a female
plant
female flowers or plants produce the
buds where the cannabinoids and terpenes
are produced
and the plants are considered to be very
sought after by growers
male flowers or plants produce pollen
and which is needed for
the formation of seed production male
plants need to be removed from an
area of female plants to allow for
female flowers to remain unpollinated
and produce chemical compounds in the
greatest concentration
this is called the sensamilla or
seedless harvest for if we have a male
and a female plant together
the female plant will then produce seeds
if the pollen from the male plant
is received by the female flower here
and these are looking at the pre-flower
determinations
and again it'll be another video going
over the details identifying those both
uh in images as well as in the field
so what if we get feminized seed and a
lot of growers were buying feminized
seed and they think this is great enough
to worry about male plants
so do you really need to id plants if
you start with feminized seed well
without a doubt i would say
yes even if the seed is 99
uh feminized the seeds are female it
still means one out of a hundred
will be male or a hundred out of ten
thousand plants will be male
so depending on how much scale you're
growing that can have a
great impact so in large growing field
it's very important once
as once one male plant can produce high
amounts of pollen
and reduce the productivity of female
plants drastically now if you're only
growing five
six seeds like a 99 chance odds are
you're going to have mostly female seeds
but still wise to go through
and be able to recognize what a male
plant male flowers look like
so in our large growing areas our
operations the large
plant production facilities flower
division is
very important as one male can
contaminate the female plants but
contaminating quotes because it's
basically just producing pollen
which will cause those females to
produce seeds and not cannabinoids
repeated walking the fields is important
to be sure to catch the males as soon as
they can visually be identified
there is some time they don't
immediately just produce pollen there is
some time to catch those
male flowers before they will produce
pollen that will be exposed to the
environment and potentially pollinate
neighboring female plants
for indoor operations a one male plant
in indoor operations can quickly spread
pollen especially via ventilation
systems and that's why it should be
removed
very quickly amongst identification
because it's pretty much a closed
environment
can spread that pollen very quickly now
for clones
ideally with clones they should all be
of known ideally female
gender however in some cases there can
be an odd male plants and knowing the
difference is still important
in this case the producer of the clone
should be contacted to inform them that
your identification
since it's not what you would be
expecting buying clones you're expecting
female plants and 100 female plants at
that good to let the producer know if
you did get a rogue mail
just as good practice because odds are
that might show that might be some
confusion
in their cloning practices may have want
to reverted back but for the most part
clones you're expecting
to get 100 female plants