are you a fan of autoflowers but
wondered why there are no cannabis
autoflower clones available
well here at this debaco university
we're going to answer that question for
you
right here in this video
[Music]
all right let's get into answering this
question on why there are no cannabis
autoflower clones
so i want you first to realize that if
this is possible cloning an autoflower
is possible but the resulting plant will
flower
much too early to produce any viable
yield so
why is this the case that it is possible
to get an autoflower to root
but it's going to yield so much earlier
why is that the case we're taking a
small
little clone from the original stock or
mother plant
well this is important because cloning
does not reset the plant's internal
clock so we want to keep this in mind
that the clone follows the timeline as
the mother or stock plant
meaning if the mother or stock plant is
an autoflower plant it takes about 10
weeks or so just as an example
from seed to flower and you clean it on
week six
the clone will heart will be in harvest
mode in only about
four weeks because it's still set on
that 10-week
seed to flowering time scale with the
stress of cloning this process
will result typically in minimal yields
a small plant
so again that timing and resetting the
plant clock simply doesn't happen
just because you clone that plant
so keep in mind as a reminder
autoflowers are simply based on days old
not the duration of light so once the
plant emerges the clock basically starts
on an autoflower
so if you clone a plant a material it is
still
x days old the cloning process does not
cause the plant to start from day one
again even though it's a small plant
even though we're kind of going through
that
uh regrowing process does not reset that
plant's internal clock
instead the plant keeps counting from
when it first emerged
this is why clones from autoflowers are
not going to be worthwhile
for total yield even though it is
possible to get them to root and to grow
into plants
they're definitely going to be smaller
plants there
so is there a situation for cloned
autoflowers you know just speaking in
general
in isolated cases for potential breeding
of lineages but this does not pertain to
very many growers and therefore this is
why
you don't see autoflowers as an example
if you're looking at purchasing clones