here we're going to look at wipe
transfer and flow blood stain pattern
interpretation
so be able to tell the difference
between these and also
what each of these can tell us about
what may have occurred at the crime
scene
so first off we have wipe patterns these
occur when an object moves through a
blood stain feathered edges suggest the
direction
so we're looking kind of here at a white
pattern this could be
events of struggle this could be
evidence of a body being moved
this is very important to be able to try
to
look at how that object may have moved
because we knew
that when it moved in this wipe pattern
the blood stain was wet at the time
so this is very fresh and very recent
from when the blood was actually
deposited
in this area wipes in swipes pattern
may offer some insight into the events
at the scene as they were occurring
so investigators should be aware that
events during the active scene may
disturb previously deposited stains so
it's trying to get the timing or the
sequence of what may have occurred
so they said these wipe in these fight
patterns to give us an a glimpse at the
active crime scene but keep in mind they
might destroy
previously deposited evidence we have
transfer patterns
these occur when a wet blade object
contacts the secondary surface
very little blood is needed to produce a
stain or to transfer it to the other
objects mirror images of blade objects
is what is produced types of patterns
can be created by bloody footwear
fingerprints hairs and also fabrics
pattern transfer stains are often
overlooked but can provide class or
identifying characteristics
in the example here we're looking at a
shoe this might be able to determine
potentially the type of shoe or the type
of tread the type of size
this can tell us some good information
in addition to it just being a bloody
kind of transfer pattern there might be
more we can glean from this and it's
important to take pictures document the
size because it may be used later
to kind of connect other pieces of
evidence that are found
we also have the pattern transfer
evaluation here we want to look for
patterns within
the stain itself so you want to compare
characteristics with
any item class characteristics so while
exact matches are unlikely in this type
because the stain would have to have
been created under complex
conditions can provide this class
evidence the goal is to create a range
of standards for comparison as this may
be a group of suspect items recovered
from the scene
and compare these standards with the
stain a good example of that would be
a shoe print pattern you know not be
able to produce some
exact same shoe with maybe some exact
trademarks
treadwear i should say but the general
tread marks might be able to be used so
again as a form of class
evidence now transfer from here or here
swipe this is kind of a zoomed in
version here we're looking at a crime
scene
we zoom in on the wall here we can see
this um what the
transfer from the hair or the hair swipe
blood pattern looks like
it's going to give just that kind of
real realistic kind of image on what may
have occurred
and remember this can be used with other
things you may find throughout the crime
scene to be able to tell the story
lastly here we have flow patterns and
this is blood flows from the fundamental
laws of physics and gravity and indicate
body movement after the onset of blood
flow
so this is important because this is
often an irregular pattern
or patterns that are different from
those to be expected may indicate that
the body was moved or
or an object was in the way so this can
be
shown here we have an individual sadly
bleeding here at the head
flow pattern we expect it to fall in
this general direction but we have an
object it may
kind of collect around there might flow
around that object
that can give us an idea of placement of
things in the room at the time
here we see kind of the regular kind of
flow pattern expected to gravity
and we see it coming in contact with the
surface here and adjusting
so again all these things taking into
consideration
can help us develop an idea of what may
have occurred at the particular crime
scene