okay looking at x-linked traits and
colorblindness which is directly related
to the X chromosome so this excellent is
basically sex-linked inheritance the
Harringtons is determined by genes and
the sex chromosomes females have two
copies of the X chromosome and the males
have one copy of X and one copy of Y the
reason why this is important is the X
chromosomes can contain about 2500 genes
while the puny little Y chromosome only
contains about 15 so excellent genes are
only found on the X chromosome and are
typically passed from mothers to sons
never master Danford in males since
there's no y counterpart so we can
almost disregard the Y so if you're a
male you have one X chromosome meaning
whatever genes you have on that are
expressed in evidence the females have
two x's meaning if there's a defect in
one they kind of like a backup copy
where the nails simply do not
that's why males were more likely to be
colorblind than females so this x-linked
dominant recessive trait so males are XY
a single copy of the X chromosome
females have two copies males only get
an X chromosome from their mother
females get an X chromosome from each
parent both mom and dad it kind of shows
it here here's our two x's and the
female our X and our Y from the nail so
x-linked dominant recessive males only
get X chromosomes from their mother it's
the only place that they can get it cuz
dad can cannot give two x's to their
daughters but their sons get one X from
mom and the Y from their dad now when
we're looking at our chromosomes we look
down here if it's an X and a Y we know
this is the map for a male if this was
two x's we know this would be the a map
for a female females get the X
chromosome from each parent they're more
likely to show x-linked dominant
disorders because they have essentially
two copies so adherence of an x-linked
dominant mutation from infected mother a
woman with an x-linked dominant disorder
has 50% chance of having an affected
daughter or son with each pregnancy and
that shows here we have our affected as
the white again
only has one X in the puny little Y sons
will get that one X from mom and they're
only extra mom where daughters will get
an X from mom and an X from dad
so as a result the odds are in this case
here the affected son and daughters have
a 50% chance of having it affected gene
now far excellent dominant with the
affected father being the case the sons
will always be safe because in this case
they have to get their extra mom and mom
is unaffected
the daughters however they will all be
basically affected by this because they
have to get one of those X's from dad in
this case it's a dominant x-linked they
will all Express that tree so that's
good in the bad of how excellent
dominant recessive disorders
another example here just put it into
some colors same basic pattern as before
I want you to take a look at these you
can pause the video to see if you can
kind of trace and see how this plays out
remembering that females get an extra
mom and dad males have to get their ex
from mom and this again shows a next
dominant affected and mother here in
this case represent I read and just see
how that kind of traces out X recessive
carry your mother remember carrier will
only have on half and how that affects
both sons and daughters sons could be
unaffected or simply affected there's no
middle ground in this case females could
be unaffected or a carrier in this case
so that's it the colorblind fun part
here so what is colorblindness so just
the basics it's an admirable condition
characterized by the inability to
clearly distinguish different colors
from the spectrum there were G Biff
spectrum difficulty mild to severe do
two cones located on the redness from
the back of your eye you have these
photoreceptors their retina they're
called cones
they're receptive to color rods or see
more than just black and white this is
an X chromosome link tree now we're
going to focus on humans what dogs don't
have the same cones that we do so not to
disappoint you but if phyto there you
have his favorite red toys a little
fire-engine or something that's red and
you're showing them the red color he
can't see the red he's gonna see it as
this kind of greyish off yellowish color
he'll recognize the shape for you is the
red fire hydrant but he's not gonna see
the red color so if you're looking to
buy dog toys you want to stick with the
blues or the yellows because that's what
they can see green not so much Purple's
also not so great Reds are pretty poor
just based on the cones that they have
in their eyes
so in here too colorblindness again
we're looking at excellent
so carriers in this case will always be
female by the circles males will either
be unaffected or colorblind because they
only have one X chromosome so close by
this house would this look worldwide
affects about one in 12 men or one in
200 women and in total about four and
half percent of the world population is
colorblind with most being male this is
kind of interesting this kind of gives
you an idea of the American flag there's
one two three four and five and how
people with different missing different
colors would look at the American flag
now if you are colorblind yourself it's
not going to be able to appreciate the
differences presented here and some of
the tests so this would be perfect color
blind test
now this by no means is a medical way of
diagnosing what color blindness you may
or may not have but you can look at
these and you should see potentially
some numbers in these some might be
easier to tell than others you're
welcome to go through and take a look at
the mall and see what you see I am gonna
reveal the answers so if you want to
take a pause this would be the time to
pause it okay for those looking for the
answers here we go
I know it's the ones on the bottom here
we're squealing lions this is kind of a
mess of squiggly lines some people have
an easier time seeing some than the
others I'll flip back for a second some
people say that the twelve is really
easy to see up here others 242 some
considers that 71 or is it a 74 and 74
so you can just get an idea here of the
answers
for those playing along to at home this
is another example here today right now
if you're seeing numbers you're not in
good shape I should be seeing shapes in
this one because animal shapes and if
you'd like to you can pause the video
now before I reveal the answers so if
you're looking to compare the two this
is what you should see kind of a bear in
this region with kind of maybe a male in
the foreground a female in the
background a fox in this region kind of
a squirrel and a rabbit over here just
giving the idea what you just actually
should be seeing in that image so
colorblindness it's a condition affects
men more than women heritage genetic
trait hiring Caucasian males and any
other group great video here explaining
and showing a little bit more we found
right here for some descriptions just to
give you an idea of you know what causes
colorblindness and does your read look
the same is what I interpreted as red
there's your green looks the same green
is most often the color most people have
trouble with and just to end here colors
of the rainbow even the idea of try to
give you some examples of some different
types of colorblindness remember
colorblindness doesn't mean you just
can't see all the colors there's
different types of colorblindness
and depending on what how defective your
cones may be or what mutations may have
occurred affects the amount of colors
that you may be able to see and how your
cones in the back of your eye in the
retina interpret the colors and keep in
mind your dog there even in the best
division he's not technically colorblind
he just lacks the cones to see red sees
definitely more of the yellows in blues
there hopefully this was helpful and you
learned a little bit