alright I'm gonna go over a brief
overview of xylem and phloem remember
these are part of vascular plants xylem
is mainly transporting water and
minerals from the roots to the shoots up
the plant and phloem while showing it
moving down they can move throughout the
plant that could be down it could be up
into the side because it's transporting
carbohydrates in this case sucrose from
source areas of the cell to sink areas
where that sugar needs to be stored so
while there's two kinds of a scar tissue
we're going to focus first on xylem
remember floral mean the other enzymes
conducting water and minerals from the
roots to the shoots there's two
conducting elements the tranq heads and
the vessel members and at a microscopic
view this is how they would look our
phloem and xylem now zaimes transporting
that water in those minerals through
these vessel elements and drynke adds
both of these are dead at maturity and
have primary and secondary cell walls
remove are in a plant here the pits and
the pits here the secondary wall is thin
or missing allowing water to flow
laterally so maybe you can see that a
little bit better here where we're
getting some lateral movement of water
now again this is still occurring from
the roots all the way up to the chute
and how it looks at a microscope while
me may not be stained the same color all
the time the xylem is this larger region
some people consider these animal clinic
straws it's may be a way to help you
remember it even though there are these
kind of perforated plates that are
occurring so it's not 100% true does
that say it is it like a straw but it
does certainly look like them on a
microscopic view in contrast to the much
smaller phloem that involved with active
transport
so mentioning phloem let's look at that
a little more detail so phloem is
nutrient conducting tissue it's in close
relation to companion cells there's two
conducting cells there's these sieve
tubes members in these seed cells you
can see an image of that here phloem
transport sugars and other items in
angiosperms which are flowering plants
the safe tube elements contain sugar
solution
see two cells are surrounded areas
supportive of cells so when I say close
relation to companion cells these
companion cells can be either adding
sugar or carbohydrates to the phloem or
taking it out of the phloem
translocation in the phloem phloem is
composed of cells and receive two
elements phloem SAP as it may be
referred to travels who perforations
called sieve two plates neighboring
companion cells carry out metabolic
functions for the seep two elements and
provide them with energy these lateral
sieve areas
connect to decieve to the elements to
the companion cells so what does all
this kind of summarizing mean will these
companion cells are helping add or take
away sugars again moving sugar is -
requires energy requires active
transport so these companion cells in
these cases are the ones responsible of
kind of this loading or unloading of the
phloem sap kind of this direct
comparison for xylem and phloem we see
xylem all the arrows going from in this
case the shoots to from the I should say
from the roots all the way up to the
shoots that one direction from the roots
working its way up through the plant to
the shoots now phloem we see the arrows
going up arrows going down to two-way
flow there's water and food being
exchanged here there's companion cells
there's food storage cells again this is
moving our carbohydrates or sugars
throughout the cell the cells here so
the plant can take energy captured
through the process of Phocis synthesis
and leaves and can bring them to storage
organs another good comparison here is
our xylem again shoots are up the top
here and our roots are down here and
that water is moving from those roots to
those shoots going to the shoes Sloan
can go in both directions here
translocation to the sink the sink is
the area that's taking on metal sugars
needing those sugars sucrose is actually
transferred from the source cells and
decieve to it to the elements this
causes water to enter the phloem from
the xylem as we see here resulting
positive pressure forces the sucrose
water mixture down towards the roots
where sucrose is unloaded here the root
is an example
we are 6l transpiration causes wanted to
return to the leaves through these
island vessels so what is this process
of transpiration that I mentioned well
it's a simple movement of water through
the plant cohesion theory and SAP accent
shown here evaporation from the cells in
the leaves produces negative pressure
and kind of that pulling force and that
gradients causes water to move upward
from the roots to through the xylem so
here's our roots here's our water
molecules entering the roots here going
up through our trunk of the tree and
exiting out the stomata which is in the
leaves the top of the plant here now of
course what is coming in here and
leaving out here also that this kind of
shows you the long way that water can
take and our root cells compared to our
atmosphere the atmosphere is more
negative indicating water's moving from
the roots where it's high water
potential to this area of low water
potential gradient in being essentially
pulled out of the leaves there hopefully
this is helpful in explaining some of
the important functions xylem and phloem
perform in vascular plants