welcome to this debaco university video
where we'll be looking at a population
lab with yeast if you get different
sugar solutions to see how that changes
the yeast population
[Music]
okay so today's lab is going to be
looking at growing yeast here we have uh
some yeast and we have some different
sugar solutions so we're going to take a
look and see what sugar solution the
yeast prefers as far as what does it
grow the best in how we're going to do
that is by measuring or observing the
amount of carbon dioxide that is
produced so we need to develop a way to
capture that so we're going to be using
fermentation test tubes these are large
test tubes and regular small test tubes
i'm going to show you how we're going to
set these up
all right this shows the basic
lab how it should look in the end with
our molasses and honey solutions we'll
also be preparing our refined sugar
here's our stock solutions of honey
refined sugar and molasses as well as
our yeast suspension ready to go
we're going to take our large beakers
this is going to hold everything be
careful this is all a glassware
and i have one of the small test tubes
now measuring the exact amount of liquid
isn't that important we want to make
sure is we're going to fill this up so i
have molasses
regular refined sucrose or sugar and
then i have honey each of these are 20
solution
so i've allocated them out into small
beakers here again we take our test tube
we take our honey solution which is 20
we add approximately
halfway
full of our honey solution
we've got our honey solution there then
we're going to take about 20 drops which
is going to equal one milliliter of our
yeast solution
20 perfect
we've got our yeast solution we can
clearly see is kind of separated out
from the honey so you want to just kind
of
mix that in to get a good even
distribution
and then we're going to fill the test
tube back up with that 20 honey solution
as close to the top as we can get
take our fermentation test tube that
we've got that
full take our fermentation test tube
add that over the top here carefully
this is always glassware
push that up to the very top as we can
see there
and then we're just going to kind of
flip this over
and then we're going to measure the air
bubble that's been produced there and
over time that yeast is going to grow
the co2 gets captured and we'll be able
to measure that over a period of time
we're going to repeat that also with the
other sugar solution
and you can see here pretty much around
the same air bubble and let's see how
they look
tomorrow
so now we've given our
these some time to grow in their various
trigger solutions and we can see there
is varying degrees of happiness going on
we have the molasses we have the honey
and we have the refined sugar this is
the clear one and we can see that there
is a difference between the amount of
carbon dioxide gas produced the amount
of bubbles the greater the bubble height
the greater the amount of yeast so in
our example here the molasses definitely
has the greatest bubble indicating that
the yeast is growing the best in this
sugar solution that would then be
followed by our sucrose or refined sugar
located right here
and lastly it looks like in this example
here the honey had the least amount of
yeast growth relating directly to the
least amount of carbon dioxide produced
how we're going to quantify this well
we're simply going to take a ruler and
we're going to measure in millimeters
the height of that bubble so we're going
to go through and we're going to take
the area from the height of that bubble
to basically the height of that test
tube and measure that in comparison
compare that to our reading we
originally took when we initially
flipped everything over
and got the initial bubble because we
left usually just a little bit of a
bubble there to begin with now we're
able to see how much gas was produced
directly correlating to the amount of
yeast here the population of the yeast
in this sugar solution
and here we can clearly see those
differences this is again the molasses
producing the
most in comparison
the honey here has the least amount
and the refined sugar is clear liquid
solution is a little hard harder to see
but that had the second most
so again we're looking here we're
directly recording carbon dioxide
production to yeast population